Turn 27: On Vengeful Wings (Part Fifteen)

[] Follow Carlyle's Plan

On Vengeful Wings
+070.M42+ To +075.M42+
I am a Blood Raven, born into the starry sky on wings of hate. Hate for the alien and his opposition to Man. Hate for the treason of brothers and fathers. – Reclusiarch Mikelus

“I see no other option,” Gabriel nodded. “Let us advance, and end this swiftly so that we may turn our attentions to New Meridian.”

The ships turned about once more, preparing themselves for the tortured ships to reach them. The troop ships carrying the Imperial Guard remained behind, as did the Litany of Fury. The venerable Battle Barge was truly mighty, but she had suffered most grievously in the fight, worse than she ever had in a single campaign than she ever had in the past under Gabriel’s personal stewardship. That she still flew, that she still possessed launch capacity, was purely thanks to the durability of its superstructure and its machine spirit. Gabriel was no Tech-Marine, but the cogitators had been able to spit out a repair length estimate, based largely around how much of the ship they no longer had access to due to the damage sustained, and what the internal sensors were capable of. It was not a welcome estimate, either. Even should they survive the rest of the battle, and make it out through the gravity reef once more, and then again make the lengthy travel back to the Korianis Sector, it would be quite some time to return the ship to its full capacity. More than a year, at least, depending on how blocked up the shipyards of the Forge Worlds were, especially considering how hard the Imperial Navy was requesting they work to rebuild their numbers.

So it fell to the rest of the fleet to reach the defense monitors before they could reach either the Litany or the transport ships it stood in front of. They forged forward with none other than the Great Father’s Fist, the last of the strike cruisers that had miraculously managed to make it through without suffering any damage at all. The rest of the strike cruisers and escort ships followed behind. Though the Sword had suffered as Captain Carlyle had told them all, the fearless woman drove her ship forward all the same, firing with forward facing lances the moment they came into range, something that the Imperial Navy ships at the rear contributed to as well. Unlike the ships under Admiral Graves, however, Captain Carlyle advanced in order to make use of the incredibly powerful plasma broadsides of her vessel. The defense monitors, on the other hand, were all fresh in terms of hull and munitions.

Their minds, however, were being flayed. Even through the void between celestial bodies, the Librarians could not help but hear the tearing apart of so many souls concentrated in one spot. Against the metaphysical backdrop of the Warp Tear behind them which still spewed daemons in their millions onto the planet below, it was more difficult than usual to see, but not impossible. Those who had been shackled in soul to the planet they were guarding were now being forced against their compelled orders by the very same one who bound them. It was killing them, leaving empty husks of skin and bone to collapse onto the decks of their ships. Perhaps, if given time, they would possibly die out entirely before being able to return to their normal stations – but doing so would involve them successfully wiping out the Imperials, and to surrender to such an eventuality was unacceptable.

“Here we go,” Gabriel said, having relocated to the lead strike cruiser. “All hands! Prepare for assault!”

Opening Moments: 26 vs. 53

The initial clash went by swiftly. The defense monitors were being driven by soul-bound madmen, who quite literally could not halt even if they possessed the capacity to do otherwise. As such, though the first shots of the Imperials were remarkably ineffectual, neither did the defense monitors do more than score powerful shots upon void shields. Their own shields were remarkably tough, a benefit of stripping out the warp engines in favor of reactors to power other systems. Their weapons punched powerfully into the Imperial ships. But rather than fall out into medium to long range firing, the defense monitors instead continued right on, forcing the Blood Ravens to turn about to try and keep up with them. The conclusion was obvious, of course, one reached by all and sundry within seconds of looking towards the actuality spheres on over a dozen strategiums.

“They’re going straight for the troop ships!” One Captain called, turning her Lunar-class cruiser to broadside the approaching defense monitors as swiftly as she could.

“Take out their engines first, if you can!” Captain Carlyle said back crisply.

Mix And Pass: 94 vs. 50

As the defense monitors pushed past and through the Imperial ships in the first wave, both sides of the Sword of Reckoning opened up with every single plasma macro-battery firing at once, then twice. Scans afterwards would prove that Captain Carlyle had simultaneously ordered a total shut down of life support, void shields, engines, and all secondary weapons in order to redirect all available power to said plasma batteries, violently and dangerously increasing yield and fire rate. Warning klaxons screamed, the tech-priests scrambling to ensure that the superheating of the coils did not melt them, as well as working swiftly to prevent fatal overloads of the electrical systems.

It was, however, more than worth it, or so the woman would declare to Inquisitor Adrastia when the woman awoke from her healing coma to inquire why the ship’s life sustainer was currently working overtime to remove the ship-wide stink of burnt rubber and sparking wires.

For in the aftermath four entire defense monitors were completely obliterated. Each salvo was tightly ordered, and tightly targeted, each of the four – two from each side at rapid speed – striking the ships completely. Not a single iota of the plasma failed to strike their targets, blowing them to white hot fragments that became as small meteor storms due to the continued momentum. In an instant, the enemy fleet was massively cut down in number, at the cost of leaving the Sword of Reckoning to flounder to turn about as its other systems were hastily brought back online. The Blood Raven ships were swifter in their pursuit, firing all the while. Torpedoes shot forward, and it was thanks to the defense monitors being front-facing, firing their main weapons only as they passed as well as towards the ships of Admiral Graves, that their own point defenses could not stop the torpedoes from striking them directly in their rears.

Yet still the enemy came on.

They could not do anything less, compelled by the hooks in their very souls.

Pursuit: 55 vs. 21

“Oh no you don’t,” Graves growled.

The Emperor-class battleship was largely meant as a carrier and command ship, but that did not mean that it did not possess its own weapons, its own defenses. To rely solely on attack craft was a death sentence. As such, as the defense monitors came on, firing, Graves ordered all batteries to begin firing at will. He could not stop the grimace as the void shields failed for a moment, lances and macrocannon fire scraping across the hull of his ship. But the ship weathered it all the same. It was enough to ensure that the ships coming behind the defense monitors were able to catch up, whether by torpedoes or other general weapons fire. What followed was a dangerously close fight, Graves ordering the ships most in danger to fall back or duck away, enough that the defense monitors had to reprioritize on other ships out of necessity – even if it meant that his own ship took that much more damage.

It was worth it, in the end.

Though the Sword did not recover itself in time after destroying four cruisers at once in time to strike the others, the Blood Ravens and Imperial Navy swiftly proved up to the task. It did help, of course, that the minds and souls of the enemy crews were extinguishing themselves throughout the entire fight. Their capacity slowed, their firing slacked off, and their overall responsiveness to the maneuvers of the Imperials faltered more and more. In the end, only two ships made it past the initial cordon, and weapons fire once more raked across the weakened shields of the Litany of Fury, and broke them. Yet more of the hull was scarred, digging deep, but before any truly significant damage could be done, the defense monitors – captains screaming as their mind dribbled out of their skulls – were destroyed from behind. The Great Father’s Fist had gone to full speed ahead and rammed one of the two in the rear to shatter it – the combined fire from every other ship dealing with the second.

And for a moment, it was over.

“All ships form up on me,” Graves ordered. “Damage and status reports.”

“The Sword will take some time and repair to fully recuperate from being so unleashed,” Captain Carlyle was swift to respond, her voice cutting through the sudden babble of various captains and tech-priests across the vox.

“Minor damage sustained across our strike cruisers,” Gabriel added, “Including now The Great Father’s Fist, as well as our escort ships.”

“I see. Let us set aside the next half hour to immediate repairs and reports to make themselves known,” Graves declared.

=======================================================================

“That concludes my report,” Captain Carlyle leaned back in her command throne. “The Sword will require heavy maintenance, but it is nothing that can prevent it from contributing in battle again if absolutely necessary.”

“I see,” Graves rubbed at his chin. “Well, I’d say it was worth it. Chapter Master Angelos?”

“All strike cruisers are capable of orbital bombardment, but the Litany is sluggish after the amount of damage she has sustained.”

“I believe that,” Graves huffed. “If any other ships had taken that amount of damage, it would be dust in the wind by now. The Litany is truly formidable.”

“She was, yes. And she will be again once we are done here,” Gabriel said.

Then all cast their eyes towards their actuality spheres.

“Scans show that the Warp Tear is rapidly shrinking in size. Our best estimates – if the rate of decay holds steady, though who knows,” Graves rolled his eyes, “It should be gone within twenty-four hours, somewhere around nighttime on New Meridian.”

There was for some a dark satisfaction, no doubt, at the reports from the auspex and sensor probes of what was happening on New Meridian. The daemons cared not at all that they were attacking those who were nominally aligned with them. Who worshipped them. Who summoned and bound and beseeched them. But Gabriel was not one of those. It discomforted him greatly to even consider taking such comfort in evil paying unto evil. They were daemons, and not to be trusted, thanked, or welcomed in any situation whatsoever. He held some faith that the Blood Ravens were of similar minds, but could not say the same for the Inquisitorial or Imperial Navy crews, if they were even fully aware of the ongoing circumstances.

“We are less certain on the daemons,” Justinius spoke up, the Chief Librarian’s eyes closed as they often were when he was splitting his attentions between the Materium and the Warp. “It is entirely possible that they have consumed enough souls, caused enough bloodshed, to maintain their presences beyond the Warp Tear.”

“For the moment they seem concentrated in the cross-continental hives after rampaging through the toxic wastes,” Gabriel joined in, looking at one of said reports.

“Hmm,” Graves murmured. “So. What now, then? Do we wait for the Warp Tear to close completely?”

“Not necessarily,” Colonel Gabriel Derosa coughed into his fist, drawing eyes towards his projected image. “We,” he gestured behind him to other Imperial officers, “Have been conferring. At the moment, New Meridian is in chaos. They are completely focused on eradicating the daemons. This includes, in certain areas, their orbital defenses. They were expecting ships to shoot down. Not,” he let a ghost of a smile cross his lips, “Daemons manifesting within their compounds.”

A sharp whistle came from Admiral Graves.

“God-Emperor, lad. Are you telling me you want to try to land on a Chaos-worshipping Hive World in the middle of a daemonic invasion?” Graves shook his head, a wary look on his face.

Even Captain Carlyle’s eyes had opened a modicum.

“I think we should consider it,” the Colonel answered. “There will never be a better time for them to be distracted as much as possible. If we wait until afterwards, they will be able to focus the whole of their efforts on us.”

“What’s to stop the daemons from turning on you next? Or on any of the ships as they try to land?” Captain Carlyle asked, her calm voice somehow sharpened now. “The anti-orbital defenses are still present.”

“In these zones,” he answered quickly, pressing a few runes on the console in front of him to forward scans with highlighted areas, “They are damaged, or outright inactive, though they are going to be repaired and re-staffed in time. If you will forgive my impertinence, Chapter Master?”

Gabriel lifted his chin.

“If the Blood Ravens could teleport to the surface, they might avoid fire that could otherwise knock out Thunderhawks and drop pods and see to what defenses could strike out ships from the sky – or at least secure the landing zone if there is no need to do so.”

“That…,” Gabriel paused. “Could work.”

“I understand that it would be dangerous for all involved,” Gabriel Derosa bowed his head to his namesake. “The daemons might turn on us. If the defenders manage to focus upon us despite the daemons, it could prove dangerous. We may not all make it to the surface. But,” he looked up, expression hard, “As my wife has mentioned more than once, it took her father but a single regiment to claim four worlds for the Imperium against armies of xenos and heretics aplenty.”

It was an undeniable point of pride for the Imperial Guard as a whole that one of their own had done such, without the aid of either space marines or the sisters of battle or even major support of the Mechanicus outside of usual duties. What was, to the Blood Ravens, as a terrible regretful shame, was quite the opposite to the Imperial Guard of Segmentum Ultima. At the same time, Gabriel could see just as many things as Governor Derosa’s son had offered, and then some. He could not deny, however, that there were many potential benefits as well. If they could land the majority of their troops successfully…

“It is only a suggestion, of course,” the Derosa added. “It is not as if I would try to order a landing without the rest of the task force. All of the potential landing zones are on the other side of the planet from the Warp Tear, at the least. For now, at least. If we hesitate too long on this, they may well rotate to be directly beneath the Warp Tear and its tide."

It Is Time To Choose, Chapter Master:
Vote Moratorium For 3 Hours

[] Attempt Landing Now
-[] Landing Zone 1: Deep within the Toxic Wastes outside of the main cross-continental hive which covers two thirds of New Meridian, this landing zone saw the least amount of daemonic attentions and is particularly hostile to life outside of the secured passages leading from defense station to outpost to trams which lead back to the hives proper. The guns here are still mostly active, from defense lasers built to shoot down entire ships to flak arrays meant to shoot down drop pods and aircraft. The Blood Ravens would be teleported down first, alone, to attempt to deal with these various stations and their defenders. Afterwards, the Imperial Guard would be able to land all their ships at their leisure, somewhat at least, and utilize the tunnels to head to the Hives.
-[] Landing Zone 2: A midway point between the Toxic Wastes and the New Meridian Hives, the daemons washed through here swiftly on their way towards bigger masses of humanity. There are less anti-orbital defenses online to deal with, but the forces of New Meridian sent some troops here to reinforce those that are still active. The Blood Ravens would have to deal with both to allow the Imperial Guard and Inquisitorial Stormtroopers to begin landing. It would be somewhat risky to land the ship here, as they would likely not be able to lift off again due to surrounding anti-orbital defenses, but full deployment would be possible.
-[] Landing Zone 3: Directly on the edge of the Toxic Wastes and the Hives, the anti-orbital defenses here are almost entirely gone. The daemons were here in their thickest numbers compared to the other zones, and as such caused significant damages. New Meridian troops came here in force to battle them, only pulling back somewhat to deal with incursions elsewhere. Landing here would allow now just teleportation, but thunderhawk and valkyrie transports to land other troops to help secure the landing zones for the much, much larger troop ships. At the same time, the daemons might well return for new targets, and the defenders of New Meridian would immediately become aware of the Imperial presence and will likely respond just as swiftly. Fully disembarking may end up taking place while under fire.

OR

[] Attempt Landing Later, With A Different Plan: Write-In

Spoiler: Imperial Forces

Blood Ravens
1st Company
SC Spiraling Fury [Minor Damage]
2 Escorts (1 Gladius, 1 Hunter Destroyer) [Minor Damage]
5th Company
BB Litany of Fury [Bombardment Cannon Non-Operational, Majority of Weapon Arrays Destroyed, Shield Arrays At 15%, Extreme Hull Damage] DANGER: Litany of Fury will require significant attentions at a Mechanicus Shipyard for repairs. Any notable damage may disable ship in permanency.
SC Rage of Erudition [Minor Damage]
SC The Great Father’s Fist [Minor Damage]
7 Escorts (x3 Gladius, x2 Hunter Destroyers, x2 Nova) [Minor Damage]

Reminder of Blood Raven Forces:
10 1st Company Marines in Terminator Armor, Chief Librarian Justinius, Epistolary Lucan, Epistolary Idmon, Codicier Aeneas (+12 Codiciers, 10 Lexicanum, 11 Telepathica Recruit Lexicanum)
37 5th Company Marines, including Command Squad, 3 Dreadnoughts including Captain Davian Thule.

Apollo Diomedes Requires Master of the Forge or Senior Techmarines To Forge The Bionics Required To Return To Battle-Capable State, But Will Not Require Dreadnought Internment. Remains In Suspended Animation Until Then.

Gabriel Angelos Conscious, Lack of Senior Tech-Marine or Master of the Forge Means Bionics Unable To Be Fully Repaired. (Combat Capacity 65%)

Confirmed Blood Raven Losses:
Honor Guard Captain Doukas Laskaris (Relic Bloodtalon Destroyed) (Single Gene-Seed Recovered, +1 Gene-Seed)
Apothecary Falkor Ryll (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
Chaplain Uther Volkoss (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
3 Honor Guard (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
4 Lexicanum (Gene-Seed Recovered, +8 Gene-Seed)
3 Codiciers (Gene-Seed Recovered, +6 Gene-Seed)
5th Company Chaplain Tarion (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
2 5th Company Marines (+3 Gene-Seed Recovered, 1 Destroyed In Battle)
1st Company Assault Terminator Sergeant Minos (+2 Gene-Seed Recovered)
9 1st Company Marines In Terminator Armor (+18 Gene-Seed Recovered)
34 5th Company Marines (+50 Gene-Seed Recovered, 18 Destroyed In Battle)
5 Lexicanum (+10 Gene-Seed Recovered)
2 Codiciers (4 Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
2 5th Company Marines (+4 Gene-Seed Recovered)
3 5th Company Marines (6 Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)

Imperial Navy:
1 An Emperor-class Battleship (Moderate Damage) (Interceptor Compliment Down By 90%)
3 Lunar-class Cruisers (Moderate Damage)
4 Frigates (Moderate Damage)
20 Troop Transports (Carrying Imperial Guard Forces) / 1 Galaxy-class Troop Transport (Carrying Imperial Guard Forces)

All Void Armsmen Utilized In Boarding Lost (Remaining Void Armsmen Now Depleted To Severely Understrength Levels)

Imperial Guard:

15 Meridian Consolidated Imperial Guard Regiments (5 Infantry/5 Mechanized Infantry/5 Armored) [1 Regiment's Worth of Casualties Evenly Spread Amongst The 5 Infantry Regiments]
1 Kauravan Superheavy Armored Formation - 15 Lucius-Pattern Baneblades of Kaurava Attached To Armored Meridian Regiment, commanded by Colonel Stubbs of Kaurava
1 Meridian Storm Trooper Regiment (10th Meridian Consolidated)
1 Inquisitorial Storm Trooper Regiment (Ordo Hereticus) [1/3 Casualties Sustained]

Inquisition
1 Inquisitorial Grand Cruiser, Vengeance-class Sword of Reckoning (Custom Variant, Heavily Modified) (Moderate Damage)

Imperial Ship Losses:
All Fire Ships
2 Avenger-class Grand Cruisers
5 Lunar-class Cruisers
6 Frigates

Spoiler: Confirmed Enemy Slain

10 Soul-Tortured Defense Monitor Cruisers [800,000~ Crew Total]
110,000~ New Meridian Vandian Stormtroopers
2,000,000~ New Meridian Vandian Guard
10,000,000~ New Meridian Conscripts
15,000,000~ New Meridian Menials
500,000~ Saharduin (Piscean Warriors, Alien Crew Members, Engineer Caste, Blood Shamans, Etc.)
Reaverlord Carnax, Khornate Alien Warlord
Grand Hunter Hraxe, Slaaneshi Alien Warlord
Admiral Maximilian Vandis, New Meridian Defense Fleet Commander
New Meridian Defense Defense Fleet: Estimated Crews At 10,000,000 (Including All Ships, Orbital Stations, Shipyard)
Nascent Forge World Opux Maxima: Enemy Populace Estimated At 1.2 Billion (Including Menials, Hereteks, Magos Hereteks, Masters of Forge-Hives, Skitarii, Obliterators, Daemon-Machines, Chaos Knights, Tanks, Artillery, Experimentals, etc.)
Fabricator-General Drakis
Black Legion Sorcerer Lord Melphas
3 Lesser Black Legion Sorcerers
322 Black Legion Chaos Space Marines
125 Black Legion Veteran Chaos Space Marines
24 Khornate Berserkers
2.2 Million Dark Mechanicus Menials
10,000~ Dark Mechanicus Hereteks
1 Dark Mechanicus Magos 01b7, Master of Forge-Hive 01b7
5,000 Gene-Hound Shocktrooper Abominations
25,0000~ Heavy Combat Servitors
300,000~ Dark Mechanicus Skitarii
10,000~ Dark Mechanicus Elite Skitarii
20,000~ Cultist Troopers
7000 Elite Cultist Stormtroopers
100 Soulrend Obliterators

Turn 27: On Vengeful Wings (Part Sixteen)

[] Attempt Landing Now
-[] Landing Zone 2: A midway point between the Toxic Wastes and the New Meridian Hives, the daemons washed through here swiftly on their way towards bigger masses of humanity. There are less anti-orbital defenses online to deal with, but the forces of New Meridian sent some troops here to reinforce those that are still active. The Blood Ravens would have to deal with both to allow the Imperial Guard and Inquisitorial Stormtroopers to begin landing. It would be somewhat risky to land the ship here, as they would likely not be able to lift off again due to surrounding anti-orbital defenses, but full deployment would be possible.

On Vengeful Wings
+070.M42+ To +075.M42+
I am a Blood Raven, born into the starry sky on wings of hate. Hate for the alien and his opposition to Man. Hate for the treason of brothers and fathers. – Reclusiarch Mikelus

The decision was made, the teleportariums readied. What forces the Blood Ravens had assembled upon them, waiting there for the moment of transition. There was no point in holding back anyone. The 5th and 1st Company were joined by their leadership, Captain Tarkus, Chapter Master Angelos, and Chief Librarian Justinian Probalis. So too were the various now oversized squads, cobbled together from survivors, joined by the remainder of the Librarius as well. Teleporting was never a zero-risk maneuver, and already some Blood Ravens had been lost to the Warp as a result of earlier events despite technically successfully being teleported. Below, New Meridian, choked with smog and anarchy and heretics, slowly rotated as a tide of daemons swept down upon it.

Rather inauspiciously, a single servitor was granted the rare right to speak across the whole of the Chapter’s command vox.

“Litany of Fury teleportarium arrays Primus and Secundus have been activated. All non-deploying personnel, evacuate teleportarium chambers. Canticles of safety enacted. Canticles of deployment begun: transition in five…,”

Gabriel looked to Justinian, who simply nodded back. Though his bionics were not yet fully repaired, he still yet was a space marine who could fight. As were all of their battle brothers, many still bearing newly sutured wounds and suffering from minute blood loss. The only Blood Raven who would not be deploying would be Apollo, still locked into an intensive bout of suspended animation that was keeping him alive.

“Four…,”

Codicier Aeneas muttered a benediction of purpose and zeal, his force sword glowing brighter as he did so.

“Three…,”

Sergeant Stromahn, last leader of the 1st Company alive now that his friend and brother-sergeant had died fighting Mortirex, inhaled deeply and rechecked his ammo counter for the assault cannon once more.

“Two…,”

Captain Thule was motionless, both his body as it floated in the fluids of his sarcophagus, and the sarcophagus itself. His mind was swamped in shadow, and as ever he struggled to push back against it. The tyranid toxin had long been successfully excised from his system, but he still yet felt its acidic burning touch in his mind. It was, perhaps, a terrible irony that such phantom pains could invigorate him, though just as often the anguish drove him to mindless depths. This, however, would be the former. He twitched, and felt satisfied by the readouts from the multi-melta.

“One. May the Emperor watch over you.”

And then there was light. Madness. Screams. Horror.

Going Down: 74

Within the defensive complexes built around three separate defense laser stations that were still operational, the Blood Ravens appeared in eye-searing eruptions of thunder and light. Almost all of them bore new claw marks on their armor. Some appeared in the air, at least ten feet up, and had to prepare themselves for the impact as gravity reasserted itself. Davian Thule shifted his weight, sensors detecting a simply massive gash that had appeared on the rear of his sarcophagus that had come dangerously close to severing the power connectors to the multi-melta, which might have resulted in a fatal overload. Somehow, every single remaining terminator of the 1st Company had been separated from one another, despite assembling in a tight formation in the teleportarium. Some within guard houses filled with Vandis troopers, and three outside in the wasteland outside the compounds themselves.

There was no hesitation.

The Landing Zones: 89 vs. 46

Facing them, in all directions, were the troops of New Meridian. Sensors and eyes alike fell upon the enemy, noting down all that was possible in those less-than-heartbeats. These troopers were somewhat equipped much like the naval armsmen that had served the Chaos ships, with most covered in flak armor. On the other hand, many of them bore plasma guns, grenade launchers, and combat shotguns. These troopers took in the new arrivals, full body armors concealing their expressions but not their body language of shock and surprise. It was this which allowed the Blood Ravens to reap a bloody toll in the first moments, bolters and heavy weapons firing at close range. Gates and heavy weapon emplacements that were normally pointed outwards were targeted by the dreadnoughts, plasma and melta beams turning them to slag, as well as those manning them that had begun frantically trying to turn them around.

The Landing Zones: 84 vs. 50

The walls of one defense laser compound shattered as a trio of terminators broke it down with their power fists. At another, a cyclone missile launcher salvo eradicated an entire group of rallying guards with plasma guns that had seared chunks of armor out of a number of 5th Company marines who had just barely managed to avoid being killed outright. Gabriel Angelos brought his daemon-hammer down upon a chimera tank, the explosion shifting it to the side slightly and ruining the aim of the gunner manning its multi-las cupola installment. A blast of flame from Kaius Jacobus killed the gunner, a handful of seconds of pointing his flamer through the now empty cupola into the troop compartment killed the rest. Grenades meant to supply the whole of the 5th Company and more were thrown, one after another, turning bunkers into charnel houses and armored defenses into shattered ruins.

The Landing Zones: 54 vs. 84

Whether it was desperation, the unexpected amount of heavy weapons capable of dealing damage to space marines, or a strength lent by the Dark Gods, the defending troopers put up an absolutely ferocious defense the further into the compounds the Blood Ravens penetrated. The result was never in doubt, of course, but the fact of the matter was that several Lexicanum, not normally meant for such open combat, suffered notable wounds that required them to be pulled back from the fighting to be tended to by the apothecaries. Brother Gaius, of the 1st Company, was assaulted by a number of suicide troopers wearing vests full of krak grenades, wounding the veteran and heavily damaging his armor enough for him to be rendered incapable of combat for the foreseeable future. Brother Julius, of the 5th, was ambushed as he hunted down the last of a platoon of Vandis troopers by a trio of men who had carried a heavy bolter together to fire upon him. The resulting wounds resulted in him falling into suspended animation, and it was highly likely he would require dreadnought internment.

In the end, however, the defiance of the troops of New Meridian could not hold off the Blood Ravens forever. They fell back until they could fall back no longer, and then died in their holdout positions. Attempts to detonate the reactors of the defense lasers, such things meant to allow las blasts to strike into space itself, failed only because the Blood Ravens reached such saboteurs-to-be before they could accomplish their tasks. Tallies were made of the dead, the living, and the wounded. The fight, however, was not yet done. The defense lasers were the biggest threats to the actual ships above. And though there were a number of batteries of hydra flak tanks – yet another proof that Vandis had long been utilizing Angel Forge for themselves – within the defense laser compounds, there were smaller vehicle parks and artillery bases spread throughout the immediate region. So long as those remained, thunderhawks, drop pods, and Valkyrie transports would not be safe to utilize, their anti-air envelop covering miles and miles.

“You have your targets, brothers, move out!” Gabriel ordered, placing his helmet over his head.

The Toxic Wastes were well named. The gasses that rose up from the crevices in the earth of the area of much of the planet were dangerous not simply to the lungs, but to the very skin. Centuries and centuries of industrial waste and sewage dumping out of the hive had transformed what was already an inhospitable place to one that was outright hostile to life in general. Only the secure tunnels and high-walled and shielded compounds with their airlocks were safe from it – and thus the environment itself became yet another defensive implement in the arsenal of the defenders of New Meridian. This had always been the assumption. Even the cybernetic monstrosities that the planet’s acolytes of the Omnissiah – the true Omnissiah , the hereteks would insist – had been tested and many times been found wanting against the wastes before centuries of improvement. In the always assumed potential for attack, the tunnels could be closed, opened to the wastes themselves, or blocked off with void shields that could obscure whole portions of the defense laser network.

Furthermore, House Vandis had stolen from none other than the Blood Ravens themselves and had fought against them in the 2nd Aurelian Crusade.

They were not foolish enough to think that the Blood Ravens would not eventually come for them. To be sure, they had not imagined the Blood Ravens would be so weakened after their trials and tribulations to be left with but two understrength companies with which to try and fulfill their inevitable vengeful impulses, but many had proclaimed it a blessing of the Dark Gods.

Outer Emplacements: 35 vs. 48

Nevertheless, they had not quite expected the Blood Ravens to go around the blocked off tunnels, and instead simply trudge through the wastes themselves. Acidic sludge sizzled and popped against ceramite, enveloping many marines all the way up to the head, but such was the speed of the space marines that it was not given the time to eat all the way through. Mines and detonation packs into rapidly dug holes breached the compounds from below, while a trio of dreadnoughts simply stomped out of the poison mist to unleash their multi-meltas and missile launchers are close range and blow their way in. Unlike before, however, they had heard the distress calls of the defense laser compounds, and thus were prepared for the Blood Ravens – as much as one could be. Ceramite glowed, was chipped, pitted, and in some cases broken, but by that point the Blood Ravens were already largely in.

Outer Emplacements: 40 vs. 55

Explosive shells were pumped into the space marines from shotguns as they approached. Heavy bolter weapons teams had shifted about in advance for the Blood Ravens, turning corridors into kill zones. Armories had been broken open, and every explosive possible had been prepared. At some of the batteries, the flak tanks had swiveled about to turn their eviscerating fire upon the Blood Ravens, the firepower meant to punch through aircraft certainly capable of making it past ceramite in most cases. Mines, hastily deployed, blocked off areas for a time before purposeful attacks detonated them from afar. Missile launchers fired down range exploded with enough force to send shrapnel flying into power armor, while volleys from grenade launchers proved enough to knock some of the marines off their feet entirely before they could extricate themselves from such targeted zones.

Outer Emplacements: 75 vs. 28

Doggedly, however, the Blood Ravens came on. Many of them bled, many of them ignored their broken or fractured bones, and came on regardless. Combat knifes cut, power fists crackled and tore, and soon enough the Blood Ravens brought their own heavy weapons to bear. Where bolters did not suffice, storm bolters and assault cannons would. Where normal frag grenades did not break the enemy, missile launchers, flamers, and cyclone salvoes did. Before the dreadnoughts, none of the enemy were safe, their claws and multi-meltas rendering all impotent before them. Though it would be noted in the aftermath that Tomb-Brother Nathan had suffered several missile strikes, nearly cracking through his armor, and severely damaging the machinery of his legs – forcing him into intensive maintenance afterwards – though certainly his insistence on continuing to fight until the enemy stopped only more severely impacted such damage.

Until finally, finally, the last of the emplacements was taken or destroyed.

Gabriel gazed upon his Blood Ravens, and their many wounds, and closed his eyes in quiet reverence as the apothecaries saw to the retrieval of battle-brother’s Horatius and Magnus’ gene-seed.

“Angelos to all. Landing zone secured. Monitoring of enemy communications shows that they are aware we’ve taken the area, but they are still trying to determine the correct response.”

“Understood. We will begin landing troops immediately,” Colonel Gabriel Derosa answered immediately.

“Stormtroopers will be descending to secure the area,” Captain Carlyle announced. “Until the Inquisitor awakens, that is as far as I am willing to push my authority over them – they shall keep the landing zones defended throughout the deployment process.”

Gabriel nodded at the news, though of course neither of them could see.

“Admiral Graves, keep us informed if you see any major movements from orbit.”

“Of course, Chapter Master.”

A familiar presence made itself known, the clogging gasses and stinking air pushed away with a minor effort of will as Justinian approached.

“And what of us?” Justinian asked, the arching of his eyebrows suggested only in his voice with his face concealed. “We can defend the landing zone now until the Imperial Guard have fully finished landing…or try and make punitive scouting efforts into the hives.”

Gabriel tilted his head back and forth.

“Perhaps, Justinian. We might also work to secure the tunnels leading to the hives proper, rather than advancing ourselves alone.”

“I see.”

The Chief Librarian shook his head and glanced north to the hives they spoke of.

“This planet reeks of Chaos and the whispers of daemons are constant – I suspect that is true even on days when there isn’t a massive tear in the Warp. I had thought to try and find Vandis through that…morass, but it is like looking for a particular piece of excrement in a sea of it. It all blends together far too easily…purposefully, I’d say.”

“Would that we could simply destroy this world from orbit,” Gabriel grunted, looking away, “Vandis could too easily slip away, however. Into the Warp, most likely, where we could not reach him.”

“We could attempt to blockade the gravity reef from the outside,” Justinian replied, though his heart was not in the argument.

“And be unsurprised when the innards of this system becomes a Warp Storm, or this celestial wreckage transforms into some sort of Daemonworld, or any manner of monstrosity, able to pump through an endless tide of daemons through the gravity reef, forcing us to try and send our ships back through the shifting tunnels and do…nothing effectual, all without ending Vandis for certain,” Gabriel shook his head. “No. There are too many possibilities of these slaves to the Dark Gods reversing our efforts here, possibilities that will not halt until we have definitively dealt with Vandis, one way or another.”

He had faced the vagaries of Chaos too many times over, in too many horrifying shapes and methods, to ever think otherwise.

“I know,” Justinian said, a quirk to his lips. “Just making sure you knew that.”

“You wouldn’t simply read my mind for it?”

Justinian splayed his fingers against the blue armor of his breastplate.

“Angelos. You know I would not cause issue to the sanctity of my fellow battle brother’s minds without cause.”

A humorless smile managed to make its way across Gabriel’s lips as he turned to face the Blood Ravens before him.

“Blood Ravens, hear me!”

Chapter Master Choices For Blood Raven Deployment
Moratorium For 3 Hours - Note, you do not have to allocate all Blood Ravens to a single choice, you can pick and choose.
[] Dedicate Forces To Defending Landing Zone Until Imperial Guard Finish Deploying (Write-In Forces Allocated)
[] Dedicate Forces To Securing Tunnels Heading Towards Cross-Continental Hive (Write-In Forces Allocated)
[] Dedicate Forces To Advanced Recon/Scouting Of Cross-Continental Hive

Spoiler: Imperial Forces

Blood Ravens
1st Company
SC Spiraling Fury [Minor Damage]
2 Escorts (1 Gladius, 1 Hunter Destroyer) [Minor Damage]
5th Company
BB Litany of Fury [Bombardment Cannon Non-Operational, Majority of Weapon Arrays Destroyed, Shield Arrays At 15%, Extreme Hull Damage] DANGER: Litany of Fury will require significant attentions at a Mechanicus Shipyard for repairs. Any notable damage may disable ship in permanency.
SC Rage of Erudition [Minor Damage]
SC The Great Father’s Fist [Minor Damage]
7 Escorts (x3 Gladius, x2 Hunter Destroyers, x2 Nova) [Minor Damage]

Reminder of Blood Raven Forces Capable of Combat:
9 1st Company Marines in Terminator Armor, Chief Librarian Justinius, Epistolary Lucan, Epistolary Idmon, Codicier Aeneas (+10 Codiciers, 2 Lexicanum, 11 Telepathica Recruit Lexicanum)
35 5th Company Marines, including Command Squad, 2 Dreadnoughts including Captain Davian Thule.

15 5th Company Marines Moderately Wounded But Combat Capable

Apollo Diomedes Requires Master of the Forge or Senior Techmarines To Forge The Bionics Required To Return To Battle-Capable State, But Will Not Require Dreadnought Internment. Remains In Suspended Animation Until Then.

Gabriel Angelos Conscious, Lack of Senior Tech-Marine or Master of the Forge Means Bionics Unable To Be Fully Repaired. (Combat Capacity 65%)

Apothecaries/Tech-Priests Working On Below
2 Codiciers Too Wounded To Fight In Next Phase Of Battle
8 Lexicanum Too Wounded To Fight In Next Phase Of Battle
1 Tomb-Brother Nathan Too Damaged To Fight In Next Phase Of Battle
1 1st Company Marine Too Wounded To Fight In Next Phase Of Batttle

Confirmed Blood Raven Losses:
Honor Guard Captain Doukas Laskaris (Relic Bloodtalon Destroyed) (Single Gene-Seed Recovered, +1 Gene-Seed)
Apothecary Falkor Ryll (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
Chaplain Uther Volkoss (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
3 Honor Guard (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
4 Lexicanum (Gene-Seed Recovered, +8 Gene-Seed)
3 Codiciers (Gene-Seed Recovered, +6 Gene-Seed)
5th Company Chaplain Tarion (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
2 5th Company Marines (+3 Gene-Seed Recovered, 1 Destroyed In Battle)
1st Company Assault Terminator Sergeant Minos (+2 Gene-Seed Recovered)
9 1st Company Marines In Terminator Armor (+18 Gene-Seed Recovered)
34 5th Company Marines (+50 Gene-Seed Recovered, 18 Destroyed In Battle)
5 Lexicanum (+10 Gene-Seed Recovered)
2 Codiciers (4 Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
2 5th Company Marines (+4 Gene-Seed Recovered)
3 5th Company Marines (6 Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
2 5th Company Marines (+4 Gene-Seed Recovered)

Imperial Navy:
1 An Emperor-class Battleship (Moderate Damage) (Interceptor/Troop Transport Compliment Down By 90%, Bomber Compliment At 100%)
3 Lunar-class Cruisers (Moderate Damage)
4 Frigates (Moderate Damage)
20 Troop Transports (Carrying Imperial Guard Forces) / 1 Galaxy-class Troop Transport (Carrying Imperial Guard Forces)

All Void Armsmen Utilized In Boarding Lost (Remaining Void Armsmen Now Depleted To Severely Understrength Levels)

Imperial Guard:

15 Meridian Consolidated Imperial Guard Regiments (5 Infantry/5 Mechanized Infantry/5 Armored) [1 Regiment's Worth of Casualties Evenly Spread Amongst The 5 Infantry Regiments]
1 Kauravan Superheavy Armored Formation - 15 Lucius-Pattern Baneblades of Kaurava Attached To Armored Meridian Regiment, commanded by Colonel Stubbs of Kaurava
1 Meridian Storm Trooper Regiment (10th Meridian Consolidated)
1 Inquisitorial Storm Trooper Regiment (Ordo Hereticus) [1/3 Casualties Sustained]

Inquisition
1 Inquisitorial Grand Cruiser, Vengeance-class Sword of Reckoning (Custom Variant, Heavily Modified) (Moderate Damage)

Imperial Ship Losses:
All Fire Ships
2 Avenger-class Grand Cruisers
5 Lunar-class Cruisers
6 Frigates

Spoiler: Confirmed Enemy Slain

Dozens of Hydra Flak Tanks And Anti-Aircraft Specced Manticore Tanks
10 Soul-Tortured Defense Monitor Cruisers [800,000~ Crew Total]
115,000~ New Meridian Vandian Stormtroopers
3,003,000~ New Meridian Vandian Guard
12,000,000~ New Meridian Conscripts
20,000,000~ New Meridian Menials
500,000~ Saharduin (Piscean Warriors, Alien Crew Members, Engineer Caste, Blood Shamans, Etc.)
Reaverlord Carnax, Khornate Alien Warlord
Grand Hunter Hraxe, Slaaneshi Alien Warlord
Admiral Maximilian Vandis, New Meridian Defense Fleet Commander
New Meridian Defense Defense Fleet: Estimated Crews At 10,000,000 (Including All Ships, Orbital Stations, Shipyard)
Nascent Forge World Opux Maxima: Enemy Populace Estimated At 1.2 Billion (Including Menials, Hereteks, Magos Hereteks, Masters of Forge-Hives, Skitarii, Obliterators, Daemon-Machines, Chaos Knights, Tanks, Artillery, Experimentals, etc.)
Fabricator-General Drakis
Black Legion Sorcerer Lord Melphas
3 Lesser Black Legion Sorcerers
322 Black Legion Chaos Space Marines
125 Black Legion Veteran Chaos Space Marines
24 Khornate Berserkers
2.2 Million Dark Mechanicus Menials
10,000~ Dark Mechanicus Hereteks
1 Dark Mechanicus Magos 01b7, Master of Forge-Hive 01b7
5,000 Gene-Hound Shocktrooper Abominations
25,0000~ Heavy Combat Servitors
300,000~ Dark Mechanicus Skitarii
10,000~ Dark Mechanicus Elite Skitarii
20,000~ Cultist Troopers
7000 Elite Cultist Stormtroopers
100 Soulrend Obliterators

Turn 27: On Vengeful Wings (Part Seventeen)

[] Plan Knowledge is Power
-[] Dedicate Forces To Defending Landing Zone Until Imperial Guard Finish Deploying (Everything not being sent to scout)
-[] Dedicate Forces To Advanced Recon/Scouting Of Cross-Continental Hive (15 Uninjured Marines, 5 Codiciers including Aneas, Epistolary Idmon)

On Vengeful Wings
+070.M42+ To +075.M42+
I am a Blood Raven, born into the starry sky on wings of hate. Hate for the alien and his opposition to Man. Hate for the treason of brothers and fathers. – Reclusiarch Mikelus

New Meridian was a hellish place. All of the worst practices of the Imperium twisted and magnified further by the work of House Vandis and their loyalists over the course of over at thousand years. In an isolated system, all resources needed to be exploited appropriately. It was only made worse with the addition of Heretek-born techno-heresy. Corpse-starch was one thing, but the total abuse of the soul continued long after the body was exsanguinated and pulped in other purposes. It was only worsened by the indoctrination from before birth towards worship of the Dark Gods. For the vast majority, sacrifice was merely a part of life, it was proper, it was expected. Those few who resisted did not last long either, or else managed to hide it right up until the end, but the end came all the same. Rituals to summon and bind daemons. To be pulped and mashed within warp-based machinery to become fuel for daemon-engines or to keep the manufactorums functioning. To serve as sustenance for the most corrupted of the nobility. Even having spent time on Forge Worlds in the past, which were their own smoke-wreathed horrors, the planet was particularly horrific to set foot upon for a psyker.

The Chapter Master could not have understood, no matter what the Chief Librarian had told him, Idmon knew. It was easier to speak as to the difficulty of finding Vandis because of baffles or misdirection, rather than try to explain what it was to be forced to listen to the screams of a billion souls as they were steadily ground down, digested, or consumed outright. Many were echoes of echoes, fragments of fragments, but every moment, every single second, more fully formed souls were thrust into the Immaterium from sudden and unexpected deaths. Those without the cursed blessing of the psyker mutation could perhaps think of it as looking through an auspex and getting a return for so many overlapping contacts that it appeared a single mass, something akin to a tyranid swarm. But it would not be the same, because the psyker would have to contend with those billion souls and their individual, completely unique, personalized pleas and screams. Those who had fallen into a vat of molten metals. Those exposed to toxic gasses. Those dying of starvation and sickness. Those who had gone proudly to the sacrifice, only to scream in pain as the truth of their ‘blessed reward’ revealed itself as they were torn to shreds.

It was, quite literally, maddening.

And yet they could not shut it out, lest they be without warning should a foe approach or attempt to attack them through the Immaterium.

Idmon ground his teeth at this before sighing and letting the frustration flow out of him. The task force was assembled, as were the codiciers who would be there to aid them in battle.

“You have your assignments. Get to it,” he proclaimed. “Do not allow yourselves to be separated. Aeneas? With me.”

The Epistolary and Codicier stalked forward alone as the scouts divided out and began their work.

=======================================================================

Scouting: 65

Defense: 96

Kaius Jacobus could not inhale the fumes of burning promethium, but he could certainly feel them. The entire plateau was aflame, the fires from the various burning vehicles, the spilled tanks of promethium, and the bodies all mixed together to force out the green and black of the toxic and acidic fog. It didn’t actually purify the air, if anything it was making it worse, but his own armor and physiology was capable of withstanding it for a time. He holstered the flamer he bore and glanced around, nodding once in satisfaction with his hands on his hips as some of his fellow 5th Company marines saw to setting the last of the charges. This was the sort of work he was more accustomed to, and this only proved it. It was one thing to be put into position of Champion in a time of desperation, but his own skills and combat preferences did not lend themselves to single face to face combat in the name of a Company’s honor. He would have to petition Captain Tarkus to allow him to return to the 10th Company after this, he knew. It was wrong to deprive the 5th of a proper Champion simply because of prior desperation putting him into the position.

“Chapter Master, this is Jacobus. Artillery company destroyed. We’ve destroyed their supplies as well and are planting explosives to remove this as a functional position for the future.”

“Good work,” the Chapter Master’s voice dipped and raised oddly through the crackling vox. “That is the last of them. With the tunnels taken and now fortified into proper kill zones, our position is unassailable save for air support – the Guard has landed numerous vehicles for just such a purpose already.”

Kaius shifted his weight as one of the broken basilisks exploded.

“What of our scouts, Chapter Master?”

“We have reports of significant enemy movement, they are undoubtably aware of us. The commanders of Vandis’ forces are apparently accepting significant losses amongst their populace to shift their military strength towards us as quickly as possible.”

Callous but likely effective, Kaius cursed silently.

“Any more details?”

“Concentrations of their specialized gene-soldiers that we have faced before,” came the disgusted response. “They match us in strength and speed, but they are mockeries of the Emperor’s holy work. Analysis has already shown they have effective lifetimes shorter than even Eversors, and yet they are deploying them in massive numbers. Worse, the enemy has deployed their own psykers, forcing our scouts back and out of enemy territory sooner than expected.”

“We will return immediately then,” Kaius said quickly, a few curt hand gestures making the Blood Ravens around him form up.

“That is well, we are issuing a general recall order to all battle brothers to prepare for the first thrust into the heart of the enemy – the Imperial Guard has landed their most elite elements to join us, as full deployment may well take days given their numbers.”

The inability for the Imperial Guard, or at least the Adeptus Administratum, to keep Imperial Guard regiments to a regulated number was as confusing to Kaius as ever. Some regiments were but a few hundred strong, while others could be vastly larger. It simply depending on the planet, the sector, the Segmentum. At the very least he could take solace in the fact that the Meridian-based regiments were all raised from a hive world and furthermore actually had a standard set of numbers for full, half, and under strength. The former scout began moving at full speed through the toxic fog, combat knife burying itself in a beast twice his size that tried to rear up out of the muck without stopping his run.

“I understand. We shall be there soon.”

Less than a minute later they detonated the plateau behind them, removing the last bit of flat ground above the acidic fog line within artillery range of their occupied outposts.

==========================================================

Gabriel shut off the vox as the Baneblades came roaring off of their transports, reactors fully awakened and pulsing. Their victory pennants and marks were on full display as their lead tank rumbled forward at high speed before coming to a sudden halt, one of its sponson weapons a foot away from clipping Gabriel. The cupola swung open and then slammed shut after Colonel Stubbs revealed herself, the veteran daughter of the famous General and Governor Vance Stubbs now wearing a sealed environmental suit, complete with helmet and respirator. She glanced around the defense laser compound and nodded once before looking down to Gabriel, her wrist-mounted storm bolters missing for the moment.

“Chapter Master. You’ve done some work down here.”

“In the Emperor’s name, we have, and yet more remains to be done,” Gabriel said, looking up at her. “We have some initial scouting reports, but we cannot wait forever. The warp tear is sealing itself, ever so slowly, and yet even now the enemy is reorienting itself and allowing many of its people to die to do so.”

A noise of disgust escaped the woman’s throat.

“Wasteful,” she grunted. “But effective at the same time. Do we have a plan?”

“There is,” he said before looking away, “I am not pleased with it.”

“Oh?” She sounded bemused.

“My Blood Ravens can move more swiftly and effectively on our own, seeking out logistical and command centers to analyze the flow of information and orders more directly,” he said, looking now to see as a number of new Imperial Guard platoons emerged on chimeras and salamanders, the armored personnel carriers revving their engines as they moved to clear the space. “In the meantime, the enemy must remain focused elsewhere.”

“Ah,” the Colonel said while lifting her chin. “And so, who better to grasp and hold the attention of the Great Enemy than the teeming masses of the Imperial Guard.”

“It is a distasteful plan, I am aware,” Gabriel shook his head, looking down for a moment. “But with Vandis hiding like a coward, and his own psykers and sorcerers working to prevent our own from locating him…,”

“I did not say that it was a plan without merit,” she chided calmly, making him look back up at her. “This is not my first war. A Guardsman’s duty is to die and die well. Our lives, noble or otherwise, are meant to be spent – it is simply a matter of whether they are spent needlessly or not.”

The Kauravan tapped her foot along the hull as she paced for a moment.

“We cannot hope to fight them with this as an island, we have far too many troops for that. We must advance into the hive itself and chain our FOBs forward,” she said as she moved. “And the more space we open up for ourselves, the greater our ability to command the enemy’s attention, correct?”

“That was the assumption, yes,” Gabriel said, shifting slightly as a new group of Valkyrie transports almost slammed into the ground at high speed before shoving out new platoons of soldiers and then shooting up in the atmosphere again.

“Hrmph. The Inquisitorial Stormtroopers might do the sort of work you're talking about, but they won’t deploy without the Inquisitor’s permission and she’s still in a coma after her emergency surgery and the daemon that manifested in the operating theater,” she growled. “No. It is a workable plan, Chapter Master. Brutal. Hard. But quite likely direly necessary.”

Gabriel opened his mouth to speak and then shut it again. Was there another way? The Blood Ravens did not care for heedless jumping into battle like some Chapters. It was, generally, far more effective to analyze, to reconnoiter, to study, and then to strike with a plan that was formulated with all possible data. But they had no time for that. It was an emergency deployment, essentially, relying on speed and boldness more than anything else. It was, he thought bitterly, Tartarus all over again, where he had lost a third of his company in the last few hours, first defending Magna Bonum, then to Isador, and then to Sindri.

But then again, he had been victorious on Tartarus, though it had become a hollow one in retrospect.

This time…he swore to himself that he would do better. As such, even now, he thought over the plan, the methods, the ideas, trying to always seek the best possible path forward to reach Vandis. Some of the wounded Blood Ravens had been seen to, as best as could be done. Others were still not yet ready. At the least, honorable Tomb-Brother Nathan was once more fully functional, and the minor damage sustained by his fellow dreadnoughts had been repaired as well. Even so, none of them, not even Captain Thule, would be able to keep up if they committed to the plan, and would have to be left behind to fight alongside the Imperial Guard. It was not, he knew, the worst possible fate. Despite the unpleasantness on Kronus, Captain Thule respected the Imperial Guard well enough.

"Very well," Gabriel inhaled deeply, letting the toxins be filtered out entirely. "Let us to it."

Chapter Master Choices
Moratorium 3 Hours
[] Deep Searching: Allow the Imperial Guard to take the brunt of the enemy attentions as the Blood Ravens seek out enemy command positions and logistics strongholds to seek to analyze the flow of information and - more importantly - control. Find Vandis, or at the least enemy commanders who can then have their own centers searched, or be interrogated themselves. The dreadnoughts, being incapable of such rapid high speed movement, will stay behind and help fight alongside the Imperial Guard.
[] Something Else: Write-In A Different Plan

Spoiler: Imperial Forces

Blood Ravens
1st Company
SC Spiraling Fury [Minor Damage]
2 Escorts (1 Gladius, 1 Hunter Destroyer) [Minor Damage]
5th Company
BB Litany of Fury [Bombardment Cannon Non-Operational, Majority of Weapon Arrays Destroyed, Shield Arrays At 15%, Extreme Hull Damage] DANGER: Litany of Fury will require significant attentions at a Mechanicus Shipyard for repairs. Any notable damage may disable ship in permanency.
SC Rage of Erudition [Minor Damage]
SC The Great Father’s Fist [Minor Damage]
7 Escorts (x3 Gladius, x2 Hunter Destroyers, x2 Nova) [Minor Damage]

Reminder of Blood Raven Forces Capable of Combat:
9 1st Company Marines in Terminator Armor, Chief Librarian Justinius, Epistolary Lucan, Epistolary Idmon, Codicier Aeneas (+11 Codiciers, 6 Lexicanum, 11 Telepathica Recruit Lexicanum)
35 5th Company Marines, including Command Squad, 2 Dreadnoughts including Captain Davian Thule.

Apollo Diomedes Requires Master of the Forge or Senior Techmarines To Forge The Bionics Required To Return To Battle-Capable State, But Will Not Require Dreadnought Internment. Remains In Suspended Animation Until Then.

Gabriel Angelos Conscious, Lack of Senior Tech-Marine or Master of the Forge Means Bionics Unable To Be Fully Repaired. (Combat Capacity 65%)

Apothecaries/Tech-Priests Working On Below
1 Codicier Too Wounded To Fight In Next Phase Of Battle
4 Lexicanum Too Wounded To Fight In Next Phase Of Battle
1 1st Company Marine Too Wounded To Fight In Next Phase Of Batttle

Confirmed Blood Raven Losses:
Honor Guard Captain Doukas Laskaris (Relic Bloodtalon Destroyed) (Single Gene-Seed Recovered, +1 Gene-Seed)
Apothecary Falkor Ryll (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
Chaplain Uther Volkoss (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
3 Honor Guard (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
4 Lexicanum (Gene-Seed Recovered, +8 Gene-Seed)
3 Codiciers (Gene-Seed Recovered, +6 Gene-Seed)
5th Company Chaplain Tarion (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
2 5th Company Marines (+3 Gene-Seed Recovered, 1 Destroyed In Battle)
1st Company Assault Terminator Sergeant Minos (+2 Gene-Seed Recovered)
9 1st Company Marines In Terminator Armor (+18 Gene-Seed Recovered)
34 5th Company Marines (+50 Gene-Seed Recovered, 18 Destroyed In Battle)
5 Lexicanum (+10 Gene-Seed Recovered)
2 Codiciers (4 Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
2 5th Company Marines (+4 Gene-Seed Recovered)
3 5th Company Marines (6 Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
2 5th Company Marines (+4 Gene-Seed Recovered)

Imperial Navy:
1 An Emperor-class Battleship (Moderate Damage) (Interceptor/Troop Transport Compliment Down By 90%, Bomber Compliment At 100%)
3 Lunar-class Cruisers (Moderate Damage)
4 Frigates (Moderate Damage)
20 Troop Transports (Carrying Imperial Guard Forces) / 1 Galaxy-class Troop Transport (Carrying Imperial Guard Forces)

All Void Armsmen Utilized In Boarding Lost (Remaining Void Armsmen Now Depleted To Severely Understrength Levels)

Imperial Guard:

15 Meridian Consolidated Imperial Guard Regiments (5 Infantry/5 Mechanized Infantry/5 Armored) [1 Regiment's Worth of Casualties Evenly Spread Amongst The 5 Infantry Regiments]
1 Kauravan Superheavy Armored Formation - 15 Lucius-Pattern Baneblades of Kaurava Attached To Armored Meridian Regiment, commanded by Colonel Stubbs of Kaurava
1 Meridian Storm Trooper Regiment (10th Meridian Consolidated)
1 Inquisitorial Storm Trooper Regiment (Ordo Hereticus) [1/3 Casualties Sustained] Will Not Deploy Without Inquisitorial Order

Inquisition
1 Inquisitorial Grand Cruiser, Vengeance-class Sword of Reckoning (Custom Variant, Heavily Modified) (Moderate Damage)

Imperial Ship Losses:
All Fire Ships
2 Avenger-class Grand Cruisers
5 Lunar-class Cruisers
6 Frigates

Spoiler: Confirmed Enemy Slain

Over A Hundred Hydra Flak Tanks And Anti-Aircraft Specced Manticore Tanks
10 Soul-Tortured Defense Monitor Cruisers [800,000~ Crew Total]
120,000~ New Meridian Vandian Stormtroopers
4,010,000~ New Meridian Vandian Guard
15,000,000~ New Meridian Conscripts
30,000,000~ New Meridian Menials
500,000~ Saharduin (Piscean Warriors, Alien Crew Members, Engineer Caste, Blood Shamans, Etc.)
Reaverlord Carnax, Khornate Alien Warlord
Grand Hunter Hraxe, Slaaneshi Alien Warlord
Admiral Maximilian Vandis, New Meridian Defense Fleet Commander
New Meridian Defense Defense Fleet: Estimated Crews At 10,000,000 (Including All Ships, Orbital Stations, Shipyard)
Nascent Forge World Opux Maxima: Enemy Populace Estimated At 1.2 Billion (Including Menials, Hereteks, Magos Hereteks, Masters of Forge-Hives, Skitarii, Obliterators, Daemon-Machines, Chaos Knights, Tanks, Artillery, Experimentals, etc.)
Fabricator-General Drakis
Black Legion Sorcerer Lord Melphas
3 Lesser Black Legion Sorcerers
322 Black Legion Chaos Space Marines
125 Black Legion Veteran Chaos Space Marines
24 Khornate Berserkers
2.2 Million Dark Mechanicus Menials
10,000~ Dark Mechanicus Hereteks
1 Dark Mechanicus Magos 01b7, Master of Forge-Hive 01b7
5,000 Gene-Hound Shocktrooper Abominations
25,0000~ Heavy Combat Servitors
300,000~ Dark Mechanicus Skitarii
10,000~ Dark Mechanicus Elite Skitarii
20,000~ Cultist Troopers
7000 Elite Cultist Stormtroopers
100 Soulrend Obliterators

Turn 27: On Vengeful Wings (Part Eighteen)

[] Deep Searching: Allow the Imperial Guard to take the brunt of the enemy attentions as the Blood Ravens seek out enemy command positions and logistics strongholds to seek to analyze the flow of information and - more importantly - control. Find Vandis, or at the least enemy commanders who can then have their own centers searched, or be interrogated themselves. The dreadnoughts, being incapable of such rapid high speed movement, will stay behind and help fight alongside the Imperial Guard.
-[] Provided the Inquisitor's people authorize the attempt, send Justinius to Adrastia's ship to assess her condition and (at minimum) provide physical healing to help recovery from her surgery, and provided Justinius judges there to be no more than moderate risk from the attempt to try to wake her from her coma. In either case, he should then rejoin the Blood Ravens ASAP.

On Vengeful Wings
+070.M42+ To +075.M42+
I am a Blood Raven, born into the starry sky on wings of hate. Hate for the alien and his opposition to Man. Hate for the treason of brothers and fathers. – Reclusiarch Mikelus

Captain’s Forbearance: 52

Justinius was welcomed aboard the Sword of Reckoning by a party of Inquisitorial Stormtroopers in an expected threat display. They had lost their commanding officer, and now their nominal master who had held the leash was comatose. That the Captain of the ship had been willing to let him aboard at all, a psyker who might well have gained dangerous access to the minds of the crew was a sign of how dangerous the situation might well be for the Inquisitor herself. What he hadn’t expected, however, was the sheer breadth of the weapons not quite pointed at him. Not a single one of them bore a hellgun variant. Instead, of the twelve Inquisitorial retinue present, the Captain herself making their full compliment thirteen, all of them bore weapons fit to tackle even a space marine. Two graviton guns, two melta guns, and the rest bore plasma guns, all of which were of the highest quality. Even the vaunted power armor of a space marine would surely falter under a barrage from such things.

“Chief Librarian,” Captain Carlyle inclined her head. “Welcome aboard the Sword of Reckoning. Follow me.” She spun on her heel with mechanical precision began marching away.

“Of course,” he nodded as he followed, the Stormtroopers bringing up the rear and sides.

All of the Stormtroopers were of considerable mental discipline and strength, but there was the faintest glimmer of something more when it came to Carlyle. And yet it was something that was clouded and murky. She, too, he realized swiftly – said realization causing the faintest twitch in the woman as she felt his witch sight rove across her – was a psyker. One of a low grade, barely reaching gamma by the standards of the Imperium. It would not take too much effort to break through her mental shields, but he felt no inclination to do so. Especially not now that he had overplayed his hand and made her aware that he now knew. Even so, he didn’t need to scour her soul to now see the faintest inclinations as to where her skills lay – for without the decades and centuries and more of a space marine’s lifetime, most human psykers would never reach the sheer breadth of knowledge and skill, instead having to focus along more specialized lines.

“Her condition?” He spoke aloud instead of giving voice to any of this.

“Physically, she is exhausted. Even returning from Opus Maxima left her with multiple skull fractures from the pressure released when she…exhausted herself, as well as myriad other wounds gained up until that point,” Carlyle responded promptly. “The hexagrammic wards throughout the ship remain hale, however, and we are still unsure as to how the daemonic presence manifested within the operating theatre.”

“And yet the Inquisitor managed to banish it,” Justinius noted calmly as they passed through yet more checkpoints and hallways, all of them manned by Inquisitorial Stormtroopers.

“Yes,” Carlyle nodded curtly. “The anesthesia had not yet fully reduced her to unconsciousness but forcing herself to fight caused…issues.”

Justinius opened and then closed his mouth as he realized where they had come to. Rather than the dormitory chambers he had been expecting, they had descending elsewhere in the ship. The prison cells, he concluded as he reviewed all the checkpoints, turrets, and bevy of hidden nozzles and waiting tanks of gasses and chemical compounds present all around him. Many of them were occupied, too, but he found to his surprise that he could not easily discern them with his powers, given the weighty amount of hexagrammic warding on several of them. At the same time, he didn’t need to, given that in bold text they were noted to reduce any possible confusion on the danger in the cells. All of the occupied cells were similarly described and defended, save the one they now stood in front of, the data slate of the door blank.

“You brought eldar prisoners into a warzone?” He asked with a raised eyebrow, lifting his chin towards some of the more heavily warded cells.

“The work of the Inquisition continues wherever its agents go,” Captain Carlyle replied, the line rote and well-practiced. “Though we serve the Ordo Hereticus, only a fool would fail to realize that the duties of the three Ordos Majoris often intertwine. Heretics deal with daemon and xeno alike, for all that they are all thrice damned for it.”

“And this chamber…,” he trailed off as he gestured towards the heavily warded cell.

“The Inquisitor insisted,” the Captain sniffed before placing a palm against a shaped panel, not wincing at all even as a quintet of small needles shot into her fingertips to take bone marrow samples.

The door slid open in silence, and immediately Justinius saw the problem.

Adrastia Condition: 11

Inquisitor Adrastia was secluded in the direct center of the chamber, manacles and straps holding her down onto the stone slab, with the inner wards of the room glowing brightly as they actively worked to prevent further Warp incursions. He had felt them on the edges of his senses, the ship’s sheer amount of defenses making it become that much more noticeable to the denizens of the Warp, the defiance worked into its bones no doubt greatly offending them. The Inquisitor herself was not in particularly good condition either. Physically, she was still in recovery from her many wounds, bruised bones and organs on their way to healing but not done yet. The surgery scars from her new bionic eyes were already mostly healed, but it too much jostling and activity could wreak havoc on the delicately made connections between metal and nerve, blood, and bone.

In terms of the soul, it looked like it had been forced through a fine barbed sieve, something vaguely in the shape of Adrastia held together by the thinnest and weakest strands of will left to the millions of broken chunks. That her soul hadn’t collapsed or dissolved outright was practically a miracle, or at least a testament to the sheer will of the woman herself. He had, in fact, read records of such things before, but almost always with regards to failed Librarians, those who had pushed too hard, too fast, and had died because of it after studies had been made of them. None of the current Librarians of the Blood Ravens had faltered in such a manner in his comparatively short tenure, but he nevertheless recognized many similar signs. He beheld now in person the results of a psychic breakthrough past the limits that the mind and soul were capable of withstanding, one born of pure fury with streaks of grief woven into it. Out of courtesy he had not examined her more closely after Opus Maxima. He knew now that that was a mistake, she had been a single step away from faltering in that most fatal and horrible ways that all psykers could. It was easy enough to see the seams that she had painstakingly worked to salve and heal before her surgery, for to his eyes scars upon the soul were just as discernable as those upon the body – both the old and the new. She had not finished healing herself from the wounds of Opus Maxima and had driven herself so close to falling off the knife’s edge afterwards that he was frankly astonished that she hadn’t fallen.

“Inquisitor Adrastia gave word that Chapter Master Angelos is trustworthy. I have elected to confer that trust onto you,” Captain Carlyle spoke up, voice as still and measured as ever.

“I shall endeavor to prove myself worth it…though I confess that her condition is even more severe than I expected,” he said as he walked in, inhaling deeply. “I shall do what I can.”

Physical Healing: 36

Soul Healing: 84

===========================================================================

“I am doing what I can, Chapter Master,” Justinius’ voice was not labored, but then again he had been frank that doing such delicate painstaking work was tiring in its own way.

“I see,” Gabriel murmured. “Do what you can, Justinius.”

“Of course. Justinius out.”

Gabriel paused only a moment afterwards to reflect on the odd friendship he had made with the dangerous woman. Whether or not it could rightly be said to be his fault, the fact of the matter was that he was woven inextricably into the decision that Adrastia had made to burn down two planets of Subsector Aurelia. First Cyrene, then Typhon. And yet, for all that she had been the one to put them to the torch, he considered her a friend, or at least an ally. After all, it had also been by her word that the Exterminatus of the entire Aurelian Subsector had ceased immediately. Hopefully Justinius would be able to aid her in some measure.

Then he inhaled, felt his bionic lungs clench and twist inside his mostly metal chest, and nodded.

“Go,” he announced upon the command channel vox.

Seeking Information: 97

Defending: 68

Simultaneously, the Blood Ravens went to work within the hive. He himself joined in, a short teleporter jump in his terminator armor landing him directly in the command center along with the terminators of the 1st Company. Immediately, the militia began firing, even while they were cut down by bolters. Low volume audio piped in from various open vox channels of different squads, some with Librarian support, some without, as well as a channel held open by Captain Thule as they Imperial Guard fought off the first exploratory attempts by the legions of New Meridian to test their strength and defenses. For once, it was the Imperial Guard that were flatly outnumbered, and the reports made mention of sheer mass wave tactics more akin to those used by the Vostroyan or Kreig Regiments than anything else.

“Clear,” Sergeant Stromahn announced. “The Tech-Priest may enter now.”

The Enginseer that had been elected to accompany their specific detachment did just that, their frame bulked significantly by their own customized power armor and powerful bionics. A sparking Omnissian power axe hung in their hand, sizzling as blood dried. Behind them also came a quartet of combat servitors, their various weapons still glowing with the heat of repeated firing.

“Impressive work, Blood Ravens,” the Tech-Priest said calmly. “The guards outside were not able to transmit a distress signal before I dealt with them. Am I free to work?”

“Quickly, Tech-Priest,” Gabriel said gravely, “We are deep within enemy territory.”

“Of course, of course,” they muttered as they approached one of the larger cogitators and plugged in immediately. “Urgh. Poor things, the Dark Mechanicus care nothing for the sacred rites of cleansing and maintenance. I…oh.”

Every Blood Raven present turned slightly at that sound. It was a sound instantly recognizable for all Blood Ravens. It was the sound of the scholar finding the data they required, the realization of a scroll or data slate’s contents. It was, distinctly, the sound of discovery.

“What is it?”

“One moment. I require analysis…,” the Tech-Priest held up a hand made solely of metal and circuits. “This was a command post of significant worth, deliberately made to appear as the myriad others.”

The cogitator bank began to hum, then glow outright as the Tech-Priest worked at it.

“I…yes. The assault was swift enough to prevent them from shutting down the data streams,” they went on before their mechadendrite began to twitch this way and that. “It…hrnngh…yes. I can see you,” they hissed, the noise rendered oddly through their vocoder. “A web within a web, but the numbers will out,” they said beneath their breath.

Finally, they turned their head – and only their head, which rotated upon a swivel point far past what an organic spine should have managed – to Gabriel.

“Numerous command circuits aligned. Orders and requisitions filtered. Commanders communicating upon higher security channels, but this terminal was not locked and shut down beforehand due to speed of death of officer.”

Gabriel’s bionic heart no longer had the same neurological leanings, but his secondary heart managed to begin beating faster in anticipation.

“Central main spire –Spire Vandis – is false target, possesses significant defenses and defenders due to assumption of Imperial decapitation strike. Ordinarily, main location of government, rule, bureaucracy. Retains purpose, but many no longer present.”

“Do you have him,” Gabriel said calmly.

“Location narrowed,” the Tech-Priest waggled their head from side to side. “Spire Jubacael, named after Vandis ancestor who discovered system and founded illegal colonies. Currently lacking in full Hive void shielding due to daemonic incursions, minor void bubbles from smaller generators present. Warning: significant defenses found, Private House Guard, genetically enhanced warriors, combat servitors, techno-heretical robotics, daemon-engines-,”

“I expected as much of a coward like Vandis-,” Gabriel muttered as the Tech-Priest went on and on.

“-Chaos Space Marines present, numbers not present in channel,” the Tech-Priest added.

The Blood Ravens stiffened for a moment.

“I see,” Gabriel grunted. “At least we know where he is now, and can try to prevent him from running.”

“Warning, Spire Jubacael is present within territory of hive under significant daemonic assault. It is almost directly beneath the Warp Tear.”

At that, Gabriel grimaced.

“And so he hides beneath the shadow of the sword itself,” he growled. “All Blood Ravens, suspend current operations and return to Rally Point Primus, we have ascertained the location of Vandis.”

=====================================================================

“Casualties are somewhat light so far, only a hundred thousand dead, Colonel,” an adjutant announced as Colonel Gabriel Derosa and the rest of his command staff looked over the flickering holographic map of the battlefield.

“Hmm. Spread?” He asked, squinting as the image bounced and flickered more.

“The 12th took the brunt of it, a third of the dead are theirs, but the rest was spread out evenly.”

“Rotate them all regardless,” Gabriel Derosa ordered. “They’re starting to get their artillery batteries sighted in, even firing at extreme distance, and earthworks are largely unworkable in the toxic areas. Captain Roche? I want you and Captain Teyrn to prepare for a sabotage operation – we cannot rely on space marine scouts to aid us in getting around to their rear guard.”

“We’ll knock out those big guns,” the two Captain’s saluted. “Or die trying.”

“I’d prefer the former,” Gabriel said dryly before the air began to shift and crackle. “Hold, everyone. That’s-,”

The scent of tainted ozone and a bow wave of unwholesome static washed over everyone in the encampment as multiple Blood Raven squads returned to the compound. The blood of heretics was layered heavily upon their already red armor, the difference showing in the layers flash fried by their transit. Already, sheets of it thick enough to be parchment was flaking off of them as they swiftly moved out of the way. Though Gabriel was less than a century old, he knew enough that teleportation was an uneasy tool at the best of times, and specific, exacting coordinates were best when utilizing it. As such, the squads were returning in generally the same place, one carefully prepared by the Librarians and boosted by a beacon, rather than attempting a scattershot arrival all across the Defense Laser park. The last of the Blood Ravens to arrive was none other than his namesake, the famous Gabriel Angelos, whose accolades and accomplishments dwarfed his own as a matter of course. If he had come through the Warp, the Meridian native would assume that he would be vomiting on the ground or dying or some such, but instead he simply watched as the Chapter Master reappeared through a tear in reality and began moving directly towards the command tent so smoothly it was as if he’d taken but a single step forward rather than hurtled through hell itself.

“Chapter Master,” he saluted, causing a cascade of copied motions from everyone else within the tent as the looming Blood Raven ducked to get inside.

To put it plainly, the superhuman looked gruesome. His terminator armor, vaunted and powerful, still bore the many wounds laid upon it by none other than a Chaos Lord, or so the rumor went, and there was a jerky slowness to his movements that was terribly at odds with the too-smooth, almost liquid mobility that every other space marine displayed. His bionic eye was cracked, his natural organic one thoroughly bruised from some blunt impact that likely would have broken a non-enhanced human’s skull into tiny little pieces. His famous daemonhammer, Godsplitter, was held in a single hand despite its immense size and weight, the power field crackling and fizzling so angrily it almost felt alive. For all of that, however, there was an incongruous nobility to the Chapter Master, something that defied his wounds, his battle damage, from somewhere within.

“Colonel,” the Chapter Master nodded to him, allowing him and the others to release their salutes. “Our efforts were even more successful than I had hoped.”

“Oh?” Gabriel raised his eyebrow.

“Vandis disguised his primary command centers, those staffed with the officers of highest import, amongst the rest. By the Emperor’s grace, we managed to locate a cogitator bank looped into the command circuits of the enemy’s forces that was not locked down.”

All fifteen officers of the Imperial Guard present simultaneously leaned forward, their hearts speeding up in anticipation.

“I…blessed be the Emperor and Omnissiah,” Gabriel breathed out. “What-,” he silenced himself as the Chapter Master raised a single finger.

“We have located Vandis. He is not in the capital spire, as some suspected, but rather he has sequestered himself in Spire Jubacael.”

Captain Vrains rolled her eyes.

“They do so love naming things after themselves, don’t they,” she snarked before paling at her casual speech in front of the Chapter Master, eyes darting to the looming figure as her mouth snapped shut. “I…that is…,”

“You are correct,” was the blessedly mild response, letting the poor woman manage to inhale properly. “Even most other hive worlds in the whole of the Imperium name their hives from the accomplishments of many, from the histories, the lexicons, but House Vandis has turned the whole of this planet into a vanity piece solely glorifying themselves.”

“And…Jubacael Vandis is the one who discovered the system, isn’t he?” Gabriel asked. “Why isn’t the capital spire named after him?”

“An effort by his son, it seems, to differentiate himself,” the Chapter Master gave the barest tilt of his head from side to side. “He is the one who built what is now their capital spire, but Spire Jubacael is the oldest in the whole of the Hive and the system. Here is what our initial scans have been able to tell,” the Chapter Master gestured, and somehow a Blood Raven who none of them had noticed entering passed out several data slates. “Thank you, Brother Kaius. You may return to the rest of the 5th Company.”

Muttered curses broke out at the news, even as the smaller space marine left. It was well known in the Imperium that age often carried a considerable amount of power. Worse, it was a place of blood and debauched heresy. Then everyone actually began reading the data slates, and the curses grew louder. Gabriel found his frown worsening as he kept reading. Directly beneath the Warp Tear, of course. Likely defended by some of the most elite forces in Vandis’ arsenal, obviously. Deep within the hive, literally hundreds of miles through a nightmarish urban landscape, expected. There would be defenses aplenty along the way, surely, defensive emplacements, chokepoints, and enough anti-air to make trying to fly troops forward and in a potentially impossible outcome. All while the entire populace of New Meridian was being whipped up into a frothing fury at the interlopers who had brought so much ruin to their home. Plus, of course, the daemons who would be present in exceedingly high numbers until the Warp Tear closed.

“This…looks like it might well be a hell of a damned grinder, Chapter Master,” he eventually said, looking up to match the Chapter Master’s grim look with one of his own. “We are already outnumbered.”

“If I may speak freely, Colonel?” Captain Vrains spoke up, glancing at the Chapter Master before back to him.

Gabriel glanced at the Blood Raven, receiving a small nod, before sighing.

“Permission granted, Captain.”

Though they were both of Meridian, Vrains was from the Underhive, and over two decades of warfare had not reduced the tendency for the Underhiver accent to creep in whenever she was highly stressed. Yet, in those same two decades he had known her, she had never faltered in her grasp over the logistics of their regiment and others.

“We will expend every solid slug, shell, explosive round, rocket, and grenade we brought with us before we get even halfway there,” she said in a rapid rush, the words twanging and stretching. “Even if we fall back to pure plasma and las usage, we’ll burn out every pack and coil we’ve got from the sheer tempo required to reach it, even if we take enough casualties on the way to pull from our dead and dying.”

Gabriel ground at his teeth for a second as looks of earnest fear appeared on the faces of the more junior officers. The elder ones just looked resigned to their likely fate. All the wretched waiting. On the ships as they traveled to the meeting point, through the gravity reef, and then just hanging about in the void as everyone else fought and killed and died. It burned at his heart that he could not refute the captain’s grim assessment. For they had all underestimated Vandis. To be sure, if they lived the scribes would downplay the fact, especially so for the Blood Ravens, but the truth of the matter was that all had assumed for some reason that a man with all the powers of an Imperial Governor and control over Angel Forge would have but a single isolated redoubt. A fortress, at the most, not an entire star system. If they had even begun to think it, they might have brought more ships filled with nothing but munitions. They had been prepared to arrive and obliterate, not potentially risk a major siege.

“I see,” the Chapter Master said, his deep timbre somehow even and calm despite it all.

“Still,” Vrains shrugged, the tension bled out of her somehow by the weight of her words, the surety of what she spoke propping her up in excess of what should have been possible, “We can probably make a good few miles of incursion, if you like, Chapter Master.”

Gabriel was gob smacked that she managed to look the Chapter Master in the eyes as she said it.

“I suppose it would be up to you.”

A single raised eyebrow over his bionic eye was the initial extent of the Chapter Master’s reaction. Before there could be more, however, the hololith shimmered for a moment, an insistent blinking sound notifying all present that someone was communicating on a secure command-level vox channel. Without asking anyone else, Gabriel’s namesake pressed the activation rune, causing a large Inquisitorial symbol to dominate the actuality sphere’s imagery. Even now, the sight of it set many of the veterans to sucking in air, a new undercurrent of fear entering their hearts and minds. The only one seemingly unaffected by that was the Chapter Master himself, who merely shifted the enormous terminator armor he wore slightly, grinding against the metal flooring.

“Colonel,” the word was uttered in a wretchedly ragged rasp.

“Inquisitor!” Gabriel twitched into a salute despite it being impossible for her to possibly see him do so, an act repeated by all but the Blood Raven. “I…we had heard…,”

“Adrastia?” the Chapter Master spoke up.

“Gabriel? Good, you live,” despite the weariness there was a faint note of what might have been joy. “Makes this simpler. Your Chief Librarian has everything else. I will not be joining you on the ground.”

Just as abruptly as it had begun, the conversation ended with a simple click. Less than thirty seconds passed before there was a bright flash of teleportation as Justinius arrived on the planet. He needed no guidance, able to sense the minds of those he needed, and as such pushed through into the command tent with all haste.

“Probalis.”

“Angelos,” the Chief Librarian bowed his head. “The Inquisitor may live, but her medicae and I have agreed – any more exertion at all may well end her. She is being placed once more into a medical coma. In the meantime, however,” he produced an item that stole the breath away of the Imperial Guard present.

For it was nothing less than her Inquisitorial Rosette.

“Explain,” the Chapter Master ordered, even as he accepted it, squinting down at the symbol of authority and fear.

“For the remainder of this conflict, you have command over the rest of her Stormtrooper Regiment and ship,” came the prompt response. “Inquisitor Adrastia judges you – and only you – worthy enough to bear such responsibility and power. Furthermore…,” the psyker’s eyes flickered across the Imperial Guard before going back to the Chapter Master.

Gabriel did not hear anything but based on the looks of both of them they held a conversation in secret. He struggled to disguise the shudder as they clearly discussed with psychically aided telepathy some matter or another. Still, he could see the raised eyebrows and faintest surprise on the Chapter Master’s face, followed by a short nod. A grim look was shared between the two men before the psyker turned and left, leaving many to breathe a sigh of relief. It was one thing to regard the Blood Ravens – rightly – as the saviors of Subsector Aurelia, as paragons and champions, but it was not so easy to get past the weight of power and command that their psykers possessed, not just in general but within the Chapter’s workings as well. Two eyes, one bionic, the other organic, narrowed ever so slightly as they fell upon him, and Gabriel felt a stab of shame in his heart that they had reacted so obviously to be caught.

“This is what we shall do next, and how we may prepare for it.”

With great speed and efficiency, the Blood Ravens have discovered which of the Hive Spires the traitorous Vandis has sequestered himself in. He has fled to the eldest Spire on the entire Hive world, named after his traitorous ancestor who first discovered the system. It is no doubt filled with the most elite forces left on the planet, and furthermore rests directly under the epicenter of the Warp Tear, stripping any chance of long-term orbital support lest the daemons overwhelm the ships present. Due to landing purposefully away from the Warp Tear, the distance is considerable. Logistic issues mean that the Imperial Guard is unlikely to be able to punch directly through to Spire Jubacael without running out of ammo and fuel. Thus making it unlikely for them to contribute majorly to hitting Vandis. However, Inquisitor Adrastia awakened just long enough to cede command of her forces to Chapter Master Angelos. Furthermore, she has revealed that there is a prepared method to contain Vandis even should he turn out to possess some measure of supernatural ability - though its efficacy is unknown. The man in question must still be reached, however, and a specialized beacon planted. Live capture is preferable, but failing that, proof of death will suffice. Once this is done, and he is taken care of one way or another, this world, this system, can finally be blasted into pieces. All Blood Ravens desire to join in this final effort.

Chapter Master's Orders (Choose 1 From Each):
[] Fly By Insertion: The fastest method would involve taking a Strike Cruiser and effectively performing a drive-by deployment of thunderhawks and drop pods directly into Spire Jubacael, those areas not currently under void shield. Then, all forces shall work to locate Vandis and either capture or kill him. Once this is done, all shall teleport back, and the system may finally be dealt with in a most permanent manner. This would also allow the Inquisitorial and Imperial Guard Stormtroopers to deploy alongside the Blood Ravens. At the same time, the insertion would be dangerous, for obvious reasons - as such, the strike cruisers would work in tandem to force enemy attentions on themselves instead of their precious cargo and their deliveries.
[] Horizontal Push: It's entirely likely that anti-orbital fire might take down even a strike cruiser, but if the Blood Ravens were to travel overland across the continent, they might reach Spire Jubacael and plant beacons allowing the Stormtrooper Regiments to join them in locating Vandis. This would take many days, however, at the least, due to the sheer size of the planetary hive and the distance between the landing zones and Spire Jubacael. By that point, it is likely that Spire wide void shields may have been restored, and the Warp Tear will certainly have sealed itself once more.
[] Something Else: (Write-In)

ALSO

[] Maintain Positions: Order the Imperial Guard to continue holding position as they have been, working to distract the enemy by their sheer weight of numbers.
[] Forward: To further distract and panic the defenders of New Meridian, order the Imperial Guard to start actively pushing into the hive, forcing the enemy to dedicate significantly more defenders towards them than anywhere else. This will, understandably, cause many more casualties amongst the Guard, but they will not shy away from their duty.

Turn 27: On Vengeful Wings (Part Nineteen)

Spoiler: Voted Plan

[] Forward: To further distract and panic the defenders of New Meridian, order the Imperial Guard to start actively pushing into the hive, forcing the enemy to dedicate significantly more defenders towards them than anywhere else. This will, understandably, cause many more casualties amongst the Guard, but they will not shy away from their duty.
[] Fly By Insertion: The fastest method would involve taking a Strike Cruiser and effectively performing a drive-by deployment of thunderhawks and drop pods directly into Spire Jubacael, those areas not currently under void shield. Then, all forces shall work to locate Vandis and either capture of kill him. Once this is done, all shall teleport back, and the system may finally be dealt with in a most permanent manner. This would also allow the Inquisitorial and Imperial Guard Stormtroopers to deploy alongside the Blood Ravens. At the same time, the insertion would be dangerous, for obvious reasons - as such, the strike cruisers would work in tandem to force enemy attentions on themselves instead of their precious cargo and their deliveries.
-[] As the Strike Cruisers approach, have the fleet direct a rain of ordnance and kinetic impactors - improvised ones, if necessary - on the orbital guns protecting Spire Jubacael, from ballistic trajectories that keep our ships at a distance from the Warp Tear. They may or may not be able to penetrate their void shields, but void shields flare when struck - a constant stream of impacts causing constant flaring may throw off their ability to get a target lock.
-[] Use Imperial Navy chaff or sensor buoys to spoof enemy auspex readings and confuse their aim even more by making it seem like there are way more sensor readings than there should be, to further shield our Strike Cruisers.

On Vengeful Wings
+070.M42+ To +075.M42+
I am a Blood Raven, born into the starry sky on wings of hate. Hate for the alien and his opposition to Man. Hate for the treason of brothers and fathers. – Reclusiarch Mikelus

To their credit, the soldiers of the Imperial Guard did not flinch when they were given their task. A doomed forward assault, a violent excursion without possibility of victory, a distraction of blood and fury of tremendous proportion. Tens of thousands, or more likely hundreds of thousands of them would most assuredly die in the coming confrontation with the fanatical cultist legions of New Meridian. And yet it was needed of them. They were called to do their duty, to not merely die standing, but die while rushing headlong against the enemy. Regiments assembled, reserves were called up, wounded were alternatively tugged back into the ships if they were simply too wounded to fight or pumped full of adrenals and painkillers to get them back into the grinder if they could be. In the meantime, the Blood Ravens steadily disappeared entirely, teleporting or flying back up to their ships, for their course was perhaps equally as deadly or even more so when considering most every possible factor.

For Spire Jubacael awaited them, and their quarry within it.

High above, in orbit, the fleet began to move. Weapons arrays came to life as they began to unleash themselves against the continent-spanning hive below them. Massive bubbles of void shields flared and shuddered as they were struck to protect individual or tightly packed spires, but the infrastructure damage left behind by the daemons added to the toll. Transformers and generatorums had been struck, conduits shredded in the fighting between cultist and daemon alike, leaving some shields flickering or refusing to come on entirely. The firing was, initially, indiscriminate, but as their destination came closer they narrowed their focus. Grabbed pieces of shattered defense stations and ship wrecks were thrust forwards with a mishmash of rigged technologies, whether it was being released from vehicle latches on the underbellies of the thunderhawks or even attached surplus thrusters meant for repairs on other vehicles. Chaff cherubim were released in enormous clouds, and though they were ordinarily meant to aid in the deflection or confusing of incoming missiles, on this day and in that moment they were to obscure enemy auspex devices. Whether it would work, any of it, or not remained to be seen. Regardless of the result, the strike cruiser Spiraling Fury, of the 1st Company Fleet, advanced. Not alone, for the Rage of Erudition and The Great Father's Fist journeyed forth as well, but it was the Fury upon which the bulk of the burden would be laid.

Forward Push: 10

Distracting Rain: 43

Spoof Attempts: 15

Rapid Insertion: 87

And a burden it was. Despite Spire Jubacael being directly beneath the warp tear and subject to the highest concentration of daemons and miscellaneous warp spawn, its shields and sensors were as high quality as nepotism could provide. It was immediately obvious that the enemy anti-orbital fire was punching past the chaff screen, the spoofing signals of the cherubim seemingly ignored entirely. The void shields of the strike cruisers flared again and again as the enemy fire struck them head on. By the time that the trio of ships had reached their destination, they were fielding swarms of daemons from above and New Meridian fire from below. Damage was inevitable as the generators were forced to cycle again and again, chunks of hull cratering and buckling beneath blasts that found purchase in the moments between. It was precisely the sort of mission and purpose that strike cruisers had been built for. To withstand punishment fit to tear apart cruisers and more long enough to deliver their own deadly cargo and escape.

If only barely, in some cases.

The signals turned green as the Spire's shield was registered as being knocked offline for a short period of time, the last prayers were finished, and the teleportariums went to work. Drop pods thundered down one after another, some of them filled with space marines, and others with weaponry. Dozens of teleportation beacon repeaters were thrust downwards as well, carried in every manner possible. Immediately, anti-air cannons leapt to life, the daemons in their targeting arrays and the warp-essence infused in their shells tearing rents in the sky to mark the passage of such deadly implements. Missiles left behind exhaust trails of toxic fumes and where they erupted acidic waves which outright melted whole drop pods was left behind to then rain back down. It was solely the fact that the drop pods at the foremost edge of the wave were uninhabited save for automated weapon systems that preserved multiple Blood Ravens from losing their lives without being able to shoot back at anything. Of course, the legions of Vandis knew as much, for their master had suspected that one day the Blood Ravens would indeed come for him. As such, even as multiple pods passed through the firing envelope, whole battalions were rushing to the locations that their tainted cogitators had declared most likely arrival points. The air shrieked as the first of those such pods arrived, a staccato beat of thunderclaps and miniature earthquakes following impacts. One pod in particular took a solid shell of flak and yet managed to land somewhat accurately to its planned destination despite missing a third of its mass and exposing more than one marine within.

Nevertheless, it managed to land without killing its passengers.

"For the Emperor!" Captain Tarkus yelled, grunting as he shoved the ruined remains of the drop pod aside.

He immediately regretted that decision and dragged the thick chunk of metal back into place as five heavy bolters, two heavy stubbers, and a barrage of plasma guns fired on his position. Gritting his teeth, he popped up and spent a half-second to mark targets before firing his bolter over his piece of makeshift cover. Around him, the rest of the 5th Company was doing the same. The heavy weapons tapered off, however, as there was the sound of a crackling electrical blast from behind them. Tarkus toggled the auto-senses of his helmet and nodded as he saw the unnatural cold bloom which sometimes accompanied the usage of psychic lightning. When he emerged, he saw the weapons teams which had hastily deployed had been transformed into black charred remains as Epistolary Damion Tyrin strode through them. One New Meridian soldier collapsed into ash as the body of the Librarian quite literally walked through him, letting loose with another blast of lightning.

"Advance, brothers! For the Chapter!" He rushed forward to do just that.

All around them, the 5th Company was rapidly working to come together. They did not have the numbers to affect a wider spread. The sheer technological capabilities of the enemy, bearing so many heavy weapons capable of striking down even space marines, meant that their only chance for survival was to come together and advance as swiftly as possible. Already around them, all could witness a bubble of energy rapidly rising upwards to envelop the spire once more, cutting them off even from teleportation travel. Unfortunate, but expected. Tarkus grimaced, though it wasn't much of a change from his usual expression and continued firing on the dozens of oncoming troopers. It disgusted him to see just how close their uniforms mirrored that of the Imperial Guard, the noble aquila replaced with the sigils of Chaos and House Vandis. Those whose helmets exposed their faces revealed a remarkable number of them looked mostly human, though others had greying or otherwise inhumanly colored flesh. More importantly, however, were the many plasma guns and hellguns in their hands.

=========================================================

"Here we are," Cyrus grunted as he glanced disapprovingly at the actuality sphere.

"So it seems," Canoness Tenenbaum muttered stiffly.

"Two of those worlds are lost," Captain Manin scowled.

"One Agri-World, and one Mining World. The latter is potentially recoverable, if we are swift enough," Admiral Scvolitch pointed out. "Magos? Possibilities on the Agri-World?"

"Possible," Magos waggled a mechadendrite. "Not without extreme cost, as Magna Agra possessed a highly developed and controlled biosphere, re-establishing it will take much time and resources. Estimated starvation deaths in interim period…just under fourteen billion."

"Well," Lord General Hamms sneered, "We shall have to make that sacrifice worth it by burning the bugs out, here and now!"

"Indeed," Cyrus sniffed. "To our ships and stations, then?"

"It would be wise," Admiral Scvolitch nodded respectfully. "We have a battle to win, after all."

Swiftly, all departed from the strategium of the battleship Glorious Emphasis. Around the command ship, the combined fleet of the Imperial Navy and two Chapters thrust forwards into the last tyranid-held system in the Subsector. They had come from all across not just the Mede Subsector, but all of the Helba Sector and beyond. Only the swiftness of the campaign had allowed it, a pace set and maintained by the expertise of a Force Commander who had spent two centuries in the Deathwatch and had fought in all three of the most recent Aurelian Crusades. The enormous combined fleet thrust forward, and naturally the Hive Mind responded. The titanic bio-ships turned to face them, organic masses equaling escorts, cruisers, and in a several terrifying cases outright battleships. The Hive Ships were the greatest threat of all, of course.

"Attention, all ships!" Admiral Scvolitch boomed through the vox. "This is it! We must eradicate the tyranids here and now, lest one of their foul splinter fleets arise again elsewhere! This is for the billions dead already, to prevent billions of more deaths! To reclaim our lost worlds! For the Mede Subsector, for the Helba Sector, for the Segmentum Ultima, for the God-Emperor! FORWARD, AND ALL SHIPS FIRE AT WILL!"

As the fleet advanced, already with lances firing at the furthest ranges, the admiral switched over to a more private vox channel.

"Force Commander Cyrus, are you certain?"

The sound of a rifle's slide racking was the first answer before the Blood Raven responded.

"It is the only way. The toxins developed must be injected directly into the Norn Queens. Then, we must find the calved Norn Queens that will emerge afterwards, and kill them before they can fully re-establish connections to the Hive Mind. Our ships will survive reaching the center of the tyranid fleet. Yours will not."

The admiral sighed.

"May the God-Emperor watch over you and the Sisters of Battle, then."

He had no more time to discuss the matter, not with the battle fully joined.

====================================================================

Forward Distraction: 12 vs. 55
Entering The Spire: 40 vs. 64 vs. 80

The fighting was exactly as grueling as expected. Less than a hundred space marines fought a desperate battle against the most elite troops that Vandis could produce. The teleportation beacons and thunderhawks that managed to get through were bringing forth the troops of the Inquisition as well, and yet even with all of that they were still terribly outnumbered. Genetically enhanced troopers, abominations of science and technology, thundered out from passages to the inner depths of the spire wielding weapons fit to tear apart tanks in each hand. Hundreds and thousands of troopers wielding lasguns and autoguns also arrived, more every minute. Heavily armored and heavily armed soldiers, almost mistakable as stormtroopers of the Imperium, were also present in ever growing number. But of course, that was not the only foe to be fought across the spire. For high above, looking like a broken grin or bleeding eye was the tear in the warp, and from it the daemons flowed. And while void shields could protect against the technological, they were less valuable in defending against those purely of the warp. For a planet, a micro-nation which eagerly and regularly communed with denizens of the Immaterium, such connections were often valuable for rituals and sorceries alike. But so too were they aware, far better than most in the Imperium, as to the danger such things represented.

Not that it stopped the daemons from going after such protections the moment the warp tear bloomed into existence.

"There, take that entrance! We must get out of the open!" Gabriel pointed, slamming his hammer into a Vandis trooper and destroying everything above the waist.

"Very well!" Justinius boomed and thrust his staff forth.

From it, a massive wave of flame poured through the doors, blackening the metal and rockcrete as it burned the hundreds of charging troops bearing the sigils of Chaos to death. Those few that survived that were at the far back, and these did not live much longer as bolter rounds began filling the newly emptied space. Within thirty seconds, every single Blood Raven in the solar system was inside, accompanied by numerous Inquisitorial stormtroopers. Attempting to kill the total fighting populace of the entire spire was likely outright impossible, for the Imperials were outnumbered more than ten to one by both forces. Their only recourse was as much brutal speed as could be managed.

Already, many of the Blood Ravens were sporting wounds, ceramite punctured or blasted through by a wild assortment of weapons.

But none had fallen.

Yet.

Forward Grind: 44 vs. 92
Penetrating The Spire Defenses 1: 65 vs. 60 vs. 12

The innards of Spire Jubacael were no less difficult to fight through than its outer surfaces. The daemons had attempted to penetrate here as well, but they had run directly into long-prepared defenses by the defenders of New Meridian. They had, thus far, proven unable to get past the first few checkpoints, evidenced by the shredded metal and rockcrete from claws and spikes aplenty. Immediately after entry, the Blood Ravens came up against cordons manned by New Meridian troops wielding heavy weapons. Again and again, their progress slowed, only for one of the Librarians to shatter the weapons, or melt them, or swivel them about to fire on those behind. There were heavy bolters and heavy stubbers, but after a certain point they began running into the true elites, the New Meridian Stormtroopers. Many of them wielded plasma guns, but there was an astonishing number of them that bore outright bolters. It was not entirely uncommon for such weapons to be wielded by those outside the Adeptus Astartes and the Adeptas Sororitas, but the quantity and quality was still immensely troubling. Especially when they began firing them all.

Still, they fought on, each meter purchased in pain, bruises, and blood.

===============================================================

To fight inside of a Hive Ship, or any of the massive void-faring tyranid bio-forms, was truly nightmarish. The walls, the floors, the ceiling was flesh, and you fought not in corridors but inside massive veins through which sloshed alien ichor. Pustules burst to release powerful acids and regrew themselves within seconds to do so again and again to clear out blockages. Active, smaller tyranids swam through the veins precisely in case of something or someone doing just what the Blood Ravens, Ebon Claws, and Lost Rosetta were in the midst of doing. Blowing holes through the veins and into inner chambers, massive hollows in which tyranids gestated or slumbered in hibernation in vast numbers did not much improve matters. Already, multiple carnifexes in this latest chamber were awakening as the blood of the vein they had fought their way through spilled out around their waists and legs. Immediately several of the Seraphim began firing their pistols, meanwhile Celestians triggered their multi-meltas. In the further distance, Cyrus could see the twitching of an out and out bio-titan as tendrils of bioelectricity ran across it to prevent any possible decay or weakness during months and years of travel. Cables of neurons writ into injectors the width of a land raider hundreds of feet long grew bright as the Hive Mind drove it back to wakefulness.

"Move! Move! Move! The Norn Queen's chamber is nearby!" Cyrus barked, ignoring how there were already warnings that some of the seals applied to his armor and that of the others were beginning to weaken from all of the bio-plasma and xeno acids they had faced thus far.

The Hive Ship shuddered so hard it was practically an earthquake, nearly knocking some of them to the floor, followed shortly by an alien scream as the actual ship itself bellowed in pain from the attacks being levied upon it from without as much as within.

"Onwards, sisters, on!" Canoness Superior Margaret Tenenbaum roared, slamming a power fist into a tyranid warrior's throat to blow its head off.

"There!" Captain Manin shouted, pointing with one finger, "Librarian Curso is certain!"

Cyrus just kept moving. It was not a common thing for him to one more don the armor of a battle brother, rather than the armor of a scout, but the environment of a Hive Ship was simply so extreme that even he needed the protections it provided. If only to reach the target. Pulling out another cluster of melta grenades, he threw them overhand directly into the wall, ducking down behind a dead tyranid as the explosion tore through the wet, fetid air. Again, the Hive Ship screamed, louder this time. But so too did something else entirely. A screech that tore at his ears as much as it did his mind. Rearing nearby, so large it could be mistaken as another battlefield ready bio-titan, squatted the Norn-Queen. From her fluted flanks spilled hundreds of eggs from the dozens of fleshy pulsating orifices, those at the very bottom already beginning to wriggle and birth themselves to reveal tyranid warriors and termagaunts slick with amniotic fluid. The hanging forest of umbilical cords twanged and bounced as the larger sacs and their larger bio-forms began to be forcibly birthed at rapid pace.

Baleful eyes the size of tanks turned their way, filled with alien hatred and fury atop a dangerously sentient mind.

"There is the beast!"

"Go! Go! Go!"

========================================================================

Forward Grind: 58 vs. 29
Penetrating The Spire Defenses 2: 35 vs. 70

The first death for the Chapter within Spire Jubacael was Brother Menelaus, of the 5th Company. Battered and bloodied from multiple wounds, his armor practically blown apart from repeated grenade assaults and a pair of heavy bolters maintaining their target for long enough, the dying battle brother was filled with just enough energy to fling himself forward and tear apart his killers in the form of the Vandis Stormtroopers before finally expiring. At the very least, his gene-seed was recoverable, but there was barely enough time to do that as the strike force continued to move on. By now, there were no daemons at all, the defenses of the New Meridians so far able to prevent them from entering any further. That was little salve to the Blood Ravens as they continued to fight, forced to leave the carcass of their brother marine behind due to the pace demanded of their mission. His ammo, weaponry, and grenades were taken, and his body trapped should scavengers come from behind. A grim thought, and yet one that was proven correct as sensors triggered no less than sixty seconds after they'd moved on, a distant explosion inaudible to the sounds of more immediate battle.

By that point, the gates had begun slamming shut, vast hewed things of metal and stone that were specifically built to repel intruders as best as possible. Turrets that fired krak missiles, twin-linked lascannon turrets, turrets that fired heavy bolter rounds, and turrets that thumped out multiple types of grenades were just one new threat to be faced. So too however came a veritable tide of gene-hounds. Abominations of bionics and genetically enhanced flesh, equals to space marines in physicality if nothing else, their torturous existences measured in months and days from start to finish. Despite the fact that they were dying from the moment they'd been decanted from their tubes, they fought viciously. More than one Inquisitorial Stormtrooper was torn apart in their hands, but just as many were wounded or killed as they opened up with their own bolters, plasma guns, and modified weapons that were quite clearly derived from the ripper guns often given to Imperial ogryns. Many more hauled oversized chainswords or chainaxes, roaring as they thundered into the fray. There was even a handful of daemon-machines, creations that could have once been combat servitors or battle automata before being melded with the dread enhancements possible through the Warp.

Wounded, damaged, their armors becoming slick with their own blood as much as the enemy, the Blood Ravens forced their way further into the spire.

===============================================================

Sunderhammer pulped the head of the possessed chaos marine, but Aramus could not spare a moment to appreciate the righteous kill. After all, there were dozens more all around him, and he yanked the hammer back until his grip was so choked it was practically holding flush against the head itself. For once, it was the shaft of the thunderhammer that became a weapon, stabbing and gouging those behind and to the sides while he utilized the head of the hammer as if it were a rock and he a primordial human in the days of old on Terra. Around him, hundreds of screaming sisters of battle were similarly engaged in close combat. Some fought against possessed marines as he did, others were cutting through swarms of cultists and madmen, and yet more were engaged against the daemons that the enemy had summoned forth. From behind him, the rest of the occupants of the thunderhawk emerged directly into the fighting. The sight of less than a handful of space marines had, ironically, not done overly much to bolster the spirits of the Adeptas Sororitas.

That changed, however, as Palantine Katicia and her Celestian Superior squads emerged as well. A raucous cheer went up from the Sisters of Battle, some outright screaming in religious ecstasy as a hero of their kind arrived to aid them. By that point, Aramus could spy the telltale evidence of the curious powers that the Sisters could on occasion wield. Before he had arrived in Cadia, he had thought such things a mixture of rumor, clandestine technologies hoarded in secrecy by the Ecclesiarchy, or perhaps even misattributed psyker abilities. That was decades ago, and as a Blood Raven such ignorance was swift to leave him once he began to investigate and document. No, the golden field which sprang up around many of the Sisters of Battle was something else altogether, a flaming aura which provided protection to the faithful while burning the forces of Chaos to ash.

"HOLD FAST, SISTERS!" Palantine Katicia shouted, her voice boosted by no known technological means, "XERSIA SHALL NOT FALL THIS DAY!"

The devoted of the God-Emperor cheered, and perhaps in response, the Dark Gods answered. Drop pods covered in the sigils of Chaos came crashing down from the heavens, and where they landed they unleashed squads of marines bearing the banners of the Black Legion. The Chaos Space Marines shouted to the Dark Gods, bellowing the name of their patrons, and immediately began advancing towards the battered Imperial lines. A quartet of dreadnoughts stomped out, insane gibbering emerging from their speakers as they began firing their assault cannons and missiles at the Imperial hard points. More than a few heavy weapons batteries were blown to pieces by the twisted half-dead before concentrated lascannon blasts began tearing them apart. Aramus let the ghost of a grin come across his face as Sarrelen unleashed the might of the Redemption By Fire, but it faded quickly as he stepped back and observed the battlefield.

The Cardinal World of Xersia was a prime target for the enemy, being a bastion of Imperial faith and morale, but more so due to the fact that it was alone in its planetary system unlike nearby Cadia. But that just meant that the Ecclesiarchy had chosen to reinforce it that much more. Which, in turn, drew the forces of Chaos like flies. The skies above were wreathed in flame and shattered metal as the fleets battled one another, and this time, it was the Imperial Navy that was retreating. Aramus could already see the orbital fire from the Chaos vessels hitting in the distance at other Imperial holdouts.

"Palantine!" He shouted, drawing the holy warrior's attention.

"What is it," she shouted back, driving her power sword deep into a cultist's chest, killing them instantly.

"Our ships are having to pull back. Saving the cathedral here will not matter if they can simply blast it to pieces from orbit!" He pointed up at the skies.

Ordinarily, one would not be able to see the ships so high up. But the Chaos ships were eager to cause as much terror and hatred as possible, and so flew low enough to scrape partially through the atmosphere. Even so, they were but black dots that occasionally fired lances of unholy fire down to the ground, but for many that was enough. The Palantine knew it as well as he did and grit her teeth. They had, after all, only just arrived down onto the planet, but while the protective powers of the Sisters were occasionally quite considerable, protecting from orbital bombardment was another thing entirely. The fact that the Alpha Legion had sabotaged many of the planet's cathedral-city void shields days ago only compounded the problem.

"So what do you suggest?" She snapped.

"We have to stop their ships before they can walk their bombardment any further. You know what that means, what that will require."

Katicia pursed her lips and nodded.

"Alicia, Valinda!" She snapped, drawing the eyes of the Seraphim Superior squad leaders. "Back into the thunderhawk."

"Mistress? But-,"

"Sisters, do you see those Chaos ships?" She pointed into the sky. "I do not want to see them anymore. Accompany the Blood Ravens. Now go!"

There was zero hesitation as they sprinted back into the thunderhawk with Aramus just on their heels.

"Thaddeus, with me! Sarrelen, remain here and keep suppressing the enemy armor!"

=======================================================================

On the far edge of the system, a trio of battered ships tore out of the warp. It was not an easy transition, and fire trailed from holes and tears up and down their hulls. Half of their engines were burnt out or broken, most of their guns were broken slag, and still they burned forward. By the time that the auspex sensors of the Imperial ships could recognize them, they had already plunged into the gravity reef. It was not even close to near the same entrance that had been taken to get into the system in the first place. But rather, it was just one of the shifting openings and paths, one only possible to know of if one had spent decades within the system learning the ways and changes that the gravity reef could undergo. Within moments, the passage had closed off entirely, enterable solely for that one instant and impossible to follow through afterwards for a simply unknowable length of time.

=============================================================

Stationary Grind: 35 vs. 88
Penetrating The Spire Defenses: 99 vs. 63

The further in they got, the thicker the defenses and defenders grew. Soon enough, they were forced to rely almost entirely upon the Librarians to push back or through the corridors and down the stairwells. More than once, the enemy had blockaded such areas with heavy barriers and three-rank formations. Stormtroopers on their bellies let loose with autoguns, whilst those just behind knelt and fired out with their own bolters, while those standing fired with their plasma guns. At other times, there were barriers, turrets, and a massive rush of gene-hounds with melee weapons, rapidly closing with the wearied Blood Ravens. More than once, Epistolary Idmon had to tear apart the entire hallway, just to preserve the lives of his battle brothers as much as kill the enemy. More than once Codicier Aeneas flickered from view, gore and flying limbs left in his wake. More than once, Epistolary Damion Tyrin had to hurl massive spheres of lightning forward.

And, of course, once they reached a certain point, pride dictated itself into the situation.

"I knew you would come for me," a familiar sneering voice crackled across the speakers, interrupting the constant calm droning of status reports and directives. "I knew it."

"Vandis," Gabriel growled aloud as he broke a gene-hound apart around the head of his hammer.

"Pathetic little creatures of the Emperor," the ex-Governor Vandis spat through the vox. "Of course," he gave a hoarse laugh, "If I had known you were so weakened by the Hound of the Black Legion, we would have wiped you out years ago."

The Chapter Master did not bother informing the man that the vast majority of the Chapter's strength had been deployed elsewhere. The enemy had not realized a difference before now, and he knew as well as any other tactician that being underestimated could be a valuable weapon.

"Brave words for a coward who flees and hides," Gabriel yelled back as Justinius blew another barred door down with pure telekinetic force, scattering the guards behind it to be shot to pieces. "First you relied upon Araghast to do what you were too weak to do. Then you could not even keep a leash around Mortirex. And now, your very world is under siege, and you hide again! We have taken your worlds from you, Vandis!" Gabriel paused only to crush another gene-hound with Godsplitter. "We have taken every single one of them! And now, we come for you!"

"You are nothing more than ignorant mongrels!" Vandis shouted back, his screeching causing the vox itself to crackle and pop from the feedback. "What you have destroyed is nothing compared to the powers of Chaos! Worlds are nothing to the powers of the Dark Gods!"

"And yet," Gabriel was the one sneering now, "You call your precious capital 'New Meridian'. Derosa rules the true Meridian, now. House Derosa is ascendent…and where is House Vandis now? Dead or cowering."

"Derosa?! That weak-willed slime of a woman is a powerless wretch, and that planet is nothing compared to the glories we have enacted here," Vandis shouted back. "The power I have, that House Vandis has secured through the Dark Gods, will long outlive the Imperium!"

This time, however, Gabriel did not answer immediately. Instead, he glanced to Justinius, the Chief Librarian having paused the moment the former Governor had begun speaking, falling deep into a trance with psychic light pouring from his eyes. The Chief Librarian raised but one finger without looking in Gabriel's direction.

"Power?" Gabriel scoffed. "Power to run. To hide. So many souls, so many years, so many generations, and yet here you are."

"Mortirex was a simple brute, and Araghast an easily led fool, Blood Raven," Vandis hissed. "They had no idea what power House Vandis holds…and neither do you. But now? I shall show you!"

As one, the Librarians stumbled save for the Chief Librarian, who lowered his finger and nodded to Gabriel.

"I know where he is," Justinius declared before wincing, a hand going to his temple. "He has begun releasing bound daemons and they are heading directly for us."

"And more?" Gabriel raised an eyebrow.

"I cannot yet see them…," Justinius trailed off before shaking his head. "But yes. I suspect that is not everything. It makes a terribly mathematic sense, I think."

"Oh?"

Justinius furrowed his brow.

"How many generations has House Vandis had to sacrifice from their populace to the Dark Gods? By volume alone, even if not in grand singular deeds? They have gathered so much of their power…bureaucratically, almost. At least that is my estimation."

Neither of them was quite sure if that made it better or worse. Neither had time to contemplate it either as the sounds of daemonic screeches and roars emerged from the distance. Within moments, bloodletters and flamers entered, the daemons of Khorne and Tzeentch disturbingly forced into working together by their bindings against the loyalists. Accompanying them were what had clearly once been gene-hounds before being possessed, all of them becoming twisted horrors akin to possessed chaos marines. Even more Vandis Stormtroopers brought up the rear. It was a tide of death which rolled towards their small group, but none of the Blood Ravens faltered. Instead, they strode forward to meet that which Vandis had unleashed. Instead, it was they who tore through their enemies. Again, it was the Librarians who did the bulk of the work, working in a chorus of psychic might that blasted apart the enemy and opened the way again and again and again.

As one, the Blood Ravens broke through level after level, even as the guardians grew more swollen with unholy power and the very gates themselves were revealed to be enchanted by the foul sorceries of Chaos. Vandis, in turn, unleased greater horrors against them. Defilers came, amalgams of daemon flesh and metal that fired armor piercing shells and acidic toxin bombs. Obliterators arrived, bellowing in pain as their bodies were ever further mutated by the virus interwoven with their bodies and souls. There was even a fearsome Decimator, something that threw Blood Ravens into walls with armor shattering force and halved the remaining Inquisitorial Stormtroopers in less than thirty seconds. Yet even that daemonic war machine was broken down by Godsplitter, the terminators of the 1st Company, and the combined strength of the Blood Raven Librarians.

=================================================================

Of course, everyone who had ever been made to face the tyranids in the Deathwatch had been made aware of what occurred at the Battle of Tarsis Ultra. It was the first confirmed in-person kill made on a Norn-Queen after all. But it was one thing to read the mission reports of Captain Ventris of the Ultramarines 4th Company, it was another entirely to try and do so themselves. Cyrus contemplated that as he watched the three senior Seraphim carry the quite frankly enormous mixture of missile and needle that the Adeptus Mechanicus had devised for this purpose through the air. The toxin derived from the Alpha strain bio-forms that they had painstakingly located and killed up until this point outright glowed from the various compounds utilized to make it. The Norn-Queen knew it was coming, somehow, the information of what occurred at Tarsis Ultra likely somehow passed by way of the Hive Mind itself. But even as hundreds of rounds of bio-plasma began firing at them, melting their power armor and bodies beneath under the vicious barrage, the delivery device remained hale from its starship grade armor. Cyrus watched from the corner of his eye as he continued to fight alongside the others in the middle of the Norn-Queen's chamber, as one, then two of the Seraphim dissolved outright midflight.

It was the last who completed the deed, accelerating her jump pack to fatal speeds to slam the device directly into the Norn-Queen's eye and deep into her head – directly into the brain. Instantly, its plunger activated, and the neurotoxin was injected at rapid speed. Literal gallons of the stuff was shot directly into the giant alien brain in under a second, the sheer pressure causing its own incidental damages. The third of the Seraphim did not survive her final act, but the damage was done regardless. The psychic backlash was the greatest that Cyrus had ever experienced, far greater than the killings of the most powerful of Eldar Farseers had he faced before. He, along with hundreds of others, blacked out as they were flung in every direction, and a number were wounded or died outright as the now berserking tyranids attacked them before they could regain consciousness. But many more did jerk awake once more, gathering together as best they could while the tyranids tore into one another.

"Cyrus to Omnis! The Norn-Queen is dead, deploying teleport beacons! Apothecaries, gather the gene-seed while you can!!"

"Gather, Sisters, gather! We have yet more to do!" Canoness Tenenbaum shouted.

"Ebon Claws, to me! The deed is done, but not the fight!" Captain Manin called.

The entire Hive Ship screamed again and again as it was struck by lances and weapons batteries, even as much of the fleet of bio-ships outside began to convulse and calve. By that time, however, the hardened cases which carried the teleporter beacons had been opened, the beacons themselves activated. Less than forty-five seconds passed before the Imperials evacuated out of the giant bio-ship, the dead that could be recovered gathered up and brought with them. Yet, even as they all emerged onto the teleportation platforms of the Astartes vessels, steaming with all the caked gore on them, all three groups could only hand off their dead and prepare for new deployments. For the psykers of the Imperial Navy had dared to watch the Hive Fleet closely, and saw where the new beacons of eldritch alien minds were being rapidly born. They, in turn, informed their Captains, who informed the Admiral, who then informed them all as to their next targets.

"All right," Cyrus reloaded his bolter as he glanced at Manin and Tenenbaum. "We have our targets. There are fifteen newly calving Norn-Queens. Too many for us to hit all at once."

"Then we must split up," Manin nodded.

"Right. If we can kill them before they can reach full maturity in…," he reviewed in his head, "A little less than an hour, we might have a chance."

"Then we must be as swift as the God-Emperor himself," Tenenbaum declared, fists on her hips before she squinted at the two Captains. "May he be with you both," she said after the slightest of pauses.

"And you as well," Cyrus grunted. "Your targets," he passed each of them a data-slate. "See you on the other side."

It was back to the teleportariums after that, the Sisters of Battle not merely murmuring but outright shouting their prayers to the God-Emperor to gird their souls and bodies during their incoming passage through the Warp. Five minutes were given over to rearming and reloading while the dead were set aside. Servitors rushed to scrub the teleportarium platforms clean, the tech-marines worked tirelessly to fine tune the machines for what would soon be demanded of them. Targeting was performed, the auspexes tracked, and once more the ships of the Blood Ravens and Ebon Claws prepared themselves for the plunge into danger-close range to the still currently berserk splinter fleet.

"Destination confirmed. Beginning sequence," the flat voice of the servitors slaved to each teleportarium chamber spoke in unison through the vox. "Initiating in three."

"…and may He protect our immortal souls, so that we may perform His holy work!"

"Two."

"Let the shadows fall, and our enemies with them!"

"One."

"May none find us wanting," Cyrus whispered.

"Initiating. May the God-Emperor watch over you."

=========================================================

Grinding: 98 vs. 39
Penetrating Bastion: 83 vs. 90

Another brother died as the Blood Ravens finally reached their destination, as guided by the Chief Librarian. Scans and estimations based on what information the tech-priests had been able to carefully analyze of the local noosphere suggested that it was some sort of inner sanctum. In this case, the information had been completely correct. Within the vast hive spire, likely costing tens of thousands of lives, an inner sphere had been carved clean out of the rockcrete and metal. The doors to even reach that place were fit for Imperial Knights, or perhaps daemon-machines of many terrible varieties. And on the other side lay an enormous citadel, sitting upon an artificially crafted plateau shot upwards. Four massive bridges stretched out from the plateau to connect to the rest of the spire, but below lay a boiling morass of what looked like magma but bore far too many unnatural colors. The fumes that rose off of the hidden lake immediately caused multiple radiological alarms to blare to life. The moment the doors were blasted through with careful applications of explosives, Brother Ligern toppled over backwards as a sniper blew his entire head off. It was only the Librarians throwing up a shield of pure force that stopped the rest of the incoming rounds from killing others. Disturbingly, the bolter rounds themselves hung in the air, caught by the blue dome's edges, letting all of the Blood Ravens see them vibrate before they finally detonated.

"Stalker-pattern bolters!" Justinius grunted as they advanced under the dome's protection. "Librarians, to the fore!"

Gabriel could only spare a moment to glance back and realize that there were but a handful of Inquisitorial Stormtroopers left. They had gamely fought on all this way, but the sheer deadliness of Vandis' forces had taken their toll. That number shrank further and further as they rushed across the bridge as more and more weapon installations opened up. It went beyond just snipers. A brace of mounted heavy bolters, lascannons, and plasma cannons began firing next. Once they hit the halfway point, the doors into the citadel slid open to reveal another tide of gene-hounds who fired their heavy weapons and brandished their gargantuan chainswords. They howled as chemical injectors emptied themselves, pumped full of fatal levels of adrenals and painkillers that pushed them that much further directly towards the struggling Blood Ravens. The Librarians, focusing entirely on maintaining the shield which prevented them from being torn apart entirely, could not even spare the focus to defend themselves. That, instead, fell to the rest of their battle brothers to step forward past them.

"For the Emperor!" Gabriel raised Godsplitter high as the gene-hounds closed in.

"Here you are, then," Vandis' voiced boomed throughout the entire cavern, "Where Araghast failed, I shall not. Where Mortirex failed, I shall succeed! House Vandis shall rise in the eyes of the Despoiler on a foundation made from your bones, space marines! Come, come and die!"

======================================================================

Cyrus reappeared on the teleportarium platform as a barely living lump, gasping and coughing out bloody flecks as his severely punctured lungs failed him. Immediately the apothecaries were on him, forcibly tearing away the melted and shattered mass that had been his armor, able to toss them aside without any specialized tools whatsoever. The Captain's longer hair had been melted short, and there was much muttering by the apothecaries when they saw the exposed spinal cord, both brought about by a nearly fatal blast of bio-plasma by a specialized Lictor bio-form. Around him, the rest of the Blood Ravens that had survived retrieval were being similarly swarmed as well. It was a testament to the sheer physiology of a space marine, and perhaps the unyielding will of the Captain of the 10th Company, that he remained conscious throughout the process of being taken to the apothecarium. The surgeries to save his life, however, would require a chemically induced slumber despite his protests.

"What do we do now? If the other Norn-Queens reach maturity…," Nero Gracchus, Master of the Apothecarion, murmured to Martellus, the Master of the Forge.

The senior-most tech-marine in the entire Chapter sighed, his hands clenching and unclenching.

"We discussed this with Cyrus when he was named as Force Commander. It has to be me."

The younger Nero looked askance at him.

"What? But-,"

"I am the highest authority in our force who retains longer term experience in combatting the tyranids," Martellus ground out. "I must take the field and continue to lead our teams."

Once again, he would have to personally grapple with the alien menace that had hunted him on Typhon. But this time, he was not crawling out of a crashed thunderhawk with broken armor and a single bolter. This time, there were hundreds of Blood Ravens in the fight. This time, he would be the one hunting them.

=================================================================

"Thaddeus! No!"

Aramus' scream brought the attentions of Konan, and the apothecary immediately abandoned his current opponent and performed a running slide to reach the side of the dying Blood Raven. All around them, the Black Legion moved in, coming from every single corridor. They were outnumbered more than thirty to one, and even if every one of them was only wielding a standard pattern bolter it could have been enough. But of course they were wielding far more than that. The penitent former Force Commander grit his teeth and continued firing all around him as the Chaos Space Marines continued to press in. Thaddeus, out of the corner of his eye, simply gurgled as he struggled to stand, the holes punched through his body by multiple kraken penetrator rounds so thorough that Aramus could actually see through his front out of his back.

"Nereus!"

The scout clicked his comm bead twice, the affirmative signal that the scout's mission was done.

"Retribution, teleport us out, now!"

"DIE, LOYALIST SCUM!"

In the split second before they were all torn back through the warp to the strike cruiser, Aramus could only manage two words before he was gone.

"You first!"

In their wake, the explosives detonated, tearing through the main plasma reactor of the ship. Bereft of such things, its void shields failed as the generators were left with no power to marshal, the guns largely fell silent, and the engines stuttered out. Even as Thaddeus was being rushed to the apothecarium of the Retribution, the rest of the rallying Imperial fleet tore the battleship apart with concentrated fire. There was no time to rest, to mourn, for the fighting down on Xersia proper had only intensified as the forces of Chaos grew incensed at the loss of their ships. What would have broken the morale of an Imperial force as their orbital protections were lost had instead only inflamed the zealous hatreds of the servants of the Dark Gods.

"I can save him, but he is out of the fight," Kogal barked at Aramus as he began removing Thaddeus' armor. "Now go! Get back down there! I will join you as soon as I can!"

================================================

Grinding In Place: 66 vs. 34
Breaching Citadel: 24 vs. 20

The entrance to the citadel was a gore-strewn ruin by the time that Gabriel Angelos smashed its doors down with his daemonhammer, aided by the power fists of the terminators of the 1st Company. Behind them lay a great many dead gene-hounds, and the remainder of the Inquisitorial Stormtroopers. Perhaps the servants of the Inquisition might have lived, perhaps not, but either way it seemed that it would come down solely to the Blood Ravens. Blood filled the lungs of one marine after a stalker bolter had managed to crack directly through his breastplate, but still he moved and fought on. Another marine had effectively lost an arm, the limb mangled by grenades but remained attached solely because of the armor's seals rather than the pulverized meat and bone within. Gabriel's hastily repaired bionics and armor were weathered in the extreme, to the point that his movements and ability to react was swiftly approaching purely normal human standards, a vast drop from the capabilities meant for a true space marine. There was not a single standing Blood Raven who had not taken painful wounds. Some could likely end up crippled, even if they lived, save for the usage of bionics.

In return, the emplacements had been smashed apart with carefully aimed missiles and thrown grenades. The defenders manning the walls had been slain from afar as the Blood Ravens picked and chose their shots while moving or were more simply mowed down by the assault cannons and heavy bolters that the Blood Ravens possessed. The Librarians, from Lexicanum to the Chief Librarian, had been forced to wholly focus their combined psychic might on the shield that let the space marines advance in the first place. Twenty-seven psykers, all to produce a mobile shield capable of withstanding the sheer amount of firepower being leveled in their direction. And even then, it had not been entirely enough, as the continually charging gene-hounds had forced their way past more than once before they had stopped coming.

On the other side of the door, however, lay something far worse than what they had faced.

No sooner had the breach been made than were the Blood Ravens charged by dozens more gene-hounds, these frothing and spitting blood as their chemical injectors outright emptied themselves. Some of them collapsed to the ground as their organs failed and nervous systems short circuited, but far more simply charged forwards as their muscles split open from rapid induced growth without any sense of pain whatsoever. Behind them were dozens more elite Stormtroopers, all of them wielding plasma guns and bolters. But neither of those two groups grabbed nearly as much attention as the black-armored Chaos Space Marines who began firing as well with their own heavy weapons. Blood spurted from Brother Idmon's nose as he strengthened his portion of the shield to deal with an overcharged lascannon blast which could have sheared through a dreadnought entirely. The fallen brothers of the Black Legion did not cease their assault, even as the momentarily shocked Blood Ravens began returning fire as best they could.

"Do you see, Blood Ravens? The power I wield, what a thousand years of sacrifices can gain you? Your deaths shall purchase me that much more!"

Gabriel focused on none of that, however, as he instead listened to the intensely weak vox signal, nearly lost within the cavernous confines of the massive hive spire. One that bounced, skipped, and faded in and out terribly on a regular basis. Yet, it was that same regular nature which was signal enough, when words would too easily be lost. He paused, waited, and then narrowed his gaze and palmed one more teleporter repeater beacon and activated it. For the signal to the Blood Raven fleet had been lost, repeatedly, whenever the void shields of the spire had sprung back into place as its punished plasma reactors regenerated it after sustained fire. By now, the ships had worked to keep themselves safe rather than sustain any concentrated barrage of fire from the planet below, but that did not mean that they did not regularly pass close enough for the more vital causes possible.

Such as ensuring there was a method to deliver those of the Blood Ravens who would quite simply be too slow to keep up with their group as they descended as swiftly as possible through the depths of the hive.

=================================================================

Aramus wetly gasped for air through his one functioning lung as he struggled to his knees. Of Sunderhammer, that which had been his long companion throughout his Penitent Crusade, there was nothing left save for a child's handful of fragments. His armor was in little better shape, the crumbling shards and plates falling from his frame into the mud to reveal his broken body. Half-blind as he was now from his left orbital cracking and spilling blood, he could still see through his right eye as his blood curdled and rotted where it hit the tainted ground. His left eardrum had burst, the right was only slightly better. Then again, even the mostly deaf could hear the booming laughter of a Great Unclean One as it rejoiced in the death and rotting of the many dead, traitor and loyalist alike. Or as it addressed him directly.

"And there…you…are, little Blood Raven. Ahahahah! Ulkair's rage for you smolders like a thousand dying stars for your strikes at him on Aurelia," it guffawed again, but there was a deadly fury of its own that undercut the joviality.

There was no witty response, as Aramus had to focus everything he had to even stagger upright, his left leg limp and twisted nearly half off of his body. In turn, the near spherical greater daemon laughed again at his weakness and pain, dragging the edge of its vast and heavy blade which had nearly killed him along the ground. As it did so, the fissures it left in the earth widened, releasing smaller nurglings in giggling packs as well as droning formations of plaguebearers. Around him, the rest of Xersia's defenders fought on. Three Ordo Majoris of the Adeptas Sororitas were represented here, and it showed in the sheer volume of melta and heavy flamer fire they directed towards the Black Legion and its daemonic allies.

"Perhaps once we are done here, I shall drag you back to Aurelia and use your body as a catalyst for his return," it mused, absentmindedly throwing up a hand throw a cloud of thick daemonic mucus which protected them both from an artillery bombardment. "He would probably enjoy that, using your corpse as a puppet. Then again, to be struck down so many times by one mewling Chapter, would he even deserve it?" It tapped one tree-thick finger against the exposed bone of its chin.

"You will not have the chance to do so," a growl boomed from speakers, making the Great Unclean One glance back down, its grin widening enough to split its cheeks.

"Oh ho! A half-life…interesting!" It laughed as the entombed librarian stomped forward, the dreadnought's frame creaking as it pushed through the mud.

Konan Barbarial flexed his assault claw before with incredible gentleness he nudged Aramus backwards past him. His assault cannon spun up, and psychic light began to glimmer all across the dreadnought's frame.

"K-," Aramus made to speak before his wracked body spasmed hard enough to drive some of his broken bones into his working lung.

He coughed and nearly fell with the force of it.

"And what do you think you shall do, little half-life? Do you truly think your meager gifts could possibly defeat me?" The Great Unclean One's laugh was sharp enough to cause many of those nearby to start bleeding from the ears.

The Librarian's response was to fire his assault cannon directly at the greater daemon's face, the explosive rounds rippling across its eyes and nose, gaining a roar of irritation from the servant of Nurgle.

===========================================================

Grinding: 42 vs. 61 vs. 99
Within Citadel 1: 84 vs. 1

The Blood Ravens were exhausted, wounded, and running low on ammo. They had no more allies to call upon, and more than a few Lexicanum had been forced to give up using any psychic powers whatsoever as they came far too close to the edge. They had been reduced, if such a thing could be rightly said, to mere space marines, utilizing all of the traditional skills of their battle brothers. Even the mighty girding strength of the terminators had begun to slip, their venerable armors pockmarked and scorched. Their Chapter Master's bionics and armor were openly in need of the direst of repairs. Blood ran from the eyes, the nose, the ears, and in the cases of Epistolary Idmon even the fingernails as the Librarians exercised their abilities as best as they could. In return, they were outnumbered not solely by the marines of the Black Legion, but by the gene-hounds and the Stormtroopers of New Meridian. Enough firepower to assail an entire fully numbered company of space marines was levied upon them, and in most circumstances, it would have – should have – been enough. Almost any tactical cogitator would return the such a result if inputted with almost all the relevant information.

Save, however, for the dreadnoughts.

Tomb-Captain Davian Thule. Brother Nathan. Brother Cordas. They had fought many times already in a staggeringly short amount of time throughout the swift campaign. None had allowed themselves to be put into slumber throughout the fighting, whether or not they were involved, for the threat posed by the enemy was judged to be worth such things. Here, now, in a moment when the spire's void shields fell once again from long range curving fire that its anti-orbital weaponry could not retaliate against, when the vox signal bloomed to life, the teleportation beacon had been triggered. In a flash of unnatural lightning and a trio of simultaneous cracks of thunder, the dreadnoughts had arrived. Delivered just as they had been on a now crashed station on a now shattered planet by a single Codicier who had flickered into reality behind the enemy surrounding the rest of the Blood Ravens.

And, just as over Opus Maxima, three pairs of twin-linked multi-meltas hooked to dreadnought reactors tore into the rear of the enemy formation directly into the Black Legion who had utilized the gene-hounds and other Vandis troops as a shield of flesh and carapace armor. At incredibly short range, veterans of the Long War ceased to exist as they were vaporized in chunks or outright by the dreadnoughts. As they turned, the fire upon the rest of the Blood Ravens slackened, and so a wearied hammer struck an anvil with three heads with their enemy caught in the middle. In less than sixty seconds, the courtyard was clear of all enemies. The subsequent time after that until more arrived as less than half that, but as the defenders emerged from their inner tunnels and passages, they were brought down by concentrated bursts of multi-meltas, which rapidly melted many of those same passages into being sealed entirely.

Soon enough, only one remained, the doors into the inner citadel itself, which an incredibly wide ramp led up to. Orders were unneeded, and indeed, the Blood Ravens advanced as one onwards and upwards, even as the enemy rapidly redirected its defenders. Soon, more gene-hounds were pouring out of the inner citadel, bracketed by Vandis troops and a handful more Chaos Space Marines. Even as they arrived, however, they began to be hacked apart from within, shouts and yells cutting off abruptly as Codicier Aeneas appeared and disappeared amongst them. The Blade of the Martyr sang out as it began the harvest, the Codicier no longer needing to remain back with his brother librarians to maintain the shield. As they advanced, turrets rose up from previously smooth stone and metal, twin-linked heavy bolters, lascannons, and heavy flamers firing before the Blood Ravens shot them to pieces.

"Wait," Justinius raised a hand as they reached the doors itself, his expression grave. "I sense much power within."

Gabriel frowned with a raised eyebrow.

"Can you match it?"

"Alone? Perhaps, perhaps not," Justinius said humbly before a grim smile crossed his lips. "But then, I am not alone."

"Very well," Gabriel nodded before rearing back and slamming Godsplitter against the doors. "VANDIS! YOUR TIME HAS COME!"

================================================================

It was going to take the servitors and tech-marines months of manufacture to match the amount of ammo being expended in this one engagement. But, for Martellus, that was something perfectly worth it. The servitors had done their jobs well, emotionless and uncaring of the fleshy battlefield that quite literally surrounded them on all sides, and as such each and every one of the Tarantulas had been delivered precisely where he had desired them. There was now a killing field in every direction, precise and blessedly plentiful machines targeting every single tyranid that got within their target zones with overlapping fields of fire. The very ground swelled and bucked, the hive ship literally twisting its innards about, bio-mass being reconstituted in the pools that filled its belly to form out new tyranids, but it wasn't going to be fast enough. Not this time.

"NOT THIS TIME, YOU HEAR ME?!" Martellus boomed. "Sing, children of the Omnissiah! By bolt and fury, by oil and flame, sing out the Litany of Steel's Superiority!"

He turned atop the pile of dead xenos and hefted his plasma cannon as the newly birthed Norn-Queen, already beginning to try and spin out larger neural cables to birth the larger tyranid bio-forms screeched in fury. It was drenched in what had to be several metric tons of amniotic fluid from its forced rapid calving, and it was that which would be their saving grace. The longer it lived, the more it fully awakened its psychic strength as secondary and tertiary nodules of psychic organs activated. The astropaths of the Imperial Navy were frantic as the final hour rushed towards its bloody conclusion, their warnings by now reduced to constant terrified screams.

"Forward, Blood Ravens! Forward! May none find us wanting!"

The ball of plasma that flew forth entered one of the alien beast's many large eyes, erupting in a fountain of gore and softer tissues, but it was most certainly not yet dead.

==================================================================

Three Front Fight: 32 vs. 85 vs. 48
Inner Citadel: 17 vs. 5

There were no more mortal defenders, no mere troopers bred in corrupt darkness under a heretic House's vanity. All that were left to face the Blood Ravens were yet more gene-hounds, many of them still wet and dripping from being decanted from their growth vats early, yet more Chaos Space Marines, and the daemons. The inner chambers of what had once been a richly furnished sanctum had become a massive abattoir, mass-sacrifice used to propel the summoning and bindings of the warp spawn. And though the majority of the Blood Ravens could not see it, there was a vast amount of sorcerous defenses as well. It fell to the Librarians alone to try and counter them, the most obvious and blunt usages of sorcery being only some of these. So while shields were produced to protect against runic arrays that let loose with torrential columns of pure warp fire, or acids that had no basis in chemical reality, others struggled to hold back an absolute tide of assaults upon the mind and soul that were otherwise unseen.

Corrosive memetic noises captured from the not-throats of Daemonettes of Slaanesh or droning Plaguebearers of Nurgle required barriers of selective deftness. Spikes of deadly rage, crystallized blood of Khornate daemons transformed into noxious gas releases to over-amplify the natural righteous fury of any living being and corrupt them from within the very brain itself had to be swept away. Patterns of light and shadow created in bursts from hidden sorcerous traps hidden in the lights above, in the floor panels, and on the walls beneath the sconces lit with tainted fire, these were even worse. Locked into those patterns of irregularly blinding flashes were things that were meant to drive an unprotected mind mad, imagery and whispers emerging as the brain unthinkingly processed them, the eyes passing along poisonous data that could very well melt the organs within the skull entirely. With no Librarians at all, it was entirely possible that the remaining Blood Ravens would simply have fallen where they fought, alive from one moment, their brains leaking out of every orifice in their head the next.

The loyal servants of the Emperor fought within a shifting, moving, unnaturally near-living nightmare.

Vandis spoke, but his words were lost amongst the cacophony of battle and the madness that he had unleashed through his prepared defenses. Godsplitter flashed and boomed where it struck, each blow from the daemonhammer ending with the dissolution of one or more of its preferred enemies. Bolters fired again and again, and amongst it all, perhaps most dangerously of all, Codicier Aeneas dared to flicker in and out of the Immaterium as he brought death through the Blade of the Martyr. Here, in a place so heavily drenched in the Warp, it was impossible to miss how every time he re-emerged to hack down one more Chaos Space Marine or gene-hound that there were marks of claws, fangs, and other things upon his armor from the other side. In one strange instance, he emerged from the Warp and slew a two thousand year old traitor marine with his left pauldron showing what looked like damage from a barbed suction cup from some vast tentacled being.

Brother Dand lost an eye as a gene-hound hacked a large portion of his face and skull away with a chainsword that had been surgically attached and then welded securely to the abominations forearm. In response, Dand hacked the gene-hounds entire arm off with his combat knife even while he pushed his bolter's barrel into its eyes and fired to blow its entire head apart. Brother Zeno had to be helped to stand as his left foot was swallowed up by a pit of unthinking teeth made up of churned together warp-spawn. The wounded marine was forced to continue forward on a stump, his physiology rapidly clotting and closing off the wound, the jagged edges of his ceramite scraping and screeching along the stone floor. Brother Tioch was forced to reload his bolter one-handed, his other hand busy holding his innards in after a pair of bound Bloodletters had nearly cut him in half, the weapons of the Blood God leaving wounds behind that seemed incapable of clotting and closing off properly. But they, and all the others, fought on nonetheless. It was the dreadnoughts who preserved them from further deaths, their bulks and linked multi-meltas proving enough to tip the scales in the physical realm as the Librarians continued to struggle. Elaborate carving and sculpting work likely performed over centuries were smashed apart as they shoved their way through, Tomb-Captain Thule holding the rear against the many enemies that attempted to surround them and the other two entombed Blood Ravens directly at the fore.

Vandis had surrounded himself, to the last, with defenders that were utterly fanatical and fearless either from chemical enhancement, genuine insanity, or pure devotion to the Dark Gods. They fought with everything they had, there was no other choice. In those moments, as the toxic and altered blood of the gene-hounds splashed and sizzled onto the armor of all around, eating into exposed flesh, as the gore torn from the bodies of the Chaos Space Marines and all their mutated and tainted biology coated the living and dead alike, as the daemons cackled and cavorted and the floors, walls, and ceilings seemed to bend and writhe and hallucinations became near impossible to tell from reality, it was difficult indeed to tell just who was who at all. By the time that they finally reached a secondary line of defenses, howling bound psykers with the sigils of Chaos branding their exposed skulls that forced the Librarians to allow their brethren to suffer from all they had protected them from momentarily as they dealt with their own twisted kind, the proud red paint and sigils of even the dreadnoughts had become covered in such offal and thick layers of splatter that they looked as dripping black hulks of growling, snarling metal.

Gabriel's bionic lungs were being run ragged, which ordinarily shouldn't have been possible, they were highly advanced and meant to be even more capable than the organs that they had been made to replace after he had been smashed flat under Kyras' fists. Then again, one of them had been badly damaged, nearly destroyed outright, as a champion of the Black Legion had managed to pierce his chest with a power sword, the blade erupting out of the back of his terminator armor before Gabriel could bring Godsplitter down on their head and torso. The heretic died, and he lived, but it was definitely a near thing. His body, so much of it metal, and so much of that metal pushed past its limits, was simply not capable of matching threats he ordinarily should have been at least somewhat better able to contest. At the very least, the power sword hadn't actually hit one of his two hearts as it sheared its way through him.

The final doors were a masterwork of adamantium, absolutely covered in sigils of Chaos, a web of defenses beyond the pale layered upon it. The turrets that sprouted from seemingly every available surface had wielded a frankly improbably amount of armament, ordinarily enough to cut down an entire army. The bodies of the slain lay where they had fallen, having fallen back into quintupled ranks as the steps ascended to the innermost ritual chamber lay. As each rank had fallen to the Blood Ravens, their deaths had fed the summoning of yet more daemons to face them, forcing yet another pause as they fought and pushed forward. But the doors themselves proved near inviolable, despite attempts from all three of the dreadnoughts firing as one. It fell, thusly, to the Librarians, and the Librarians alone.

"We shall break this last gate, you have my word, Gabriel. In the meantime, however…," Justinius declared before glancing back out into the wrecked ruin that they had left behind them.

Already, they could all hear the howls of the gene-hounds, the shouted orders of mortal troopers, and the snarls of warp spawn.

"See to it, Justinius," Gabriel clapped a hand onto his friend and brother marine's pauldron before turning about. "Blood Ravens! We hold this ground! Pile these worthless traitors for our barricades, and let us bring death to the enemy!" He raised Godsplitter high. "MAY NONE FIND US WANTING!"

========================================================================

Konan Barbarial had volunteered to go with Aramus. He had not needed to. The Epistolary had fought in the 1st Aurelian Crusade, and in the 2nd, but not at the side of the Force Commander. Rather, he had been attached to the 4th Company forces, protecting the initiates they had left to them on their Recruiting Worlds in both of the Crusades. The fact that a number had been stolen away into the Warp, however, had burned at him, and thus he had joined for his own self-imposed penitence. They had served for not too long, by comparison, in the 13th Black Crusade alongside Aramus and all the others. But scarcely a year before the by now famous battle upon a single small hill, he had been laid low by a quartet of daemons. His body had been ruined, but his mind and all the power of his soul remained. Even as a dreadnought, he had been quietly humorous, stoic in battle, and a comforting presence for the thimble's worth of his brethren left alive. By all rights, he was one of the more powerful Librarians in recent centuries in the records of the Blood Ravens.

His death was magnificent.

The Great Unclean One, whose name the daemon had boastfully announced as Pestilax to the defenders of Xersia, was bleeding wounds that would not regenerate and heal. Aramus had watched as every blow of Sunderhammer had barely seemed to do any damage. Bolters, flamers, meltas, and more had been levied against the greater daemon, and yet as he'd known and expected it hadn't been nearly enough for the short amount of time that they had fought the monster. But the psychic flames of Konan burned and burned brightly. Huge swathes of Pestilax were aflame, by this point, scorching his putrid green and grey flesh and muscles black down to the bone. Even the gargantuan blade had been chipped, the top fourth of it broken off by a lucky blow. The false joviality was gone, the split grin now a rictus thing of forcibly held shape rather than anything genuine. Indeed, such was the daemons fury that it cast the blade aside, planting it into the ground to begin poisoning everything around them and bring forth an unending tide of daemons of Nurgle to spill out onto Xersia's surface. Instead, it had reached forward, ignoring an assault cannon firing directly into it, and grasped Konan Barbariel's dreadnought sarcophagus to haul him off the ground entirely. Thick, sturdy legs of metal were torn off first. Then the damned assault claw which had struck and broken part of his blade. Finally, squeezing, Pestilax drew the half-dead Librarian close, the crunching and tortured screech of metal announcing the death of the assault cannon.

"You have ceased to amuse, little broken thing!" Pestilax roared at the dreadnought, the bloated gasses which blew forth from his mouth heavily eating into the metal and rusting off the entire outer layer of the dreadnought in one go. "Your soul shall rot for eternity in my gullet!"

Such was the declaration of Pestilax the Despairing, who had ravaged billions with plague and sword alike, who had cut down Bloodthirsters of Khorne, whose putrefying works had defied and ruined the works of Keepers of Secrets of Slaanesh, who had torn the wings from more than one Changer of Ways. This, Xersia, was to be his greatest triumph yet as he took one of the greatest bastions of faith in the Anathema left in the Cadian Sector. Billions of faithful, defended by millions of zealots, were to be turned to mulch and worse for Nurgle's Garden. Thus, would Pestilax ascend to the Exalted Court of his kind at last, as he had always been sure he deserved. It was an announcement that carried the threat for what felt like more than a mile around, to cause and generate that much more despair as one last champion of the Anathema failed at defeating him. Already the pall of grief and pain and horror was spreading, even into the adamant hearts of the Sisters of Battle as they were forced to behold one of their greatest of enemies openly triumphant. It was victory, as assured and eternal as Nurgle Himself. Weapons fire slacked off, as that supernatural despair spread, the ripples generating and feeding upon each other to spread faster and further, to the point that even those who were nowhere near the battle felt uncertainty trickle in.

What could one say to such a thing? Such a threat, and such obvious power? A great many things, depending on the individual, but Konan Barbariel, Epistolary, Entombed Brother-Marine of the Blood Ravens Chapter of the Adeptus Astartes elected to say but one word. It was not a shout, a booming bellow, a rumbling blast of courage and fury.

But rather a single, utterly calm word.

"No."

And Konan Barbariel exploded into psychic fire colored the purest black. Though other wounds had been dealt before, and many during this battle, that fire brought the greatest continual bellowing scream from Pestilax since he had first manifested onto Xersia. The greater daemon of Nurgle stumbled back, arms flailing as his face and upper body were covered in it all. The sphere of black fire then expanded and shifted. Daemons, Death Guard, Sisters of Battle, Imperial Guard, it did not matter. Those who could see, stopped as that final act played itself out. From the sphere, no, the egg, emerged a pitch-black corvid which spread its wings wide, blurred at the finer details but somehow unmistakable through the haze of heat and impossible fire. At its very center lay a massive red core, within which the last of the dreadnought shell was burnt, vaporized by the intense heat until that too was gone. There was only the faintest impression of a body left behind, and then that too dissipated as the raven of black fire swept forward and flung its wings forward to completely cover the entire body of Pestilax. The greater daemon was completely engulfed, and the noise that screeched across the entire battlefield was one of true pain that escalated in volume and length seemingly constantly before cutting off as the black fire finally began to somehow burn at itself. The red core slowly faded as more and more of it burned away as the black fire burned all the hotter before it was finally gone all together and the raven dissolved into a covering blanket of fire.

Which, finally, exploded.

There had been no smoke, for the fire had been too hot for such things. As such, it was for all to see, to witness, that of Pestilax, there was no longer any sign at all. All that was left were the impressions in the blackened yet cleansed dirt where once there had been a clear extension of Nurgle's Garden. Even his sword was gone, for all that the fire had not even touched at it. A great many daemons remained, of course, but great numbers of them were dissipating entirely. All across the battlefield, the servants of Nurgle faltered, for where they had once been empowered by the arrival, now they were that much more drained and fearful for the forced departure. For the servants of the Emperor, there were cheers and shouts, and screams and snarls, as the unnatural despair and uncertainty that had nearly spelled their doom was banished. That mental space was now filled by an all-encompassing fury.

Aramus stood, barely alive but still on his feet, staring at the assault claw and arm which was all that remained, his weary body finally managing to clot his wounds enough that he would not necessarily die from blood loss. And yet, it was not all that remained, he saw. There, somehow, laying on the ground in front of him, lay large talisman that he managed to convince his shattered left hand to close in a death grip over. It There was a steady warmth there, comforting, somehow, despite how it should have been destroyed along with its wielder. Yet it had not. And here he still stood. Slowly, painfully, he reached for and found his combat knife on his belt, as a few of the more fanatical heretic troops crept closer, horror and confusion turning to zealous anger as they beheld a foe who they could take it out on. Others, having seen the end, saw the claw and grew that much angrier, and headed for it instead. To do what, Aramus didn't know. He didn't care, either. Over two thirds of the bones in his body were broken, and he absolutely had less than half the amount of blood in his body that he should. His armor was a shattered wreck, and less than slivers were left of Sunderhammer. He had one eye he could see through, and one lung breath through. His combat knife remained sharp as ever, however.

It was going to have to be enough.

==============================================================

Pulling Back: 86 vs. 38 vs. 18
Final Gate: 100 vs. 44

They were, to a man, wounded. Some lightly, some extensively. They were beginning to run low on ammo. On grenades. On missiles. Every single one of the Librarians had been called to work upon breaking the wards upon the door. This left every other marine vulnerable to the many defenses still left in the citadel, dizzying and strange things meant to befuddle and outright break the mind and poison the body and soul. Many were forced to steadfastly ignore the pained screams and pleadings of dead brothers now passed on. Others had to work to not twitch and fire into hallucinations of enemies alive and dead and thus waste what ammo they had. The dreadnoughts were less affected, but not entirely immune either. By now, all three were constantly rambling to the ghosts. It was Gabriel alone, however, who stood steadfast. None of the Blood Ravens had been tested in their lives in the exact same way, though there were many commonalities. By the end of the Civil War, all had stained their hands in the blood of those they had once called brothers.

None, save Gabriel, however, had watched as Cyrene burned. Had been responsible for reporting the planet's corruption to the Inquisition. Typhon was the machinations of Kyras, and Calderis and Meridian would have suffered the same were it not for the Blood Ravens, but Cyrene was his burden alone to carry. Here, now, targeted by the defenses of Vandis, he listened to the screams of billions of souls.

But, of course, none of them had time for serious contemplation of such things, for they were being attacked. What had to be the last of the gene-hounds were charging now, the cultist troops were trying to push through the three hallways that lead directly to the innermost sanctum. There were no more Chaos Space Marines left, or at least none that were willing to defend Vandis to this extent, but there were plenty of daemons to fill the space. Though their armor became ever more pockmarked and scraped and blasted, the Blood Ravens refused to falter. Each salvo became that much more precise, for not a single shot could be wasted. Those that reached the front lines had to contend with Gabriel and the other marines who bore chainswords and combat knives. There had, previously, been no open cover whatsoever as the Blood Ravens had made their approach. The better for the turrets to target them, of course. Now, however, the piles of dead gene-hounds and Chaos Space Marines had been dragged about, thick masses of muscle and bone pushed together with black-painted ceramite, and it was behind these that the Blood Ravens could duck behind.

"Justinius! How much longer!" Gabriel called behind him.

"It is done!"

The speed of it made the Chapter Master whirl, an eyebrow cocked high despite everything else going on. The Chief Librarian sneered as he waved a hand, the final gesture in ten minutes worth of work. All at once, the accursed sigils dimmed and outright melted off the door. There was a series of pops and screeches as the daemons bound into the very door itself were torn asunder by the cleansing work. A shockwave of force and unintelligible sound burst forth and sent many of the enemy on their backs, the Blood Ravens mostly remaining upright by way of bracing themselves upon the dead chaos space marines and gene-hounds. In that time, the dreadnoughts saw fit to cleanse the hallways entirely with their multi-meltas. The doors did not last that much longer as they were smashed open.

"Vandis!" Gabriel roared as the Blood Ravens staggered into the room.

On the other side, in a wide circled chamber upon a slightly raised dais in front of a large altar, stood Vandis. The last recorded pict-images of Vandis had been of a somewhat portly man with a large mustache and beard who seemed to favor the velvet and gold colors of Meridian's upper spire inhabitants. What stood before them now was a monster. The nobility of the human form had been stripped away entirely; every inch of his skin had been transformed into craggy blue-purple scales. A third arm sprouted from just under his left arm, but was insectoid and thin, terminating in a long slicing blade of bone. His facial hair had all been transformed into writhing lengths of tentacles that twitched this way and that where they lay. His spine had clearly grown, as with the rest of him, to the point that he was lopsided now, each of his upper vertebrae sprouting spike growths which punctured through his gristle and scales to touch open air over what should have been his right shoulder. A trio of horns sprouted from his forehead, each of them wide and emblazoned with burning blue sigils of Tzeentch. Below them, however, lay seven more eyes, bringing the heretic to a total of nine. The heretic was swollen with power, a crackling nimbus of fire and lightning surrounding him, with a large ring made of a mobius strip of gnashing teeth haloing the back of his head. When he grinned, it was with knife-length teeth that should not have fit inside a closed mouth.

"Blood Ravens. Look at you all. So weak. So pitiful. Congratulations," Vandis clapped with a dry chuckle. "You have chosen a most auspicious place to die when you should have done so before now."

"Coward. This could have been over with long ago, if you had ever the courage to face us rather than try and drown us with your followers," Gabriel hissed out. "But such is the weakness of traitors and heretics."

Vandis chuckled, the very air curdling around the noise.

"Weakness? No, fool. It is the whims of the strong to use the weak as they wish. And look at you," he splayed out all three arms. "You think you have truly harmed my forces? I have billions of slaves, of souls, to feed the fire of industry and regain the favor of the Dark Gods. All you have done will amount to nothing in the years to come, a mere footnote on my rise to power."

"No, Vandis," Gabriel growled. "Today is the day that House Vandis falls. Forever."

The former governor sneered, the lips of the left half of his face splitting open with the size of it until reaching a hole where the ear should have been.

"I knew you would not simply lay down and die, but…truly? Look at yourselves," Vandis laughed as he looked at them. "Your armor is as black as Abbadon's Legion now with the blood and rot of the fallen. You are bloodied and broken. I can feel the weakness of your paltry psykers, after so long. Do you truly think you can face me and win? The God of Fate Himself is my patron, yours is but a silent corpse on a flickering, dying throne!"

For a moment, Gabriel considered, taking stock of his troops. His battle brothers. Himself. The plans they had made, had theorized, up until this very moment.

"Patron or not, we will find victory this day," he nodded as the vox crackled and cleared. "Justinius!"

"Yes," the Chief Librarian spat and summoned forth all of his power. The rest of the Librarians did the same, and soon enough a thick bubble of sheer psychic might surrounded them all.

It was completely blinding, though Vandis laughed at the sight of it.

"Is that it? Truly? That is the measure of your strength? Hah! If I'd known you were so weak, I would have sent the rest of the gene-hounds and simply had you cut down sooner!"

"Aeneas," Justinius whispered solely through his mind into that of another with the faintest of touches.

Gabriel did not see it, but he heard it when Vandis' laughter cut off into choked surprise. The light, casting itself through the Materium and Immaterium both, was allowed to fade. There, standing only a few steps down the dais than he had begun, stood Vandis. Hurtling through the air, his entire chest caved in after what looked to have been a casual backhand, was Codicier Aeneas, the Librarian landing in a crumpled heap at Gabriel's feet. Immediately, Apothecary Medici was at his side. But more importantly was what was stuck into Vandis' chest. It was not the holy Blade of the Martyr. But rather it was a black and white icon, pressed deeply into the heretic's chest. Vandis raised an eyebrow, his tentacles twitching towards it. It had barely drawn any blood at all, and what did drip down to the floor sizzled and ate through the stone. Again, Vandis sneered.

"Was that…it?" He guffawed outright, his chest expanding and contracting beyond the limits that it should have as he did so. "This is your grand attempt? What is this?" He held it closer to his nine eyes, the tentacles having wrenched it upwards and out of him. "Oh ho! A symbol of the Inquisition? A prospective little slave to the next wretch who bumbles past as part of the Corpse-Emperor's most holy Inquisition?" He rolled all nine of his eyes as he glared down at the fallen Aeneas, the Codicier having already slipped into suspended animation.

"No, Vandis," Gabriel answered for the unconscious Librarian. "It is not."

The heretic narrowed his eyes, his head tilting to the side.

"The Blood Ravens, even as we are, could defeat you, make no mistake," the Chapter Master continued before the smallest of smiles quirked his lips. "But you do not deserve the honor of truly facing us in battle."

Vandis had enough time to open his mouth before the advanced teleport beacon hidden inside the Rosetta activated. For it was known that it was not the true symbol of authority, for even unconscious that remained solely at Inquisitor Adrastia's side. This, however, was something else altogether. Once, it had been won through much hard work and favors paid by Adepts of the Mechanicus trained on Mars itself. Twice, it had been given over to a Jokaero and given back with its form and ability altered further. Now, it triggered, and within less than a second the transition occurred. But rather than the flash of light and burning smell of caustic ozone that was typical of most teleportations, there was only a sudden deafening silence. Gabriel could not even hear his own bionics, let alone his own breathing. That was the least of the effects, for the entire Librarius, as one, collapsed to their knees or beyond that save for Justinius himself who was forced to lean heavily upon his force staff.

A rising, unfamiliar, near uncontrollable rage filled Gabriel as he beheld what Adrastia's last resort was. It was not the fact that it was a cage, for that was expected. But rather, it was the things surrounding it which seemed to demand his ire regardless of whatever else he thought. At each of the four points of the cage lay strange columns of brass and titanium, hexagrammic wards scrawled across every single inch of them. The bars and body of the cage was equally covered, and yet Gabriel felt something deep in him, something from his very soul, cry out to strike at the columns for reasons he could not fathom. Hazard symbols in High and Low Gothic were writ across each of the columns as well as a confusing number of other languages, carefully placed to not interfere with the hexagrammic works that had painstakingly been put into place. Near silent frothing fury, was visible, but still not audible, on some of the more injured Blood Ravens.

The effect on Vandis was far more immediate, and it was that alone that kept Gabriel from striking the columns – the sarcophagi, some part of his mind tried to correct for some reason. Within the cage, Vandis screamed, his very flesh and scales twisting and seemingly burnt as if he had been engulfed in an invisible fire. His nine eyes bled, wept, multicolored liquids that seemed to somehow phase out of existence the moment they left his person. The nimbus of power that had surrounded him disappeared outright, the mobius strip of teeth gone. It looked, quite simply, like parts of Vandis were dissolving the longer he stood within the cage. His third arm lashed out, trying to cut through the bars, and yet where the mutated limb touched the metal, it ceased to be, severing it into numerous pieces. Again, the blood and chunks seemed to fade out of existence. Vandis shouted, screamed, his mouth opening wide enough to eat a man whole, exposing that his lower jaw actually extended down past his pectorals, and yet there was still no sound whatsoever.

Then, in another stuttered splash of not-color and un-sound, the cage disappeared entirely and its occupant with it.

The last symbol that Gabriel had seen, one surprisingly prominently placed at the precise middle of each of the columns, confused him. He knew the symbols of the Inquisition, but this was not that. Rather, it beheld the Inquisitorial ][, but in its center was a scowling skull, one with an open eye above its original two. In all his years, Gabriel had never seen such a symbol before. But he could not contemplate it long, however, as the sound returned to the room and with it much pained groans from the Librarians as they dragged themselves to their feet. He turned to Justinius, the Chief Librarian wiping his lips from the blood that he had uncontrollably vomited for a moment.

"Justinius, what...-," Gabriel paused as his friend raised one hand, the Chief Librarian taking a few more seconds to recover.

"All right. Ask," Justinus grunted as he reached down to kneel next to Aeneas, placing a hand on the fallen Codicier's pauldron.

"What was that, Justinius? And those symbols-,"

"Something I never thought to see in person, and in fact dearly wished to avoid," the psyker responded dryly before standing up to face him once more. "That was a Quieting Cage, a horrid device of incredible power if levied upon the correct target. I know of only one organization in the entire Imperium which steward them and have the capability of loaning them out," he shuddered while looking back to where Vandis had once stood. "Our records are extensive, even with Kyras damaging it in some portions, but that…," Justinius waggled a finger, "That was one even he did not want to look at long enough to pass into the fire."

"But you know of it regardless," Gabriel stated, leaning some of his weight onto a now upright Godsplitter.

"It is my responsibility as Chief Librarian to know all of what is in our records," Justinius made to shrug before shuddering again. "And yes, I do. It is an invention of a secretive, near invisible society in the Imperium, an organization made up solely of Blanks. They are known, in some circles, as the Sisters of Silence."

Gabriel mulled over that information even as more screams and howls went up from elsewhere in the citadel, likely coming to either support their master or avenge him if they learned of his death. He knew of blanks, or nulls, depending on who was speaking. He had not, however, ever had the misfortune to be near to one, or the technology that they might craft or have crafted for them.

"Is that why…," he gestured at himself, then at Justinius.

"Yes. If sufficiently powerful, the Null effect can drive the ensouled to insane fury," Justinius nodded wearily, "As the universe seeks to correct what it considers an error, an 'un-thing' which should not be yet is. To a daemon, or psyker, or anything relating to the Warp…it quells them most effectively. Fatally, in some cases, according to our records – but even then all we have is largely speculation and rumor."

"I see," Gabriel nodded once before glancing over the terribly embattled 5th Company.

Tarkus Varianus raised his head to meet the eyes of his Chapter Master, the Captain of the 5th Company clearly willing to continue fighting on. But Gabriel's eyes moved on, to the rest of the remains of 5th Company and across the terrible damage they bore. Even the dreadnoughts were sparking and leaking oil from a few places. It would not be impossible for them to fight their way out, all the way back to the surface, to continue the slaughter.

"I have had enough of this planet, this system," he said instead, thumbing his vox, listening for the crackling to clear up as the void shields fell once more. "This is Gabriel. We are ready for extraction. Lock on to my signal and teleport us out before the void shields raise once more. Send the evacuation signal to the Imperial Guard as well."

A moment, then the light enveloped them all.

And, for the first time in Gabriel's life, he actually appreciated the horrid sensations that it carried with it rather than what he knew could have been instead.

=====================================================================

A bloody faced Colonel Gabriel Derosa pulled the trigger and let his hellgun fire on full auto as they retreated back towards the drop ships. Around him, the rest of the soldiers of Meridian did the same. His wife's Baneblades had been the first in and now were most certainly attempting to be the last out. Eleven barrels of hell let loose on a near constant basis, it wasn't as if they were bereft of targets in any sense. The daemons had backed off by this point, this far from the shrinking warp tear, and there were already reports that the foremost elements had already escaped from the cross-continental hive's limits and were now descending as swiftly as possible into the few securely held tunnels. But there were far more men and women to move, to shift, a mass of humanity that by virtue of its size simply could not move overly swiftly.

"Keep moving, damn it, keep moving!" He threw himself unceremoniously into the dirt to avoid a grenade's explosion, popping up immediately afterwards to shoot the thrower.

The enemy sensed weakness, or at least thought they did, and their pursuit was near relentless at this point. Every time one of the damned gene-hounds showed up, if there wasn't enough concentrated fire on them each could account for at least ten of his guardsmen before it could be brought down. The war machines, corrupted Leman Russes and Sentinel walkers were, in a way, less of a threat. One of the Baneblades could hit them, or other heavy weapons teams could try and take care of them due to how obvious they were as targets. The gene-hounds, on the other hand, could hide amongst the masses of the enemy until they got close enough. Gabriel shouted and pointed, ordered and shot, and ever so slowly gave ground to the enemy as more and more of them evacuated.

"This is Colonel Gabriel Derosa, we could use some support if possible!"

"Stand fast, Colonel," the ever-cool voice of Captain Carlyle answered him. "The Sword shall provide it. Our objective is contained, there is no more reason not to usher this ruined and tainted world onto its final fate."

Shortly after, as if the God-Emperor himself had turned his attention to New Meridian, tightly concentrated and expertly aimed salvos of plasma began to rain down from the heavens all amongst the enemy. The anti-orbital defenses in this area were already destroyed, or had been during the fighting on the part of the Imperial Guard, and as such there quite simply was no defense at all as the Inquisitorial ship brought all its fury to the heretical denizens of the planet. Gabriel watched as whole blocks were vaporized into craters filled with liquidized metal and stone, the living and the dead both obscured by the superheated and then rapidly cooling leavings. Less than ten minutes after that, the Blood Raven strike cruisers added their own firepower. By then, the sheer volume of concentrated orbital fire was rupturing spire levels above and below their retreat, and the enemy simply had no response to it anymore.

It would take another five hours to finally shove everyone onto the ships in standing room as they were rapidly taken up into orbit and allowed to move about, sit down, or outright collapse. First were the most injured, then those more lightly wounded, and third came the dead that could be recovered. Many were not and would have to accept their pyre being joined with that of the heretics. The priests, of course, spoke of them as martyrs, and declared their souls sheathed in their righteous sacrifices towards the God-Emperor's side. Gabriel hoped that was true. It wasn't that the Meridian regiments had not taken casualties since his mother started reforming and reorganizing them, he had made it to Colonel in a hundred different battles, but none so many in a single battle. Perhaps, though, that was the point. One last hateful deed of spite on the part of House Vandis.

In the meantime, however, the ships had not ceased firing, though they understandably reduced their shots in some areas to allow for the evacuation and retreat to proceed apace. Four times, the enemy tried to assail their positions with aircraft, only to be shot out of the sky by the Hydra flak tanks they still had on the field. On the fifth and final time, it was flying daemons, and those were far harder to deal with, but that time the Blood Ravens reappeared on the field, though it was solely their Librarians. For all the praises his mother sang of them, he could not help the revulsion he felt as the mutants levied their abilities against the Heldrakes. On the ground, however, the enemy could not make their way through the constant orbital bombardments.

But, in time, it did end. The last of the tanks was loaded, the last of the troops onboard, and they finally left the accursed mirror world behind them. Whatever dark secrets it might continue to hold, whatever old blasphemies had been done there, it would not matter in the long run on the history of the universe. Gabriel, as did many others, managed to get to a viewing port, or a spot near a channel-wide vox broadcast as the final order was given. He listened to the voice of his namesake, of Gabriel Angelos, announce, once more, the death of a world. And all watched, or listened, or both, as every Imperial ship present concentrated fire on a single point. The enemy had no more defenses, and the warp tear was on the other side of the planet when they began. Before the planet could rotate enough that the many, many anti-orbital cannons left in the hive could once again be able to fire upon any of their ships, the damage was done. The continental plates began to shudder, shake, and finally, shatter. The mantle of the world began to spill out, the entire sphere wobbling and cracking open. It was not a swift death, none of the ships they had brought with them carried true Exterminatus munitions, or if they did, they went unused in this instance. Even without it, however, New Meridian died.

"So it is done," he sighed in satisfaction. "I'm headed to my bunk, if anyone needs me…uh, don't."

"Your bunk, or your wife's?" Captain Beltsworth snarked, getting a burst of laughter from the other officers.

"I'll figure it out when I get there!" He called back with a roll of his eyes.

===================================================================

"Mortirex escaped," Gabriel sighed as he listened to the unceasing reports from the servitor.

"A foe for another day," Tarkus bowed his head for a moment. "Chapter Master, If I may…?"

"Go," Gabriel waved a hand, "Be with your battle brothers and your company. They have earned their rest, as have you."

"I could say the same to you, Angelos," Tarkus saluted before turning and leaving the strategium and the bridge entirely.

"He is not wrong," Justinius murmured to him.

"No. But I will rest easier once we are back within the gravity reef and leaving this blasted system behind," Gabriel shook his head slowly. "And do not pretend you do not require recuperation yourself, Justinus. You and the rest of the Librarius."

The aura of palpable power that surrounded the Chief Librarian in almost every moment was largely missing. The omnipresent glow behind his eyes had faded, leaving only his pupils as dimly glowing blue circles. Even the psychic crackles which normally surrounded his head or the head of his force staff were gone. All that remained was a wearied, wounded space marine, standing next to his equally wearied, if far more wounded Chapter Master. The two elder marines simply stood, leaning a bit harder on the actuality sphere's projector than normal to remain upright.

"Set course for the gravity reef tunnels."

Hunt for Vandis Concluded:

Objectives

Main Objective: Capture Or Kill Traitorous Heretic Ex-Governor Vandis [Successful]

Secondary Objective: Destroy Hidden Black Legion Anchorage In Eastern Fringe [Successful]

Tertiary Objective: Kill Chaos Lord Mortirex of the Black Legion [Failure]

Relations:

Admiral Graves, Battlefleet Korianis: Neutral[+] Is Now Good[-]

Hidden Relations Connection Found: Inquisitor Adrastia <-> Sisters of Silence

Promotions:

5 5th Company Marines Deemed Veterans
4 Lexicanum Judged Codicier Worthy In Control And Strength

Further Notations Below, And To Follow In Subsequent Turn Post

Spoiler: Imperial Forces

Blood Ravens
1st Company
SC Spiraling Fury [Minor Damage]
2 Escorts (1 Gladius, 1 Hunter Destroyer) [Minor Damage]
5th Company
BB Litany of Fury [Bombardment Cannon Non-Operational, Majority of Weapon Arrays Destroyed, Shield Arrays At 15%, Extreme Hull Damage] DANGER: Litany of Fury will require significant attentions at a Mechanicus Shipyard for repairs. Any notable damage may disable ship in permanency.
SC Rage of Erudition [Minor Damage]
SC The Great Father’s Fist [Minor Damage]
7 Escorts (x3 Gladius, x2 Hunter Destroyers, x2 Nova) [Minor Damage]

Reminder of Blood Raven Forces Capable of Combat:
9 1st Company Marines in Terminator Armor, Chief Librarian Justinius, Epistolary Lucan, Epistolary Idmon, Codicier Aeneas (+11 Codiciers, 6 Lexicanum, 11 Telepathica Recruit Lexicanum)
10 5th Company Marines, including Command Squad, 2 Dreadnoughts including Captain Davian Thule.

Apollo Diomedes Requires Master of the Forge or Senior Techmarines To Forge The Bionics Required To Return To Battle-Capable State, But Will Not Require Dreadnought Internment. Remains In Suspended Animation Until Then.

Gabriel Angelos Conscious, Lack of Senior Tech-Marine or Master of the Forge Means Bionics Unable To Be Fully Repaired. (Combat Capacity 25%)

Apothecaries/Tech-Priests Working On Below
1 Codicier Too Wounded To Fight In Next Phase Of Battle
4 Lexicanum Too Wounded To Fight In Next Phase Of Battle
1 1st Company Marine Too Wounded To Fight In Next Phase Of Battle
20 5th Company Marines Too Wounded To Fight In Any Battle [Total Bionics Cost To Return To Full Functionality: 125]
3 5th Company Marines Interred Into Dreadnoughts [3 Dreadnought Chassis Used] [Tomb-Brother Irnus, Mestor, Nephrus]

Confirmed Blood Raven Losses:
Honor Guard Captain Doukas Laskaris (Relic Bloodtalon Destroyed) (Single Gene-Seed Recovered, +1 Gene-Seed)
Apothecary Falkor Ryll (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
Chaplain Uther Volkoss (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
3 Honor Guard (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
4 Lexicanum (Gene-Seed Recovered, +8 Gene-Seed)
3 Codiciers (Gene-Seed Recovered, +6 Gene-Seed)
5th Company Chaplain Tarion (Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
2 5th Company Marines (+3 Gene-Seed Recovered, 1 Destroyed In Battle)
1st Company Assault Terminator Sergeant Minos (+2 Gene-Seed Recovered)
9 1st Company Marines In Terminator Armor (+18 Gene-Seed Recovered)
34 5th Company Marines (+50 Gene-Seed Recovered, 18 Destroyed In Battle)
5 Lexicanum (+10 Gene-Seed Recovered)
2 Codiciers (4 Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
2 5th Company Marines (+4 Gene-Seed Recovered)
3 5th Company Marines (6 Gene-Seed Destroyed In Battle)
2 5th Company Marines (+4 Gene-Seed Recovered)
2 5th Company Marines (+4 Gene-Seed Recovered)

Imperial Navy:
1 An Emperor-class Battleship (Moderate Damage) (Interceptor/Troop Transport Compliment Down By 90%, Bomber Compliment At 100%)
3 Lunar-class Cruisers (Moderate Damage)
4 Frigates (Moderate Damage)
20 Troop Transports (Carrying Imperial Guard Forces) / 1 Galaxy-class Troop Transport (Carrying Imperial Guard Forces)

All Void Armsmen Utilized In Boarding Lost (Remaining Void Armsmen Now Depleted To Severely Understrength Levels)

Imperial Guard:

8 Meridian Consolidated Imperial Guard Regiments (1 Infantry/3 Mechanized Infantry/5 Armored) [7 Regiments Lost i.e. 700,000~ Fatalities]
1 Kauravan Superheavy Armored Formation - 15 Lucius-Pattern Baneblades of Kaurava Attached To Armored Meridian Regiment, commanded by Colonel Stubbs of Kaurava
1 Meridian Storm Trooper Regiment (10th Meridian Consolidated)
1 Inquisitorial Storm Trooper Regiment (Ordo Hereticus) [1/3 Casualties Sustained] Will Not Deploy Without Inquisitorial Order

Inquisition
1 Inquisitorial Grand Cruiser, Vengeance-class Sword of Reckoning (Custom Variant, Heavily Modified) (Moderate Damage)

Imperial Ship Losses:
All Fire Ships
2 Avenger-class Grand Cruisers
5 Lunar-class Cruisers
6 Frigates

Spoiler: Confirmed Enemy Slain

New Meridian: Enemy Populace Estimated At 7.2 Billion (Including Menials, Conscripts, Vandian Guard, Stormtroopers, Leman Russ Tanks, Hydra Flak Tanks, Manticore Tanks, Land Raiders (2), Baneblades (5), Chaos Knights (10), Chaos Warhound Titan (1), 500~ Leman Russ Tanks, Other Tanks, Artillery, Experimentals, Etc.)
10 Soul-Tortured Defense Monitor Cruisers [800,000~ Crew Total]
500,000~ Saharduin (Piscean Warriors, Alien Crew Members, Engineer Caste, Blood Shamans, Etc.)
Reaverlord Carnax, Khornate Alien Warlord
Grand Hunter Hraxe, Slaaneshi Alien Warlord
Admiral Maximilian Vandis, New Meridian Defense Fleet Commander
New Meridian Defense Defense Fleet: Estimated Crews At 10,000,000 (Including All Ships, Orbital Stations, Shipyard)
Nascent Forge World Opux Maxima: Enemy Populace Estimated At 1.2 Billion (Including Menials, Hereteks, Magos Hereteks, Masters of Forge-Hives, Skitarii, Obliterators, Daemon-Machines, Chaos Knights, Tanks, Artillery, Experimentals, etc.)
Fabricator-General Drakis
Black Legion Sorcerer Lord Melphas
3 Lesser Black Legion Sorcerers
425 Black Legion Chaos Space Marines
150 Black Legion Veteran Chaos Space Marines
30 Khornate Berserkers
2.2 Million Dark Mechanicus Menials
10,000~ Dark Mechanicus Hereteks
1 Dark Mechanicus Magos 01b7, Master of Forge-Hive 01b7
50,000 Gene-Hound Shocktrooper Abominations
25,0000~ Heavy Combat Servitors
1,000,000~ Dark Mechanicus Skitarii
10,000~ Dark Mechanicus Elite Skitarii
20,000~ Cultist Troopers
7000 Elite Cultist Stormtroopers
250 Soulrend Obliterators

Turn 28: A Breath Choked By Ash (Part One)

A Breath Choked By Ash
+075.M42+ To +080.M42+
Be Faithful! Be Strong! Be Vigilant! - The Emperor of Mankind

When the Blood Ravens exited the gravity reef around System Jubacael after weeks of careful travel, there was only a short time spent amongst the rest of their allies. Inquisitor Adrastia had awoken, finally, and was well on her way to recovery. Her appreciation for the live capture of Vandis was considerable, even if she very obviously did not provide any answers as to when or how she had acquired the device used to do so. While the loss of her entire Stormtrooper Regiment stung, and her ship had sustained moderate damage, she frankly assessed that the task had been well worth it. If not for the capture of Vandis, then the destruction of the anchorage itself. On that, at least, all present could agree upon. Admiral Graves, for his part, admitted that he was likely to get quite the haranguing from the Lord Admiral of the Korianis Sector due to the loss of a number of his ships. He was, somewhat, hopeful that the stamp of the Inquisition's approval for his aid would ensure he didn't lose a rank or worse. Adrastia did admit that she found him useful, and for an Inquisitor, that was quite a statement – though for good or ill seemed to depend. The Imperial Guard shuffled off to the only planet named Meridian within several lightyears after a few heartfelt goodbyes. The Blood Ravens, on the other hand, could not afford to do so. Rather, their ships direly required repairs, their Chapter Monastery most of all, and so continued on to the Forge World Zerann. Communications began to pass back and forth by astropath to the rest of the Chapter, and so it was that it was not within Subsector Aurelia, but within Subsector Krasus alongside the Inquisitor and the remaining ships of the Imperial Navy that the Blood Ravens were joined together once more.

Sharing reports was all well and good, but it was another thing entirely to behold each other with their own eyes after but five years or so apart. And so it was, over Zerann, within the nearly shattered wreck that was the Litany of Fury that the Blood Ravens met one another. On the one side was the ragged 5th Company, half of the 1st Company complement that had been sent after Vandis, and a large number of psykers. On the other, vastly outnumbering them, was the entire rest of the Chapter. As battle brothers joined with one another once more, speaking, telling, joking, commiserating and letting the bonds of brotherhood flourish, the officers turned inwards for a short time. If only to properly take stock with one another and what had occurred in their respective campaigns. The Hunt for Vandis was first of this, told by Gabriel, Justinius, and Tarkus to the rest of the Chapter's upper leadership. There was surprise, sorrow, and pain, but most important of all was the triumph of victory. Even the bitter tang of Mortirex's escape could not taint that overly much.

Then came the tales of the Helba Campaign. Of a Chapter reduced to a single company. Of tyranids in excess of what were faced in the 1st Aurelian Crusade. But so too was the Imperial response far greater. The extinction of the Odaken done with, the Order of the Lost Rosetta had turned to their now most hated of foes aside from the forces of Chaos, and had reinforced the Mede Subsector. The Imperial Navy of Helba, as well as the Imperial Guard, had all responded as well. It had been quite a large campaign, for the Mede Subsector was large, the Helba Sector actually closer to the galactic core than the Korianis Sector considerably. As such, a tyranid tendril gaining strength that much closer to Terra demanded extreme responses. World after world was reclaimed, and much information pried loose and disseminated about the new 'Shadow Towers', constructs of flesh and brain meant to expand and empower the Shadow in the Warp to the extent of outright preventing warp travel within any system with said tower. A delaying tactic, the better to allow the Hive Mind time to safely devour. In the end, with Cyrus as Force Commander, the whole of the Order of the Lost Rosetta, the remaining Ebon Claws, and as much force that the Imperial Guard and Navy could muster, the xenos were beat back. Five long, grueling years were spent pruning them from world after world, until reaching their original entry point into Imperial space. There, Cyrus revealed that they had undertaken the direst of gambles, directly going after the Norn-Queens hidden on the enemy bio-ships. It was purely through the aid of their allies, luck, and the experience of Cyrus that victory was achieved and the Chapter survived the fighting at all. Indeed, purely by the numbers, the losses experienced outweighed those of the Blood Ravens fallen fighting against Vandis and his lackeys many times over.

Victory, and victory, purchased in blood. Such was the life of a space marine, set down by the Emperor himself since the founding of the Imperium.

Now there was time, even if only a modicum of it, to rest and recover. The Mechanicus was both shocked and outraged by the presence of a nascent Forge World dedicated to their dark cousins, and for destroying it so utterly it was considered just and fair for them to repair the damage to the ships of the Chapter, including those damaged in the Helba Campaign. Especially the Litany. The very spine of the battle barge's superstructure was a near hair's breadth away from cracking irreparably. Then again, the Fabricator-General declared that sustaining such damage in the course of destroying Opus Maxima meant that such holy wounds demanded immediate and strong attentions. Some things, the loss of a few thunderhawks, could also be replaced in time, either through Zerann or others, but the repair of the ships was far more important. Which was made more significant due to just how incredibly busy the shipyards of Zerann really were. The Imperial Navy desperately needed to replace the ships lost against the Suysh, and there were crash training programs for all levels of crew for such ships apparently being carried out across many of the worlds in Korianis according to the Fabricator-General. As such, the repair of the Litany would take a considerable amount of time, but would be done highly comprehensively, as well as the other ships' repairs.

Assured that those Blood Raven ships that required longer-term repairs would be well guarded by the Mechanicus, the Chapter finally turned towards Subsector Aurelia.

============================================================

"Governor Derosa," Gabriel returned the smile that the Governor was offering him.

It had taken weeks of work on the part of Martellus, but finally, his bionics were finally fully restored and fine-tuned that much more. He did not garb himself in the mantle of his terminator armor, for that required much longer to fix, but a regular suit of power armor was more than sufficient. He stood at half-attention within her office, the rest of the servants and attendants sent out of the room entirely. The Blood Ravens of the 1st Company remained outside as well; a courtesy offered to a close ally of the Chapter. The meeting request had been unexpected, but not unwelcome. Elena Derosa opened her mouth, holding up a glass of some alcohol or another before thinking better of it and placed it on the table on a small coaster of real cork and wood.

"Chapter Master Angelos," she bowed her head to him. "Thank you for meeting with me."

"It is no trouble…," Gabriel trailed off. "Unless it is?"

"Perhaps," she shrugged. "You are aware of the latest cultist problems on Meridian?"

At that, Gabriel's lip curled in distaste.

"I am, yes. More than just usual riots, outright cultists devoted to-,"

"Him, yes," she cut him off, shuddering as even the very thought of the name passed through her. "They are being suppressed well enough by the PDF, but that they haven't stopped – that they're showing up more and more as their very dreams are apparently twisting them around…it is not a good sign. The Ecclesiarchy is sending priests into the Underhive regularly now, trying to buoy their faith, but I do not know if it will be enough."

"A fair consideration," Gabriel rubbed at his chin, walking to join her at one of the enormous windows of her office.

The view of the planet below was lost below the clouds, leaving only a white-grey expanse below and the stars above.

"The very planet of Aurelia was his prison, and it was badly damaged. The Grey Knights, have they done anything more in our absence?"

Derosa waggled a hand.

"They have spent most of their time near Aurelia itself, but have also visited here, on Meridian, as well as Calderis, Typhon, and even…," her irritation softened, "Even Cyrene."

Gabriel sighed.

"They have not offered much reasoning behind their movements, and their authority and position seems enough to scare away anyone loyal to the Emperor from interfering. But-," she was cut off as a rather loud beep came from the console built into her desk. Her expression tightened slightly. "Excuse me," she pressed a rune on the console. "What is it?"

"Governor Derosa, my humblest apologies, but…-,"

"Chapter Master," Gabriel raised an eyebrow as the secure channel vox clicked to life through his comm bead. "Be forewarned, Grey Knights approaching. What are your orders?"

"Calm yourself Sergeant Stromahn," he said quickly even as a now pale-faced Derosa received the same news from her own adjutants. "Do not provoke them."

"…understood, Chapter Master."

"Gabriel," Derosa looked up at him, "I assume you've received the same news as I?"

"Indeed. It seems that Inquisitors and their agents do so love to show themselves without warning," he gave a half-smirk before folding his hands behind his back and turning to face the doors. "Shall we see what they want?"

"It does not appear we have any other choice," she muttered before assuming a similar position. "Let them through, sergeant," she muttered to her own household guard.

Less than a minute passed before the Grey Knights arrived, pushing through the doors. There were only three of them, but each radiated considerable psychic might. Their leader bore a force halberd, the fierceness of his gaze palpable as he glanced from Governor to Chapter Master and back again.

"Justicar Tolmen," Derosa bowed curtly.

"Governor Derosa," the lead Grey Knight grunted. "We bear grave tidings, best delivered by person rather than by other…more easily intercepted methods. Chapter Master, this involves you as well," he said with a slight aside glance. "The Ordo Malleus had finished its investigations and studies. Based upon all of the data gathered, there is only one conclusion – the daemon is beginning to force open the bars of his cage."

Gabriel grit his teeth as Derosa leaned down heavily upon her desk.

"It is as we suspected then," she sighed. "Do we…is there any possible…?"

"The sealing ritual relied upon the planet being whole. It is not. Its freedom is, unfortunately, inevitable."

"So there is nothing to be done, then?" Gabriel asked as Derosa cursed quietly to herself.

The Justicar slowly turned his head to face the Chapter Master.

"There is already chatter that his influence is calling those devoted to the Fly Lord towards him, reports of certain devotees leaving their bases behind. We are already doing what we can to reinforce the seals – elsewise he would have already broken free," the Grey Knight said flatly. "Some few years, half a decade, perhaps. Then we will have to contest him outright."

"Along with all the flotsam that he can draw to his side by that point," Gabriel said, eyebrows furrowed.

"Correct."

"Do we have any idea as to who might listen to his call?" Derosa asked without looking upwards from her desk. "Or who already has?"

"Some," Tolmen tilted his head towards one of his brother marines, the other Grey Knight stepping forward to speak in a curiously raspy voice.

"Two warbands have recently abandoned their holdings ahead of multiple strike teams sent to hit them – the Plaguebones, formerly known as the Snakebones, and the Death Bringers. Both former loyal Chapters to the Imperium that fell to Chaos."

Gabriel let the information wash over him, the dismay a heavy weight which settled on his soldiers.

"Neither was at full strength at the time of their excommunications," the second Grey Knight continued, "But together, they are a considerable foe. There may be more, it is difficult to tell."

"If we know they are coming, we can prepare our forces to stop them then!" Derosa said, eyes bright with hope which withered as the looked at the impassive Grey Knights. "Can we not?"

"Given current circumstances throughout much of the Imperium, re-dedicating significant quantities of the Imperium's forces for a long period of time from their other duties may prove disastrous."

Derosa's head drew back in shock.

"So we're to be abandoned?"

"No. We cannot allow a daemon of this strength free reign, even this far on the Eastern Fringe," Tolmen shook his head. "Our Brotherhood shall arrive when the warnings we have inscribed on the seals activate, and the Blood Ravens will presumably be on hand to aid in the coming fight. If you have any other allies to call upon," he glanced at Gabriel, "It may be time to do so, if only that they may prepare themselves."

Their warning delivered, the Grey Knights swiftly departed, leaving Derosa and Gabriel behind to contemplate the future. Elena elected to do so with the fortifying drinking of three flutes of some bubbly alcohol, though Gabriel instead simple cast his mind out and reviewed what forces the Blood Ravens possessed.

"Half of the Meridian regiments are deployed elsewhere and cannot possibly be called back. A fourth are still in training, and the other fourth recuperating after Vandis," she spoke up eventually. "And I do not trust the Penal Legions to fight properly."

"You have Penal Legions?" Gabriel raised an eyebrow.

"I do now," she nodded. "Food and water riots, the greatest banes to Meridian's ongoing functioning under Vandis, have dropped more than 80%."

"Most precipitous, Governor."

"Yes, well," she did not smile, merely shrugged. "It helps when the hungry and thirsty are fed and watered…so long as they depart the planet forever."

Gabriel considered that for a moment.

"None of the Penal Legions of Meridian are slated to return, are they," he stated the truth he'd realized.

"No. They are recombined, reorganized, and sent out continually. Productivity has never been higher, crime and riots are a small fraction of what they once were, all at the comparatively low cost of equipping and training them before deploying them wherever Segmentum Command wishes. And yet, I shudder to think what the daemon might do if they were brought into the fight here."

"I understand. I must return to my battle brothers. Be well, Governor."

"You as well, Angelos."

===============================================================

"We all knew it was coming," Justinius mused as the rest of the Chapter's leadership met once more. "At least we have a vague timeline."

"Should we try and fortify Calderis and Meridian?"

"We can try," Gabriel frowned, "But their main target will be to destroy Aurelia, and in doing so, free Ulkair."

"The good Governor is no doubt heavily fortifying Meridian, and unfortunately there is little we can do for Calderis," Cyrus grunted, "It's too wide and open, any major fortifications would become an obvious target, even if it was only to try and evacuate the civilians."

"Argus cannot hold all of the people of Calderis regardless," Tarkus shook his head. "Our best bet would be to position troops there if we are to defend it at all, and with what settlements we can…and still the many nomad clans will be difficult to herd in."

"A fair point," Gabriel allowed. "As for allies, perhaps we may call upon the Order of the Lost Rosetta. We have our differences, but their homes are a short distance away from here, they cannot ignore the threat that the daemon and its slaves may pose."

"What of the Scarlet Lions?" Captain Marcus brought up, his hellishly grotesque face twisting in thought. "They were capable and stalwart."

"And thoroughly infiltrated by the Alpha Legion," Cyrus pointed out before sighing, "Still, they may come to our aid…if they are not otherwise engaged."

"Are there any others?" Gabriel asked, looking around the room before sighing. "If any of you have further thoughts, come and inform me."

Major Warning Delivered By Grey Knights: Ulkair, the Great Unclean One which has plagued Subsector Aurelia for centuries, is breaking free of his prison. His emanations and influence have begun seeping out and is beginning to draw servants and slaves of Nurgle towards his aid while beginning to corrupt the menials of Meridian. He is likely to finally break free in half a decade, give or take a year.

Ship Notations: Litany of Fury Unavailable For Combat For Current Turn. Legacy of Polonius Unavailable For Combat For Current Turn. Blood And Iron Unavailable For Combat For Current Turn. Other ships sustained minor to moderate damage that was repaired prior to turn start.

Kraken Splinter Invasion Results:

Kraken Splinter Defeated, 0 Norn-Queens Survived, Planets Reclaimed, 2 Planets Consumed, Clean-Up Duties Begun Throughout Mede Subsector
130 Scouts [2nd Stage] -> 100 Scouts [2nd Stage] After Fatalities (+25 Gene-Seed Recovered) -> Following Required Implantation 100 Battle Brothers [Unassigned] Additionally Active
197 Scouts [1st Stage] -> 145 Scouts [1st Stage] After Fatalities (15 Gene-Seed Recovered) -> Advances To 145 Scouts [2nd Stage] Active
10th Company Aspirants of 700 -> 600 Neophytes [1st Stage] -> 500 Neophytes [2nd Stage] -> 392 Survivors, Required Implantation Immediately, Granted By Authority of Captain Cyrus Octavius of the 10th Company. -> Following Implantation 359 Scouts [1st Stage] Additionally Active [3 Manifested Psyker Capabilities Following Implantation, Remanded to Librarius -> Gain 3 Lexicanum]
x4 Thunderhawk Transporters of Faith's Horizon Lost In Battle
x4 Thunderhawk Gunships of Sciencia Est Potentia Lost In Battle
10 4th Company Dead (+5 Gene-Seed Recovered) / 10 4th Company Deemed Veterans
7 2nd Company Dead (+10 Gene-Seed Recovered) / 12 2nd Company Deemed Veterans
[247 Gene-Seed Remains After Implantation Process And Recoveries]

New Notables Identified In Hunt For Vandis/Kraken Splinter Invasion Campaigns

5th Company Veteran Sergeant Trogus – Identified during the Hunt for Vandis for successfully keeping his entire squad alive throughout the fighting, whereas every other sergeant was either killed or lost members of their squad, despite repeatedly taking on spear-tip position alongside or occasionally outright replacing the marines of the 1st Company if required. A true protégé of Captain Tarkus, Sergeant Trogus possesses an equally stoic and taciturn temperament mixed with significant if tempered aggression in battle. A true warrior, a true leader. (+F, +W, Bedrock of Battle)
4th Company Veteran Sergeant Hantu – Fought on the front lines throughout Helba Campaign, proving not simply adept in battle but remarkably diplomatic, swiftly becoming tapped for regular cooperative and coordinative measures with the Imperial Guard and Sisters of Battle also fighting in the campaign. Possesses a remarkable affinity for combined forces combat, and was even granted the honor of commanding certain battles entirely with all three forces under his banner. (Legendary Fellowship: Within The Raven's Shadow, +W, +I)
2nd Company Veteran Nicholas – A Meridian High Spire-sourced assault marine who bears all the aggressive tendencies of Captain Hadrian Priscus, Veteran Nicholas repeatedly distinguished himself in the campaign for accomplishing the highest number of high-value target kills through individual combat, exceeding even Force Commander Cyrus. Slaying Hive Tyrants in their nests, ambushing Lictors as they skulked through the battlefield, and cutting down Zoanthropes before they could fully unleash their might, Veteran Nicholas bears a considerable amount of skill, outperforming all others in the 4th Company at the time of this notation. (+WS, +P)
Chaplain Sardus – Became especially notable after surviving a thunderhawk transporter crash behind enemy lines caused by tyranid flying bio-forms during the Helba campaign. Dragged other Blood Ravens forced into suspended animation for survival to safety, proceeded to hold out against non-stop tyranid attacks for three days straight until rescued after having run out of ammo on the second. A true student of Hannibal Palrun, the Master of Sanctity, tireless in energy and unfaltering in battle to the extreme. (+T, +W)
Chaplain Bellero – Slew a tyranid bio-titan after surviving getting stepped on by the beast directly into a highly acidic reclamation pool, Brother Bellero's armor and entire first layer of skin was gone from him even as he climbed and beat the bio-titan to death about the head with his half-broken crozius. Collapsed into suspended animation afterwards, but later returned to battle after healed. Became most proficient at targeting the larger bio-forms of the tyranids despite being largely on foot and began to lead others to do the same as the fighting intensified. Distinguished himself a dozen times over and received commendations of appreciation from both Imperial Guard forces and the Order of the Lost Rosetta as a result. (+S, +T, +F)
4th Company Veteran Sergeant Gelon: Due to the rapid pace of the campaign, Sergeant Gelon found himself and his squad often made do with only basic equipment, himself wielding only a bolt pistol and chainsword for the majority of the conflict. However, this did not prevent Sergeant Gelon from leading several rescue missions for Blood Raven positions as well as that of their allies, at one point preventing advancing fronts from collapsing on ten different occasions in a single month during a crucial phase. Provided invaluable support and guidance to younger scouts and neophytes during the campaign as well. Became targeted by the Hive Mind for assassination, survived all twelve attempts. (+F, +W)
Apothecary Aratos: Headed and protected field hospitals set up to support the advances on multiple different worlds, not merely from tyranid swarms but from various Lictors as well. Swiftly became known amongst the Imperial Guard and Sisters of Battle for taking in patients from their own medical camps when capacity was exceeded. Provided expert healing and is personally responsible for saving the lives of the Canoness Preceptors Lanati Kahele and Elizabeth Drake of the Lost Rosetta after both were nearly killed by tyranids. Protects his patients with remarkable ferocity, whether by chainsword or heavy bolter. (+I, +F)

Relations Changes Post Hunt For Vandis/Kraken Splinter Invasion/Latest Penitent Crusade Actions

Ecclesiarchy: Hated[+] -> Bad[+]
Imperial Guard: Suspect[-] -> Suspect
Ordo Xenos: Neutral -> Neutral[+]
Ordo Hereticus: Suspect -> Neutral
Order of the Lost Rosetta: Suspect[+] -> Neutral
Order of the Sacred Rose: Hated and Suspect -> Suspect[+]
Lord Admiral Bernard: Neutral[-] -> Neutral[+]
Admiral Graves: Good[-] -> Good
Lord General Cervantes: Hated -> Hated [-]
Lord Sector Alexander: Bad -> Bad[+]
Inquisitor Adrastia [REDACTED] (Ordo Hereticus) - Liked[+] (For An Inquisitor) -> Liked[+]
Canoness Superior Margaret Tenenbaum of the Order of the Lost Rosetta: Suspect[-] -> Neutral
Segmentum Ultima Command: Suspect[-] -> Suspect
Gained New: Helba Sector -> Mede Subsector: Liked
Gained New: Order of Our Martyred Lady: Neutral[+]
Gained New: Order of the Valorous Heart: Neutral
Gained New: Ebon Claws Chapter: Good
Gained New: Ebon Claws Chapter Master Manin: Good

Lead The Chapter (All Technically Available):
[] Further Black Crusade Contributions – Send forces to aid in the Black Crusade, even though Aramus's presence apparently counts enough for some. (Write-In)
[] Train 1st Company Battle Brothers In Terminator Armor Usage (Write-In Amount) [Note: Those selected will be unusable for any other purpose during the turn this option is selected i.e. 5 years.]
[] Assign Unassigned Battle Brothers [135] To Companies (Write-In Battle Brother Allotment)
[] Assign Veterans To 1st Company If Desired (Write-In, If Desired, Not Required)
[] Assign New Fleet Additions (Write-In Fleet Assignments For Acquired Frigates/Destroyers/Gunships) [IF ANY AVAILABLE]
[] Significant Mechanicus Offer – The Shadowed Grave: Careful analysis of the recovered Eldar data from their captured ships has revealed much, but perhaps nothing as useful as the possible location as to a vast potential bounty, a hidden ship graveyard within a nebula between Imperial territory. It is, going by the data, filled with ships from a variety of races and eras, amongst them ancient Imperial hulls. One group of which may include a coffin-ship detachment of a currently unidentified Titan Legio. Ordinarily, this alone might draw the Mechanicus forth, but there is more; The Corsair data reports them beginning to be pushed out of the area by an incursion sent forth by the Dark Mechanicus, that heretical sect of traitors to the Cult of Mars. Already, the forces of Zerann and Aerus are marshalling their own legions of Skitarii and ships, and they invite the Blood Ravens to join them, but are prepared to go ahead without you, for the data indicates that speed of utmost importance. Defending and examination of this hallowed grave must be done, either way. The full force of Zerann's 1st Explorator fleet is being readied for this. A single company seems it would be a good contribution given the strength of the Mechanicus forces already dedicated to the fight. [] (Write-In Forces Assigned, If Any)
[] Significant Mechanicus Offer– Fragments of Light: After the Space Hulk designated the Judgement of Carrion was fully disassembled, a small amount of Imperial vessels were successfully recovered and repaired to functionality. It's most twisted components, as well as those of clear xeno origin, were disposed of. It has been decades since then, and data analysis has finally completed of the many cogitators within. Most importantly, traces and fragments of an STC have been located, pointing to a desolate system within the Halo Stars which touch the Eastern Fringe. It is entirely unknown what may be there, whether it be xenos, nothing, or all the horrible monstrosities of the Dark Age of Technology. The Explorators of Aerus would highly appreciate the dedication of some Librarians to aid in an area where the Astronomicon's light is so weak. The Explorators are not incapable fighters in the slightest, but a company of space marines could be of considerable value to the fight. [] (Write-In Forces Assigned, If Any)
[] Deathwatch Desperation - Rise of the Alien: The Deathwatch is being strained to the breaking point, by their own secretive messages to all Chapters in the galaxy who can hear them. Watch Fortresses and Stations are under assault, alien civilizations are rising in ever higher number, deadly threats are growing in severity and breadth. Normally only the best of the best marines would be given over to the Deathwatch, but out of sheer desperation the Ordos Xenos is loosening their standards in an uncharacteristic display of acceptance. That is, apparently, how bad the problem has gotten across every single Segmentum. Ordo Xenos Inquisitors are calling in favors, the Deathwatch is calling upon nearly every Chapter possible to send someone, anyone, as many space marines as possible. With such threats as the Black Crusade, the War for Armageddon, the Hive Fleets, all of the Deathwatch cannot hope to fight back against the apparent thousands of full-scale alien invasions of the Imperium going on across the galaxy without help. How could you possibly stand by and do nothing, in the face of this? (Write-In Additional Forces Sent To The Deathwatch)
[] Deathwatch Campaign Offers: The Deathwatch is being entirely overwhelmed. They are desperate for a great many more soldiers than many chapters are willing to give. They are, even, willing to give out targets to whole chapters that a single or grouping of kill-teams cannot normally defeat on their own. These are no mere minor invasions, but great gulfs of foes of extreme issue. It is highly advised that the Chapter focuses their efforts on only one of these potential targets at a time, else risk being similarly overwhelmed as the Deathwatch has been.
-[] The Saharduin Swells: The Saharduin homeworlds and their recently reconquered holdings have become engulfed in utter anarchy. WAAAGH!! Killmash is proving itself to be especially resilient, fighting not just the Saharduin, not just the Dark Eldar who are doing hit and run raids on both, but a new tendril of Hive Fleet Leviathan which has recently arrived, speculated to have been aiming for this cluster of space for centuries. The Imperium has abandoned the subsector entirely as a result, not having enough strength in this moment to contest the four-way war in any respect. Worse, the last reports of the sensor probes and satellites left behind before they ceased transmitting all togther were confusing reports of silently moving but remarkably swift ships of unscannable metals, attacking all four previous factions with remarkably power and deadliness. All battle damage sustained in returned seemed to literally melt or fade away mid-battle. Anyone who attempts to involve themselves in this will be doing so utterly alone. Even the Deathwatch dare not risk any forces into the swirling madness. Recent losses in the Helba Sector and Larsa Sector have significantly increased previous estimates on required times to build and train crews for Imperial Navy ship replacements, but even then, issues elsewhere in the galaxy may lead to the Saharduin matter being tabled for the foreseeable future. Only the incredibly powerful or the incredibly foolish would try to involve themselves at this time.
-[] Ending The Kra: The Kra Empire's home space has been discovered by the furious Adeptus Mechanicus. With Forge World Amasca reclaimed, as well as the rest of Subsector Tulmis, the Kra have been forced entirely out of Imperial space. Now the Larsa Sector has turned itself to vengeance against the invading aliens, but it is the Mechanicus who are leading the charge, their powerful combined fleet and titans of the Legio Vindicatia and Legio Mortidan having proven the superior to all Kra technology. Apparently the aliens attempted to surrender once they truly comprehended the strength of that which they sought to claim, but they will find no merciful hearts in the cold iron minds of the Mechanicus. Any who join in this effort will be, rather understandably, subordinated to the Mechanicus until the fighting is done. (This Is A Passive-Active Action, Meaning Barring Unforseen Events, The Chapter is merely contributing forces to the ongoing extermination of the Kra which is being overall commanded by another force, and will not take up turn posts in and of itself. Basically, 5 years of aiding the Mechanicus directly in battle against the Kra)
-[] Hive Fleet Kraken Splinter Clean-Up: The Helba Sector has been saved, but only in the most technical sense. The combined forces of the Sororitas of the Lost Rosetta, the Blood Ravens, the Ebon Claws, the Rogue Trader Tarquindil Dynasty, and a rallied Imperial Navy and Imperial Guard managed to break the bulk of the tyranid forces and their void-going bioforms, but that will not be enough. Though there are rumors of Eldar involvement in the matter, enough to involve the Ordo Xenos, the job is technically not done. Cleansing the tyranids down to the last spore and disparate synapse creatures will take many, many years. Any aid given over to this will be quite valuable indeed. The Ebon Claws and the Order of the Lost Rosetta seem especially dedicated to this, each having their own grudges against the vile alien creatures. (This Is A Passive-Active Action, Meaning Barring Unforseen Events, The Chapter is merely contributing forces to the ongoing hunting down of the remaining tyranids, and will not take up turn posts in and of itself. Basically, 5 years of hunting tyranids down, aiding the Sector, the Ebon Claws, and the Lost Rosetta)
[] Terminator Exchange: Theodosia is willing to produce some Terminator Armor for you, having gotten those specialized forges and designs online. But she will, one, require a full squad of marines with at least one psyker amongst them to safeguard the area - not that she doesn't trust the defenses and holy blessings of the Omnissiah, she just wants to ensure protection for your own equipment. And the hexagramic wards of the Blood Ravens should be especially valuable. Second, for each set of five terminator suits you desire built, she will require aid in other things, allowing her to free up production systems for what you desire. [1 Squad+Librarian Required To Help Oversee Production Whenever Selected. 1 Squad Required For Minor Favor Works In Exchange Per 5 Suits]
[] Calling For Allies: It seems that the daemon Ulkair is once more readying for an attempt to break free and wreak havoc. This time, he is calling through the Warp to those enslaved by Nurgle, desiring them to aid him in the destruction he so desires to enact. Yet the Blood Ravens, battered as they are, are not without their own allies and connections they may elect to choose. While it is unlikely that all would simply lay aside their duties and desires immediately, perhaps with forewarning, they may be able to aid when the inevitable does occur? [] Write-In Who To Contact. EX: Scarlet Lions Chapter, Order of the Lost Rosetta, Ebon Claws Chapter, Other Individuals) Success is NOT Guaranteed. The galaxy is anarchic, and they may well be unable to turn away from their own conflicts. This merely informs them that in about 5 years time or so (1 Turn) their aid would be greatly appreciated.
[] Something Else (Write-In)

Training For Gabriel
As Apollo's Skill Is No Better, Training Referred To Cyrus For Ballistic Skill, Last Skill To Be Improved Through Training

Train Your Chapter
The Blood Ravens have lost so many, both fresh blood and veteran. It may aid in the rebuilding of the Chapter for you to work upon them and try to impart the skill and experience that the Blood Ravens of the past once possessed. [Only Strength Can Still Be Trained]

[] Select Main Characteristic (1d100+Trainer)
- [] Specify Teacher

Things To Consider – Chapter Master Gabriel Angelos
- Remember that Chapter Master Angelos, Chief Librarian Probalis, and Apollo are mighty champions and can be deployed on operations. They need not remain in their ships doing nothing. To have them participate in an operation, it must be specified that they do so.
- If Ulkair is beginning to rise in power again, much is to be done to prepare for this, whether in numbers, arms, or allies.
- The Deathwatch seem desperate indeed, willing to take scouts, veterans, or even tomb-brothers, should they be sent to them.

Nero Gracchus – Chief Apothecary (Choose 2):
[] Implant Test-Slaves with Gene-Seed to harvest At Start Of Next Turn. Write-In the amount of Gene-Seed you wish to use. [Possess 247 Gene-Seed+130 Gene-Seed From Unassigned Battle Brothers]
[] Implant Neophytes [2nd Stage] (??? Total)/ Psyker Neophyte [2nd Stage] (??? Total) with Gene-Seed (I.E. Implant However Many Survive Recruitment This Turn, If Any At All)
[] Write-In

Things To Consider – Nero Gracchus
- The Apothecarium is growing well, the trainees and graduates are a good boon to my efforts. I may even be able to focus all of my efforts on studying our gene-seed soon.
- The Arcanum may have the largest of our Apothecarium, but it is the Potentia that possesses the most advanced, as befitting its name. This should aid in the works of the Apothecarium for its purposes in the future.

Justinius Probalis - Chief Librarian (Choose 1):
[] Request to recruit and train potential psyker aspirants from the Adeptus Astra Telepathica. High likelihood of successful training and implantation for recruits made in this manner.
[] The Raven's Talons: Justinius believes that it should be possible to craft weapons that would be highly effective against daemons and the malefic powers of the Warp itself, as Godsplitter is. With five usable shards taken from Wailing Doom of the Unknown Craftworld's Avatar of Khaine from Typhon Primaris, he believes he could make similar weapons. Whether another daemonhammer, a blade, axe, maul, or spear, he thinks it possible. [100 BP Per Raven Talon, Powerful Anti-Daemon Power Weapons, x4 Shards Remaining For Usage In A Weapon. Success is not guaranteed for creation.]
[] The Raven Aegis: The powers of the Warp and the daemons of Chaos are things that you know for a fact the Blood Ravens will face in the future. Creating talismans which would protect against such things would be incredibly valuable indeed. Justinius' successful efforts at using the materials of the fallen Avatars of Khaine from Craftworld Ulthwé has made him believe it possible to create such things. [50 BP Per Raven Aegis, Powerful Anti-Daemon/Warp Protection Talisman. x6 Shards Remaining For Usage In A Talisman. Success is not guaranteed for creation.]
[] Something Else Entirely - (Write-In)

Things To Consider - Justinius Probalis
- The latest combat against the daemons of the Judgement of Carrion has made me think on the daemonhammer that the Chapter Master wields. We could, perhaps, use more of such weapons. It was created using a shard of the weapon of an Avatar. Perhaps we could make some ourselves, if we studied it enough?

Martellus Ravias – Master of the Forge (Choose 1):
[] Build Order (675 BP Available)
[] Bionic Replacements For Those Wounded In The Hunt For Vandis (Costs 125 BP For 20 5th Company Marines To Be Returned To Full Combat Capability)
[] Full Repair For Gabriel Angelos' Extensive Bionics (Costs 35 BP)
[] Extensive Bionics For Returning Apollo Diomedes To Duty (Costs 35 BP)
[] Improve the Forges Of
-[] The Omnia Arcanum [0/1000] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
-[] The Litany Of Fury [0/750] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
-[] The Howling Hatred [0/750] to receive an additional +25 BP/Turn
-[] The Rage of Erudition [0/750] to receive an additional +25 BP/Turn
[] Construct Forge Facilities On Company Ships (Current/Former)
- [] The Ravenous Spirit [0/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
- [] The Spiraling Fury [13/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
- [] The Burning Seeker [0/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
- [] The The Great Father's Fist [0/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
- [] The Legacy of Polonius [0/500] to receive an additional +50 BP/Turn
[] Study The Hrud Fusils For ???? (Warning: May end up losing some Fusils as a result of the study) [200/????]

Things To Consider – Master of the Forge Ravias
- We should probably build more Tarantula turrets.
- The Forges could use improvement, I think. It is not blasphemy against the Omnissiah to improve what facilities we have, increase their capacity and sophistication.
- We have proven, now, our techmarine cadre to have the ability to properly construct the forges on our ships. We should continue this practice, for the Chapter is dangerously under-equipped compared to the strength it once possessed before the Purge.
- We should work to ensure that our ships possess Thunderhawks or some form of strike craft at the least in abundance for defensive and offensive purposes in void and planetary-combat. Especially if we plan on our ships engaging in such in the near future!
- Have we considered building more Tarantula turrets? Deploying them to aid our forces in upcoming fighting would be most valuable indeed, all things considered.
- Thank goodness the Potentia has returned to service. Amongst the rest of the ships within the Chapter Fleet, it possesses the most advanced forge facilities, as befitting its name. This will surely aid me in construction of more advanced technologies in the future, as well as their study!
- Our Chapter will remain low in number for quite some time yet. I believe that one of the best ways to alleviate such issues is the noble Tarantula turret.
- Hrud Fusils are prizes indeed. It is said they are an extremely advanced example of symbiosis between melta and plasma weaponry. I could attempt to study them, and discover if they may inspire further secrets of the Omnissiah in their nature - though surely not as if I would be committing to xeno tech-heresy. Obviously.
- Cyrus is extremely good at guiding his students. We require many more suits of scout armor than anticipated, otherwise they'll be near defenseless on the battlefield, Chapter Master.

Cyrus Octavius – Master of Recruits (Choose 1):
[] Enact Blood Trials Upon All Four Of Your Viable Recruiting Worlds (Calderis/Trontiux III/Meridian/Junius) And Train Those Who Survive
[] Enact Blood Trials Upon The Following Of Your Recruiting Worlds (Write-In) [Note: If desired, as to leave one or more planets to grow their population, recover, out of lack of Gene-Seed for the potential crop, etc.]
[] Something Else (Write-In)

Things To Consider – Master of Recruits
- The only thing that can truly help the 10th Company is time, dedicated time, to train your initiates, neophytes, and scouts.
- So many scouts require armor and equipment. Otherwise, they are but moving targets.
- With the arrival of many experienced 1st Company Sergeants, more Blood Trials can be enacted without Cyrus' direct observation.
- The Deathwatch would not ask so desperately if it were not needed. We could, conceivably, send scout marines to them. A number of these scouts would die, but they would die doing the Emperor's work. Those that survive would return with a vast amount of experience as well.

Turn 28: A Breath Choked By Ash (Part Two)

Spoiler: Plan Favor Grinding

-[] Assign Veterans To 1st Company If Desired
--[] Return 10 1st company Sergeants assigned to 2nd Company to 1st Co., Promote 10 2nd Company Vets in their place, Send all remaining 2nd Co. vets to 1st Co.
--[] Send all non-Sergeant 4th and 5th Co. Vets to 1st Co.
-[] Train 1st Company Battle Brothers In Terminator Armor Usage
--[] Train all 1st Co. members not currently in possession of Terminator Honors (including new additions)
-[] Assign Tomb-Brother Nathan of the 5th to 1st and Tomb-Brother Mestor of the 5th to the 4th.
-[] Look for potential members of the Honor Guard from the Chapter Veterans.
-[] Reassign Kaius Jacobus from the 5th to the 10th as scout sergeant, return 1 of the scout sergeants to the 1st, nominate Veteran Sergeant Trogus as the new Champion of the 5th.
-[] Assign Chaplain Bellero as the new Chaplain of the 5th
-[] Give unused Raven's Aegis to the Codicier Aeneas
-[] Assign Unassigned Battle Brothers [135] To Companies
--[] Assign 70 to 5th Co.,
--[] Assign 45 to 2nd Co.
--[] Assign 20 to 4th Co.
-[] Significant Mechanicus Offer – The Shadowed Grave:
--[] Send 4th Co. and Fleet + Detachments from Librarium/Reclusiam/Apothecarium/Armory
---[] Deploy Gabriel, Apollo, Justinius and Martellus
-[] Ending The Kra
--[] 2nd Co. and Fleet + Detachments from Librarium/Reclusiam/Apothecarium/Armory
---[] Deploy Hannibal and Nero
-[] Hive Fleet Kraken Splinter Clean-Up
--[] 5th Co. and Fleet, 1st Co. Squad + Detachments from Librarium/Reclusiam/Apothecarium/Armory
-[] Terminator Exchange
--[] 2 Squads of 1st Co.
-[] Calling For Allies
--[] Approach Governor Derosa for aid in contacting/ couching requests to the more hostile parties listed below.
--[] Approach Sector Command
--[] Approach Scarlet Lions
--[] Approach Order of the Lost Rosetta
--[] Approach Inquisitor Andrastia
--[] Approach Forge World Aerus
--[] Approach Forge World Zerann
--[] Approach Rogue Trader Tarquindil
--[] Approach Knightly Houses of Trontiux II
-[] Favor usage
--[] Use 1 Major Mechanicus Favors to request aid from them
--[] Use 1 Minor Favor to gain 8 Thunderhawks (4 gunship, 4 transport) from Governor Derosa
-[] Something Else (Write-In)
--[] Aid Meridian, Blood the 10th Co.: Captain Cyrus is correct in his declaration that ill-equipped Scouts are naught more than moving targets. However even the newest implanted Scout possesses resilience, training, reaction times and zeal far in excess of the usual cult dross. The like of which is steadily infesting the underbelly of Meridian. While we can't immediately equip them to the standards normally demanded of the 10th Co. we can still provide them with weapons and armor aplenty that Imperial Guardsmen would be envious of. Send in the 10th Co. to quell the cult uprisings on Meridian. Buy Governor Derosa the time and breathing room she needs to see to the Hive Worlds defenses while continuing the training of these newest of Blood Ravens in a relatively safe manner. (@torroar Is this an appropriate write-in?)
---[] 10th Co.
-[] Select Main Characteristic (1d100+Trainer)
--[] Master of Sanctity Hannibal
--[] Train Gabriel's BS with Cyrus
-[] Write-In: Prepare for Plagues: Ulkair is awakening. A Great Unclean One. His stirrings, lackeys and, Emperor Forbid, awakening, will lead to plagues sweeping throughout the populace of the local Sub-sector. Study the records of years past on the afflictions common to this particular sore from the Warp and prepare medical provisions and triage techniques for it. Spread the findings them to all medical and military organizations likely to be involved in the coming cleansing so as to reduce the impact of this creatures insidious presence. x2
-[] The Raven's Talons [100 BP 1x Shard]
--[] Daemonhammer
-[] Build Order: (675 BP Available)
--[] 47 Suits of Scout Combat Armor (376 BP)
-[] Bionic Replacements For Those Wounded In The Hunt For Vandis (Costs 125 BP For 20 5th Company Marines To Be Returned To Full Combat Capability)
-[] Full Repair For Gabriel Angelos' Extensive Bionics (Costs 35 BP)
-[] Extensive Bionics For Returning Apollo Diomedes To Duty (Costs 35 BP)
-[] One Raven's Talon (NOTED ABOVE) (100 BP)
-[] Enact Blood Trails Upon The Following Of Your Recruiting Worlds
--[] Meridian

GM Note: Non-crossed out portions of the voted plan will be taken care of later in the turn.

A Breath Choked By Ash
+075.M42+ To +080.M42+
Be Faithful! Be Strong! Be Vigilant! - The Emperor of Mankind

The newly strengthened 4th Company met with the ships of Zerann and Aerus just outside of the capital's solar system. Though the Legacy of Polonius was too grievously damaged to serve until fully repaired, the 4th Company yet possessed a battle barge and other strike cruiser along with their escort ships. At the same time, with a potential Titan on the line, and their most hated foes in the Dark Mechanicus, the Basilikon Astra had come out in force. Not too much, of course, as Forge World Aerus was also splitting their strength towards pursuing a potential secret in the Halo Stars, but they still contributed some forces. It was Forge World Zerann which had contributed the bulk of the troops and ships present, in fact involving themselves to the point of summoning forth two of their Ark Mechanicus' vessels with an assortment of cruisers and escort ships.

"Chapter Master Angelos, it seems the winds of the Motive Force has brought us together once more to face our enemies," Archmagos Derillion's grinding androgynous voice is as flat as the last time they had spoken.

"Archmagos Veneratus," Gabriel inclined his head as the holo-image of Derillion wavered and shuddered before him. "The Blood Ravens are glad to join with the forces of Zerann and Aerus once more."

The bridge of the Scientia Est Potentia was, despite the influx of battle brothers to the 4th Company, largely unchanged from its usual operations. Gabriel stood before the actuality sphere, examining the combined fleet as they gathered together in the void. Behind him, standing next to the command throne where Captain Hadrian Priscus sat, was the Chief Librarian, eyes closed and staff clasped in his hands. Psychic light quietly burned behind his eyelids as he inaudibly murmured. The Archmagos Veneratus had not changed overly much, at most he seemed to have added a few more pounds of metal onto his frame.

"And we appreciate your coming. You have reviewed the data files on our destination, yes?"

Gabriel pressed a few runes on the actuality sphere, replacing the immediate area around the battle barge with old auspex scans taken of a nebula known by a simple numerical designation. Though he did raise an eyebrow as he noted a new entry into the logs, aided both by the most far ranging Mechanicus probes as well as the information collected from the Dark Eldar. Where once it had been an easily missed piece of boring stellar phenomena, that was no longer the case.

"It has been renamed into the Cerulean Vault?" Gabriel asked, squinting slightly.

What might have been a sigh from Derillion, though it came out more as a somehow flatulent burst of shrieking metal.

"Unfortunately poetic, yes," the Archmagos Veneratus shook their head. "The nebula is characterized by largely blue-tinged stellar gasses, and one of the younger tech-priests who were helping collate the data deigned to name it as such. Despite our best efforts, it has stuck."

"I see," Gabriel's lips quirked. "And what do we know, truly, about...the Cerulean Vault?"

The five eyes of the Archmagos whirred and clicked.

"The information we possess is largely extracted from the foul xenos cogitators, which identifies it as an ancient graveyard from some battles in the past, though the contempt of the alien towards all else colors much."

"I see."

"More pertinent than anything else, however, is the presence of the Dark Mechanicus. The heretics cannot be allowed to scavenge from this place, even if it means that we gain nothing of it at all."

"Victory is its own reward," Gabriel recited calmly. "What issues may the nebula cause for our own ships, then?"

"Sensors are highly reduced in range, and cannot easily penetrate beyond a negligible distance beyond the outer shell of the nebula, which gives credence as to its usage in the past as a point of gathering to surprise and ambush other foes. We must be exceedingly cautious once entering the nebula."

"Of course, Archmagos. The Blood Ravens stand ready to depart when you are ready."

Within the hour, the combined fleet gathered close, and as one dipped into the warp. Thankfully, the nebula's presence was further in the territory nominally claimed by the Imperium, rather than the past few major operations the Chapter had undertaken. The light of the Astronomicon burned bright and strong, at least enough to reach the nebula proper without much issue aside from some minor drift here and there. Waiting before them, silently, was the Cerulean Vault. It was a massive thing, easily capable of swallowing multiple battlefleets without issue. It would, in fact, be likely near impossible to chart its innards accurately with anything approaching swiftness.

"Hmm," Gabriel murmured as he glanced over some recorded data from the last few auspex probes that the Mechanicus had previously launched.

They broadcast reasonably well as they plunged into the gaseous mass, but the data that they returned after doing so was massively dwarfed in range and clarity. Even then, on occasion, some of the probes ceased broadcasting far before they should have. Quickly, and without warning. There was something about the nebula that disquieted the serfs, he could see it as he stood on the bridge. They avoided looking at it through the viewports whenever possible. He glanced back at Justinius, who had by now stood up from the command throne and now gazed at the nebula with his eyes burning with power.

"What do you see, my friend?" Gabriel half-turned.

"There is sorrow in this place," Justinius said softly, gripping his staff tightly in one hand, the other reaching up to grasp at nothing. "And anger."

Gabriel frowned.

"Can you see anything more?"

"No," Justinius gave a minute shake of his head. "Not without spending more time, time we do not have, studying it."

"Do you suspect it is...tainted?"

Justinius blinked, his eyes returning to their normal hue as he looked at the Chapter Master.

"It was the haunt of the Dark Eldar for some time, and now the Dark Mechanicus seek it," he sighed. "That may well be enough."

Before either could say more, the vox bank began to blink as an incoming communication request came through. Justinius lifted his chin and Gabriel turned away, pressing the acceptance rune on the holo-table of the actuality sphere.

"Chapter Master, we are prepared to enter the nebula. Are the Blood Ravens?"

"We are," Gabriel leaned forward with his hands against the holo-table. "Let us begin."

With the two Ark Mechanicus of Zerann leading the way, the combined fleet plunged into the opaque blue which contrasted so sharply with the black of the void.

Entering The Cerulean Vault: 62
????: 59

"It is said that some nebulae possess certain properties which strip the void shields from some ships. Thankfully this is not one of them," Captain Hadrian declared from the command throne. "Still, I do not care for the way it blinds and deafens us."

Gabriel agreed, but did not bother responding to the ongoing quiet litany of irritation that the brother-captain had been muttering for days. Instead, he studied the logs and information that the Mechanicus had been able to glean. Deep within the Cerulean Vault, there lay a rogue planet, one that had come to a vague sort of rest in its depths. Its gravitational field was not so strong as to cause the ship graveyard they were seeking to collapse onto its pitted surface, yet remained enough strength keep them from floating elsewhere. Thankfully, the Mechanicus had largely stripped the logs of the massive quantity of data on various tortures and atrocities that the Dark Eldar had committed while within the nebula.

"Archmagos, how close are we to reaching the graveyard proper?" Gabriel asked across the vox.

Though it hissed and crackled, whatever properties of the nebula fouled auspex scans and sensors so well seemed to be less oppressive upon vox communications. Already that had proven valuable to prevent multiple near-crashes as the ships travelled along.

"According to the coordinates we retrieved, soon enough," the Archmagos' voice came through quickly, though being out of breath was impossible for them. "We shall see for ourselves what bounty might be found, or might need to be burned to prevent the touch of heresy staining it."

Reaching The Graveyard: 49
????: 42
The Nightmares Of The Dead: 66

In the end, the first blow was dealt not at the hand of the Blood Ravens, nor the Mechanicus, not even their twisted heretical counterparts. A strange, mournful screech came across the vox. It was a terribly garbled thing, what might have been binary, what almost sounded like High and Low Gothic mixing together. It came across every channel, and then the dark blue of the nebula lit up all around them like lightning through storm clouds. Gabriel watched, eyes wide, as now dozens of hulks were revealed all around their fleet, some dangerously close, further detail impossible to make beyond vague shape. The light, such as it was, came from dark spheres almost impossible to see redlining thrusters to fling themselves forward.

"Registering target lock!" Hadrian shouted, arms clenching hard on the armrests of the command throne. "Multiple incoming projectiles, I can't tell the type!"

"All ships," the Archmagos called out on the Imperial channel, "Evasive maneuvers, but do not stray too far beyond vox range with the rest of the fleet!"

The Scientia Est Potentia shuddered as impacts fell across its flank despite Hadrian's best efforts.

"These are directed mines," Hadrian announced, both outraged and puzzled at the same time, "How are they still functioning after all this time!?"

"Locate the source! Did we just fly into a minefield!?" Gabriel shouted, glaring at the somewhat unhelpful actuality sphere.

"No," Justinius boomed, thumping his staff against the floor of the strategium. "But we have entered the territory of two minds driven mad."

"I - yes, I can see them," Hadrian said as the battle barge descended.

Up ahead, near invisible amongst the choking blue, further flashes of light could be seen. On the actuality sphere, however, a series of notifications and targeting locks flared to life before Gabriel's eyes.

"These...these are the mines of a Tartarus-class Minelayer," came the garbled voice of the Archmagos. "But-,"

"There are two of them!" Hadrian shouted over him, and Gabriel saw it was true.

Yet more than that, Gabriel saw as a handful more mines detached from now empty cavernous holds on the ships on the scans and flung themselves towards the Imperial ships. But a handful of kilometers away, another of the so-called Tartarus-class Minelayers was releasing its own mines. Those mines, however, flew towards ships that were not bearing the aquila of the Imperium nor the true cog of the Mechanicus of Mars. These, illuminated ever so briefly amongst the blue nebula, were ships of blackened bronze and rusted blood red, the cog symbols engraved upon their hulls twisted things. The skull-half of the cog had been replaced with a shrieking daemon's face, the eight pointed star replacing the outer teeth of the cog's gears.

"Dark Mechanicus presence confirmed!" He heard one serf cry out, a similar call coming from one of the tech-priests from one of the Zerann Ark Mechanicus.

Despite visuals and auspex both being considerably crippled by the nebula, it was impossible to miss the auspex probes being sent out by the Dark Mechanicus ships as well en masse. Sensor pings and vox channel bounces confirmed it as well as anything else. Both outside forces had arrived at the same time, and yet the ghosts of the Cerulean Vault seemed unable to yet lay silent.

"Hadrian!" Gabriel called out to the Captain of the 4th Company.

"I know!"

Imperial Fleet: 97
Dark Mechanicus Fleet: 88
Nightmares of the Dead: 62
This time, when the battle barge shuddered, it was because it was firing every single weapon it had that could be angled properly. Not at the Dark Mechanicus ships, not yet, but at the minelayer. Even the bombardment cannon thundered out. There was another loud squealing cacophony from the vox as the Tartarus-class, revenant as it might have been, was torn apart by the guns of the Imperium and Mechanicus working in tandem. Opposite them, through the murky blue of the nebula and the silent hulks of a great many other ships, the Dark Mechanicus expressed their respect for the long-dead and still moving machine spirits of the past in their customary manner - with a heavy barrage of lance arrays and plasma batteries. The shriek that emerged this time was somehow less guttural, a barely functioning set of plasma generators igniting for the last time and briefly lighting up the nebula and revealing even more silently floating hulks.

"Minelayer confirmed destroyed, Dark Mechanicus ships are advancing towards us!"

"There is a series of rapid-fire communications being exchanged by the Mechanicus ships and that of the enemy, but it is purely in binary!"

The command vox channel for the Chapter crackled to life.

"They are exchanging hateful greetings and oaths of destruction in the name of the True Omnissiah," the Master of the Forge revealed. "Just as we would, in the name of the Emperor, when faced with heretics."

"They appear to not think that we Blood Ravens are deserving of their hatred, or perhaps think themselves immune to our own!" Hadrian snarled.

"Then disabuse them, Captain!" Gabriel called back to him.

"Gladly. MAY NONE FIND US WANTING!" Hadrian howls at the top of his lungs as the first bursts lance and macro cannon begin to skitter across the void shields of various ships.

Cerulean Vault Located, Dark Mechanicus Fleet Unable To Begin Scavenging Operations Due To Timely Arrival. Imperial Fleet Unable To Set Up Before Enemy Arrival. Immediate Mutual Combat Begins. Graveyard Hulks Make Rapid Maneuvering Exceedingly Dangerous/Difficult. Solid-Ammo Weaponry Such As Macrocannons Will Be Stymied By Physical Barriers.

Choose Blood Raven Fleet Tactics For Battle (Choose 1):
2 Hour Moratorium

[] Close Boarding - Charge for the Dark Mechanicus ships and attempt to board and destroy them as is the most suggested action by the Codex, exchanging close range fire all the while.
[] Ranged Firing - Remain at medium to long range, attempting to use the weapons of the Blood Raven fleet to cause as much damage as possible while preserving the ships.
[] Close Guarding - Remain as close as possible to the Mechanicus ships to protect them from enemy boarding assaults and close range strikes, allowing the Mechanicus fleet to unleash their full arsenal with less restraint.

Imperial Forces Present
4th Company Fleet (Battle Barge - Scientia Est Potentia / Strike Cruiser - Burning Seeker / 6 Escorts (x2 Gladius Frigates, x2 Hunter Destroyers, x2 Nova Frigates))

Zerann Battlefleet (2 Ark Mechanicus / 7 Mechanicus Lunar-class Cruisers / 10 Escorts (x10 Firestorm Frigates)

Aerus Battlefleet (3 Mechanicus Lunar-class Cruisers / 3 Mechanicus Dictator-class Cruisers / 5 Escorts (x5 Cobra Destroyers)

Dark Mechanicus Forces Present
Total Number Unknown, Dark Mechanicus Modifications And Nebula Scan Baffling Make Sure Classifications Difficult

1 Cardinal-Class Heavy Cruiser
2 Unknown-Class Heavy Cruisers
5 Unclassified Cruisers
8 Unclassified Escorts

Maddened Machine Spirits
??????

Turn 28: A Breath Choked By Ash (Part Three)

Spoiler: Plan Favor Grinding

-[] Assign Veterans To 1st Company If Desired
--[] Return 10 1st company Sergeants assigned to 2nd Company to 1st Co., Promote 10 2nd Company Vets in their place, Send all remaining 2nd Co. vets to 1st Co.
--[] Send all non-Sergeant 4th and 5th Co. Vets to 1st Co.
-[] Train 1st Company Battle Brothers In Terminator Armor Usage
--[] Train all 1st Co. members not currently in possession of Terminator Honors (including new additions)
-[] Assign Tomb-Brother Nathan of the 5th to 1st and Tomb-Brother Mestor of the 5th to the 4th.
-[] Look for potential members of the Honor Guard from the Chapter Veterans.
-[] Reassign Kaius Jacobus from the 5th to the 10th as scout sergeant, return 1 of the scout sergeants to the 1st, nominate Veteran Sergeant Trogus as the new Champion of the 5th.
-[] Assign Chaplain Bellero as the new Chaplain of the 5th
-[] Give unused Raven's Aegis to the Codicier Aeneas
-[] Assign Unassigned Battle Brothers [135] To Companies
--[] Assign 70 to 5th Co.,
--[] Assign 45 to 2nd Co.
--[] Assign 20 to 4th Co.
-[] Significant Mechanicus Offer – The Shadowed Grave:
--[] Send 4th Co. and Fleet + Detachments from Librarium/Reclusiam/Apothecarium/Armory
---[] Deploy Gabriel, Apollo, Justinius and Martellus
-[] Ending The Kra
--[] 2nd Co. and Fleet + Detachments from Librarium/Reclusiam/Apothecarium/Armory
---[] Deploy Hannibal and Nero
-[] Hive Fleet Kraken Splinter Clean-Up
--[] 5th Co. and Fleet, 1st Co. Squad + Detachments from Librarium/Reclusiam/Apothecarium/Armory
-[] Terminator Exchange
--[] 2 Squads of 1st Co.
-[] Calling For Allies
--[] Approach Governor Derosa for aid in contacting/ couching requests to the more hostile parties listed below.
--[] Approach Sector Command
--[] Approach Scarlet Lions
--[] Approach Order of the Lost Rosetta
--[] Approach Inquisitor Andrastia
--[] Approach Forge World Aerus
--[] Approach Forge World Zerann
--[] Approach Rogue Trader Tarquindil
--[] Approach Knightly Houses of Trontiux II
-[] Favor usage
--[] Use 1 Major Mechanicus Favors to request aid from them
--[] Use 1 Minor Favor to gain 8 Thunderhawks (4 gunship, 4 transport) from Governor Derosa
-[] Something Else (Write-In)
--[] Aid Meridian, Blood the 10th Co.: Captain Cyrus is correct in his declaration that ill-equipped Scouts are naught more than moving targets. However even the newest implanted Scout possesses resilience, training, reaction times and zeal far in excess of the usual cult dross. The like of which is steadily infesting the underbelly of Meridian. While we can't immediately equip them to the standards normally demanded of the 10th Co. we can still provide them with weapons and armor aplenty that Imperial Guardsmen would be envious of. Send in the 10th Co. to quell the cult uprisings on Meridian. Buy Governor Derosa the time and breathing room she needs to see to the Hive Worlds defenses while continuing the training of these newest of Blood Ravens in a relatively safe manner. (@torroar Is this an appropriate write-in?)
---[] 10th Co.
-[] Select Main Characteristic (1d100+Trainer)
--[] Master of Sanctity Hannibal
--[] Train Gabriel's BS with Cyrus
-[] Write-In: Prepare for Plagues: Ulkair is awakening. A Great Unclean One. His stirrings, lackeys and, Emperor Forbid, awakening, will lead to plagues sweeping throughout the populace of the local Sub-sector. Study the records of years past on the afflictions common to this particular sore from the Warp and prepare medical provisions and triage techniques for it. Spread the findings them to all medical and military organizations likely to be involved in the coming cleansing so as to reduce the impact of this creatures insidious presence. x2
-[] The Raven's Talons [100 BP 1x Shard]
--[] Daemonhammer
-[] Build Order: (675 BP Available)
--[] 47 Suits of Scout Combat Armor (376 BP)
-[] Bionic Replacements For Those Wounded In The Hunt For Vandis (Costs 125 BP For 20 5th Company Marines To Be Returned To Full Combat Capability)
-[] Full Repair For Gabriel Angelos' Extensive Bionics (Costs 35 BP)
-[] Extensive Bionics For Returning Apollo Diomedes To Duty (Costs 35 BP)
-[] One Raven's Talon (NOTED ABOVE) (100 BP)
-[] Enact Blood Trails Upon The Following Of Your Recruiting Worlds
--[] Meridian

A Breath Choked By Ash
+075.M42+ To +080.M42+
Be Faithful! Be Strong! Be Vigilant! - The Emperor of Mankind

In the ancient days of yore, when Terra still had oceans, there had been combats such as this. In the stark blue of the oceans, and in some cases in the utter darkness of the depths. The same had occurred many times before on other planets throughout the galaxy and beyond. Warfare, violence, that intrinsic prerogative and act by both those who were savage and those who considered themselves enlightened, by beasts and men alike. A space where sensors were deafened, where some of the most advanced works of humanity were rendered dangerously close to the same effectiveness of the naked eyeball. Cogitators thrummed, auspex arrays pulsed near constantly, all ships strained to discover the foe so that they could tear their throats out. Though two fleets proclaimed servitude and worship to the Omnissiah, the form of their worship was both starkly different and grotesquely similar depending on the ritual and behavior in question.

Mechanicus: 85
Dark Mechanicus: 36
Blood Ravens: 71
Nightmares of the Dead: 56

Lances of blinding, obliterating light skewered the murky blue of the nebula, sometimes striking against suddenly revealed bubbles of void shields, sometimes impacting against long dead hulks of metal and plastic. Unlike the dumb torpedoes that many in the Imperium's navy had access to, what was launched in waves were more advanced pieces of technology. Primitive machine-spirits tugged ordnance, maneuvering with mini-thrusters as much as was possible to actually reach the enemy. Daemons screamed and howled as the melded flesh-warheads of the Dark Mechanicus shot through the nebula's innards. But so too did other things howl in the dark blue of the nebula. Macrocannon salvoes, erupting with the very last of what remained in dust-covered magazines, impacted against the shields of the Blood Ravens as they rotated their ships in close defensive formation around those of the Mechanicus. Revenant plasma generators which burned non-existent fuel heated up ancient lance turrets, long-cold barrels superheated once more as shrieking beams punctured the void shields of a Dark Mechanicus cruiser. Redirecting power from weapons, from areas where life-support was nonessential, even partially from the engines, all towards the shields, Hadrian Priscus of the 4th Company commanded the ships of the Blood Ravens to guard their allies. Through their adamant defense, the ships of the Mechanicus were left pristine.

Mechanicus: 72
Dark Mechanicus: 84
Blood Ravens: 91
Nightmares of the Dead: 5

But as almost all fighting there knew, the hatred brought about through zealotry and worship was powerful indeed. Long range was often the preferred methodology of the ship-born servants of the Omnissiah, where their advanced weaponry could blast and shatter and rend their foes long before they could be in danger. But with so many dead hulks strewn about the area, they were obstacles for both sides. Sheer mass of dead, and in some cases undead, metal was proving a deterrent to victory all sides. It needed to come to an end, one way or another. Exact timing was impossible to say, either through immediate observation or through later examination of the auspex logs. It didn't matter, in the end. Screaming in binary and scrap-code, the fleets of the Mechanicus advanced, and thus the Blood Ravens were brought closer as well. Close enough, as it turned out, for the bombardment cannons of the astartes ships to begin firing with something approaching measurable accuracy. The revenants of the nebula were struck silent since they had first begun screaming, now witness once more to true full-scale warfare. Troop transports, boarding torpedoes, assault rams, teleportarium beacons, these and more were launched between the two main fleets, yet before any of the corrupted skitarii and maddened machine slaves of the Dark Mechanicus could bore into the hulls of their hated brethren, they found themselves confronted with the ships of the Blood Ravens, aggressively firing to tear them apart. In one case, the strike cruiser Burning Seeker threw itself in the way of some of such boarding methods. There, scrap-code bellowing skitarii and deathly silent war robots found themselves felled by bolter, missile launcher, and lascannons as soon as they tried to emerge from their boarding transports.

Mechanicus: 3
Dark Mechanicus: 24
Blood Ravens: 95
Nightmares of the Dead: 68

"There, there!" Hadrian shouted across the vox, eyes wide and teeth bared in a feral grin. "All ships, fire bombardment cannons, lance arrays, everything! Their void shields are about to regenerate, fire now!"

As one, the ships of the Blood Ravens fired. The nebula was brightly lit within, casting horrific shapes and inhuman visages as shadows as an Ark Mechanicus long tainted by Chaos was slain. A single point at middeck, a miniscule hull breach nearly sealed, initially formed by a lance salvo by the revenants of the Nebula. A point of vulnerability, a point of utter destruction as the combined strength of the 4th Company shot under Captain Hadrian's order. But the revenants were not so discriminate. Though space was silent, the vox came alive with the screams of horror and fury as one of the ships of Aerus was snapped in half by a charging ancient grand cruiser using the very last of its fuel and energy to ram them. With a terrific scraping and shredding, the Lunar-class cruiser was torn apart. The shrapnel spread amongst the other Aerus ships as well, while practically a cloud of torpedoes launched from below the immediate combat plane destroyed one of their cobra destroyers. More might have suffered such a fate if four fifths of the torpedoes hadn't become duds through decay and time, harmlessly bouncing off of void shields and hulls alike. Void shields broke, hulls were burnt and battered, in some cases blown apart entirely as the fleets struck against one another. Though in some cases, the ghosts suffered the anger of Hadrian, especially after their success at harming the fleet of Forge World Aerus.

Mechanicus: 48
Dark Mechanicus: 22
Blood Ravens: 83
Nightmares of the Dead: 51

Weapons batteries fired without pause, masses of servitors loading cannons all the while. Capacitor banks began to crackle and smoke as they energized lances and plasma projectors again and again. The Cerulean Vault began to be filled with angry red, dying orange, and more. The warp-infused vessels of the Dark Mechanicus released even more unwholesome colors, things unnatural to the naked eye. Fuels mixed with ground souls and the essence of chained daemons ignited in fireballs that burned in impossible symbols, writhing and curling as if alive and luxuriating in the deaths of the vessels they once powered. The tempo was increased ever more the longer the fight went on. But no matter what the Dark Mechanicus ships attempted, they could not breach the line created by the Blood Ravens, allowing the fleets of Zerann and Aerus to fire with impunity, though all had to readjust when a few more ships of the past exhaled their final dying breaths through torpedoes and weapons fire. At one point, there was even a forcible launch of strike craft through a purposefully decompressed hangar bay carrying deadly explosive payloads that required thunderhawks to fend off. The machine spirit of the ship which had done so screamed one last time as its reactors finally died with that final exertion.

Mechanicus: 89
Dark Mechanicus: 7
Blood Ravens: 47
Nightmares of the Dead: 25

In the ferocity of combat, cold logical minds had calculated. As ships fought, some taking wounds, some dying, they had continued to stalk down the path of mathematics. The ships shuddered, machine-spirits wailed and gnashed their teeth, scrap-code filaments extended through the noosphere were burnt by holy firewalls prepared by the tech-priests of Zerann and Aerus, and still the grand cogitators worked alongside those linked to them. Flesh and silicone worked unceasingly. Finally, the end of the long equation came. The Blood Ravens had weathered the storm for them well. The old ghosts were growing ever more silent, invigorated with a fatal finality from the aggression and movement of their fleets. The heretics waited before them. Far below, sacred munitions were prepared, passing through a ten thousand gallon bath of oils and sacrament, binary chanting to the Omnissiah reaching a fever pitch as the notification went out through the noosphere.

Derillion, Archmagos Veneratus of the Machine Cult of the Forge World Zerann, no longer possessed an organic mouth with which to express their thoughts. No disgusting flapping hunk of meat was required for their words to be communicated. Their mechadendrites, however, did curl and twitch with eager malice as the long calculus concluded. The targeting solutions had been found. The time was now, and without the bombastic calls of fleshbags, only the cold efficiency of the machine, was the order given out with less than a picosecond of delay. Across the fleets of Forge World Zerann and Aerus, both old, one reborn a scant few years ago, a series of nova cannons awoke. Thrumming with energy, firing in unison, payloads of absolute devastation were flung into the far distance at incredible speed. Each and every one impacted its target within a margin of a hundred meters of distance, an astonishing level of accuracy for ships with lengths in kilometers at a distance with so many hulks of dead vessels in the way.

In that instant, the end result was just as the math predicted: zero combat-viable ships remaining.

Glory and hallowed be the Omnissiah and the Motive Force.

======================================================================

It took another day before the tech-priests were satisfied, a day of launching endless boarding parties of both skitarii and astartes to scour the ships of the enemy to fully cleanse them. Unlike other times in the past, there would be no salvaging these ships. They had not been corrupted by the touch of Chaos, but rather had been forged in the heart of it, on daemonic and accursed Forge Worlds. From their very foundations, their keels to their guns to the wiring throughout, the ships of the Dark Mechanicus had been soaked in the corrupting influence of the Warp in far too many horrific ways and rituals. Daemons had been fused with certain portions of their machinery, their existences beyond redemption. As such, each of their hulks was destroyed piece by piece, blow by blow, the remainder blown and scattered away from the great bounty of the Cerulean Vault. Over a hundred thousand skitarii were deployed to the rogue planet, scouring it further, finding almost no sign of the Dark Eldar save for a few remaining mass graves and weapons left behind as they evidently evacuated some time in the past. Beacons were set up, grand ones, to ensure that the Mechanicus could return at any time they wished. The ghosts were already growing more and more faint, many rituals of purification and consecration performed by the ships of Zerann and Aerus. Vast trails of promethium and blessed oils, hundreds of thousands of gallons of it, were used to paint vast ritualistic symbols through the nebula, cleansing the hulks to the best effort of the tech-priests. The Blood Ravens, of course, were on hand to impress the importance of fully dying to those few ghostly entities that denied said rituals. Whether by binary prayer or melta bombs and bombardment cannons, the dead would rest one way or another.

Only then did the salvaging effort truly begin, as well as a more in-depth investigation of those same ghosts who had so violently reacted to the arrival of their ships. It took all of a few hours for a sobering truth to be revealed to all present. For scans could be made of the ship which rammed the Aerus cruiser and broke it apart. Of the mine laying ships, and more specifically their origins thanks to their rareness and age. The strike craft that had flown without pilots, of the torpedoes that had been but duds, these were taken in and examined in person by the tech-priests. There were no major signs of corruption discernable on the ships, either by the tech-priests or by the Librarians of the Blood Ravens, and yet there did not need to be.

"This is a grave born of the Horus Heresy," the Archmagos Veneratus declared, their voice as flat and emotionless as ever, the words washing over the assembled Blood Raven leadership like a freezing wind.

Across the strategium of the battle barge, serfs shivered as the words were spoken aloud.

"The confusion and grief of these machine-spirits is now understandable. Their outrage, their pain, forced to battle against those whose berths they had been laid alongside in the forges of Mars and beyond," Derillion continued.

The Blood Ravens bowed their heads in unison, allowing a moment of solemnity to pass as they contemplated the shattering of the Emperor's dream. The ending of the Great Crusade. The death of Primarchs, the corruption of so much of humanity, and the beginning of the Long War which continued to the modern day. Of the promises of that era, lost and burnt in the ashes of traitors and heretics. The holographic projection of Derillion did the same, the twitching of their mechadendrites stilled entirely. They too had suffered greatly in the splitting of the Mechanicus, and now after having combatted those same heretics they could now fully behold the grave for what it was, what it meant.

"Do we know what souls lay in rest here?" Gabriel asked softly.

"Preliminary investigations show that these came from two separate expeditionary fleets, designations unknown, who both sought to use the nebula as an anchorage point to make maneuvers onto enemy territory with impunity," Derillion said, shaking their head slightly. "A secret location, yet in an era when sharing such information was more…common," they say with distaste, "They ended up colliding with one another here."

"I see," Gabriel sighed.

"Our work here is now even more important than imagined, for there may well be secrets of that lost time just waiting to be rediscovered and recovered," Derillion insisted. "Yet more revenant ships may remain."

"The Blood Ravens are committed to this course, Archmagos Veneratus, worry not," Gabriel said calmly. "We shall remain to aid you yet."

Cerulean Tomb Confirmed As Horus Heresy Ship Grave, Aerus Fleet Suffers Notable Losses, Zerann Fleet and Blood Raven Fleet Suffered None. Total Eradication Of Dark Mechanicus Fleet.

=========================================================

Cyrus grunted wordlessly as he looked over the battered and bloody survivors of the Blood Trials.

The ring they had fought in was not like that of those on Calderis, places of history and sacred shedding of blood in testing. It was not the arenas of Typhon, burnt and blasted to cinder and ash and less. It was not the twice-burned and twice-destroyed places of Cyrene, nor the corrupt frozen landscapes of Aurelia. It was a place of heat and magma and harsh edges, a side chamber of a manufacturing plant which made ready use of geothermal power. Molten metal washed like a lake next to them all, providing near suffocating heat. He could not have brought himself to the level of gross acceptance of before, not now, even with the threat barreling down at them. Once had been enough, and it had torn at him. He'd been surprised, something that was rare these days, at the competence of the survivors who had fought against the tyranids. He'd found himself surprised once more with this recent crop of recruits. Here, covered in grime and blood and soot, it was impossible to tell which of them were from the underhive, which of them were from the spires, which had so-called noble blood and those who had that of the sewers. All had been tested, of course, by the apothecarium, genetics and physicality requiring utmost purity despite whatever circumstances of their lives. Unlike before, he had not elected to substitute the true Blood Trials with full combat against a tyranid swarm.

Time would tell, however, whether these newest recruits would survive.

73 Aspirants Recruited On Meridian / 5 Psyker Aspirants

=========================================================================

"IN HIS NAME IN HIS NAME IN HIS NAME!"

The resounding shout through a thousand phlegm and vomit-slick throats was in perfect droning unison as the mob slowly lurched its way upwards out of the Underhive. But no sooner did they reach the threshold than the front ranks began to collapse backwards. A firing line of bolters boomed in their own steady unison, with a cry all their own as well. The Litany of Fury, the Litany of Hate, the Litany of Spite, the Litany of Contempt, these and more were all chanted out by the battle brothers of the 10th Company. Many of the mind-blasted ranks of the hivers were growing more resilient with each passing day, packing on diseased muscle and green fat webbing throughout their bodies, but it was not enough to withstand steady bolter fire. The handful amongst their number that had truly been overtaken by Nerglish Rot, half-daemon by that point, were put down by those further back wielding sniper rifles.

"Sewer gates sealed; the area is isolated. Release and burn."

An entire river of promethium was released into a cult meeting deep within the sewers. A foreman who had preached for months about giving into despair and pain, of finding salvation through it, of finding joy through death, gurgled along with his congregation in surprise and pain before the promethium was set aflame. Ten thousand died in less than a minute, many of them from the force of the promethium striking them before the fires were even set. The sacred chosen of the Cult, those who had become most horrifically mutated and transformed by Nurgle's gifts, were those that needed to be burnt the most.

"Talon-5 here, it's confirmed. Colonel Franc has just revealed his mutation. The symbol of the foe is carved upon his chest, and is currently weeping multi-colored pus."

"Understood. Eradicate."

Spire Donnus, one of the lower-level spires of the Hive, was beholden to a brief display of rather intense pyrotechnics that year. In fact, the same was going on all across the whole hive, across multiple spires. It had been organized by the beneficent Governor, it was said ad nauseam, for a truly memorable Candlemas. To show the people of Meridian that there was much good in their service to the Imperium, to the God-Emperor. The church bells rang out in joy, food rations were doubled, and conscription standards were vastly lowered for the following week for all those who were possessed of sufficient fervor. There would be much opportunity for advancement, indeed, as another founding of regiments had been called. Many amongst the PDF were even being promoted, and that was why they would no longer be serving upon Meridian itself. Save for the fact that said officers were being promoted to death by the hands of the Blood Ravens to remove their corruption both fiscal and religious from the PDF, it was all even true.

Major Cultist Reduction On Meridian, PDF Ranks Cleansed Of Cultist Corruption, Regular Corruption. 73 Aspirants -> 49 Neophytes [2nd Stage] / 5 Psyker Neophytes [2nd Stage] Require Implantation. Implanting = 49 Neophytes 2nd Stage -> 49 Scouts [1st Stage] / 5 Psyker Neophytes 2nd Stage -> 5 Lexicanum. 145 Scouts [2nd Stage] -> 145 Battle Brothers Awaiting Assignment. 359 Scouts [1st Stage] -> 359 Scouts [2nd Stage].

===========================================================================

The home worlds of the Kra Empire burned. Their holy grasslands, where their ancestors had once roamed in millennia past, were now scorched ruins. The Cairn Mountains, where the honored dead were buried, had been shattered by orbital bombardments, months of artillery fire, and the inexorable advance of the Legio Vindicatia and Legio Mortidan. The greatest examples of Kra sciences, their proudest achievements, had been rendered to scrap metal and ashen ruin, along with every single one of their cities. The pinnacle of Kra warfare, newly unleashed for the first time for this first glorious war of conquest against the weak two-legs, xenos-built titans, had failed. They had not even been granted the honor of testing hooves against the supposedly inferior two-leg versions, and had instead been brought low by those bearing the black and red raven. Their fleets were shattered ruins, pushed downwards onto the worlds they had so desperately defended to become kinetic strike weapons against their people. Every single evacuation ship that had launched had been destroyed, whether by anti-aircraft weapons and strike craft while within the atmosphere or by the guns of the Imperial ships waiting above. Kra matrons no longer tried to take their herd-calves to safety out of the cities, for there was no safety to be had in the burning once-grasslands or shattered mountains. Kra champions sang their death songs as heartily as they could, their power armors growing strained and breaking from prolonged continual combat beyond any of the war sagas that had been performed in the past. Every planetary void shield's reactor complex had been destroyed, whether by skitarii rangers, inserted tech-priest Myrmidon teams, or by the unyielding Blood Ravens.

No more did the Kra sing of glory, of victory, of conquest and expanding the Great Herd across the stars. No more did their foundries thrum with flame and ore, no more were the maker caste crafting masterpieces of technology whilst respecting the ancient ways with every step. The skies, beautiful and purple, were now red and black, choked with clouds of smog and ash from the grave pits where tens of millions of Kra dead were steadily shoveled to oblivion by skitarii and blocky machines of the Adeptus Mechanicus. The High Chieftain and the Council of Winds, the fifteen most prominent leaders of the entire Kra race, the entire Kra Empire, were gone. They could not sing out to the people any longer. Most assumed them dead, many could not muster the energy to do even that much, to do more than imagine and focus on trying to live just one more day. Even more no longer did even that much, and by the time that the literal millions of skitarii marching across their worlds reached them, they met their destroyers not with defiance or death songs but with blank stares and silence. Neither approach would avail them, in the end, with the greatest consternation behind the killing being held by the unfortunate tech-priests relegated to clerical work, tallying how many power cells had been exhausted, how many missiles were used, how much fuel was expended both in powering holy war machines and burning the bodies of the living and dead xenos.

Brother-Captain Macharius Sicarius watched it all and then turned away, letting the flames of a now dying race halo his red armor. Before him stood an enormous amount of metal and weaponry, the Fabricator-General of Forge World Amasca a true hulk of technology. If anything, Fabricator-General Phi-F00-1 looked closer to a Kastelan war robot than anything else, though they possessed three more arms and an entire swarm of mechadendrites. They loomed over him, yet there was no malice in it, merely height. Around them were several other highly placed tech-priests of Forge World Amasca, for the insult done to their home world and to the Omnissiah demanded their personal attentions to the Kra. For it was Amasca that had been lost, looted, and they who had been forced into the depths to fight a gurilla war before the rest of the Adeptus Mechanicus could send them aid.

"Blood Raven contributions towards accomplishing vengeance for Forge World Amasca are worthy of recompense and reward," Phi-F00-1 stated, their words an androgynous and metallic tumble of words. "All estimations point towards damage to the Titans Damascus Inviolata and Mortis Irae Metallica becoming untenable without Blood Raven intervention and destruction of foul xenos titans."

"The 2nd Company could not simply stand aside and watch," Macharius responded calmly, "We are glad to have preserved the god-machines, though I regret we did not do so earlier."

"The pride of the princeps in refusing your aid will be seen to," the Fabricator-General said as they ponderously shook their head, "The titans shall be repaired, restored, rather than recovered from death. As to the leader of the strike team, our appreciation must be extended, their sacrifice was great."

The Brother-Captain of the 2nd Company chuckled.

"I will make sure to inform brother Hannibal as soon as he is awoken from his suspended animation and his surgeries are completed by the Master of the Apothecarion."

The Fabricator-General no longer possessed eyelids, but there was a strange silence punctuated by the clicking and whirring of their various visual sensors and cameras.

"I was informed that the killing acts were done by delivering melta explosives into their inner reactors by hand."

Macharius nodded.

"Correct."

"The explosion yields which resulted ensured that the northwestern continent was impassible for all organic beings and organic tissues, a state which continues to be present now from radiation and toxin spreads."

"Correct," Macharius nodded again before blinking. "Ah, yes. Brother Hannibal and his teams carried with them teleporter beacons as well. They were pulled out just as the explosives went off."

"I…then he yet lives?"

"He had forth degree burns across two thirds of his body, but yes," Macharius smiled, though it looked somewhat off to the Fabricator-General, though they were long enough distant from flesh that they were not entirely certain why. "As I said, the Master of the Apothecarion is seeing to him."

"I see," the Fabricator-General lied. "Nevertheless, calculations prove that the Blood Ravens have had a non-negligible effect on the success of the campaign and preservation of holy creations of the Omnissiah. Recompense must be made."

"Forge World Amascus was only just recovered," Macharius deferred, shaking his head and cutting his hand through the air, "We could not ask you to expend yet more of your strength. Better for you to repair what you can yet, now that the Kra's threat is ended."

The Fabricator-General was silent once more.

"This implies that there is something which requires the strength of the Blood Ravens mightily indeed."

The Brother-Captain pursed his lips and then sighed. It burned deep in his chest, despite the fact that they had only just a few weeks ago intervened to save a Warhound and Warlord titan from their princeps' own pride. But he remembered the words of the Chapter Master, all of the Blood Ravens did as they were sent out on their missions. As such, he revealed the impending threat to the Subsector Aurelia and greater Korianis Sector. The Fabricator-General did not interrupt, and in fact barely asked questions before some other matters called them away. It was not until the very last of the Kra was dead and thrown into the burning pits to reduce the bones of their living, their dead, and even those buried before the Imperium arrived above their worlds. There would be utterly nothing left of the Kra save for their entries in the records of the Imperium and the Adeptus Mechanicus.

Only then did the calculus of deed and reward come to fruition. It was a minor thing, for the most part, as the truth was that the Mechanicus of the Larsa Sector had greatly exhausted themselves in their violent effort to exterminate the Kra race for the insult of their incursion. Still, when the operations finally ended and the first mineral surveyors and astropathic choirs were being set up for what would be strip mining colonies had arrived, so too came a promissory note from the Fabricator-General. Because the ships of the 2nd Company had been thoroughly scanned and examined by the Mechanicus, it was part and parcel of flying ships amongst fleets of multiple Forge Worlds. A certain dearth had been noted, and while it could not be fully filled, their deeds were technically worth something going by the math of the tech-priests.

Kra Empire Ended, Kra Race Exterminated, Mechanicus Forces Grateful For Aid. Blood Raven Deeds During Operations Were Considered Reward-Worthy. 2nd Company Fleet Gains 8 Thunderhawk Gunships For Howling Hatred, 4 Thunderhawk Gunships For Ravenous Spirit.

==================================================================

"BURN IN THE GLORY OF THE EMPEROR!"

All twelve of the immolator tanks on the field ground to a halt, their treads coated in alien viscera so thick that it would take hours of servitor work to clear them again and began to spin their turrets about. Holy, blessed fire, so hot that it was outright white and blue, spilled outwards into the onrushing tyranid horde. A trio of lictors leapt atop one of the tanks, piercing through the hull of the tank, but before they could actually hit the sister within they were brought low by a burst of bolter fire. High above, the Ebon Claws flew on their startlingly quiet jetpacks, keeping an eye on the rest of the advance. Around the sides of the burning wedge which had pushed deep into the nest, the Blood Ravens of the 5th Company advanced alongside the rest of the Sisters of Battle deployed to the combat zone. Save for the fact that the power armor of the Sororitas was specifically molded to shout out the Ministorum's adherence to the Decree Passive, by this point the amount of alien gore splattered across them all made it difficult to tell who was who. It was only further emphasized by the fact that both the Blood Ravens and the Order of the Lost Rosetta both cleaved towards a black and red coloration, gallons of tyranid blood and pounds of tyranid splattered bodies. Ambushes were pre-ambushed. Buried hordes were burnt and shot apart before they could gain too much momentum.

A battle brother was overwhelmed and thrown to the ground by a group of hormagaunts, but before the beasts could begin the actual killing, a pair of sisters wielding multi-meltas outright vaporized them while avoiding hitting the Blood Raven. When a group of sisters were cut off as a number of raveners burst up from below, it was a group of Blood Raven assault marines who arced up and then right back down, boots and chainswords first, to save them. When tyranid fliers began to rise up and try to knock the Ebon Claws from the skies, heavy bolters boomed out in unison from both Blood Raven and Lost Rosetta squads. A duo of zoanthropes lashed out with disgusting alien light, flipping an immolator tank upside down and nearly killing its crew, but before they could do more they were skewered and cut apart by Ebon Claw power swords, the space marines taking them out at high speed while redlining their jump packs.

They fought in unison.

It may have taken until the final nest located by the stringent efforts of the Ordos Xenos and their sanctioned psykers, the mysterious emanations which were later discovered to be strange beacons left behind by what had to have been Eldar to reveal hidden, and the work of the Blood Ravens's own Librarians and lore. They had certainly fought alongside each other for the years of deployment. But there had been a rather immense amount of friction, at least between the Blood Ravens and the sisters of the Lost Rosetta. They had fought alongside the Ordos Xenos, the Imperial Guard, and certain deployments of the Mechanicus, but nowhere was there more issue than between the two groups from the Korianis Sector. Thankfully, time and again, the cool temperament and shockingly humble nature of Tarkus Varianus, Brother-Captain of the 5th Company, saw a swift end to argument, to questioning, to threats and accusations. As was his wont, he weathered the fiery words of the sisters just as he would barrages of enemy weapons fire and made a slow grinding advance through logic and calm response.

Here, now, as the last of the major tyranid synapse forms in the whole of the Helba Sector died, their last major nest burnt and vaporized beyond a single cell, the work had paid off, they fought as one. In unison. Callouts and words of warning were heeded by all, and the pace of combat that could only be sustained by ones such as they. When one stumbled, another helped them stand, regardless of the banners that they personally flew, for all served the Emperor. Prioris Pattern Exorcist artillery tanks were located directly next to Blood Raven and Ebon Claw Whirlwinds, accepting targeting coordinates as a group. In the upper skies above, against heavier tyranid flying bio-forms, thunderhawks flew alongside lightning fighters. The chants and prayers of the Sisters of Battle were joined by the bellowed litanies of the chaplains.

They fought as one.

The last hive tyrant rose to defend its nest, and died at the hand of the Canoness Superior Margaret Tenenbaum, Chapter Master Manin of the Ebon Claws, and Captain Tarkus of the 5th Company of the Blood Ravens. It was atop its smoking and torn apart corpse, their combined force seeing to the eradication of the now feral tyranids of the soon-to-be destroyed nest, that they truly paused for the first time since beginning the cleansing effort years ago. The three regarded one another, or perhaps more accurately Chapter Master Manin watched, bemused, as Captain Tarkus and Canoness Superior Margaret regarded one another. Her entire body still trembled and shook with adrenaline, but she bore her helmet due to the sheer amount of poisonous gasses and acids being thrown about by the enemy, so it was impossible to tell her expression.

"You fought well, Canoness," Tarkus said after a moment. "The final blow was well struck."

It had the benefit of being entirely true. The Canoness seemingly supercharged her gauntlet, the power field's eruption as she slammed her fist into the hive tyrant's throat blowing the entire head off. In response, however, the Canoness simply grunted and nodded, looking away.

"A good battle, but it will be yet many years more before we can truly declare the Sector cleansed of the tyranids," Manin spoke up, holding up and examining his crackling lightning claws close to his face. "I welcome your aid, Captain Tarkus, but…," he lowered the lightning claw and sighed. "I cannot aid you in your upcoming struggle."

Tarkus shook his head.

"I could not ask that of you, not when your home is still so infested and your chapter so reduced, Manin," he said.

"It still brings shame to us that you have aided us twice, and we cannot yet repay the favor," Manin growled, clenching and unclenching his fists. "We are…weak, weaker than we ever have been before."

"There will come a time, perhaps," Tarkus smiled, though it could not be seen beneath his helmet. "It just won't be right now."

"And what of us, then?" the Canoness crossed her arms.

"That is up to you and the Emperor, my lady," Tarkus shrugged ever so slightly in his armor. "You both know of the threat that he may pose should he be released, of what he may be bringing forth to aid him in such. But, as Chapter Master Manin said," he gestured out across the burnt mountain valleys around them, "There is much work to be done here, and elsewhere. The Blood Ravens will stand their ground, but we would welcome your aid if it could be given."

The Canoness was silent for a moment before snorting.

"The daemon is a threat to the Korianis Sector, not just the Subsector Aurelia. We cannot allow its release."

And that, it seemed, was that.

Relations Change
- Chapter Master Manin of the Ebon Claws: Good -> Good[+]
- Canoness Superior Margaret Tenenbaum of the Lost Rosetta: Neutral

All Major Synapse Bioforms Eradicated In Helba Sector, Cleansing Efforts Will Still Be Required For Years Yet, But No Longer Require Significant Military Effort. Lost Rosetta Will Aid Against Ulkair.

=================================================================

It wasn't even what they were looking for, at first. They needed records, and so sought them out. The idea put forth by the Chapter Master was to spread such information to various organizations throughout the Sector about how to prepare for the potential comings of this servant of Nurgle. Afflictions and diseases favored demanded preparation and stockpiling of medicines and more. It was a war fought in the veins, through capsule and needle, through injection and centrifuge, rather than bolter and grenade. An admirable effort, of course, but it became more quite unexpectedly. Delving into the records as deeply as could be done, some of the Blood Ravens lost themselves in the search, their purpose drifting towards simple scouring of the information available.

The Blood Ravens, for better or for worse, had always been devoted to the pursuit of knowledge. To further their capabilities against their enemies. To seek out information on the Unknown Primarch, on their very origins, a mystery and shame without compare throughout the history of the Chapter. Such was their devotion to it that tomes and secrets had fallen into their hands, into their repositories of knowledge, which would be deemed by some as heretical to even know about much less possess. At some points in their history, they had been able to bargain with that knowledge with others. At others, they had worked quite hard to prevent the Chapter's destruction at the hands of particularly Puritan members of the Inquisition, ambitious agents of the Ecclesiarchy, and so on. At the moment, however, they dove deep into their records, for it was near unheard of for the Chapter to ever forget a foe once entered into their records. Or at least, so it was said. That a corrupted brother, fallen to Chaos, had been Chapter Master but more importantly Chief Librarian was a definite worry.

Records Research: 95
Sabotage of Kyras: 88

To the great fury and shame of the Librarians of the Blood Ravens, they found yet one last example of the venom and ruin that Azariah Kyras had pressed into the Chapter's heart. Records speaking of Ulkair had been vastly reduced, purged, from the Chapter archives. A dagger plunged into the honor of the Librarius, of whose ranks had been so carefully pruned until the final purge came when the Civil War began in earnest. Yet, within that dark contemplation, that time of tossing tomes aside and frantically digging through scrolls, there came a dim glimmer of hope. Deep, deep within the Omnis Arcanum, within the Ultima Librarium Sanctorum, a clue had been left behind. One located by none other than the once-eyeless Nero Achillian, Epistolary of the 4th Company. For he saw with sight beyond sight, the ghostly words left behind on the echoes of scrolls that no longer existed. From there, he pursued the trail left behind, the sheer significance behind the records left behind by none other than the legendary martyr of the Chapter, Azariah Moriah. Though his student, Kyras, was not yet fallen at that time, the wise Chief Librarian of the time had known that even if they succeeded in defeating Ulkair at Aurelia, that his threat would not be permanently ended. His certainty in this, then, was just what was needed. The clues led elsewhere. All the way to another ship in fact, something found only after the Blood Ravens came together as a Chapter once more after years of separated operation. Upon the Litany of Fury, deep within the chamber where the psychic beacon lay, almost impossible to discover in any other circumstance, was a secret compartment. How long it had been there, it was impossible to say. All those Librarians who had passed through the Litany and been near the beacon in the past had not discovered it, or at least none of those currently living. Yet Epistolary Nero had found it, following the clues left behind by Azariah Moriah. A simple press of the hand, a drop of blood, and intense focus to reveal and then unlock something locked solely with the power of the mind and soul, otherwise impossible to discover much less unlock with flesh or metal. There, within, lay a wonder.

A single scroll, a piece of vellum caked in power, layered with wards of secrecy, of preservation, of power. Upon it? Words, penned in the very blood of its author, Azariah Moriah himself. A ritual, devised and prepared in desperation for the first coming of Ulkair had been a shock to the Subsector and Chapter. Even Kyras, driven mad and corrupted as he later was, had been witness to it. All other Librarians who had participated in the unexpected conflict had died; the knowledge lost to all but one who would never see reason to perform it again. After all, it was prepared and meant solely for a single entity, no others. In that specificity, in that precision, it was both potent and powerless, should one attempt to turn it upon another target. It had been well hidden, incredibly so, with almost all other clues to Ulkair lost by the hand of Kyras.

But not this one.

For indeed, though they had changed their war cry, their chapter call, there remained a truth that all Blood Ravens acknowledged still.

Knowledge. Is. Power.

Binding of Ulkair Ritual rediscovered! Penned By Chapter Master and Chief Librarian Azariah Moriah, this ritual was built to bind the powerful Greater Daemon Ulkair into a vessel and restrain his influence utterly. In the past, it was used to bind Ulkair into the planet Aurelia, and though the planet was lost to the Warp for a thousand years, it was not until the bindings themselves were actively assaulted by the Black Legion that Ulkair was once more capable of influencing the outside world. Should Ulkair manage to be released from the shattered and weakening prison of Aurelia, a successful enactment of this ritual could seal him once more into another world, one which could be once more watched over and waited for – with proper record keeping this time around, rather than somewhat forgotten like Aurelia. Records on past afflictions and other techniques, methods, and tactics destroyed long ago by Kyras, but medical stockpiles prepared by many nonetheless.

================================================

The call went out. The passage of Araghast the Pillager had not been unnoticed by the rest of the Korianis Sector. At the time, many had had their suspicions, and the later Civil War between the Blood Ravens had only confirmed such things. Still, in the years since, the Blood Ravens had fought hard to re-establish themselves, not only in numbers but in soul and in regard. The rest of the Korianis Sector watched as they threw themselves headlong into many fights over, and mutterings were had due to their approval by the Inquisition as pure. Purified through struggle, through the shedding of the blood of the xeno and the unclean. They had fought alongside the Imperial Guard and Imperial Navy, and the character of Chapter Master Angelos was somewhat well known by this point. The marine who had willingly consigned Cyrene, his birth world, to the flame for the crimes of heresy. Perhaps, perhaps, perhaps, it was murmured, the Blood Ravens truly were now purified. It was not, after all, as if space marines had not fallen before, that regiments and fleets of the Imperial military had been corrupted, and yet others still fought on. They even managed to fight alongside the Order of the Lost Rosetta, that notoriously aggressive, violent, and especially fervent Ordo Minoris of the Adepta Sororitas. Scribes trawled the stacks, expeditions braved the literal mountains and valleys of information gathered up by the Administratum, and then made compact and debate with the Ecclesiarchy when it turned out that only they had been allowed to bear records that actually possessed the name of the Greater Daemon in protected holy vaults lest the knowledge be allowed to fester and rot the very air around it elsewhere.

The call went out, co-signed by Governor Derosa of Meridian, and further by the Governor of Calderis, for it was their worlds that were in the most immediate danger. To be sure, there was much suspicion and concern about the Blood Ravens, even now. For if the traitor Kyras had truly fallen to Chaos for so many centuries, that was as many years of a Chapter being led by the Dark Gods in some measure or another. Could they possibly be truly pure now? Redeemed? The Inquisition had judged them so, and they had performed ably since in their capacity as the Emperor's Angels of Death, and yet suspicion remained. It would, quite likely, remain forever in some measure or another. Such was the way of the Imperium.

Sector Command: 54
Scarlet Lions: 69
Inquisitor Adrastia: 70
Forge World Aerus: 15
Forge World Zerann: 25 [OVERRIDEN BY MAJOR FAVOR USAGE]
Knightly Houses of Trontiux II: 97
Rogue Trader Tarquindil: 34

But so too was the way of the Imperium to honor its oaths, its bonds forged in the fires of war.

First, surprisingly, was the Knightly Houses of Trontiux II. Long-time allies of the Blood Ravens, the Chapter having rushed to aid their world when it was in danger of falling entirely, they had not fought alongside one another since. That, it came to be, would change. For the knights would march in the defense of the Blood Ravens, in the defense of the Subsector, of the Korianis Sector itself. How many, it was asked. All, it was answered. King Myrlen, of the House Myrlen, would lead the totality of Trontiux II's knights forth to war once more. The king declared via astropath that when the servants of Ulkair, of Nurgle arrived, they would face the knights of Trontiux II, and then they would die. When last the Blood Ravens had seen them, they had been shattered, exhausted, broken. They had long since repaired and rearmed, and though they were a minor Knight World compared to the greater examples elsewhere in the Imperium, their strength was not to be dismissed by anyone.

Then came a simple confirmation from Inquisitor Adrastia. The friend of the Chapter Master, the one who had come to him in his darkest time, who was the end of Cyrene through his confession of what he had discovered there, the one ally in the Inquisition who was absolutely most directly responsible for the Chapter's continued existence through her approval. She sent word, curt though it was, that she herself had unfinished business with the Greater Daemon, for it was the daemons machinations which had brought Araghast the Pillager and Eliphas the Inheritor to Subsector Aurelia in the first place. Though they had recently fought to capture Vandis, and the death of Merrick had caused a psychic breakthrough in her which required the Inquisitor's psyker rating to be raised, in the years since she had recovered. All throughout which she had performed her duties as required. Beyond that, even, as it turned out. Because the next message came from those with whom she had most recently been working with, apparently coming together quite simply because of their shared friendship with the Blood Ravens.

The astropath had struggled to properly communicate the bombastic nature of the Scarlet Lions, but their message came through. When last the Blood Ravens had encountered them, there was much worry that the Alpha Legion had further infiltrated their Chapter, had corrupted more thanks to their generally diffuse recruiting practices. Who better, then, than Inquisitor Adrastia to aid Captain Bartorius and Captain Kallek in investigating the rest of their Chapter? Though it was unfortunate that, apparently, one more company of the Chapter had proven corrupted, the majority of the Scarlet Lions was yet pure. Having felt the touch of Chaos upon their souls, they were eager to take bloody recompense in as many ways as possible. Though portions of their Chapter were still dedicated to their own conflicts, bound by honor and deed, some of the Lions of lost Lemnos would not allow their allies to fight the daemon and its servants without them.

As for Forge World Zerann, they were largely focused on looking over their bounty from the nebula, refreshing their troops and ships, but the Blood Ravens called to receive what they were owed. The Fabricator-General accepted the terms of the exchange, and promised that aid would come, and not in the form of fire ships like the last time. Active aid, in fact, for in truth Angel Forge and the ancient teleportariums and other examples of technology in Subsector Aurelia were definitely worth protecting. Cold logic, cold reasoning, but so long as the math worked out to have the Adeptus Mechanicus send aid, the Blood Ravens would accept it. What form it would take, however, was not yet entirely known.

Such was the extent of the good news.

Sector Command was not unaware of the threat, especially as to what it could represent if Ulkair was able to escape Subsector Aurelia. At the same time, however, they had been actively seeking out combat beyond the borders of the Sector. Much of the Sector's ships had been lost or tremendously damaged in the failed attempt to quell the Saharduin and the ensuing chaos as greenskins and Dark Eldar arrived. Even more had been lost in the taking of the traitorous governor Vandis. They, quite simply, did not possess the ships to spare. The routes between the Sector's worlds still needed protection. The most vital worlds across the Korianis Sector required ships to guard them at all times, especially if it was true that there would an incursion coming. Even more of its Imperial Guard had been savaged in other conflicts and required much replenishment yet. Still, they marshalled what they could, and with significant lobbying from Governor Derosa, acquiesced to the return and redeployment of all Meridian regiments from a dozen battlefields, allowing them the chance to fight for and defend their homeworld.

Such was the extent of the middling news.

Forge World Aerus would be sending nothing, for they had nothing to give. Their fleet, damaged in the fighting within the Cerulean Tomb, was all they had left. The massive fleet they had sent into the Halo Stars had encountered not an STC, nor anything good of the Dark Age of Technology. They had come across abominations of the past, instead. What was known was that a single Ark Mechanicus had returned, badly damaged with less than a tenth of its crew remaining, and no others. Living nightmares of the Old Night had been waiting for them, and they had taken their due. The Forge World barely had a fleet left to its name, its millions of skitarii reduced immensely, and it was all they could do to guard their own now incredibly vulnerable world. Fabricator-General Theodosia sent her regrets, but they quite simply had been so badly savaged in the pursuit of the Quest of Knowledge that losing almost anything more could break them.

The Tarquindil Dynasty of Rogue Traders, as it turned out, were similarly engaged. Though the Blood Ravens were aware that the Dynasty had essentially been coopted by the Ordos Xenos, that did not mean that the Rogue Traders were not engaged in their own stereotypical works as well. The fleets were already busy colonizing worlds both empty and occupied by aliens and had in fact contributed a considerable amount of their standing forces to aiding the Deathwatch. It was, Chief Librarian Justinius said sardonically upon receiving the astropath's message, as if they had a direct line of knowledge as to crisis areas of xenos incursions across the Imperium and seemed to have some sort of incentive to intervene. Other efforts were being put forth at staking claims on worlds for resources, looking for resources, and engaging in the 'trade' portion of the name of their station. It was not as if they were actively ignoring the Blood Ravens and their plight, but rather that they were engaged in combat, exploitation, or both against seven separate alien races currently causing trouble to the Imperium. The nominal head of the dynasty sent a fruit basket as an apology, the basket itself being woven not out of wicker but out of gold and adamantium, whereas the Inquisitor Lord Tarquindil sent a more formally worded letter of verbal support against the daemon.

Calls For Aid Sent Out! Entire Knight World of Trontiux II will deploy to aid. Some Scarlet Lion companies on the way. Inquisitor Adrastia will aid the Blood Ravens once more. Forge World Zerann will send aid, type and significance unknown at this time. Forge World Aerus absolutely incapable of aiding anyone at the moment. Tarquindil Dynasty is involved in seven separate wars against xenos races, unable to send any aid. Sector Command resources also exhausted due to multiple campaigns, Saharduin Swells disaster, loss of ships during defeat of Vandis, is marshalling some resources, but specifics uncertain at this time. However, due to Derosa involvement, all Meridian regiments spread across the stars have been recalled to defend their home, significantly adding to Imperial Guard numbers for Subsector Aurelia.

====================================================================

Gabriel sighed as he reloaded the bolter. All these years, and he hadn't yet fully mastered his new body. The damage sustained in the aftermath of the hunt for Vandis certainly hadn't helped matters. Though he had long switched over to wielding a various kinds of pistol in the past while wielding a melee weapon in his main hand, it would be a poor space marine that did not attempt to excel in every form of combat available to them. Wielding a thunder- or daemonhammer was not an excuse to simply lapse in one's abilities and training. And so he practiced. Carefully, steadily, continually whenever he had a spare moment. He was alone in the training chapel save for Cyrus, though he knew that elsewhere on the battle barge other younger battle brothers and many of the 10th Company were being pushed beyond their limits by the Master of Sanctity. To look at the space marine now after much attention from the Master of the Apothecarion, it was impossible to tell that he had taken any wounds while fighting the Kra at all.

Ballistic Skill: 164+62+Cyrus(25)=251/500
Chapter Advancement: 479+83+Hannibal(20)=500+/500

"Have you any further thoughts on replacing the Honor Guard, Chapter Master?" Cyrus asked while quietly causing the servo skulls bearing targets to increase their speed.

"Any of the 1st Company could fill their ranks, but as for the portions requiring actual positions, such as Captaincy and so on, there are plenty of veterans known to us already who might fill them," Gabriel grunted as he sighted and fired. "It is simply a matter of selecting them and promoting them to the Honor Guard."

Honor Guard Positions Can Be Filled By Any Of Those Veterans With Requisite Skills, As Present In the Famed Members Post.

Final Decisions To Be Made:
Moratorium 5 Hours

Honor Guard Promotions, If Any
[] Write-In Members From Famed Members Post For Positions, Non-Positional Honor Guard May Be Any Chapter Veterans
OR
[] Leave The Honor Guard Fallow For Now

AND

Promotions, Redistributions, Company Re-Establishment
[] Redistribute some of the 145 Unassigned Battle Brothers To Already Established Companies (Write-In)
[] Re-Establish A Blood Raven Company (Write-In Must Also Include Captain/Specialists And Number Of Brothers Assigned)
OR
[] Retain Unassigned Battle Brothers For Upcoming Conflict Instead Of Promoting To Any Specific Company

Turn 28: A Breath Choked By Ash (Part Four)

Spoiler: Form the Chain of Command

[] Plan: Form the Chain of Command
-[] Honour Guard
--[] Captain: Jordis Mencis
--[] Apothecary: Apothecary Ikai
--[] Chaplain: Chaplain Tasanor
--[] Champion: Veteran Nicholas
--[] 9 1st Company Veterans transferred to Honour Guard
-[] Redistribute some of the 145 Unassigned Battle Brothers To Already Established Companies
--[] 18 to 2nd, 20 to 4th, 9 to 5th
-[] Retain Unassigned Battle Brothers For Upcoming Conflict Instead Of Promoting To Any Specific Company
--[] 8 Remaining Unassigned Battle Brothers
-[] Re-Establish A Blood Raven Company (3rd)
--[] Captain: Hantu
--[] Company Champion: Amicus Antal
--[] Epistolary: Idman
--[] Apothecary: Aratos
--[] Chaplain: Galloss
--[] Transfer 90 Unassigned Battle Brothers to 3rd Company
--[] Transfer 9 5th Company Veterans & 1 1st Company Veteran to serve as 3rd Company Sergeants
--[] Transfer Tomb-Brother Andradus & Tomb-Brother Nephrus to 3rd Company
--[] Transfer The Great Father's Fist, 1 1st Company Gladius Frigate, 1 2nd Company Hunter Destroyer, 1 4th Company Hunter Destroyer, 1 5th Company Gladius Frigate, 1 5th Company Nova Frigate to 3rd Company Fleet
-[] General Reassignments
--[] Assign 1 5th Company Veteran as the final 5th Company Sergeant
--[] Reassign 1 1st Company Veteran to replace Hantu as 4th Company Sergeant

A Breath Choked By Ash
+075.M42+ To +080.M42+
Be Faithful! Be Strong! Be Vigilant! - The Emperor of Mankind

In the depths of the Omnis Arcanum, a grand ceremony was taking place. Though they were ravaged and battered by circumstance and time, the Blood Ravens retained some traditions that they could not deny. In this case, it was a rare and bittersweet occasion. Sweet, for it was a thing of revival, of recreation, but bitter for that it needed to occur at all. It was a draught that many of the Blood Ravens alive today could not help but be familiar with, even if two centuries ago it would have been unthinkable. But then, many unthinkable things had happened in shockingly fast succession. Cyrene. Tartarus. Rahe's Paradise. Kronus. Kaurava. The Aurelian Crusades. Kyras, and all that followed. Despite that, however, there was nothing but joy in Gabriel's hearts, regardless of it being flesh or bionic. The leadership of the chapter had assembled, as had their most senior members from across company and specialists both.

"Come forth Sergeant Hantu of the 4th Company," Gabriel intoned, dressed now not in his terminator armor, but in more ceremonial robes, something repeated across all those present save for the Librarians who retained their psychic hoods and armor. "Come forth Brother Jordis Mencis."

From before them, surrounded by saluting and unmoving ranks of Blood Ravens with their armors painted in the Chapter's colors but without any other identifying sigils, Hantu came. Armor refurbished and repaired after the damage sustained in the Helba Campaign, with a few extra additions. A handful of purity seals created by the Sisters of Battle, to mark the armor of the one who had fought alongside them and garnered what could almost be considered friendship. A few stenciled scrawls that, while perhaps crude by the reckoning of some, marked the approval and comradeship with the Imperial Guard Regiments who had fought alongside him. He bore no astonishing relics, nothing of incredible power, save for his armor, bolter, and knife. All of which were of utterly standard make. Then he knelt. Then came Jordis, still holding onto the same chainsword that he had wielded as part of the 2nd Company. His armor was pitted and scarred, marks of remembrance and respect from the battles he had waged, any and all true damage to the armor that could interfere with its function repaired. His face was scarred from a grievous slash by a Suysh Royal Guard, twisting the left half of his mouth into a permanent sardonic frown.

"Who comes before the Blood Ravens now?" Gabriel called out, looking down upon Hantu.

"Warriors of worth," Cyrus spoke up immediately, "Ones who bring victory to those they lead, to those they fight alongside."

"Brothers of integrity," Tarkus added, "Ones who have held true to the Chapter, the Imperium, and the Emperor."

Then the deck groaned slightly as the awakened

"I…shall…speak," Davian Thule announced through his speakers, "For I, Davian Thule, was Hantu's Captain."

"I shall speak," Macharius Sicarius proclaimed, "For I, Macharius Sicarius, was Jordis' Captain."

"Speak, then," Gabriel nodded. "Speak of these brothers."

And so Davian Thule did. He spoke of the brave, the loyal, the strong. A battle brother who had fought on Kronus and many battlefields besides. Who had not hesitated to refuse the offers of the heretics during the Chapter Civil War, who had never faltered. Even if he had not distinguished himself as an exemplar earlier in life, space marines were not so chronologically restricted in their lifetimes and capacity for accomplishment like other humans. The moment of exultation, of glory, could come centuries down the line from when one was a scout, and yet all the work before then was also of worth. For his was the bolter firing in the battleline alongside the others and his was the voice who called his squad to their objective while the battle unfolded. Then Macharius spoke, speaking of the younger, but no less brave Jordis, who was born of Calderis' desert warriors. A leader, a friend, a battle brother who guided and taught and fought with the same striding exemplary skill. Who had slain a Suysh Queen on his lonesome, nearly dying in the attempt but surviving instead through grit and willpower.

"We have heard, we have listened, and we have decided," Gabriel announced when Thule finally fell silent, the dreadnought almost drooping with the effort of so much concentration and unbroken speech. "Brother Hantu, long have you served as sergeant. Now, we call upon you to rise to the position of captain, to take command of the revived 3rd Company."

"And I shall do so," Hantu raised his head, eyes glimmering with emotion. "And I shall strive to prove myself worthy of the legacy of its last Captain."

"See that you do so, for to do otherwise would shame not just the Chapter, but yourself," Gabriel said seriously before laying Godsplitter lightly across Hantu's two shoulders. "Now rise, Brother-Captain Hantu of the 3rd Company! And you, Brother Jordis, we charge you to rise as Brother-Captain of the Honor Guard!"

"I shall do so," Jordis nodded resolutely, not even looking at the nearby Apollo who stood within the shadows, watching another take his former place. "May none find us wanting."

"MAY NONE FIND US WANTING!"

The assembled brothers of the revived company saluted, slamming ceramite to ceramite, while those garbed in their robes copied the gesture. There would be a ceremonial feast afterwards, even if it would be paltry by the standards of many other Chapters throughout the Imperium. Even now, some things remained, such as the tendency of the Blood Ravens towards quiet contemplation and study. If not of the enemy, then of themselves. But there was much studying of the former to be done regardless, for it would be one of the last moments of peace that the Blood Ravens could grasp for before war came again.

============================================================

The signs had already been there, for many years now. The people of Subsector Aurelia shifted uneasily in their sleep, whether in the Underhive or in the upper spires. Mutation was on the rise, even in areas bereft of major radiation or chemical hazards. Nightmares spread like a plague. The diseased ballooned in number, even as they were immediately cracked down on by the servants of the God-Emperor. The judgement of the Grey Knights was sound. There was nothing sufficiently dramatic and immediate to give an immediate example of warning, but then that was the way of Nurgle. To decay, to rot, to slowly ooze from the wound. Aurelia's structural integrity was ruined, in the long run, by the machinations of Chaos and the past actions of the Black Legion and Azariah Kyras. It quite simply could not hold forever. It did not crack apart, explode, erupt or anything like that. Not yet, perhaps.

Instead, the Warp began to...curdle, for lack of a better word.

Travel to and from Subsector Aurelia began to grow more difficult, slowed. It was worse inside the Subsector proper, ships attempting to move from Calderis to Meridian finding what should have been short trips greatly extended. At least five freighters that were ferrying supplies showed up weeks after their original estimated arrival times. Astropathic messages were garbled, confused, a few words here and there becoming unintelligible in transit somehow. The premonitions of the Librarians grew dark indeed, filled with death and decay, and the Blood Ravens began to gird themselves for what they knew had been coming. It was not quite the same as a warp storm, something which tore asunder reality and Immaterium alike in a violent eruption, but it was dangerously similar. Ulkair was growing in strength, it was the only answer. But this time around, the Blood Ravens would not fight the daemon and its ilk alone.

Ferried on Mechanicus war barges came the knights of Trontiux II, with much proclaimed fanfare and righteousness in their vox calls. Though they were a minor House compared to much more famous and acclaimed Knightly Houses, even a single knight could change a battle's outcome. High King Myrlen had not idly boasted when he had stated that the whole of his world would come to aid the Blood Ravens as they had once done for him. The Mechanicus Adepts of Angel Forge were especially pleased to see the Knights of Trontiux II, and there was much conversation and meeting between them as they slowly cooled their heels in anticipation for the warring to come. A little over fifty knights had come, fully supplied, and ready for battle against whatever would come to Subsector Aurelia. Being the closest, however, at least due to being in the same Sector, they had been the first to arrive to aid the Chapter. But they would not be the last of the Korianis Sector, for shortly afterwards a fleet detachment from Forge World Zerann arrived. Direly needed as they might have been, the Mechanicus was not one that easily broke with their oaths and debts. An army it was not, but the ships possessed enough crew and skitarii to fight admirably in the void and given that Astartes ships were not meant for pure void combat like others, it was a welcome boon indeed.

Other allies required slightly longer to arrive as the riots slowly started to get worse on Meridian but arrive they did.

From those further allies, the first was the Scarlet Lions, the 2nd and 3rd Company of that Chapter just as bombastic as ever. Captain Bartorius and Captain Kallek had come as promised, their ships long refurbished and repaired from their past joint efforts. Though some in the Blood Ravens were intensely curious as to the hints and suggestions made, as well as disturbed at the idea of such Alpha Legion infiltration efforts being carried out on other Chapters, Gabriel had firmly decided that he quite simply did not wish to know. Too many secrets had nearly destroyed the Chapter once, he would not have that fate befall them once more. The Scarlet Lions, thankfully, seemed to agree on the matter, and all that Bartorius and Kallek cared to discuss was upcoming battle plans and potential positioning. In the meantime, drills would be undertaken between their Chapters to ensure good cohesion when they fought alongside one another.

Next to slip from the steadily worsening local Warp environment was a familiar single ship, without escort or aid. But then it did not necessarily need it. For the Sword of Reckoning was no mere Grand Cruiser, it had long been modified and enhanced by the Ordos Xenos and the Mechanicus. The personal vessel of Inquisitor Adrastia was a grim and powerful ship, as befitting its owner.

"Gabriel," Adrastia said with a small smile as she gazed up at the Chapter Master, the docking bay of the Omnis Arcanum conspicuously emptied out. "How are you?"

"Well enough, all things considered," Gabriel sighed, looking into the middle distance for a moment before refocusing back on her. "And you?"

"My superiors were most interested in my…changed psyker rating," Adrastia grimaced and rolled her new eyes.

One had been regrown through psychic measures, the other a perfect outward replication of absolutely masterful bionics work.

"But the recovery of Vandis was considered quite the catch," she smiled, a dangerous and very satisfied thing that washed away the lines of age and stress completely.

For the briefest of moments, at least, before her natural demeanor reasserted itself.

"This matter with Ulkair is, I believe, the last bit of unfinished business with this Subsector," she nodded. "Afterwards, there might even be some genuine peace here."

"Aurelia has suffered terribly this past century, it is true," Gabriel nodded, the two moving to stand side to side to look at the Sword of Reckoning as it hung in the void next to the Omnis Arcanum. "But so have you."

For a moment, his old friend stilled. It had nearly been a century since the Aurelian Crusades. Unlike space marines, Adrastia was far more vulnerable to the ravages of time, though she had been quite young when they had first met by any base human standard. As an Inquisitor, however, she had access to far more resources to deal with those same ravages of time than others. As near as could be told, she had not yet even begun to rely on any major cybernetic enhancement or replacement aside from her one eye. Her force sword, inferno pistol, and power armor were all of clear artificer work, bearing the emblems of Mars itself, as well as the Inquisition. He also knew, even without being told by Martellus, that her Imperial Rosette bore the workings of a rosarius device.

"Governor Derosa has done admirable work, however," Adrastia sniffed. "She has expended considerable effort and capital on reversing the rot that House Vandis fomented for all those years."

"It was once remarked by one of our number that she might have served better sooner if she had been a Sister of Battle," Gabriel said softly.

"I disagree," Adrastia shook her head. "Under Derosa, industrial output has massively improved, efficiency has increased, and Meridian itself has contributed far worthier Guard regiments than the detritus that Vandis managed to get the Administratum to take. With Angel Forge reducing production of luxury goods by 50% and redirecting those processes and resources to more important things, especially. Statistically, she has contributed far more to the Imperium than she possibly could have running about with a single bolter."

"Hah!" Gabriel laughed, though it was a brief-lived thing. "A fair point."

They stood in silence for a moment more, gazing into the void, before comm beads activated for them both. One from the Librarius for the Chapter Master, one from the Sword of Reckoning for the Inquisitor.

"The Ordo Malleus is here," Adrastia said at the same time as Gabriel saying, "The Grey Knights have come."

And so they had.

Knight-Captain Tegvar had been with the small detachment of Grey Knights present above the planet Aurelia, keeping close watch over the Empyrean there, and was taciturn and standoffish even by the standards of their kind. Though they had only resided upon a frigate, that had changed with the new arrival. Identifying himself as Knight-Captain Beothinon, he had brought with him four more Nova-class frigates as well as their own strike cruiser. For indeed, it was a rare enough occasion that the Grey Knights were able to be so prepared against a daemonic incursion, having years of knowledge ahead of time to prepare. To that effect, a full hundred more Grey Knights had come, for they would not let a Greater Daemon such as Ulkair be released without a fight.

Yet a new question reared its head with their arrival. For shortly beforehand, the Librarius of the Blood Ravens had discovered what might well be considered the last gift of Moriah. A ritual of binding, the same which had imprisoned Ulkair before. A rare thing, a unique thing, a potentially priceless piece of knowledge. The Grey Knights clearly regretted their relationship with the Blood Ravens up until that point, not simply because of their casualties they had taken in Kaurava under Boreale's incompetent leadership, but from the taint of Kyras which lingered upon the Chapter's good name even now. And, in truth, likely would in some minds forever. It was a delicate matter, to admit to such a piece of detailed knowledge with regards to daemons, after everything. But perhaps it should still be done?

Though it certainly was not the last of the questions to be made.

Conferencing between all assembled parties came to another set of conclusions as it pertained to the enemy. The Tarot was clear, at least as clear as such a tool could be, especially when the precognitive abilities of the Blood Ravens Librarius was put to work on the matter. Ulkair had been calling for his slaves and servants, promising reward and favor aplenty for any who committed to the effort. Though a great many of the Plague God's servants fought in the 13th Black Crusade, such was the devilry and threat of heresy and corruption that there still remained notable elements throughout all the Segmentums that swore to the Dark Gods. There remained, even now, many fallen worlds, corrupted systems, and even whole Sectors sworn to Chaos. It was, unfortunately, impossible to ascertain just how many would come, or what variety, though some amount of Chaos Space Marines was expected at minimum.

The universe was not kind enough to do otherwise.

The issue at hand, then, was the defense. Two possibilities were raised, depending not upon the enemy but upon the forces of the Imperium. For it would be the latter that surely alter the behavior of the former. The experience of all the space marines involved, and the logs of the Blood Ravens and Grey Knights, all concurred in extrapolation. The end goal of the enemy was obvious, the release of Ulkair from the eroding prison that was Aurelia. Such could be accomplished in a variety of ways, the simplest of which would simply be the destruction of Aurelia itself. The crumbling planet was both physically and metaphysically the anchor which pinned Ulkair in place in both the Materium and Immaterium. A sustained orbital bombardment of sufficient strength, or explosives planted at crucial fault lines upon the surface, could destroy it utterly. Therefore, the first defense against such a method was obvious, a naval blockade of the planet of sufficient strength to ward off such a method from being attempted.

Yet, if this was done, all agreed, the Great Enemy would certainly attempt another method. Assuming that they did not possess rituals and castings to free the Great Unclean One was foolish. Furthermore, should their first method of attack be denied to them, the greatest secondary solution would be to invade the rest of the Subsector in force. The Blood Ravens could not allow the enemy to freely attack two of their Recruiting Worlds, and the greater Korianis Sector would suffer greatly if a world of Meridian's value was destroyed or damaged irreparably. Angel Forge was, despite being on a Hive World, one of the most sophisticated Forge-Temples of the Mechanicus in the Eastern Fringe, possibly all of Segmentum Ultima.

All of which was made more complicated by the fact that no one could say save for Ulkair himself who amongst the servants of Chaos would be coming to his aid.

But no one, not the Blood Ravens, not Inquisitor Adrastia, not the Grey Knights, not even Ulkair himself could have expected what happened just a few solar months before the end of the year. For it was, as they spoke in orbit over Meridian, that a wave of absolute chaos and terror swept across not just Subsector Aurelia but the whole of the entire galaxy. Hundreds of thousands of psykers sang out in a language that was not their own, many executed afterwards from the subsequent bouts of blindness. Dreams and nightmares melded alike, for those touched by the Warp and those not. Those of the Ecclesiarchy that were truly touched by the divinity of the God-Emperor shuddered, for they felt the Empyrean shake and twist as it became unbalanced, like a great weight had been thrown into a lake, before a new yet subtly different equilibrium asserted itself. The Astronomicon was, ever so briefly, obscured as a new light blinked through the Warp, sending millions of souls into destruction and damnation without a chance for salvation.

A name was whispered upon the astral winds, from no discernable source, as something new came to a fractured half-fruition – and yet that was just enough.

For in Commorragh, the gladiator known as Yvraine was born anew before a shocked crowd of Dark Eldar after being slain by a Priestess of Morai-Heg.

And she was filled with a new, unfamiliar, holy light.

But Subsector Aurelia, and the Imperium, knew nothing of this. All they knew was that the Warp itself had gone beyond curdling, it was practically beginning to simultaneously rot and solidify. Nightmares began to be had across the populace of both Meridian and Calderis, shortly followed by three simultaneous uprising on the Hive World. Bandit groups on Calderis that had sprung to life with the total extermination of the tyranids and near total extermination of the greenskins began attacking various settlements bearing flags of rotted flesh with a familiar symbol upon it. Warp travel began to get slower and slower still, though it remained somewhat possible. There was no telling, however, if that would remain the same forever.

The decisions needed to be made, and soon. It was entirely possible that the Warp would become all but impossible, and so the distribution of the ships and forces they had available needed to be doled out to the worlds of the Subsector immediately. It was just as entirely possible that the Warp would not become so intractable, but which choice was the better? To deploy the majority of their naval strength over Aurelia to ensure its protection, or to try and protect Meridian and Calderis as well, keeping the enemy from utilizing those worlds – or possibly even Typhon and Cyrene – for their dark purposes? Knight-Captain Boethinon grimly declared that there were more than enough souls on Meridian, for instance, for a great many terrible rituals to be enacted, some that might be enough to release Ulkair at a distance.

But it was Subsector Aurelia, the home of the Blood Ravens, and so their decisions would carry the most weight.

And thus, Gabriel Angelos felt the weight of his mantle fall upon him almost heavier than it had ever been before.

Decisions of the Chapter Master:
12 Hour Moratorium

Ritual Knowledge Decision
[] Tell the Grey Knights about the Ritual of Binding that Chapter Master and Chief Librarian Moriah devised which specifically targets Ulkair. Reaction of the Grey Knights unknown.
[] Do Not Tell the Grey Knights about the Ritual of Binding that Chapter Master and Chief Librarian Moriah devised which specifically targets Ulkair. Reaction of the Grey Knights unknown.

Deployment Decisions
[] Aurelia Focus: Focus the majority of the defender's strength at Aurelia, preventing the enemy from taking the quickest path towards their damning victory. This will likely put the rest of the Subsector at greater risk, but some forces can be distributed to other portions of the Subsector than just Aurelia. (Write-In Force Deployment Locations, and Forces Deployed) [Deployment Locations = Aurelia, Meridian, Calderis, Typhon, Cyrene]

OR

[] Subsector Focus: Focus the majority of the defender's strength across the Subsector, ensuring that the enemy cannot easily attack any one world, unless the concentrate the totality of their strength on a single target. Such as Aurelia, Ulkair's prison. This carries with it risk, but so too does it carry the chance of ensuring better protection for the Subsector if Warp Travel becomes even more difficult and the enemy attacks in multiple locations. (Write-In Force Deployment Locations, and Forces Deployed) [Deployment Locations = Aurelia, Meridian, Calderis, Typhon, Cyrene]

Imperial Forces Available

Entire Blood Ravens Chapter+Fleet [See Front Page]
Inquisitor's Forces

Inquisitor Adrastia of the Ordo Hereticus
23rd Alphic Wolves (Tempestus Scions Regiment)
1 Ordo Hereticus Vengeance-class Grand Cruiser 'Sword of Reckoning' [Possesses Ancient Retribution Battleship-grade Plasma Macrobatteries, Significantly Upgraded Armor, Shielding, Engines]

Grey Knights

1 Grey Knights Strike Cruiser
5 Nova-class Frigates
Knight-Captain Darig Tegvar

1 Grey Knight Terminator Squad [10/10]
1 Grey Knight Purgation Squads [10/10]
2 Grey Knight Strike Squad [10/10]

Knight-Captain Beothinon

100 Grey Knights

Knights of Trontiux II

Exalted Court of House Myrlen, House Merlyn

x5 Knights Castellan, x1 Princeps/King Merlyn
x12 Knights Errant

House Legrin

x10 Knights Errant, Baron Legrin

House Aerian

x10 Knights Errant, Baron Aerian
x20 Armiger Helverin

House Xerult

x8 Knights Errant, Baron Xerult

House Baroon

x5 Knights Errant, Baron Baroon

Scarlet Lions

Battle Barge Scion of Honor, 5 Sword-class Frigates

Captain Bartorius of the 3rd Company, Full Strength Company

Strike Cruiser Purity's Blade, 5 Sword-class Frigates

Captain Kallek of the 2nd Company, Full Strength Company

Adeptus Mechanicus

1 Retribution-class Battleship [Flagship, Commanded by Magos Militant Lu-Tu-7]
2 Adeptus Mechanicus Cruisers
4 Lunar-class Cruisers

Waaagh Birdmuncha, Part 6

Spoiler: Voting results [*] Patrolling the Under-Caldera with Dreng and Gunnars. The problems above are being seen to by those just as well-equipped as you to deal with them, but the problem below is something you're uniquely capable of contributing to. The greenskins being able to fill the vacuum left by the Skaven would be disastrous for the Karak, and you've mapped the Under-Caldera and have the senses to detect where the remains of the Waaagh might be digging through into it. So you part ways with King Belegar and find your way to Karagril, where Clans Angrund and Huzkul are preparing to fill the warrens of the Under-Caldera with enough eyes and ears to hopefully respond to any breakthrough, leaving just enough behind to see to the Karak Drazh Underway defences. Dreng is as focused as you remember, and after a brief nod of approval at your work with the Eye, he sets to work planning the patrols, the task much easier with the MAP you summon, which not only shows the tunnels but also their positions relative to the Caldera above. The most troubling parts are a pair of natural caves right under the Caldera and the artificial avenue dug between them. They had been used as warehouses from the very first decade after the Karak was founded until shortly before the Karak's fall, and more recently Clan Mors had used it as an outpost before the Civil War had forced them to pull back to a tighter defensive perimeter. So it's there that you choose to hold your vigil. --- [Greenskin tunnelling: 6] The strange sound of liquefied soil being brought to a boil that wouldn't be possible under normal circumstances echoes through the caves as a faint, distant whistling, varying in pitch and volume as separate sections of the Caldera above are targeted. The caves are somewhat interesting, as the floor was smoothed out by Dwarves but hasn't been maintained since the fall, and now a knee-height forest of stalagmites cover most of the floors, except where the Skaven had cleared it for their former base. But there's only so much of your attention this novelty can capture, and after your interest wanes, you take to patrolling up and down the connecting avenue, so you can run a careful eye over each of the caves every so often. You're so lost in trying to keep from becoming lost in your thoughts that you don't notice the person approaching until they're almost on top of you. Even if they are directly to your rear, it's an embarrassing lapse in caution for a Grey Wizard. "Journeywoman," you say, and Gretel falls in beside you. "Magister," she says, her tone careful. "Come to join the vigil underground?" She nods. "Hubert is at the West Gates, and Adela is in the Caldera with Magister Johann. I felt this would be the most efficient application of my time and effort." "You might be right." You look up at the ceiling, and even through the rock and soil you can still see/feel/taste the aftershocks of the Waaagh's obliteration. "A stitch in time, and all that. If they do manage to punch through striking them down still won't be glorious, and if they don't this will be forgotten. But only having to clear the greenskin ecosystem out of Karag Rhyn is an enormous stroke of fortune. The cost in time and effort and lives if the greenskins take root where the Skaven used to rule would be enormous." You smile. "That's why your College and mine get along so well. We understand the inglorious necessities." She doesn't reply, and you let the silence stretch for a while as the two of you walk down the avenue. "Okay, spit it out. I can feel your curiosity." Not metaphorically, either. The unanswered question she's contemplating asking is a faint tug on the Ulgu within you. "The 'Eye of Gazul', Magister. Was it literal?" You mull over your answer for a time. "In that Gazul was involved, yes. But I think it would be more accurate to describe the Tower as His sword, rather than His eye." "So the Dwarven Ancestor-Gods are..." She trails off, and glances back down the avenue. "Gods? Oh, yes. I've seen some books dismiss them as an extension of ancestor veneration, but they're quite real." You might not have been quite so sure on the matter until a few hours ago, but you leave that part unsaid. Gretel is silent for a time longer. When she does speak again, it's in a hushed voice. "Is Gazul their Morr? Or is..." Another look up and down the corridor, and she switches to Old Reikspiel. "Is Gazul an aspect of Morr? Or are both aspects of the same being?" You think you see where she's going this. "Aspects of Morai-heg, for example?" She frowns at you, but nods. You'd encountered the idea before. Some human priests insist the Elven gods are just renamings of human ones, and some Elven priests insist it's the other way around. You try to reach an answer that doesn't draw from the secrets you've gained from the Liber Mortis or from Gunnars. "I don't think the theory can be extended to the Dwarven Ancestor-Gods," you say. "Gazul doesn't have the aspects of dream and prophecy as Morr and Morai-heg do. And their Pantheon doesn't have Ancestor-Gods of the wild, like Taal and Rhya and Ulric." You switch back to Reikspiel. "As far as I understand, Morr and Gazul are allied, or at least their respective organizations are. I know the Black Guard has an understanding with the Zhufbar Order of Guardians." She falls silent, mulling that over, and you reach your destination and cast your Magesight over the cave's ceiling. [Greenskin tunnelling: 85] [Rolling for location...] [Rolling for who...] And you frown at what you 'see'. The Waaagh field of the surviving greenskins, even when some of them were actively fighting Princess Edda's throng, should not be visible at this depth. But you can see a crackling, fizzing energy out of the corner of your mind's eye as you frown upwards. "Khazuk!" you yell, and all eyes in the cave snap to you, belonging to several hundred Clan Huzkul Dwarves and five Rune-festooned members of Clan Angrund. They see the direction of your gaze, and in a moment the atmosphere of the cave is deadly serious, and the only sound is the distant piping of boiling soil and the scuffling of soles on stone as runners take off towards Karagril and the Citadel. Dwarves do not believe in taking chances, and your word carries enough weight that nobody here doubts the urgency in your tone. Then, right on the edge of hearing, the faint tink tink tink of metal on stone. The Dwarves circle cautiously, straining their ears for a direction, and a thought brings Branulhune to your hand as Gretel summons her scythe once more. It's hard to spot the place where the energies are leaking in through all the energies that have already done so, but you narrow it down to about a quarter of the cave and Gretel and the majority of the Dwarves silently follow your lead as you carefully step through the stalagmites. Then the energy strengthens, and you can clearly see the point where it's welling, and all eyes follow your pointing finger to it. Several seconds later, dust starts to float down from that point, and then entire pebbles. By the time a stalactite is dislodged and plummets to the ground, a score of handguns and your revolver are trained on the forming hole. "'Ey boss!" comes a slightly muffled voice as a choppa dislodges more and more of the ceiling around the forming hole. "I think this is it!" A massive head sticks through the hole, and takes in the amount of firepower levelled at it. "Oh zog." A ripple of fire from the Thunderers scattered amongst Clan Huzkul seals the fate of the unfortunate Orc, but the corpse is yanked out of sight and moments later a slightly muffled WAAAGH indicates the other Orcs in the ceiling have accepted the offer of battle. A great deal of stomping causes the roof to rumble and more stalactites to fall, and then the ceiling gives way, and at least a dozen Orcs are plummeting downwards inside a shower of rubble. [Clan Huzkul vs Orcish 'Charge': 20 vs 8] Clan Huzkul was not ready for such an enthusiastic approach, but gravity was not kind to the plummeting Orcs, and they lay groaning long enough for the Dwarves to get over their surprise and move forward, finishing them off where they lie. You keep your revolver levelled on the opening above. Through the dim light of the tunnel, you can see the glint of eyes staring back down at you with more intelligence than most would give a greenskin credit for, and you can see the waning Waaagh that centers on him. Warboss Birdmuncha. [Rolling...] "Zog that," he says, his voice a low rumble that reverberates through the cave, and then he's gone. --- Reinforcements from Karagril aim enough firepower at the hole in the roof to fell a small army, but no further greenskins emerge from it, and your vigil in the Under-Caldera finds no more interlopers. Word trickles down to you of the long, hard work of clearing the greenskins from the soil one group at a time, which got significantly harder once reality healed enough to disallow the boiling of non-liquids, and of the glorious battle at the West Gate, which will probably be what the songs that will be sung of this day will focus on. The sun sets and work continues by the light of great bonfires lit by Adela and stoked by Maximilian. The Waaagh finally winked out when the final charge at the West Gate was repulsed, and somewhere in the small hours of the morning, Princess Edda stopped finding pockets of greenskins left underground. When dawn breaks, the Dwarves carefully comb over every inch of the Caldera and cave in every single break in its surface. If there's greenskins trying to wait out the Throng, they'll quickly run out of air, and a final few holdouts dig their way out and are quickly cut down by the unflagging Dwarves. Princess Edda's Throng reports that they never set eyes on Warboss Birdmuncha. Somehow, you don't think he suffocated in the soil-dug tunnels. You told the Halflings supplying breakfast to point any and all wizards your way when they turned up looking for food, and they gradually accumulate on the balcony of the Citadel you've chosen to do today's brooding in, and they exchange stories. Johann and Adela were in the thick of the fighting in the Caldera, as Johann's gilded body and Adela's affinity for Aqshy made them better able than anyone else to handle the heat given off by the boiling soil, and both acquitted themselves quite well. Maximilian had once more been riding one of the gyrocopters, and to his satisfaction he finally managed to successfully fire his Silver Arrows from it, and accounted for quite a toll of greenskin stragglers. Hubert fought in the extremely successful defence of the West Gate, and managed to both bloody his blade and make good use of his Lightning Bolt to contribute to the battle. Panoramia is the only one amongst you who hasn't joined the battle, but she might make the most difference of anyone in the coming days, and she stares fretfully over the churned soil of the Caldera. "Ho, Dawri," comes a voice by the door, and a chorus of tired greetings respond to Prince Kazrik's arrival. "Wandar, rikhazkal?" you ask cautiously. "Everything's fine," he reassures you. "Okrag, then," you say, less than reassured. If he wasn't on official business, he'd be celebrating with his father. "King Belegar's Dalaz Kron," he says. "Many scores to settle at the closing of such a momentous chapter in history. He's instructed me to tell each of you that you're each to be granted a Boon, and should start to consider the form you wish it to take." Prince Kazrik hurries off to see to the next set of scores soon after that, and chatter amongst the other wizards quickly turns to speculation on how they will cash in their token of royal largesse. You, however, are simply trying to catch up with the events of the last two and a half days. You assumed military command of Karak Eight Peaks and waged a successful campaign against two greenskin Tribes, three Skaven Clans, and a horde of trolls. You made peace with a dragon. Then you fired the Eye of Gazul for the first time in hot blood, and in the space of a few seconds ended a Waaagh that could have been an existential threat to the Karak and reduced it to merely moderate threats on two separate fronts. Out in the Caldera, Dwarves still carefully comb over every square foot of soil looking for any disturbance that could indicate remaining greenskins. At the West Gates, the stragglers still make occasional forays against the defenders there, since Da Howlaz have them penned in on the other side of the Western Approach. And at some point the few remaining Clan Mors forces under Karagril will collapse, and the constant pressure from Karak Drazh will have to be held back by Dwarves. There may never be a total end to fighting here, but this battle is well and truly won. Karak Eight Peaks is once more in Dwarven hands. All because you and Johann stole a gas mask. [Title Gained: Azrildrekked.] [Trait gained: Royal Boon (Transcendent)] [Dwarf Favour gained: 40.] --- To be continued. In the coming day or so, I will continue the turn where things left off. I plan to have a big wrap-up of the Eight Peaks campaign at the end of the IC year, and there will be three different ways these events will have ended up shaping Mathilde: one from these past two days as Thane, one from these past four years as Loremaster, and one reflecting on her personal life. I will be taking suggestions for possible entries to this list; please make these suggestions with an eye to Mathilde's continued evolution as a character, rather than mere mechanical advantage. The draft below is very rough and a lot is likely to change between it and a final list of options to vote for. I will be away from my computer from the 20th until just after the New Year, and while I'll have my mobile and will remain active in the thread, I will not be posting updates during this period. Spoiler: Current Very Rough Draft of Shinies Menu Lesson Learned: The Battle for the Caldera & Waaagh Birdmuncha [ ] Battle: General of Fog Upgrade Trait: Warrior of Fog > General of Fog: The easiest victory is against a blindfolded opponent. +4 Martial. While in command, +20 bonus to scouting and moving forces unseen, +10 bonus to surprise attacks and ambushes. The Rangers were your eyes and ears, and where they could not penetrate, you had to go in personally to find out what was happening. The information acquired thus is what truly won the Battle for the Caldera. [ ] Battle: Strategy & Tactics: Greenskins New Martial Skills: Strategy - Greenskins (+5 to command and planning rolls while fighting or leading greenskin armies) and Tactics - Greenskins (+5 to command and reading the battlefield while fighting or leading greenskin units). You fought a lot of battles against a lot of greenskins. You've learned how they fight, and how they think. [ ] Battle: Advanced Strategy & Advanced Tactics: Skaven New Martial Skills: Advanced Strategy - Skaven (+10 to command and planning rolls while fighting or leading Skaven armies) and Advanced Tactics - Skaven (+10 to command and reading the battlefield while fighting or leading Skaven units). You've built on the understanding of the Skaven you inherited from Frederick van Hal. It could be that no living human has your mastery of fighting against the ratmen. [ ] Infiltrator: Nobody seems to guard anything well enough to keep you out. +2 Intrigue, +10 bonus to infiltration. [ ] Scout: Sometimes the best weapon is knowing where everything is. +2 Intrigue, +20 to infiltrating all but the highest-security areas. [ ] Battle: Assassin New Trait: Assassin: Combat is easiest when the other person doesn't realize they're in it. +2 Intrigue, +40 bonus against unaware targets. [ ] Battle: Trucemaker New Trait: Trucemaker: Sometimes the best victories are won by not fighting. +Diplo, bonus to attempts to secure truces or ceasefires. [ ] Battle: Thief trait of some sort [ ] Battle: Waaaghbane upgrade Sometimes you just need to get your hands dirty. Bonus to command roles after Mathilde has personally taken the field. [ ] Blooded > Campaigner: You've seen more than your share of battles. +2 Martial, +10 bonus to fighting alongside others. When in doubt...: You would have never had the confidence to attack to boldly if you didnt have the utter trust in your allies ability to hold onto your gains. You will have to leave that behind if you ever change your job, so you should absorb all you can during the rest of your stay here and try to aquire that strength. Bonus to fortifying. Allows spell creation. "Fog of War upgrade that expands it into applying at some level even when we are not in command? Basically making us a bit better at personally blinding scouts, discovering or causing surprises, etc—or at least doing so in a manner that better favors our side of the battle" --- Lesson Learned - Karak Eight Peaks [ ] Karak: Polyglot New Trait: Polyglot - Able to learn new languages very easily, either from dedicated study or from immersion. Picking up Khazalid helped you find a place in Karak Eight Peaks. Learning Queekish might well turn out to be the greatest coup of this entire campaign. Languages, you've discovered, are extremely important. [ ] Karak: Collegiate New Trait: Collegiate - Bonus to convincing wizards from the other seven Colleges of Magic to work with you; bonus to assisting and teaching wizards in your employ or under your authority. Come to think of it, the only College that hasn't contributed to this adventure in some way is the Light Order. And the dragon probably counts for them. [ ] Karak: Mapping trait Allows quick and accurate mapping, and future recall of those maps. [ ] Karak: Infiltrator Getting in and out of where you shouldn't be [ ] Diplo trait: Skaven understanding [ ] Magical multi-wind superprojects Interrogator -> Chameleon You've spent so much time in the minds, cultures and shapes of others that you can blend into almost any crowd. +2 Intrigue, +1 Diplomacy, +5 to avoid drawing unwanted social attention. Having Fun Isn't Hard If You've Got A Library Card: Your book collection has contributed to your success, and you're dedicated to continuing that state of affairs... by hook or by crook. [Bonus] to convincing people/institutions to give you access to controlled texts or to find merchants who can sell rare books, [bonus] to finding books while attempting to loot a place. [ ] Bureaucrat + Practical > Warrior of Paperwork: Scholarship is just a specific form of paperwork. You can live with it. Combines the two traits, +2 Learning, remove penalty to writing papers yourself. [ ] The great library of Karak Eight Peaks You have built one of the greatest personal collection of knowledge on this side of the world, and that fact is starting to spread. those in relevant fields or interests (Wizards, scholars etc.) are beginning to recognise the wisdom of your words (or at least you likely have a book on the subject) Patsy: Where Possible you will arrange for your enemies to blame either themselves or each other for your thefts. Eshin being an easy scapegoat was convenient but it opened your eyes to how theft isn't just a means of acquiring your enemies strengths but also a way to sow disunity among them on its own. Follow the Paper Trail: You will keep your eyes peeled for documents that give insight into your enemies thought processes when infiltrating or stealing from them. Getting materials to learn Queekish has given you a decent Idea of what important papers look like and how they are stored. "Know your enemy" extends to their paperwork just like anything else. Undecided on: Count The Cards: You've felt the influence of gods, distant and near, faint and mighty. How could you fail to notice the meddling of your oldest friend when it happens right before you? Mathilde is aware, in a broad "high result/low result" way, of all rolls that the players see OOC. --- Personal Change [ ] Personal: Ancestor-Gods New Faith: Ancestor-Gods (will be concurrent with worship of Ranald, and will not conflict with it) You've learned some of the secrets of the Ancestor-Gods, and felt the power of at least one of them. You're beginning to appreciate them in a way that few humans have the chance to. [ ] Personal: Remove Disdain for Sigmar Removed Trait: Disdain for Sigmar, +1 to Piety (for no net Piety change) Time and distance has healed the grudge you still carry. [ ] Personal: Xeno-affinity Bonus to gaining diplomacy traits focused on cultures outside Old World humanity [ ] Personal: Unphased Upgrade of 'Blooded'. [ ] Beatified Word is starting to spread amongst Ranaldites of your unconventional but close relationship with Him. They are more likely to identify themselves to you, more willing to cooperate with your goals, and may seek your wisdom.

075.M42 Interlude: Of Bitterness and Pride

075.M42 Interlude: Of Bitterness and Pride

The chains had been forged from the extracted iron out of the blood of several thousands of innocents, deep within one of the eldest of the Forge Worlds of the Dark Mechanicus well within the Eye of Terror. Sorcerers of the Black Legion had utilized dread rituals and spells gleaned from all of the Four Gods, workings to bind not just the flesh but the mind and the soul, creating a triparted imprisonment. The one who had headed the rituals had been none other than Khayon himself. They could have been, and had, used to chain down rebellious Daemon Princes and Greater Daemons who had dared to offend the commissioner of the chains and in each of those instances had not failed. That they had not yet been used upon the one they had been designed for, the accursed so-called Living Saint Celestine, did not matter. Not on this day.

For the one they bound, the one who was being dragged along the bridge of the Vengeful Spirit, was amongst the most deceitful, resourceful, and difficult to ensnare throughout the whole of the galaxy. Two of the Aphotic Blade held each end of the chains, four more of that deadly brotherhood just behind the prisoner with weapons held at the ready. Six of the Aphotic Blade were enough to ruin entire Regiments of the Imperial Guard, to face down the 1st Company Elites of the pathetic lapdogs of the Corpse-Emperor. It was considered barely enough for the prisoner, and as such many more of the Black Legion were present on the bridge as well, their weapons similarly held at the ready. Many were carefully watching each other, just in case some hidden gambit could be enacted, some sort of triggered word or phrase or movement which could reveal some of the eldest traitors in the galaxy to be traitors once more.

The Despoiler stood, glowering into the depths of the void, his back to the prisoner as they were hauled forth.

If one looked hard enough, they might see the weapons fire being exchanged between more than a hundred ships. Over Cadia proper, the supposedly indomitable Phalanx squatted, its guns and presence ensuring that more than a third of the planet's orbit and terrestrial territory was nearly uncontestable. Ships flowed out of the rotting Imperium, pumping millions more detestable sycophants and wretches onto the field. Some were of the pathetic Imperial Guard, others of the blind Sororitas, and yet more were of the foolish genetic detritus that dared to lay claim to the title of Adeptus Astartes. The territories held by the Living Saints were growing stronger with every day, the battle lines crashing into stalemate again and again while letting them build their defenses and infrastructure up. The one known as Celestine had been one thing…but the other?

'The Warmaster Sabbat'.

A title as insulting as it was informative. Creed had been slain by his own hand, the Space Wolves had quit the field decades ago, and yet the Imperium had barely been kept functioning by Celestine's presence. But presence alone was not enough, and so the Despoiler had ground the Corpse-Emperor's servants down year after year, claiming ever more territory in the name of the Dark Gods. But this one, this so-called Warmaster, was not as Celestine was. No flitting champion, Sabbat had learned at the foot of Imperial Colonel-Commissars, Generals, Lord Generals, and two Warmasters besides during the Crusade to reclaim her own worlds. Her ascension to Supreme Commander of the Cadian Gate had been uncontested even by the treacherous and petty leaders of the Imperial troops, especially once her appointment was further anointed with none other than the Emperor's own favor through the words of his Custodians.

"Abaddon…," came the sinuous hiss from the prisoner as they were bodily thrown forward to land in a clattering heap behind him.

Only then did the Despoiler turn about and gaze dispassionately down at a furious Fabius Bile. The Clonelord glared up at him, his armor and equipment torn from him, skeletal and pallid skin granted an even more unwholesome shade from the eldritch lights that played across the Vengeful Spirit's bridge. He writhed, even now, in his chains. Here, in the heart of Abaddon's power, of his flagship, there was no hint of obsequiousness on Fabius' face. Not a single mote of fear. Only spite and anger at being accosted, his laboratory broken into, and so unceremoniously transported. Abaddon flicked an eye up to the Aphotic Blades, noting the glint of fresh blood on their power claws and boots, and nodded with grim pleasure at the definite sign that Fabius had not come quietly.

"How many," he rasped, tilting his head slightly and raising the Talon of Horus to inspect it.

"Twenty, Warmaster," the lead of the Blades said calmly. "Each equipped as a true Astartes. They fought…well enough."

At that, Fabius scoffed.

"There were ten of you at the start, fool, and if my refinements had been completed-," he began to rant up at the terminator before a harsh laugh from Abaddon silenced him and made Fabius turn his head back around. "What?" He snarled.

Abaddon did not respond verbally. Instead he lifted his chin, and Fabius found himself dragged upright into a forced standing position before being frog marched forward so he could gaze down the length of the bridge.

"I wanted to thank you, Fabius," Abaddon finally said, his lips splitting unwholesomely as a hideous mockery of a smile emerged onto his face.

That, finally, seemed to manage a small chip through the armor of contempt and arrogance that the greatest apothecary in the galaxy garbed himself in.

"…what?" Fabius whispered.

"I wanted to thank you," Abaddon repeated before gesturing out towards the void – and Cadia. "You have ever disdained the Dark Gods, spurned them, and yet made use of whatever you wished of them. And yet," he raised a finger as Fabius made to speak again, "You finally went too far."

"I don't know what you're talking about," Fabius said stiffly, trying to turn his head away before one of the Aphotic Blades forced it back again with terminator-armor assisted strength.

"Yes you do," Abaddon let loose a cruel laugh as ships began to appear all around the Vengeful Spirit. "Your precious…New Men."

Fabius' eyes went wide.

"No."

"Successors to humanity when humanity's destiny is bound up with the Dark Gods? And yet you dared to try and hide them?!"

Another dozen ships appeared, projected upon the actuality sphere which showed the entire Cadian star system. More were coming all the time, identified and catalogued by the powerful cogitators of the ship. Some were war ships of various classes, some old and finally wrangled to come forth and others so young that metric tons of amniotic fluid was still dripping from their semi-organic metal shells. But the vast, vast majority were transports. Some cobbled together from scrap metal, others outright Universe-class Mass Conveyors, all of them daubed in the sigils of Chaos and the Dark Gods. Beside him, Fabius tried to throw himself at Abaddon, but the chains stayed his movements to little more than more writhing.

"NO!" The Clonelord bellowed. "You wouldn't dare! They're mine, they're -,"

Abaddon backhanded him lightly enough to only shatter his entire face, making Fabius collapse backwards into a heap. The dark amusement was gone from the Despoiler now, his eyes burning with fell unholy light.

"Everything is the Dark Gods', fool!" Abaddon roared. "And that includes your New Men! They have been bereft in fulfilling that truth, but that changes here and now! Did you think you could hide them from the gaze of Tzeentch? That their rages and furies were unseen and unheard by Khorne, that their enhanced senses did not delight Slaanesh, their flesh did not enchant Nurgle with ideas for new plagues?!"

Fabius raged, spitting and cursing, as more and more of the transports arrived. From across the galaxy, they had come. Indeed, despite the Inquisition's best efforts to root out the New Men from where Fabius had seeded them, a great many had survived the initial culls. Those survivors had, in time, grown in number for Fabius had engineered them to be able to breed true, and breed they had. For more than a century the New Men had grown like a cancer across the Imperium. On Hive Worlds, Agri-Worlds, Forge Worlds, Civilized Worlds, Mining Worlds, they had grown. On occasion, Fabius had even made sure to deliver more to yet more worlds, ensuring that his great creation would live on and be fruitful.

But where the Inquisition had failed?

The Alpha Legion had not. For the Dark Gods were most interested in the New Men, the creations of the one who defied them so, and the bargains the Alpha Legion made were far in excess of what the Inquisition would ever have considered acceptable. World after world after world, the Alpha Legion had done its work. It had been slow going, and dangerous as well, for no matter how one regarded them the New Men were quite deadly in battle. But they were not, no matter the Primogenitor's efforts, without flaw or weakness.

"For some, it was a fight. But for many," Abaddon chuckled darkly as he reached down and grasped Fabius lightly enough not to kill him, raising him higher to look out as more ships arrived. "It was simple enough. You engineered them for loyalty, Fabius. For love!"

Finally, the Despoiler tipped his head back and laughed, the sound a horrific soul-shriveling thing that was further backed by the laughter of daemons and spirits which made many of the bridge crew shudder as they worked.

"For most of them, all that was required was to be told that failure to comply would end up harming you," Abaddon snorted. "After that, they all but threw themselves into our ships, desperate to try and save you. But with enough time, enough decades," he drew the word out, "The Dark Gods took their due."

"No, no, no," Fabius shook his head, moaning through his obliterated mouth, "No!"

"Yes," Abaddon hissed. "Those," he gestured with one hand to one swathe of transports, "Ended up swearing to Khorne. Those," he pointed to another group, "To Slaanesh. To Nurgle. To Tzeentch. Many to Chaos Undivided, to the Black Legion, to me," he bit the last word as it emerged from his mouth. "It seems that your vaunted refusal to accept the Dark Gods is unique to you, and none of your creations."

Fabius could only scream in wordless rage.

"I wanted you to see this. I wanted you to know. And now, when I kill you, and you reawaken in some cloning sleeve somewhere else, you will remember," Abaddon drew Fabius close, the Clonelord's eyes widening. "Yes, Fabius. We know. We've known for some time now."

Finally, the Primogenitor's eyes narrowed to slits.

"If you think yourself capable of revenge, come and try," Abaddon threw him down before chuckling again. "But if you are not…perhaps consider praying."

Then he stomped the clone of Fabius Bile to death with a single movement before turning back to face the actuality sphere.

"Open the vox," he demanded, and with a crackle of technology and a squeal of daemons, his will was done.

Almost immediately, thunder tore through the vox, killing several lesser crewmen outright as their minds and souls were blasted to pieces. Power thrummed through the air, vibrating with a bitter rage beyond anything of mortal comprehension.

"S-P-E-A-K."

"Are the ships prepared?"

"Y-E-S."

A grin split Abaddon's face once more, his fists clenching and unclenching in anticipation.

"Then deploy them. Deploy them all!"

There was a moment's silence, just long enough for Abaddon's eyes to narrow and a fury be born in his heart, just long enough for the defiance to be felt.

"V-E-R-Y-W-E-L-L."

======================================================================

When the Phalanx's venerable cogitators and auspex scans had returned their conclusions, many on the bridge of the ancient vessel were set to panicking and screaming. Many denied it outright, they had to, as their minds could not withstand a universe where it was true.

Tor Garadon was not amongst such unfortunates.

For he was an Imperial Fist, and such behavior was beyond him. Instead, with gritted teeth behind an impassive expression, he strode to the actuality sphere's projection of the Cadian System with his hands folded behind his back. With the rest of the Chapter deployed to the surface, he was left as commander and custodian of the Phalanx, and with it secondary to overall control over all Imperial void assets by the orders of the Warmaster Saint. Still, to look upon what was now approaching deserved some measure of contemplation, one that he allowed to last a solid second before blinking and refocusing his mind.

"Attention all ships, multiple Gloriana-class Battleships are on approach. Prepare defensive pattern Tertius-4, pull back from engagements across the southwestern quadrants of Cadia – we must redistribute our firepower," he announced.

To the Machine Spirits of the Phalanx, what came from the Eye of Terror were unmistakable no matter how much the energies of Chaos had washed over and through them. Few in the Imperium could scarcely have believed that they still even existed, and many had hoped that they had been torn apart in the ten thousand years since the Horus Heresy, for the servants of the Dark Gods had never shied from destroying what their rivals desired if they could not have it for themselves. And, to be certain, all had suffered damage in the continuous wars beyond the view of the Imperium, deep within the Eye. Some, at certain points, had even been so badly damaged that some servants of Chaos had assumed them irreparable. And for most, they would have been.

For most.

"D-O-R-N-S…P-R-E-C-I-O-U-S…P-H-A-L-A-N-X. I H-A-V-E B-E-E-N L-O-O-K-I-N-G F-O-R-W-A-R-D T-O T-H-I-S F-O-R A L-O-N-G T-I-M-E."

None of the Glorianas were precisely as they had been during the Horus Heresy. They had been altered, repaired, modified, changed again and again while drenched in the depths of the Eye, of the Warp. But even so, the Phalanx could tell them apart, and that information was conveyed to the utterly dismayed Imperial Navy and many Astartes ships.

At the head of the incoming Chaos fleet, obscenely bulging with weapons arrays and a multitude of cannons and devices to the point that it was half again as large as it had been in the Heresy, was none other than the Conqueror. No matter when, no matter who, the Conqueror refused to be anything less than the first to battle. Alongside it, the useless fripperies and pointless accoutrements removed, was the Pride of the Emperor and the Nightfall. All the perfume, whether floral or fear-based, had been scrubbed clean. Gone were the torture chambers, the places of art in terror and decadence. The former flagships of the Emperor's Children and Night Lords had been 'corrected' by their new master, function overwhelming form utterly. So severe were the changes that few save the Phalanx could even have fathomed their origins based on outward auspex alone. Save, perhaps, that somehow after all these years and the best efforts of their new master the ships had stubbornly retained their names. A single kernel of defiance from long corrupted Machine Spirits that had otherwise utterly submitted. Much more tragically, however, was the presence of two other ships at the rear of the formation. Much less altered, whether because the attentions of their master had been on the other ships or elsewhere, or perhaps because they retained something else about them, they were unmistakably daubed in the colors and sigils of Chaos. But for all that, they remained the Flamewrought and Fist of Iron.

But none of those ships, hideously weighty with weapons of absolute devastation, could outmass the Iron Blood. In the ten thousand years since the end of the Horus Heresy, it had been a constant project. There had always been something to improve, another efficiency to squeeze out. The deeper the energies of Chaos had infused it, the more it had changed. The more its master had changed, the more too the Iron Blood had warped. At some point, however, the distinction between the two had begun to matter less and less, the longer the master worked. Both had become utterly changed in time. Now, all these years later, there was no longer a distinction at all. For the master was the ship, and the ship was the master.

Perturabo gazed upon the universe with senses beyond any flesh. Input flowed from every sensor, every camera, every auspex, seeing across a spectrum of science and madness both. The hull and void shields were his skin, his armor, his flesh. Power conduits his veins, his reactors his hearts. Though it had taken more than a thousand years, that which had been the Daemon Primarch had slowly melded and mixed with his ship, his body. His mind churned with the power of the Gloriana's cogitators, stretched and expanded beyond the wildest nightmares of any sect of the Mechanicus. Information flowed and thought-fast the fleet advanced, adjusting and readjusting with every minute to ensure the most perfect formation possible.

Though the Dark Gods had compelled him to come, the Despoiler had not dared to try and compel and command him. If he had, the supposed successor to Horus would have found himself incinerated under the guns of his ships and creations.

Far more disappointing were the three strike cruisers that followed along behind his body.

Three. And upon those ships, less than a handful of true Iron Warriors. There were many more who bore the colors and emblems of his Legion, but of true veterans, those who had not joined under Warsmiths in later years, those who had been there? So very, very few left. Some to ascension, others to the various foes of the Dark Gods, but so very, very many had fallen to one another. Assassination. Sabotage. Bitter rivalries whose fruition came to pass again and again, ending with the death of one more Iron Warrior, and often more than that. When Perturabo sneered, it was with the flexing of miles of metallic superstructure which bent and groaned. But then, he had not expected much better.

The only thing that could be trusted was himself, and his own personal creations.

============================================================================

"Look out, here they come!"

Some bore the look of Chaos Space Marines. Some bore the weapons of Chaos Space Marines. But command had sent down warnings that they were not, necessarily, Chaos Space Marines. Already, hundreds of them were attacking across hundreds of miles of trenches and defensive lines. There were others, too, who were garbed like Traitor Guard, like the more militant members of the Lost and Damned armies that the enemy had thrown at Cadia since the Horus Heresy, and all of them shared a horrific speed, strength, and toughness. Lasguns burned at their skin and flesh, and they did not fall. Boltguns tore at them, but they continued to lope forward and return fire of their own. When they crashed into the Imperium, they did so with cries to 'The Creator' and the Dark Gods on their lips.

"What…are these things!?"

Each of the awful creatures looked human, at least at first, but soon the differences became apparent. Joints that swiveled too far, limbs just too long or too short, proportions slightly differing in too many ways to be discounted, ways that changed and altered as the fighting went on. Many of them even transformed just before fighting, looking like normal humans albeit Chaos worshipping ones beforehand. Guardsmen screamed and died in droves as their lines were overrun by mobs of them, some organized, some not. Within moments, the New Men of Fabius Bile were breaking through in dozens of locations. One Kasr was broken open in less than a day. Much to the consternation to the Warmaster Saint, the fighting would only grow more intense in the following days as more and more of the New Men were deployed. Whole worlds out in the Imperium that had unknowingly been host to vast populations of New Men had been burned over the past century with their populace abducted, all in an effort to gather up a new influx of troops. Fabius Bile would rage, would seethe, and to his great frustration would find when he sought out the most hidden of the worlds he had deposited New Men upon that the Alpha Legion had gotten there first.

The Clonelord had continually refused to serve the Dark Gods, but his children and creations would do.

For now.

High above, the newly reinforced Black Fleet was now under the control of none other than the Daemon Primarch Perturabo, and he mercilessly prosecuted the void war. The Phalanx might have been outnumbered, but so too would the Glorianas be if they approached too quickly while enough of the Imperial Navy and ships of the Adeptus Astartes remained. A slower approach would be required. Instead, though the irony was likely lost on some, the Gloriana core took position over Cadia much like how the Phalanx had, instilling and creating a zone of absolute control and defense, letting ground troops deploy utterly freely.

And the 13th Black Crusade ground on.

Turn 25 Results - 2482 - Part 2

Spoiler: Unfinished business [*] Plan Slow and Steady with more papers -[*] Found an internal investigation division, to investigate possible misconduct. -[*] The Colleges want you to do a series of lectures on your paper, Waaagh and Peace. Travel to Altdorf and do so. -[*] You have set up a Shrine to Ranald. Expand it into a Temple to the Gambler - a gambling hall with clean cards, guaranteed unloaded dice, fresh sawdust in the fighting ring, and a lottery every Festag. Costs 100gc. -[*] Investigate how living things react to exposure to the Vitae. COIN. -[*] Have additional rooms excavated underneath your Penthouse: -100gc for 4 rooms. -[*] The Gambler: Investigate how living things react to exposure to the Vitae. -[*] Serenity: The ability of Alkharad to assume a projected form of mist. (ALMOST FADED) After the utter chaos of the Battle of the Caldera and a beautiful unveiling of the Eye of Gazul, Dreng and Prince Gotri will be scrambling to fortify the new outer borders of the restored Karak. Most urgent is the constant skirmish against Karak Drazh, but there's also the Western Gates that need to be rebuilt almost from scratch, the walls, watchtowers and redoubts that plug the very few gaps in the natural mountainous barriers between the Karags, and, of course, the undoubtedly innumerable Skaven-excavated passages below. It will be the work of decades to restore the Karak's defences to something that will satisfy the Dwarves, but though Dwarves approach fortifications with the desire for perfection inherent in all Dwarven endeavours, Dwarven Thanes and Siege Engineers are required to be capable of understanding and implementing the concept of 'good enough for now'. The world so rarely gives the Dwarves as much time as they'd like to fortify. But while recent events have seen their previous tasks backburnered, you are instead freed to return to unfinished business. You check in on Maximilian, who has returned to grappling with the Skaven book on Chaos Dwarf anatomy, and then turn to your own pile of books and notes. The scheduled beginning of your lectures is fast approaching. --- While Dame Mathilde Weber was watched with interest by her fellows among the Grey College and was known to many of those that make it their business to know what occurs on the fringes of civilization in the Old World, to the Colleges in general she was not that prominent a name until very recently. The Matrix was only useful in a few niches and the papers she produced upon the Eight Peaks Expedition were solid enough, but only attracted the attention of those already interested in what she was reporting on. Then the MAP and then the improved MAPP circulated, and hot on its heels was a paper reporting not only hitherto unknown capabilities of vampires, but also a series of countermeasures against them. This got the attention of some, and those that did watch out for her work were very quickly rewarded by the publication of Waaagh and Peace. In language understandable to any Magister and even some of the more advanced Journeymen, the paper promised to completely revolutionise what the Colleges considered possible in the intersection of counter-magic and the greenskins. Some dismissed it as clearly impossible, but many more sought any advantage they could get over the greenskins' shamans, and when Magister Weber scheduled a series of supplemental lectures, dozens cleared a spot in their calendars for them. But a quirk of fate pushed things a little further. When Barak Varr received news of a million-strong Waaagh marching on Eight Peaks, that information flowed north, through Black Fire Pass, and into the ever-listening apparatus of the Grey College. And when the next day brought news that it had been obliterated, that too travelled north. And thanks to the eternal efficiency of the staff of the Grey College, that meant that those wizards that had expressed an interest in the lecture received a small note informing them of a possible delay or cancellation due to seven figures of advancing greenskins. And directly atop that in each of their pigeonholes was another note, informing the reader to disregard the first note due to the utter destruction of said greenskins. To say this increased interest in Dame Weber's lecture would be an immense understatement. --- The Grey College does not often play host, and never to as varied an audience as the one accumulated for your lectures. It has been decided that the information you are to share can only be used to the detriment of the greenskins, so there is no reason to give it the usual restrictions that magical information would normally be shielded by, and the predicted crowd quickly outgrew the usual location of the gathering field of the Amber College. The University of Altdorf was asked to provide, and over the complaints of the local dramatic club they granted the use of their Magnus Hall. To your eyes, the stage that usually hosts orchestras and plays looks quite outsized for you alone and your nerves and your ego are warring over how to feel about the vast area of seats arrayed in front of the stage, and in the balcony that rings it, which is already filling with those about to be your audience. "Should be quite a crowd," says Regimand, who has been managing some of the details while you were in Eight Peaks. "Algard and Dragomas signed off on the other Universities sitting in, and the Emperor okayed foreign guests." That explained the woman with the very odd combination of magics intertwined inside her and an outfit barely within the constraints of decency. "Kislev or Bretonnia?" you ask, nodding in her direction. "Bretonnia, I assume. The Kislevite ambassador has requested transcripts, as their lot are still occupied with their Ogre problem." As Regimand bustles off to see to one detail or another, you run several of your senses over the gathering crowd. There's a veritable rainbow of robes from all eight Colleges, from the neat and unadorned robes of Perpetuals to the heavily runed robes of Battle Wizards to the eclectic fashion tastes of Magister Lords. Algard is present in the very centre of the balcony, flanked by No-Relation Reicthard of the Bright Order and Elspeth von Draken of the Amethyst. And though they were the most gratifying and intimidating of your audience, they were far from the most exotic or unexpected. One of the Hedgewise, under a grey robe and a fair few cloaking spells, almost certainly here under a false name. If they're not also here by invitation and under the protection of the Grey College, they're likely to be on a pyre or in a shallow grave by sunrise tomorrow. An Arabyan magician, dressed impeccably in the silk doublet and hose that was currently in style in Altdorf, only slightly incongruous from the curved dagger on his waist to mundane eyes, and rather more so to ones capable of seeing the magical beings trapped within the stones of his rings. Arabyans insist their Djinns are completely distinct from Daemons, and though academia is still divided on the issue, politics dictates acquiescence. Daroir of Nagarythe, with a fully battle-ready Shadow Warrior on one side as a bodyguard or a date or both, and on the other an Elf that bears the universal expression of a harried bureaucrat, a stack of note paper, and a midnight-black feather quill. A mercenary wizard of Tilea, looking very nervous and holding in their lap what you guess to be a declaration of good standing from a Tilean Prince or Doge or Triumvir or some other variety of ruler, which would be all that stood between them and being labelled a Black Magister and executed. There's a Grey Wizard in the row behind them, almost certainly keeping a watchful eye on them. A Runesmith of Karak Norn, keeping a wary distance from the wizards and compulsively checking the medallion on his chest, no doubt bearing a Rune of protection from magic of some sort. Several Priests, mostly Verenan and Myrmidian, though there's a Taalite-and-Rhyan pair close to the back. And almost indistinguishable from the Verenans, academics of several stripes, carefully clumped according to affiliation. The University of Altdorf locals are keeping their distance from their University of Nuln cousins, and both are keeping a much larger distance from the interlopers of Marienburg's Tempelwijk. As the Hall fills near to capacity and the appointed hour approaches, you take a deep breath and go over your notes one more time. --- "There are as many ways to categorise magic as there are beings who wield it, but one of the most common and fundamental is distinguishing those that wield the magic of the Aethyr, and those that wield the power of their God. I have come to realise that this is the biggest barrier in the way of understanding and countering the magics of the greenskins. "The definition of a greenskin Shaman is not a greenskin capable of casting magic, nor one capable of directly channeling the power of the greenskin Gods. They store and direct the energies of the Waaagh, tapping into the energy field that bridges the greenskins and their Gods, but is not entirely of either. It possesses some qualities of the Arcane, some of the Divine, and some unique to it, so any approach that treats it using preconceptions developed from dealing with other magics is doomed to failure. So to understand greenskin magic, you must first understand the Waaagh. For those of you keeping notes - three As, no exclamation mark. "To students of history, Waaagh might seem a rough equivalent to a horde or a beastherd, such as Waaagh Urgluk, Waaagh Grimfang, Waaagh Gorbad, or Waaagh Grom. This comes from using greenskin terminology without understanding it or them. Waaagh is the energy that develops from greenskins engaged in or anticipating bloodshed, and when a ruler arises among them of great martial prowess and tactical acumen - what they call Brutality and Cunning - it fills all their followers with that anticipation, and the energies this produces fills those greenskins with confidence and bloodlust as well as attracting more greenskins to the banner and drawing the attention of their Gods. This results in a self perpetuating cycle of growth and conquest centred on the leader that begun it. That is the Waaagh. "By itself, the Waaagh and its energies are largely only psychological in effect. In the hands of a Shaman, either a Goblin channelling the Cunning of the Little Waaagh or an Orc the Brutality of the Big Waaagh, it becomes something very different. Imagine a Light Order Choir tens or hundreds of thousands strong amplified by a War God with no concept of subtlety, and you might begin to understand how this magic operates. At first, this is a terrifying thought. Sober reflection, however, quickly leads one to suspect that such a system would be hideously vulnerable to attack from a number of different vectors, and that it all turning on the axis of a single Shaman means that it would not take much destabilization to bring the entire spellcasting apparatus crashing down. These suspicions are absolutely correct, and once you understand enough about the Waaagh to know where to target, you won't need to try to match your strength against that of the Waaagh. All you need is a push in just the right place. And over the course of these lectures, I will give you that understanding." --- It is the fundamental problem of magical academia - how do you explain something when everyone experiences that thing differently? The Elves of Ulthuan use poetry, a language where every word has a dozen contradictory meanings, and a lifespan measured in centuries. The Colleges find the best results from a Master and Apprentice system, so that the teacher and the student end up with similar magical senses and a solid understanding of where they differ. But the drawback of that is that it makes widely disseminating information impossible and standardization close to it. So every Wizard who puts quill to parchment ends up turning to metaphor, and every recorded Magesight observation is described through the lens of a more mundane sense. Usually sight, sometimes sound, the more repugnant magics often as smell, and for you, the Waaagh is best described as the taste of metal in your mouth and the feeling of an unpleasant vibration in your bones. But as fundamental a problem as it is, it's also one that your audience will be familiar with wrestling with. While you do have to filter your observations through metaphor, you don't have to worry about it misleading them the way you would with laymen. So you merely couch your metaphor with a few others from your library - the discordant tones of a Light Order observer, the sensation of half-welcome heat mixed with entirely unwelcome humidity of a Bright Order Battle Wizard, the staccato pulsations of a Runesmith. Those that have felt it for themselves should be able to translate to their own senses, and those that haven't will have to figure it out when they first do. You regret that your Magesight had apparently decided that Waaagh is a flavour, as if it was a sight you could replicate it with your MAPP. The least intuitive thing about Waaagh energies is that in stark contrast to the beings they arise from, it is entirely predictable and acts more like a mundane gas than the flighty and whimsical energies of the Winds. It is attracted to greenskins, more to those fighting than those not, denser around Bosses in accordance with their place in the hierarchy, and to Warbosses and Shamans most of all. A set of ironclad constants at the centre of the often-anarchic animosity of the greenskins is one of their strengths, but with this lecture you begun to transform it into a weakness. Reliability is vulnerability. You explain all of this in painstaking detail in the first phase of the lectures, and take a break from there to field questions and talk some of the more prominent attendees into understanding. Those that have faced the Waaagh tend to get it, and those who haven't tend not to, and you begun to wonder if it might be possible to emulate or capture Waaagh energy for teaching purposes. The second phase of lectures focuses on spell disruption, and where previous attempts went wrong. Your audience remains about the same size but grows in prestige, as Apprentices drop out but Battle Wizards and Lord Magisters read the transcripts so far and decide to see the rest in person. You explain to them that you can't kick away at the foundations when the air is thick with the energy the foundations are built upon, as those energies rush in to fill the void you just created and you may as well have not bothered. But if you blast those loose energies away - much easier than doing so to the energies being actively shaped by a Shaman - then the strength becomes a weakness as the spell begins to dissolve as the energies are drawn to the many small vacuums this results in. Or if you must strike directly, strike at the centre rather than at the foundations, and let the spell collapse inwards, resulting in every facet of it becoming weaker and less controllable, making it possible to combat it more conventionally. As the phase draws to a close, you explain the most finicky but most potentially devastating method of indirect interference - charging the air with Winds to make it more or less resistant to the Waaagh and thus either direct them away from the Shaman and weaken them, or to them and overload them. This is the least developed possibility for the simple fact that you can and have tested how Waaagh reacts to Ulgu-energized air - very favourable for the Little Waaagh and somewhat unfavourable for the Big - but can't replicate the experiment for the seven other Winds yourself. So you leave that in the hands of your audience, and hope to see a series of supplemental papers emerge in coming years as your colleagues in other Colleges try it for themselves. The third phase, in your opinion, is where the real meat of the lectures are. This is where you describe not how to merely prevent the casting of hostile magic, but to turn it back on the Shaman and sometimes any greenskins unfortunate enough to be in the blast radius. Enhancement spells being used as a channel to drain away the Waaagh from an area completely and psychologically devastate the greenskins is your personal favourite, but using the previously described air-charging method to steer a spell without touching it directly is pleasingly elegant too. The trickiest part is when a Shaman calls for the direct intervention of Gork or Mork, but while you very much emphasize how inadvisable it would be to try to directly counter a God, the energies a Shaman uses to suggest a target are fair game, and while moving them about without disrupting them would require a great deal of control, just about anyone could muster enough strength to scatter them and leave it up to luck for the God to decide where to intervene. As you're witnessed, They have no compunction against stomping their own believers. As you're wrapping up the last few lectures and fielding all the questions you have patience for, Algard approaches you one evening. "Very fine work, Magister. But with the adulation taken care of, there's another matter. The Ar-Ulric has asked to see you." A thousand terrible scenarios flash through your mind in an instant, and you make no attempt to keep the expression on your face from showing it. "Believe me, I understand your concern. But the request has gone through the official channels, and I've spoken to the Emperor and Dragomas about it, and if this is a trap of some sort, the Ar-Ulric knows damn well that all eight Colleges will march on Middenheim and the Imperial Army won't do a thing to prevent it." "Is it an order?" you ask flatly. "No. He has no authority over you and I won't lend him mine. The decision is yours. But I won't deny that I'm curious, and ever since the trouble with Nordland started the Ulricans have been incredibly tight-lipped, and if you can bring any new information to the table it would be an enormous help." [*] Agree to meet the Ar-Ulric. [ ] Refuse to meet the Ar-Ulric. --- After the weeks spent in Altdorf trying to communicate the intricacies of Waaagh magic, it's a relief to be able to sequester yourself in your laboratories and dedicate some serious time to further unravelling the mysteries of the Aethyric Vitae, and specifically how it reacts to living creatures. You're fairly confident it's going to go rather poorly for your test subjects, but finding out exactly how and when it goes badly would tell you whether your current safety measures are adequate, and make it possible to bring others into the project suitably forewarned. You start small, with a collection of various invertebrates who decided to try their luck with the Karak's crops and would now pay the price. Modern conventional classifications split non-magical animals into six different classes, and you begin with the most basic - Vermes, represented by a snail. It oozes its way around a sample dish containing a single drop of Vitae, and you watch from a safe distance as it moves over the tiny dollop without paying it any heed. You give it a few more moments, then carefully approach as it tries to make its way over the lip of the dish and peer down. The single drop has obeyed conventional fluid dynamics by spreading across the slime track, and with the tip of an obsidian scalpel you try to encourage the two substances to mix. They refuse, and the Vitae shows a stubborn determination to remain contiguous, apparently being drawn towards itself. Over several cautious hours you scale up the experiment in very gradual increments, until the poor snail is wading unhappily through Vitae half the depth of its body, with no unexpected reactions from either. You rescue the critter one last time and graduate it from active experimentation, dropping it into a small tank in a corner of the laboratory with a trickle of water and a handful of lettuce leaves. You add the results to your notes - because a lack of reaction here is just as telling as something more dramatic would have been - and move on to the next step in the hierarchy of Animalia: Insecta. The beetle darts around the tray with what seems like nervous energy, but your Magesight sees no mirroring stirrings in the ambient Winds. Whether this is because the insect feels no emotion or that its emotions are incompatible with the Aethyr is a question you're not here to answer, and either way you predict the same lack of reaction that the snail experienced. At first you're mostly right, and you take a few notes on how the liquid regathers itself after being scattered by the darting movements of the beetle. But the beetle eventually calms, and approaches the tiny puddle of vitae to drink from it. All seems fine at first, but after about a minute there's a very tiny burst of magical energies and the beetle writhes and expires. A very small autopsy later reveals a rupture in something roughly analogous to a stomach, which you reason was caused by the sudden expansion of the Vitae transforming into the Eight Winds. Strange, you muse. The Winds normally exist as a phase of their own, interacting with mundane matter in ways according to their nature. But in the fraction of a second the transformation from Vitae to Winds takes, it physically expands. Is the Vitae expanding like a boiling liquid does, and then transforming directly into incorporeal Wind? Or is it passing through a gaseous phase before becoming Wind? The cause of the transformation puzzles you too, and you put aside your test creatures for a while as you run some tests directly on the Vitae. At the cost of a few sample flasks, you determine that while the Vitae is mostly stable, enough agitation is sufficient to cause it to transform into Winds. Your hypothesis is that the unfortunate beetle's stomach provided this agitation. Interesting, but once more, the Vitae is not reacting to the creature itself - only to being agitated. Next is Pisces. You're less than keen to fill an entire fishbowl with the Vitae, so you repeat the experiments one more time with a larval newt imported from Ulrikadrin, and all that you discover is that a gill chamber is as agitating to the Vitae as a beetle's stomach. About what you expected. Larger fish tend to be more intelligent than smaller fish, at least according to some Manannian doctrines, and you believe they might be able to spark a different reaction to the Vitae, but the logistical problems and safety hazards inherent in testing that hypothesis lead you to move on to Amphibia, represented by some Badlands lizards retrieved by scouts. The lizards are naturally quite terrified when they arrive, and you can see a very faint ripple in the ambient Shyish. Intelligent enough to fear death. A single drop of Vitae glistens upon the scales of a terrified lizard for a moment, before exploding into Winds and sending the test subject skittering away in panic. You coax the poor creature into a nice dark box to nurse its bruise and move on to a second test subject, and you douse most of the lights, move quietly, and provide some of the surplus test subjects from the first two phases. The lizard calms somewhat as it eats, and though it watches you carefully, it does not react to the dropper moving slowly over it. The drop of Vitae lands atop its back and the creature freezes for a moment, before carefully returning to its feast. The drop moves slowly down its side and then falls onto the floor. You skip right past Aves and onto Mammalia to test your newfound hypothesis, and a few volunteers suffering bruised hands later confirms it: a sufficiently strong emotion of a type attractive to the Winds will spark the transformation, and for some reason it requires less Wind concentration from emotion than it did from your own manual concentration of Ulgu in previous experiments. Is it because a Wind manipulated by a Wizard is partially shielded from the Vitae? Because Winds moving freely and drawn to emotion is somehow more reactive? Or does one or the other possess some other quality that changes how readily Vitae reacts to it? You can't think of a way to narrow down the possibilities further, so you move on to further testing of the results of Vitae consumption - though this time, of course, on a much smaller scale. Vitae does not readily mix with other liquids, but very careful experimentation does reveal a way to stir it just enough to mix it without agitating enough to trigger the transformation, and before the waters can still once more and the Vitae can be drawn back together, you present the mixture to a series of dehydrated test subjects, who eagerly gulp it down. All of them show various levels of discomfort a few minutes later, coinciding with the sudden release of magical energies within them, but while the Amphibia test subjects have the energies escape through them and fill the room, the Aves and Mammalia ones have the energies initially remain within them, and they display heightened fear, anger, and curiosity responses as the Winds slowly radiate back out of them, similar to how animals act in Wind-rich environments. You increase the dosage, and find a medium-level dose that so floods the test subjects that the crowded energies are forced to intermingle and begin to curdle into Dhar. Unfortunate, but the mercy killings do provide an opportunity to do an autopsy, and you confirm that while the intermixed doses do cause internal bruising to the digestive organs from the Vitae transformation, it's not strong enough to cause severe or permanent damage. You feel confident enough in your understanding to bring in live test subjects once more, and flasks of the Vitae are carefully moved around by volunteers who are under strict instructions to remain unemotional. You then graduate to having them handle it directly, and most subjects remain unharmed. There was one overly-clever volunteer who got a little too curious about the strange, gleaming substance they were running their fingers through, but they'll heal in time. A very sceptical squad of Dwarven volunteers very carefully replicates these tests, and though the Vitae does slide away from the prodding of a Dwarven digit, the repellent effect isn't enough to have it crawl up a test tube. The volunteer's emotions prove irrelevant to the Vitae, and the only way they are able to spark the transformation is via agitation. So. Vitae is safe to handle by Wizards as long as one is gentle, as they can control the magic within them and keep it away from the Vitae they are handling. It is safe to handle by Dwarves as long as they are gentle, as their emotions do not sufficiently stir the Winds. Non-magical sentients must remain gentle and also serene, as too much of the wrong emotion will draw a Wind to them which could transform the Vitae. You close the cover of your notebook, pleased with the progress you've made, and turn to the paper on Alkharad's gaseous form. [Writing paper: Learning, 79+27+20(Necromantic Insight)+6(Library: Vampires)=132.] Magic, you know, is often spoken of as if it has laws, but what it actually has is tendencies. An Apprentice will first be taught things like propagation speed of magic through the air, and then taught all the different circumstances under which that might not apply. So while most Wizards would happily say there'd be no way for a Wizard to be present and active in real time in two different places hundreds of miles away at once, they'd likely start adding disclaimers and provisos if you asked if it would apply to an ancient and studious Necrarch Vampire. So while it is definitely news that there exists at least one spell that can break that particular norm, it is not particularly shattering news, as the origin of magic makes it fundamentally antithetical to limitations and predictability. It does, however, remain a very important paper to write. If this particular ability was not limited to Alkharad - who won't be causing any trouble from his position on your shelf - then it could very well be used to mislead and befuddle Vampire Hunters across the Empire and beyond. If a Vampire could be a province away while still interfering with matters through a form of mist, they could lead any pursuer on a merry chase in any direction they pleased. So you put pen to paper and describe everything you saw of the Vampire's ability to be active in two places at once, and after some thought split the paper into two sections, the first describing the characteristics of the spell in terms a layperson could understand and not getting into the technical side of things until the second half of the paper. You're quite pleased with the result, feeling you've managed to write a paper that could be equally of use to an uneducated Vampire Hunter as it would be to a scholarly Wizard. When you label and address the paper to be sent back to the Grey College, you give instructions that the Light College pass it on to the Templar Witch Hunters, and the Amethyst College to the Fellowship of the Shroud. [Observations on a Necrarch's Extreme-Range Real-Time Interaction Ability. Subject: Rare, +1. Insight: Revolutionary, +2. Delivery: Compelling, +1. Precious, +1. Accessible, +1. Tactically Significant, +2. Total: 8.] --- When it comes to personal enrichment, people are very good at convincing themselves that they can get away with it and that the harm done will be minimal. Traditional countermeasures are to try to counteract these tendencies by making them believe getting away with it would be impossible or that even minimal damage done would be unforgivable. The reputation of the Grey College is great for the former, especially when you've sufficient grasp of bureaucracy to back up your threats with random spot checks. As for the latter, faith and patriotism are safe bets. So you set to building twin sets of accountability infrastructure: one for the EIC, and one for the Temple to the Gambler you're building. The EIC a straightforward matter, as there is already a strong streak of patriotism within the company, giving you a good pool of candidates to draw from. They are to focus on actual misconduct that might threaten the Empire or the EIC's relationship with it rather than mere accounting irregularities, so you don't foresee any major conflicts of loyalty. Anyone misbehaving seriously enough to attract the attention of the newly-formed division would be betraying their friends in the company as much as they were the company itself, after all. And the first few examples will serve to make it clear to everyone else that the consequences will be severe and unavoidable. The Temple is a trickier matter. One of the first decisions you made was not to engage in player-versus-house games to prevent resentment from the patrons and adversarial thinking from the staff. The Temple will fund itself by taking a rake from the card games, a commission on the bookmaking, and the sale of beer, ale, wine and liquors to the clientele. Hiring from amongst those Undumgi who have taken wounds that won't allow them to patrol any more gets you the bar staff, but for an affinity for cards, an ability to spot cheats, and to honour the Gambler, you need to recruit from further afield. [Recruiting dealers and priests: Piety, 73+26=99.] You reach out to Heideck, and make it crystal clear that you're looking for those dedicated only to the Gambler, and that any Deceiving or Night Prowling directed towards Dwarven hosts or Undumgi protectors will result in very harsh consequences and you'll not be shielding anyone from them. He says he'll put word out, and you turn your attention to other matters until the faithful begin to trickle in. Retired merchants, battered mercenaries, sailors seeking good solid rock under their feet for a change - all people who have spent a lifetime entrusting themselves to Ranald and are quite ready to instead facilitate the chance-taking of others. One quite convincing card sharp got quite a way into the interview with you having only barely set off a few minor suspicions, until he stopped mid-sentence, listened to the sliver of Ranald's attention that had just turned your way, then apologized and left. By midyear, the Temple begins to fill with those knowingly or unknowingly paying homage to Ranald. Anyone seeking to cheat was very quickly seen through by those that know when the Gambler is suddenly supplanted by the Deceiver. And under the watchful eye of a newly brevetted Lieutenant Snuggles, the cat statue became the perch of choice for Karag Nar's small but growing feline population. --- Thus concludes the work Mathilde performed these past months, but not every waking moment was filled with work. With whom did she spend her free time, this past year? The four with the most votes will be chosen, not counting those locked in. [+] The Wizards of Karak Eight Peaks (locked in) [+] Social interaction initiated by someone else (locked in) [ ] King Belegar, as he scrambles to deal with having very suddenly accomplished his dream. [ ] Gretel, who's apparently spending her newly-earned wealth to make herself at home. [ ] Max, during the few breaks in the silence as the two of you worked on Queekish in the Room of Serenity. [ ] Elder Hluodwica, as the Halflings prepare for their first proper harvest festival in this new home. [ ] Francesco Caravello, proud leader of the Undumgi and possible future Thane. [ ] Oswald Oswaldson, newly-minted Chief Bombardier of the Undumgi. [ ] Soizic, military leader of the Undumgi. [ ] Sir Ruprecht Wulfhart, leader of the frontier town of Ulrikadrin. [ ] Barak Varr, to watch the progress of the canal. [ ] Karak Hirn, to satisfy your curiosity about Prince Ulthar. [ ] Roswita, as she campaigns through Hunger Wood. [ ] Kasmir, to see how he's keeping himself busy in Sylvania. [ ] Anton, to see how his firearm factory is going. [ ] Wilhelmina, to see how she's going when she's not a terrifying financial juggernaut. [ ] Julia, to see what she has gotten up to as Stirland's most experienced spy master. [ ] The Amber College, to see how your donation of Lustrian eggs is going. [ ] Other (write in) - Parts of this turn were originally posted as fragments over the holidays: Part 1 Part 2 Part 3 Part 4 Part 5 - The vote over whether to meet the Ar-Ulric took place as part of Part 4 above. Voting on this matter is closed. - There was also a 'Holiday Opportunity' vote that allowed the thread to decide upon a single province that will heed Belegar's message and seek to align itself with the Dwarves, and the thread voted for the Bretonnian duchy of Carcassonne. - After some thought, I've decided to leave the glimpse inside King Thorgrim's mind and the vote for Dwarf-influenced provinces where they are in the 'canonical' threadmark order. - I'm drawing a blank on better populating the social vote options. As always, suggestions are very welcome. - There will be a one hour voting moratorium.

Turn 25 Social - 2482

Spoiler: Voting results [+] The Wizards of Karak Eight Peaks (locked in) [+] Social interaction initiated by someone else (locked in) [*] King Belegar, as he scrambles to deal with having very suddenly accomplished his dream. [*] Anton, to see how his firearm factory is going. [*] Sir Ruprecht Wulfhart, leader of the frontier town of Ulrikadrin. [*] Emperess Heidi and Mandred for Mandreds First Birthday. "The gates are only opened to allow the High King's army to march to war." A sentence repeated a thousand times by a thousand historians, with only minor changes in phrasing. The gates of Karaz-a-Karak once stood open to all visitors, and that now they only open in times of war is a wonderfully poignant metaphor for the decline of the Karaz Ankor as a whole. All future historians will, however, have to decide for themselves how big an asterisk they will have to place at the end of that sentence. Thorgrim Grudgebearer will be remembered by history as never having the opportunity to become involved in the defence of Karak Eight Peaks against Waaagh Birdmuncha, but none will be able to deny the involvement of Karaz-a-Karak in the rebuilding of the newly-reclaimed Karak. The Gates of Karaz-a-Karak swung open once more, and for the first time in four thousand years they did not do so in solemn silence. Tens of thousands of voices rise in song, and not a song of vengeance and glory, but a song of industry and exploration. Ai Anar Dawi Un An Âlit A Kur... Though each is armed and armoured, for the times are still what they are, the weapon of choice on display is a pick, rather than the perennial favourite of an axe. Wagons do not carry weapons of war, but clever devices of excavation and construction. Those leading the expedition are not Lords or Thanes, but Guildmasters. And nowhere is to be seen the Rune of Grimnir, and instead this expedition courts the favour of Grungni, Valaya, Smednir and Morgrim. Some will equivocate, and say that this Throng's mission is merely an indirect approach to warfare. But what none can deny is that the High King has not sent a Throng to destroy, but an Expedition to create. Khazukan Ankazadit-ha. --- "You never sent to Karaz-a-Karak for help," King Belegar says, his voice low and troubled as he looks over the West Gate, where for months a constant flurry of activity has been working to give it a fighting chance of being able to resist any other Waaaghs that might wander this way. You consider his words for a long moment before replying, his tone and the guilt on his face telling you the entire story. "As you say," you eventually reply, your voice neutral. "If you wish to leave my service, I will give you the strongest of recommendations and-" "Belegar," you interrupt, and his face turns to you. "I am a Grey Wizard. I've kept bigger secrets for lesser reasons. I'm not going anywhere." He exhales, and a tiny amount of the tension seems to go out of him. "Thank you," he says simply. "The others of the Council have already agreed, but they were merely onlookers. I feared-" You smile. "I'll take it as a compliment. My silence is yours. Though I do hope it was expensive." He nods down at the work below. "In just under three weeks, every Dawi of the Karak will be able to return to their chosen profession. Karaz-a-Karak is sending a significant portion of their Guild of Stonemasons, the Guild of Miners, the Guild of Prospectors, the Guild of Metalsmiths, the Guild of Toolmakers, and the Guild of Engineers to labour for Karak Eight Peaks at Karaz-a-Karak's expense for the next three and a half years." You do a quick mental count. That's about how long it's been since the Expedition gained the initial foothold at the Karak. "Was that duration your idea, or his?" "Mine," he says shortly, his voice laced with suppressed anger. You nod, and for a long, quiet moment the two of you stand in silence, watching the work below. You think of the Emperor, of Dragomas and Algard, of Abelhelm and Frederick. "Sacrifice," you say eventually. "All worthy rulers sacrifice their time and effort. Some their lives. A few, even their sanity. But the hardest test is when it is their honour they are called on to sacrifice." "My honour is my life and without it I am nothing," King Belegar says softly. "And yours has taken a few hits because you've had to play politics for the good of the Karak," you say. "But I wouldn't still be here if you were so short on honour that this battering would destroy it." King Belegar shakes his head. "Some say humans are Vornari. Perhaps a furrow in the soil can be smoothed over. But Dwarves are Durazi, and stone does not heal." You give him a flat look, and hold it in silence until he turns to face you, and then you turn your gaze to the ancient gates being restored below. He sighs. "Point made." --- "Right," you say brightly as you accept the mug of ale from Hubert, who's distributing the contents of the keg you keep on your balcony. "I call this august order, to order." "We're august?" Adela asks doubtfully, sipping cautiously at the ale. "We're an order?" Panoramia asks, looking away from the scrutiny she was giving your Grey Tower. "We succeeded," you say simply. "There's pots of glory to go around and don't any of you hesitate before grabbing some for yourself. So yes, we're no mere study group, we're a band of intrepid adventurers and a wonderful symbol of intercollegiate cooperation. And it's retroactive, too." You see exchanged looks and tolerant smiles, and wonder if your ducklings are getting perhaps a little too used to you. "I mean it," you say, your voice firm. "I guarantee you Dragomas was not thinking of Cathayan diplomacy when he walked into the Dark Lands, and if he had been slain there he would have been one example of Journeyman foolishness amongst hundreds. But because he lived, and because of what he accomplished, every step of his journey gets cast in that beneficial light. Every one of you should seize that same benefit for yourselves. You could have pottered around Altdorf doing odd jobs for bored burghers, and instead you risked your lives out here on the edge of civilization." "We barely-" Gretel begins. "No," you say. "Okay, you know what? Wait here." --- Ten minutes later, you return to the balcony with your teaching aid. "This," you say brightly, "is Little Franz, the Cooper. Say hi, Franz." "Hello," the lad says nervously. "Tell the nice Wizards about yourself," you nudge. "Um, I'm from Merfeld, between Hochsleben and Karaz Angazhar. I was doing my apprenticeship under Da when some Axedwarves came through on the way to join the Expedition, and I joined them." "How many battles have you been in, Franz?" "Um, been at seven battles, but I only actually fought at two of them. Me and my friend Big Franz got two Orcs together at the Battle of the Citadel, and I got this," he pulls on the collar of his tunic to reveal a nasty burn covering his upper chest, "at the Battle of Kvinn-Wyr." "Thank you, Franz. Okay, any comments about this fellow's contributions to the Expedition?" You get silence as your answer. Your Ducklings quite clearly see the roadblock you've erected in the path of their self-effacement and look very awkward indeed, while Johann is concealing a smile and Panoramia keeps trying to catch your eye so she can roll hers at you. "No? Nothing?" "It was very brave of you," Adela says firmly. You blink at her exaggeratedly. "Was it? But he only-" "Okay, yes, we get it," Hubert interrupts, looking extremely uncomfortable. "Harder when it's someone else, isn't it? Thank you, Franz. Wolf will show you out. Take a bottle of something from the shelf as a thankyou." Wolf appears at the door a moment later, wagging his tail at Franz, and leads the thoroughly confused lad away. "Point made, I trust? Be at least as kind to yourself as you would be to Little Franz, the Cooper. Each of you fought in a fair few battles, accounted for your share and then some of foes, and risked your life in doing so - and your soul. Every time we reach into the Aethyr might be the time we pull back a fistful of daemons. So don't downplay your accomplishments. Gods know there'll be enough people to do that for you in life." Your ducklings busy themselves with their tankards, and you finally turn your gaze to Panoramia, who sighs and shakes her head and you smile. "With that lesson concluded, let's get on to the meat of things. We won. The decisions must now be made as to where your futures lie. I'm sticking around and I'd quite like to keep all of you, but your futures matter more than my compulsion to collect wizards. So, Johann?" "I'm going to at least stick around long enough to wrap up our studies," he says. "Thought so. Maximilian?" He shrugs. "Dwarven apprenticeships aren't known for brevity. I'm not going anywhere." "Panoramia?" "I'm very happy working with Halflings, and there's a lot more work here than the Moot." "Adela?" You turn your attention to her, a little worried you're about to lose some of your Ducklings. "I'm not sure," she admits. "The work with the Engineers has been intriguing, but I don't like being this far from my family." "I understand." In theory, anyway. "If there's anything I can do to help, let me know. Hubert?" He looks uncomfortable. "I don't know yet. Things are complicated." "Ulrican things?" He nods. "Want to talk about it later?" Another nod. "Okay. Gretel?" She turns to look at the Citadel far below, one tower of which is hers for the next 98 years. "I'm staying," she says firmly. "Is your Order okay with that?" "Why wouldn't it be?" she asks, frowning. "Oh, right. They're not like yours. As long as I follow the Articles and pay my Tithe, it's my business where I live and what I do." "That's alright, then," you say lightly, quelling the pang of envy. "How about Magister exams? I know Panoramia's putting hers off until the fields are in a good place, but the rest of you..." "Not yet," Maximilian says. "Once I'm a little further, I'll start working on mixing Gold Magic with Dwarven blacksmithing techniques, and once that's in a solid place I'll present that as my Masterpiece." "My work with the Engineers seems promising," Adela says. "I think there's a Masterpiece somewhere in applications of using Flashcook in steam mechanisms." Hubert shrugs. "The Celestial Order doesn't value swordplay very highly," he says, trying and failing to keep dissatisfaction out of his voice. "I don't know what my Masterpiece could be." You turn to Gretel, who shrugs too. "Something will turn up," she says vaguely. "What about you?" Adela says. "Already a Magister," you say with a smile. "That's why I get to boss you guys around." "No, when will you go for Lady Magister? Surely that," she waves a hand towards the Eye of Gazul, "qualifies as a Grandmasterpiece." "Or the dead Waaagh," Gretel says. "Hard to present, though. Ship a cartload of ash to Altdorf?" "It's a little more complicated at the Lord Wizard level," you say with a smile, "though I appreciate your faith in me. Perhaps I'll put my name forward in the next few years." --- Watching someone ride a Shadowsteed for the first time is one of the finest entertainments you've ever encountered, but Hubert quickly gets a grasp of it, having been trained for the saddle in his youth, and likely been destined for a Knightly Order before magic intervened. You resist the urge to ride literal circles around him with your much stronger grasp of the spell, and instead ride at a relatively sedate pace alongside him. "Okay," you say. "Spit it out. Someone's got to tell me what's with the Ulrican drama so it may as well be you." "I'm not privy to the exact nature of the disagreement between the Winter Wolves and-" "I can literally see your lies. Stop dancing around the topic and skip right to the part where you tell me what the hell is going on. I'm about to meet with a Grand Master and I've got a meeting with the Ar-Ulric next month, and I'm as ignorant as the first time I heard about Nordland and Middenland griping at each other. If I have to blow my aura of mysterious smugness by walking into these blind I'm not going to be happy." He's silent for a long moment. "Okay," he finally says. "I only know the barest details-" "That's all I need, I can fake the rest." "Fine. Do you know of the Elves of Laurelorn?" You shrug. "Vaguely. Less crazy than Athel Loren and less smug than Ulthuan, so they don't really come up much. Why?" "They've converted to the worship of Ulric." The sound of phantasmal hoofbeats dominates for a long moment. "Bullshit," you eventually say. Hubert sighs. "So many believe. Including the Winter Wolves." "But the Ar-Ulric says otherwise?" "Yes. And the Ar-Ulric..." The word 'supposedly' is very loudly not spoken. "Speaks for Ulric." You rack your memory as best you can. "They've always claimed everything west of the Salz. The disappearances in Nordland, they've been enforcing their claims. And Middenland is supporting them." "Which is a straightforward decision if they are coreligionists," Hubert says miserably. "But if one doubts their conversion..." You exhale. "Fuck." Hubert nods. "This is why you're conflicted?" "My family asked me to pass on what information I could," he admits. "I would like to prove to them I serve Ulric. But the more time I spend at Ulrikadrin, the more I wonder if they are His truer servants." You nod in understanding, and feel very glad that the God you serve doesn't feel the need for this type of infuriating aloofness. --- Hubert disappears into the growing community of Ulrikadrin to spend some time with his fellow Ulricans, and you take a deep breath as you approach the Temple of Ulric that is the current headquarters of the Winter Wolves. During your last meeting with Sir Ruprecht Wulfhart he seemed quite nervous about you, but that was on neutral ground when his order was still rootless. Now, his order has won a home, been chosen as the leaders of that home, and established a treaty with Karak Eight Peaks, and on top of that this meeting will take place in his God's church. You doubt he'll still be on the back foot. You're kept waiting for a few minutes in the hall of the Temple of Ulric, and find yourself facing the flame on the altar, which had been quite laboriously and carefully carried all the way from the Sacred Flame of Ulric at Middenheim, which the Winter Wolves were once charged with guarding. It is said that the Sacred Flame will not harm a true follower of Ulric, and history tells of Magnus the Pious striding into the flame unharmed to win an alliance with the Ulricans. In modern times, this practice is discouraged, which strikes you as inconvenient. Having someone able to prove they hold Ulric's stamp of approval would simplify matters a great deal. You take the opportunity to give the flame careful scrutiny under Magesight, and though at first you think it's entirely mundane, the fact that you feel colder the closer you get to it and that Wolf has perked up and is staring confusedly through your eyes definitely indicates that something is up. "It's tempting," comes the cultivated accent of Middenland nobility behind you, and you turn to see Sir Ruprecht approaching. "It was part of the watch on the flame to keep pilgrims from testing themselves." "Any of them pass?" "Not in my lifetime," he says. "Which goes a long way to tempering temptation. Perhaps the truly faithful does not test his God." He salutes and you return it, which neatly sidesteps the question of rank - you speak instead as two warriors of the Empire. "Ulrikadrin seems to be flourishing," you say, doing your best to start off with a light topic before you get into the matter of religious strife. "Largely because of the amount of Dwarven industry," he says wryly. "I must admit we did not expect to be so tied into the Karak's economy, but it has been very much to our benefit, and King Belegar is honourable. I might have preferred we live simpler lives as woodcutters and hunters, but though all here revere Ulric, most of my people have not sworn their lives to him, and they are accustomed to the trappings of civilization." "I've heard of worse compromises," you agree. "How goes the planning for your Keep?" He sighs, and then laughs. "I've never seen so many grown men getting so much enjoyment out of so many arguments. We've decided on a peak close to the mouth of the valley - the wolves are most comfortable above the snowline, after all - but the details elude us. We've yet to imagine anything that King Belegar's architects haven't said they could manage. Some want a fortress that could stand against any foe, others want a grand temple to rival Middenheim, a third group wants to carve out a high valley for the wolves to run free in, and a fourth wants a series of bridges and tunnels to allow us to travel freely throughout these mountains. It could be that a decision will never be reached within my lifetime, but there is charm in living amongst our people." As smooth a segue as you're likely to get. "Speaking of Middenheim," you begin, and Sir Ruprecht tenses up. "The Ar-Ulric has asked to see me." "Ah," he says. "And you believe it to be to do with us." "It seems likely. I simply want to know where you stand." "I could say the same," he replies softly, his eyes fixed on you. "I stand with King Belegar," you reply simply. "My service to him has the stamp of approval of the Emperor himself." He said he'd heard good things. That counts, right? "You are King Belegar's ally, just as the Empire is his ally." He mulls that over for a time. "That does simplify matters," he finally says. "Very well. Our official position is that we are independent to the Empire's Cult of Ulric, but not opposed to it. We could not in good conscience stay and serve the Ar-Ulric, but nor could we outright oppose him, so we left. We will fight to remain independent if we must, but otherwise we do not wish to raise our swords against any sons of the Empire." You consider that, and then nod. "That simplifies matters too," you say. "Would you want an official relationship with the Empire?" "We would spill blood to defend it," he says firmly. "But politically, it would be simplest for everyone if we did so through our alliance with King Belegar, and his with the Empire." "Keep it unofficial. Got it. I'll have a few words in a few ears." He exhales. "Thank you. Between you and Hubert, several amongst us have been made to re-examine our feelings about Wizards." You pause, and smile sweetly. "How kind of you to say. Between you and Hubert, I may be led to re-examine mine about Ulricans." He smiles, then falters and begins to frown, but you've already turned away and started to leave before he can digest that. --- "Why," you ask with a frown, "does it have bubbles in it?" "No idea," Anton says happily, considering his own glass of wine. "It does add a bit of festiveness to it, though. Just make sure to stick to the stuff in Dwarven-glass bottles, otherwise they have a tendency to explode." "Not usefully," gripes Reinhild Gerber, the designer of the firearm this factory is dedicated to, who has become a very close but entirely platonic friend of Anton's since you were last here. The room is filled with Stirland notables, some of which you've recognized from your time as Spymistress and several of whom you've exchanged some friendly words with so far. Being a celebration of a long-range firearm, the party could not take place in the late evening as is typical for soirees, but instead in the early afternoon. This hasn't stopped anyone from indulging in the finest wines Blutdorf has to offer as they mill about in the courtyard of Anton's castle. The air buzzes with surprisingly intense conversation, as those present take advantage of one of the few occasions nobles and burghers can mingle without it being seen as gauche to get down to some serious business. You occasionally catch a glimpse of Wilhelmina as she flits through the crowd like a shark on the prowl, no doubt making sure that her dominance of Stirlandian trade continues to grow. For your part, you did a single lap of the crowd for politeness' sake and have now taken residence at Anton's side, leaving Wolf to socialize in your place. Having started at smarter than a typical wolf and then gaining the ability to call upon your own mental capacity just as you can his, he's astonishingly successful at convincing each and every person he encounters to feed him tidbits from the buffet tables. You've turned from your examination of the Bretonnian bubble-wine to a more serious examination of the rifle in front of you, one of many scattered throughout the party. The revolving mechanism that an early prototype you saw had is at first glance removed, but you quickly realize it's instead been turned sideways. Instead of relying on the multiple barrels like a repeater handgun or the multiple chambers of a Dwarven revolver, the trigger guard revolves forwards and then back to deliver powder and shot into the barrel in a single set of movements while also recocking the gun. If it works the way that Reinhild claims, the rate of fire should be quite astonishing, but from the look of it so too is the level of intricacy required. "The 'Stirland Repeater'," you say thoughtfully. "How expensive did the finished model end up being?" you ask, and catch the look that Anton and Reinhild exchange. "More than we'd hoped," Anton admits. "Material and labour, eighty crowns." You wince. "That's more than a handgun costs to the buyer." "Sure," Reinhild says quickly, "we'll not be replacing the handgun at a stroke. But the jump in price and maintenance required is lesser than the jump when the Empire first went from crossbows to handguns, and it delivers a greater increase in firepower." "Oh?" you ask neutrally. "One shot every two seconds, with a fifteen-round magazine." You look back down at the rifle, and turn the trigger guard experimentally. "Reload time?" "Fifteen seconds." You raise your eyebrows as you calculate that. "Twenty rounds a minute. It can maintain that?" "In trials, eight out of ten can manage ten minutes of sustained fire." "Impressive. But the cost - has the Countess been told?" Anton nods. "I worked out the details with Gustav and Wilhelmina. The whole crossbow thing sat badly with a lot of people - I mean, as you know, right? And now she'll let herself be 'convinced' to reverse that. Instead of a unified force of handgunners, there'll be an elite core with Stirland Repeaters and the rest will have crossbows. Same price, a higher weight of fire, less troubles with the traditionalists." "And all of it comes out of Blutdorf," you say thoughtfully, and Anton smiles. "Can I take this one?" "Of course," Anton says. "Wanting to add it to your arsenal?" "I'm happy with my revolvers, but I might show it around Altdorf while I'm there." --- Your pigeonhole at the College has been accumulating mail faster than you're accustomed to recently, but most of it is entirely expected, consisting of polite thankyous for your lectures, requests for clarification on one point or another, and notifications that you're being cited in one paper or another. But one note takes you by surprise, both at the title of the sender and the careful, blocky script of the message it contains. You smile, note the date, and slightly rearrange your schedule. The next day sees you an hour's ride east of Altdorf, where the Knights of Taal's Fury are encamped. If asked they'd claim to have no chapterhouse but the wild, but the wild does not provide halberds, armour, or heraldry, and when not pursuing the enemies of the Empire they return to this place to rearm, rearmour, reconsecrate their banners, and re-establish contact with the civilization they fight to protect. Some are dedicated enough to Taal that they erect their tents inside the palisade, but most take the opportunity to remember what it's like to sleep under a proper roof, on a proper bed. As not only a Grey Wizard, but one that has fought alongside the Knights in the past, you're welcomed into the camp without trouble and find your way through it towards your hosts: Magisters Esbern and Seija, who are more embarrassed to have been caught inhabiting one of the chapterhouse's bedrooms than they are at the state of relative undress you find them in. You politely refrain from commenting as you wait for them to dress, and the three of you go for a walk along the Talabec, with Wolf and two demigryphs for company. "The Knights are a convincing sponsor," Esbern chatters as you walk. "And our new partners," he nods at the demigryphs, who are romping ahead with Wolf, "served as Masterpieces, and the Expedition as our Deeds. So we both reached Magister about six months after we returned to the Empire." "Didn't change much," Seija says with a shrug. "Got full access to spells, which is nice, but apart from that," Esbern shrugs. "Civilization things. Ranks, titles, tithes... rather pointless. Though that might just be the Ghur talking." "Ghur has a point," you say with a smile. "Apart from that, we've been sticking with the Knights. They see as religious obligation what comes naturally to us, so it usually works out. Mostly been in Ostland, dealing with Norscans from the north and those- what did they call them?" "Yhetees." "Yhetees from the east. Dragon got most of them, but the rest scattered and a lot of them ended up in Ostland, and we had to stamp them out before they made it to the Middle Mountains. The Knights collected the claws for us, and figuring out what they're good for should keep us busy for a while. Don't usually see their kind this far west, so there's not been much study on them. And then we all came back here to see where we'd be needed next, and since you're in and out of Altdorf lately, we thought we'd ask you to visit. We were curious how the We turned out." "And Wolf," Seija says. "And Wolf," Esbern says, smiling over at the frolicking puppy and kittybirds. "The We are..." you search for the words. "Gradually civilizing themselves. They and the Dwarves have gotten accustomed to each other and their silk is rather valuable, so once they've finished educating themselves they'll be free to choose whether they want to continue as hunters or transition into crafters." "I'm surprised the Dwarves allowed them that choice," Esbern says. "As for Wolf, leaps and bounds," you say, smiling as you watch him. "We've developed Link of Psyche, so he's as smart as I am when he puts the effort in, and he's wise enough not to bother most of the time so he can leave the work to me and go off and play with Johann's pups. Been meaning to finally teach him Lingua one of these days." "Johann has dogs?" Seija says. "Gold Johann? Smiles a lot? Metal from the neck down?" Esbern continues. "Sort of. Wolf-rats. We found a litter and Johann decided to raise them and see what happens, and it turned out better than expected." "Being a feral monster is a bad survival strategy," Esbern says with a nod. "Very few creatures are born that way. Most have to be made that way." "Which is a field the Skaven excel in," you say with a sigh. You spend most of the day with Esbern and Seija, and apart from having to order Wolf to jump into the Talabec to wash off the scraps and splatter of whatever it is he and the demigryphs found, slaughtered and ate, it's a very pleasant time indeed. --- The Reiksguard gave the Stirland Repeater a great deal of examination and fired off a good couple of magazines before they were willing to admit it wasn't a convoluted assassination attempt - perhaps they remember the little green tokens - but they did finally agree to pass it on along with your message about the official and unofficial relationships desired by Ulrikadrin. Then you were turned over to an entirely different set of Reiksguard dedicated to the protection of the heir to the Empire, but these ones were entirely under the sway of the Empress and merely paused to give pats to Wolf before waving you into the Empress' wing of the palace. Empress Heidi has had ample time and opportunity to solidify her grasp over the population of the palace, and nobody bats an eye at you once more appearing as the preparations for Mandred's first birthday are underway. Ladies in waiting bring drinks and biscuits, and the two of you chatter about current events while they see to things, and smile at Wolf as he snuffles inquisitively at the happily gurgling future Emperor. "So," Heidi says as the last of the crowd of helpers finally leaves. "Did you really steal half the taxbase of Stirland?" "It was only a third, and we only rented it," you say primly. She chuckles. "I wouldn't even have heard of that if I hadn't been making a nuisance of myself to the Steward. It's keeping out of center stage nicely, and with you half a continent away you'll be able to easily sidestep any blowback even if things go wrong." "I think you're underestimating the kind of blowback the Grey Order is capable of. But nothing should go wrong. It's an entirely legitimate trading company that knows its interests are aligned with that of the Empire." "Fine, keep whatever caper you have planned to yourself," she says, waving a hand airily. "What brings you to Altdorf, anyway?" "I am Mandred's secret godmother," you remind her. "Don't worry, your position is secure. Even if I was swarming with other mutual friends of our mutual friend, you're the sort of person I want in Mandred's corner in the decades to come." "It's not that. I kind of feel like..." You hum, and lean back in thought. "Well, it's the old story, isn't it? A long-wished-for child of a King - well, an Emperor - and in the absence of six good fairies, since the closest thing we have is the Asrai and they're no good at all, it feels like my responsibility to check in, see he's got a good start in life." "Beauty, wit, grace? That sort of thing?" She looks to Mandred, who is giggling as he pulls on Wolf's tongue. "Bit early for dance and song." "I don't know if I can gift him intangible concepts," you say with a smile, "though, ironically, I could gift him with intangibility itself. Once he's grown up I might end up teaching him or arming him or guarding him or something, but for now my gift is rather more modest." From a pocket, you produce a small, carved piece of wood, and hand it over to Heidi. "A little horse," she says, with slightly unsure cheer. "Imprint," you say in Lingua Praestantia, and a sliver of Ulgu writhes in confirmation. "Neigh at it." She gives you a flat look, then turns back to the horse. "Neigh," she says, and the horse replies with a soft but convincing whinny that brings a smile to your face. "It will only respond to you or Mandred," you assure her, "and it's completely safe, there's less magic in it than a dandelion." Heidi stares thoughtfully at the horse, and you can faintly feel the reflected radiance of divine attention turning her way. "Do you have a chisel?" she asks, and you summon one. "Carve your Order's sigil onto it, there's a possibility of an irritating misunderstanding about this in six months that it would neatly bypass." You raise an eyebrow at her, then shrug to yourself and obey. Heidi then turns the toy over to Mandred, and though she spends quite some time trying and failing to convince him to make a noise approximating to 'neigh', Mandred's happy gnawing of the horse convinces you that he likes his gift anyway. - No vote. Next update will be the meeting with the Ar-Ulric. - The Stirland Repeater is based on the IRL Kalthoff Repeater, which was made in the 1650s. - Part of this update was originally posted here.

A Meeting in Middenheim 1

It is well known that Ulric does not approve of magic, but it is equally true that Ulric does not approve of gunpowder, and yet Middenheim bristles with cannon. In the South of the Empire, Ulric is often seen as a primitive and backwards God, but mainstream Ulrican belief is that Ulric's first commandment is survival. All His other virtues - self-reliance, bravery, honour, honesty - are second to surviving the war and weathering the Winter. So apart from a few extremists in the woods, the Cult of Ulric is capable of negotiation, compromise, and coexistence. Despite Algard's concern, the Ar-Ulric is no more hostile to the Colleges of Magic than he is to the Gunnery School of Nuln. You remind yourself of this as you approach Middenheim, the very heart of the Ar-Ulric's power. You've had a fair bit of experience with mountain fortresses in your career, from Castle Drakenhof which was built atop a mountain, to the various Karaks you've visited that are built within them. In contrast to all of them, Middenheim is built into the mountain of Ulricsburg to the extent that the two names are interchangeable, with towers and crenellations stretching far into the sky until they abruptly cut off at the flattened peak. Legend has it that Taal gifted the mountain to Ulric, who hammered the top of it flat with His fist for reasons known only to Him. He then lead the Teutogens to it, who built their city in it (with no small amount of assistance from a neighbouring Dwarven clan) and discovered on the flattened peak a still-burning fire caused by Ulric's fist, which supposedly continues to burn to this day as the Sacred Flame of Ulric. You make your winding way upwards, slightly reassured that most of the looks you get are admiring ones directed at Wolf, rather than distrustful ones directed at yourself. You pay a brief visit to Lady Magister Stanisława Skłodowicz of the Gold Order, the High Wizard of Middenheim, both out of politeness and to make your visit official and visible. She feigns interest in your adventures among the Dwarves, and you feign interest in her latest concoctions, decoctions and recoctions in her search for the Universal Solvent. Etiquette properly assuaged, you bid her farewell and climb the final stretch to the very peak. Being the only horizontal part of the city in the open air, every part of the peak of Ulricsburg not dominated by the Great Temple of Ulric or the Graf's Middenpalaz is in great demand, and densely-packed buildings stretch even higher into the thinning air. When you finally emerge from the claustrophobic streets of the most cramped noble district you've ever encountered, you finally set eyes on the Great Temple, a vast structure made of bare stone and a formidable fortification in its own right, the only decoration being a wolf's head carved above the main entrance. Ulrican services are an every-now-and-then affair, rather than taking place every Festag like Sigmarite ones, but many Ulricans regularly consult with their priest for advice over personal matters and self-improvement. Because of this there's a constant flow in and out of the great entrance that you join, and as you do you carefully avoid making eye contact with the White Wolves standing guard. Your understanding is that the Winter Wolves were a sort of sect or sub-order within the White Wolves, consisting of those who had taken a Giant Wolf as a mount-slash-partner, never quite given official recognition but long enshrined in unofficial tradition. They formed the core of the not-quite-a-schism against the leadership of the Cult of Ulric, and took the name with them when they left. Very obviously a rebuke, but as no such organization officially existed, it was not quite a rebellion. A line that Sir Ruprecht has been very careful to stay on the right side of. You have a quiet word with the first priestly-looking fellow you cross paths with, who hurries ahead to pass on word as you emerge into the courtyard, where only the pulpit and the Sacred Flame itself mark this as the gathering place for the faithful, who must stand exposed to the elements instead of sitting under a roof when they hear the word of their God. It's much easier to avoid the eye of the White Wolves here because the Sacred Flame captures your attention at once, and not just because of it somehow radiating mundane heat and Divine cold at the same time. This was a point where history was made, the Empire was saved, and the very existence of the Colleges was made possible. 179 years ago, a time when Sigmarites and Ulricans were denouncing each other as heretics and Chaos cultists, Magnus of Nuln was fresh from his victory over the Tzeentchian Magi and seeking an alliance with Middenheim to fight against the Everchosen Asavar Kul. He disguised himself and slipped into Middenheim and this Temple, where Ar-Ulric Kriestov was in the middle of denouncing him specifically. Magnus threw off his disguise, said 'if I am a blasphemer, then the Fire of Ulric will surely consume me,' and walked into the Sacred Flame and stood there unharmed as he stared down the Ar-Ulric. In the immediate term it meant an alliance with Middenheim, but after the victory against the Everchosen and his being crowned Emperor, him having stood unharmed in the Sacred Flame of Ulric meant that he could do what was then unthinkable - legalize magic. "Dame and Magister Weber," comes a voice that is not quite booming, but contains the indication that booming is a possibility, and you turn to face the approaching figure. As you take him in, you also note that filing discreetly into the courtyard is an even score of White Wolves, reinforcing the handful of attendants that the Sacred Flame always has. You bow, and the figure returns it with a very slight bend at the waist that would be a deadly insult from an equal but is quite welcoming from an Elector of the Empire, and as he turns his attention to Wolf you take the opportunity to size up the Ar-Ulric. He is Ar-Ulric Carl Valgeir, a wiry and greying man in his forties who is reputed to be as politically wily as he is pious. His family has deep ties to some of the most influential noble families in Middenland, and according to information passed along by the Grey College, he has an extremely complicated relationship with Graf Boris X Todbringer, the Elector Count of Middenland, who in the internal matters of Middenland is his biggest rival, but in external matters of the Empire is his closest ally. The touch of the Divine is obvious on him, though you can't tell if it is him personally or the regalia of his office: the Hammer-Axe of Skoll on his belt, and the Wolfplate visible under his robes. "Interesting," he says at last, turning his gaze from the cocked head of a slightly uncomfortable Wolf. "All wolves are born of Ulric, but not all die of Ulric. This is perhaps the least bad reason for that, amongst a great many very bad reasons. Does he retain the nature of a wolf?" "When it suits him," you reply cautiously. He whistles, and after a few moments a side door swings open and another wolf stands framed in the doorway, before being knocked into the courtyard by two additional and equally inquisitive wolves who didn't stop. The first wolf turns and throws itself at one of the other two, and the nearest White Wolves edge away as the three devolve into a yipping and biting tumult that if it weren't for being able to borrow Wolf's instincts, you'd think was a fight to the death. Wolf cautiously advances, and the disagreement comes to a halt as he nears, and there's a few tense moments before they relax slightly and then it's a matter of a great deal of sniffing and licking of teeth. "Very well," he says. "Let us speak as one faithful to another." "As you say," is your very careful reply, and the Ar-Ulric purses his lips and closes his eyes for a moment. "I wish to speak first of those that have left the pack," he says at last, turning to look at the Sacred Flame. You mirror his turning, though you keep looking sideways at him. "I cannot speak for them, but I have worked with them and spoken with their leader." "He always was headstrong," he grumbles. "But I might have done similar, when I was his age. Tell him that it is not in doubt that he and his continue to serve Ulric." Externally, you nod in assent, and murmur "I will pass on your words." Internally, your mind whirs. This is far too mild a response to someone flirting with schism. No matter his theological beliefs, the politician in him must recognize the precedent he's failing to punish here, that he's acknowledging that one can serve Ulric while splitting off from the Cult of Ulric. There must be... Oh. Oh. But why wouldn't Algard already know? ...well, how could he know? A lot of people know what you know - everyone in Karak Eight Peaks, and then some - which is why you never thought to pass it on. But none are part of the intelligence apparatus, are they? You keep the bland look on your face as you pen a mental report to Algard and the Ar-Ulric changes the subject. "Second of all," he says, "have you heard of the recent converts to Ulric?" "The Eonir," you confirm. "Thank Ulric, someone that doesn't say 'Wood Elf'. I've spent more time than I like educating my congregation on the difference between our new allies and those infernal tree cultists in Bretonnia. As the politics are messy right now, they've asked me to set up a meeting rather than go through official channels." "With who?" you ask, frowning. Surely not the Dwarves? "With yourself." "Very well," you say evenly. Keeping a bland look on your face while you internally process your shock is Apprentice-level stuff for Grey Wizards. "When would be agreeable?" "Now suits them," he says. "They're in the Garten. They say you'll be able to find your way in. Leave your companion here, they get stroppy about the small fluffy things being chased." --- Known to locals as the Garten, the Great Park of Middenheim is a sprawling piece of artificial nature in varying gradients, from the carefully monitored precision of the orchards and hothouses to the artfully wild-looking glade that is only slightly spoiled by scattered benches, topiaries and gazebos. Your Magesight instantly spots what you're looking for, and though magically it's a very neat piece of work, you suspect that it won't be long before a groundskeeper with a theodolite spots something amiss and the Ducal Arborist starts raising a fuss at a portion of the Park having been folded neatly out of the mundane dimensions. Unlike the defences of the Colleges, no attempt has been made to obscure the nature of these magics and you're quickly able to deduce the right trees to walk between, and you find yourself in a fold of tamed forest that you suspect would make Panoramia's jaw drop. Every tree is lush and green and evenly spaced from its neighbours without any pattern in their layout being obvious, the foliage abounds with twittering birds and chattering critters, and from no apparent direction, the sound of a brook burbling cheerily underscores the scene. It is, you suspect, very deliberately designed to be what one might imagine if asked to picture a Wood Elf that was the complete opposite of the Asrai. Sitting in a low tree fork and smiling mischievously at the hummingbird investigating the flower in her hair is an Elf, and you very quickly have some uncharitable ideas as to how this unorthodox alliance might have been possible, as the neckline of her light green dress dips as low as the side slits climb high, and her bare feet don't so much hint as they do shout that the dress could be the only garment upon her person. But even as your mundane senses pass judgement, your magical senses tell a very different story - at first you thought her invisible to them, but then you realized that the physical being before you is merely the anchorpoint of a soul that fills the dimensional pocket more thoroughly than the air around you, interwoven in every tree and beast and blade of grass, and the only place she isn't is in a polite distance around your person. "I," she says, her gaze turning to you, "am Vicereine Cadaeth of what you may know as Oldenlitz, Ambassador to Middenheim on behalf of the Eonir and of Laurelorn."

076.M42 Interlude: Detached Debauchery

076.M42 Interlude: Detached Debauchery

The planet Cadia, the Cadian System, the Cadian Sector, the Cadian Gate. A place of constant vigilance, continual warfare, blood, death and pain. Sagas could be written about the many heroes and villains who had fought and died there, for so very many of them had in fact died during the 13th Black Crusade. There had been death on a scale for almost a century that beggared belief for the small-minded. But for those who had fought in a realm without time and where the laws of space and reality were malleable, it was familiar. For the more intelligent members of the Imperium, who comprehended that their stellar nation had been fighting in one way or another since its very founding, it was grimly accepted. To the war-bred, war-loving orks, it was one of the greatest fulfilments of their every impulse, with a great variety of strong opponents to fight and kill. To the myriad Necrons afflicted by the dying curse of a C'tan, it was a place to enact their foul desires for flesh and blood, to drape and try to consume. To the tyranids, it was a significant amount of biomass as well as a place to analyze threats, and that was all that mattered.

To the Kabals of Commorragh, it was a harvesting ground like no other.

In such dire times, an entire sixth of the Dark City consumed by the energies of the Warp and the servants of Slaanesh invading, the need for slaves was greater than ever. For the usage of the Haemonculi Covens, for torture and sustenance for the citizenry, for amusement and entertainment in the arenas to ensure that Vect was able to provide the image of control and business as usual. Years of hard warfare and effort had pushed the slaves of Chaos back to the ruins of the Gate of Khaine, but the fighting had never actually ceased. It did not help that an entire satellite realm had been consumed by the Mandrakes and their own twisted ascension, nor that the strange and disturbing 'Ynnari' had caused another major Dysjunction prior to their departure. The sheer anarchy of the fighting against the daemons and their servants had allowed the one called Yvraine time and ability to escape with a significant amount of followers and ships, but already Vect had organized multiple hunting groups to find and kill them for their temerity. There were even rumors that another incursion had been attempted through the Gate by other forces but had been thrown back by none other than Vect himself, but only Vect himself knew whatever it was he had so wounded and the greatest of the Dark Eldar would not speak of the matter. Amidst said distractions of Slanneshi, Ynnari, Mandrake, and other entities, there was also the frankly audacious sabotage on the part of their pathetic cousins of the Craftworlds, collapsing a vast number of the Webway's portals leading to the Dark City, requiring frustrating effort to construct a bevy of new portals that could still force connections to realspace.

Regardless, matters had finally reached an acceptable equilibrium, and yet to fuel it the Dark City required ever more to feed upon to sustain itself.

The Cadian Sector, thankfully, provided all that the Kabals could want and more, though some of the lesser Kabals did seek out slightly less dangerous hunting grounds. The greater Kabals, on the other hand, saw it for what it was.

A challenge.

A way to test the skills, to ride the line between life and death like never before, all in the search of prestige and glory, spoils in flesh and soul and goods.

What an array of targets to test the skills!

Necrons, the old foe, for those who wished to prove that they could fight just as well or even better than the Dominion of the ancient days long past. Or, for certain Dark Eldar, a chance to rewrite past failures into current victories, exacting old vengeances upon the Necrons despite them being so consumed by the Flayers Curse that they could not possibly respond precisely how they wished. Some enterprising and perhaps foolish younger Dark Eldar captured a handful and dared to bring them to Commorragh. It would take much work to prevent their recall systems from working, or so it was thought, and yet there were more than a few Wych Cults who were joyous for the opportunity to battle against the ancient enemy in the arena. Others simply took the time and joy to fire upon their ships, re-enacting old battles in the void and blowing the accursed ships to pieces beyond regeneration.

Greenskins, ever popular with the Wyches, and able to withstand frankly incredible amounts of pain. Always a good product in the Dark City for those wishing for quantity if not quality. Which wasn't to say that the pain of orks was particularly sour, but rather that it was somewhat bland. They could not season their cries with fear without a rather extensive amount of effort, and if the day was close to ending and the grasp of She Who Thirsts was particularly strong that day it behooved the average Dark Eldar to simply purchase something that could produce a heaping amount of pain without expiring as quickly as a more fragile human might. That there were some of the greatest of their kind around was only another spice for the feast, and there were rumors that none other than Hesperax herself was making noise about finding and killing the so-called Beast of Armageddon in single combat.

Tyranids, unlike necrons or orks, were far less amusing. They were a nuisance, but a dangerous one. The Hive Mind had, once or twice, managed to infiltrate the Webway, but no sect of Eldar would accept such a thing. The Hive Mind did not leave behind terrified survivors to be captured and enslaved. All it did was consume and cleanse the galaxy of prey and targets, and this was simply infuriating. Tyranids were not worth capture, for even a minor bio-form had the potential to bring a spore into the Dark City and cause further infections. Given the fighting still ongoing any disruptions to the effort at containing the forces of Chaos within Commorragh such problems were unacceptable. At the same time, the most desperate or daring Dark Eldar were willing to make an attempt at capturing particularly interesting and dangerous tyranids, for the Haemonculi were more than a little interested in experiments that could be done with such material. None had taken up the standing offer to try and transport an entire Hive Ship to Commorragh, however, as Vect had made a clear announcement that any attempt at such foolishness would result in total extermination of the Haemonculi Coven and Kabal in question beyond any chance of recovery.

Humans, such valuable subjects, were far more favored than the tyranids. For torture, for experimentation, for entertainment. The fighters being deployed in the Cadian Gate were some of the best that the pathetic humans had, and the Wych Cults were quite pleased with those that could be taken away. Even better with the flood of ships traveling this way and that. The sigils that they wore, the Gods that they worshipped, it didn't matter to the Dark City, it needed souls to drain of vitality and pain to sup upon. Especially the Sororitas and Astartes, if only because it was that much more orgasmic to break them down and shatter their mistaken assumptions about the place of humanity in the galaxy. Ten thousand years of thinking of themselves at the top, when in truth they were lower than the boot! But they would learn. They all would learn.

Even better were these 'New Men' that the brutish simpleton that called himself the Despoiler had unleashed. In the utter chaos of the Cadian Sector, if a few dozen ships went missing, what did it matter? They had brought more than a billion to the field in the first day, apparently sourced from worlds across the Imperium and beyond, from places that the Inquisition had not been able to find and that the infamous Fabius Bile had not been able to hide. The latter fact was especially amusing. The only human to ever be taken into one of the Covens not as a subject, but as a student and member. Many of the Haemonculi were incredibly taken with dissecting and altering the creatures that were brought to them, for depending on which of the Dark Gods they had ended up indoctrinated by, there were a variety of mutations and differences. Which was building already on the various differences based on environment and which batch of experiments that Fabius had finished with throughout the years.

So many targets, so many holds filled and flush with spoils, all for the wealth and glory of the Kabals of Commorragh. If it happened to distress and infuriate the humans all the more, so much the better. If the Despoiler could not deploy a group of New Men or trained regiments of cultists because their ships had been taken in transit, resulting in the Imperium scoring several minor victories on his northern flank, so be it. If an entire company of space marines, two regiments of Imperial Guard, and a thousand Sisters of Battle never reached their deployment zone, ensuring that an influx of daemons was capable of overrunning a fifteen square mile area of Imperial territory – and causing thousands upon thousands of fatalities – then so be it. If a battlegroup fresh from a Dark Mechanicus Forge World's shipyards did not arrive in accordance with the Daemon Primarch Perturabo's timetables, so be it, his bitter wrath and rage as his precise plans were upended time and again were so powerfully ambient through the Warp that certain extreme seekers of sensation would dance their ships close by to savor it before heading elsewhere. The monstrous cybernetic creations would win favor in the arena to those they were sold to, the spoils sold off to other Covens, the slaves taken even worse fates than what the forces of Chaos had imagined. What did the Dark Eldar care for any of how any other felt? The brutes and barbarians and maddened foes would play at war, and the Dark Eldar would feast as they wished. Such was the true way of things. Millions upon millions of souls. All to be tortured. All to suffer. All for the pleasure of the universe's true masters.

And so the 13th Black Crusade ground on.

Turn 28: A Breath Choked By Ash (Part Five)

Spoiler: Truth and Task

[] Plan: Truth and Task
-[] Tell the Grey Knights about the Ritual of Binding that Chapter Master and Chief Librarian Moriah devised which specifically targets Ulkair. Reaction of the Grey Knights unknown.
-[] Subsector Focus
--[] Aurelia
---[] Grey Knights not assigned to Meridian, Adeptus Mechanicus, Exalted Court of House Myrlen; House Merlyn, Gabriel Angelos + Honor Guard, Apollo Diomedes, Justinius Probalis, Blood Raven's 1st Company
--[] Meridian
---[] 10 Grey Knights, Inquisitor's Forces, House Legrin, Scarlet Lions 3rd Company, Hannibal Palrun, Martellus Ravias, Blood Raven's 3rd Company
--[] Calderis
---[] House Aerian, Scarlet Lions 2nd Company, Nero Gracchus, Blood Raven's 4th Company
--[] Typhon
---[] House Baroon, Blood Raven's 2nd Company
--[] Cyrene
---[] Xerult, Blood Raven's 5th Company
--[] Other
---[] Spread 10th Company equally amongst the theaters, leadership to Meridian, fleet to Cyrene.
---[] Spread unassigned specialists equally amongst the Blood Raven companies.

A Breath Choked By Ash
+075.M42+ To +080.M42+
Be Faithful! Be Strong! Be Vigilant! - The Emperor of Mankind

The warp around Subsector Aurelia was growing more turbulent. There was, as of yet, seemingly no sign of the remaining number of their allies as promised. What they had was considerable, of course, by certain standards, but the slaves of Nurgle would not easily be repelled. This, Gabriel knew well. The Lost Rosetta had sworn they would come, but they had not yet materialized. And yet he could more hope for their arrival than for the utter hordes of Meridian Guard that Derosa had herself promised. It had been only a few weeks ago that she had spoken to him, red-faced with shame and anger. Much effort and resources had been expended, negotiating for the return of various regiments, and at the time agreements had been made with most of the commanders of the battle zones they were dedicated to. Agreements that had been broken, as it turned out.

A series of complicated orders and counter-orders had resulted in the Jericho Reach absorbing a significant amount of strength out of the Eastern Fringe. Though Hive Fleet Dagon had been largely broken, the greenskins of the area left to follow their precious prophet, and the Tau retreated wholly to their own lines, there remained a significant amount of threat in the area. Apparently. What scant reports that Derosa had managed to acquire pointed to Necrons, of all things, being the main issue. Apparently there was an entire Dynasty within the Reach, one that was beginning to wake up faster and with more strength than the local commanders liked. Worse, the ongoing Achilus Crusade was threatening to break apart as a result of worlds within its lines being revealed as Tomb Worlds, with Necron strike forces cutting apart supply lines and fortified positions literally from within. There were even rumors of Dark Eldar taking advantage of the chaos.

Because of course there was.

Still, it was not all unfortunate news, only mostly.

The 1st Meridian Consolidated, created with the best veterans of the Aurelian Crusades as their core, who had not yet lost a single battle since their founding, had managed to arrive alongside the 2nd and 3rd Regiments on-board a small detachment of Imperial Navy ships that subsequently left. While the greater majority of possible Meridian Regiments had failed to materialize, the three best equipped and most veteran of all said regiments had managed to make it. The 1st and 2nd had already deployed themselves onto Meridian proper, while the 3rd had been pushed to help in the potential defense of Calderis with some short negotiations between the Governors of those two worlds. These were no mere cowering Guardsmen, such as many of those that Gabriel and the Blood Ravens had seen before on many worlds. These had fought and survived tyranids, Chaos, greenskins, Eldar, and more. They might not have been the legendary Kasrkin of Cadia or increasingly well-known Kauravan Stormbreakers, but they were some of the best Guardsmen that Gabriel could judge having seen. And they would spend every moment they could building up their defensive positions and fortifications, an act and art that the Imperial Guard often excelled in.

And so, the year of 75.M42 passed, with only more death and destruction on the horizon.

=========================================================================

Aramus let out a tired sigh as his armor was removed, piece by piece, by the works of the servitors. Less than six months ago, one of the greatest Chaos Lords under the Despoiler had been slain. Yet you would not have known it, from the works of the enemy. Multiple enemies, now. Mad necrons, who he had never faced before, and yet now could count dozens of encounters under his belt. An endless tide of greenskins, better equipped and more cunning than any he had ever fought before. Tyranids, an enemy he was more familiar with, but nonetheless another complication that the Imperium could ill-afford. So it was that Nemesis Tessera had come under assault once more, and the Retribution, damaged as it was in fighting to slay the Lord Ravager and unable to do more than make for patchwork repairs, had departed the Cadian Sector proper to one of the branches of the Gate.

The fighting had only grown worse, everywhere.

For everyone.

It would be weeks before his terminator armor was fit for battle again, he knew that much by now. For all that he was not a Tech-Marine, so many decades alongside Sarrelen had taught him more than he knew the Adeptus Mechanicus would likely feel comfortable with. But that didn't matter. Not at the moment. He was much more focused on the newest arrivals on the ship. A buzz of excitement flowed amongst the serfs, he knew, and even more than that amongst the other passengers of the ship not of the Blood Ravens. But for the nominal commanders of the vessel, there was far more complicated feelings. Embers of shame burned anew at their presence, slivers of fear that they would be found wanting once again.

It felt like some kind of cosmic joke, if Aramus was honest with himself.

How had it come to pass that the Retribution was the closest ship to the ruined hulk of the cruiser that had served as the ferry from Holy Terra, whose berths had been designated for the usage of none other than the Adeptus Cutsodes? That they had survived the ship's death was not a surprise, nor was it a surprise that the forces of Chaos had expended so much effort to try and kill them in the first place. Aramus didn't know why they had been in Nemesis Tessera in the first place, though he had his suspicions given that it was the main stronghold of the Inquisition in the Cadian Gate that he knew about. That everyone, at this point in the 13th Black Crusade, knew about. By now, it was most likely that the Inquisition had long removed their most potent and dangerous artifacts and lore from the location, but they had stubbornly held onto it as a gathering and mustering point thus far. Which, in turn, continued to make it a target.

But none of that mattered now.

The latest incursion from the Despoiler's forces had been repelled, albeit with casualties, and now all that remained was continual intermittent combat against various xeno forces at lesser strengths. Yet even that seemed potentially too much for the battered Retribution, even though Aramus was more than willing to make that most final of choices. At the moment, however, he didn't dare make that decision. Indeed, he didn't dare make any decision at all save to journey to the strategium of the strike cruiser, for despite his position as Force Commander of the ship, there was quite simply a higher authority now present that he could not bring himself to go against.

So it was that he arrived in time to hear a garbled message being bleated out on the vox, badly translated as it was by a truly exhausted astropath.

"This is Master Osmadiel of the Dark Angels to all righteous warriors of the Imperium, we require assistance at Caliban! Repeat, we-,"

Aramus blinked at the words, his stride a half-stutter as the door closed behind him with a quiet thump. Every Blood Raven left amongst the Penitents save for Sarrelen was present, but none of them were near the actuality sphere itself. That position was reserved for another, who stood in near total stillness as he gazed upon the projected imagery of the solar system and the remaining Imperial elements within it.

"The rest is garbled, cut off. What should we do? That is only one distress hymnal against many, especially compared to Cadia," Adrien Kogal grunted, his white armor blackened and still smoking in a few places.

"Cadia has the Warmaster, Caliban has none. But...," Thaddeus cut himself off. "I..-"

Auramite gleamed in the dim light of the strategium. Nemesis Tessera had been protected, again, but not without cost. That thought was never more apparent than now, as Aramus gazed upon the actuality sphere and saw just how many red marks there were, designating all a manner of Imperial assets that had been utterly lost. He was most focused upon the Candle of Zeal, or rather the mark showing where the tumbling hulk that had been the Candle. But that moment passed and his gaze slid down to where Shield-Captain Aristos stood, the Custodes not having turned about to look at anyone else since he had arrived.

"We will go to Caliban, understood?" The Custodes finally announced, cutting through the quiet muttered argument between Adrien and Thaddeus with a single sentence.

Aramus bowed his head.

"Yes, Shield-Captain."

None would gainsay a Shield-Captain of the Custodes publicly, at least none who wished to live another day. That did not mean that there were not indignant Inquisitors who disliked a potentially valuable strike cruiser leaving the area, or perhaps that they were not the ones speaking with the Custodes instead. It was both honor and curse, it seemed, for the Shield-Captain had not deigned to utilize a private vox channel when he had announced that the Retribution would become their newest ferry. While a number of ancient and incredibly potent strike craft and personnel transports had been lost with the destruction of the Candle, the wrecks and all of the Wargear that the Custodes wielded had been brought over to the Retribution, which in turn had quietly frustrated more than a few overeager members of the Mechanicus present. And, if Aramus was honest, likely many in the Inquisition as well. Even now, he could see more than a few icons representing Imperial ships covering the wreck of the Candle, likely hoping to scavenge something or other.

And so they went.

=====================================================================

The state of the Imperious Spear was grievous, that was without question. The Dauntless-class Light Cruiser had been savaged by its travails in the Warp. A vast trio of canyons had been shorn into its hull, exposing much of the ship's inner decks to open void. Pockmarks that were in truth massive craters peppered the stern, while the engines flickered like a dying man's heartbeat. Something had taken the relatively powerful lance weaponry at the front of the ship and bent the barrels like string into a melted knot.

The transmitted holo-cast danced and bulged, barely holding the connection.

"Canoness Tenenbaum," Gabriel said softly, eyes wide as he beheld her.

A harsh red puckered line marked a line across her face and head, evidence of something nearly bisecting her entire skull. Her left pauldron was fractured, impacted, broken from some massive amount of concentrated force. Grime and soot covered her and her armor, and faint lines of smoke could be seen behind her. What little could be seen of the ship's bridge looked in similar conditions. Gabriel could even see a pair of Sororitas hauling a limp sister out of frame.

"Chapter Master Angelos," the seething Sororitas hissed back, though it was not him that the anger seemed directed towards. "I see that the true fight has yet to begin. That is well. We require resupply."

It was no idle statement, either. Gabriel could see another member of the Lost Rosetta in the background walking past with a heavy bolter that looked to have literally melted the barrel somewhat in a manner that he recognized. It was the sort of damage that he had only seen in weapons fired without pause or maintenance for far too long, to the point of emptying entire pallets of ammo in single battles. It was also badly dented in multiple places, with the exact same sort of patterns associated with heavy continual bludgeoning while wearing power armor. For all of that, the sister's eyes were not glazed over, nor were her pupils shrunken to pinpricks, nor blown out. She was, whoever she was, utterly and terribly stable. That much, Gabriel somehow knew in his very soul. Sane? That was another question entirely, and one with uncertain answers when it came to the particularly faithful.

"Of course, we will do what we can. But what has happened to...," he trailed off meaningfully.

Tenenbaum sneered and blew some air out of her mouth to shift some loose strands of hair out of her face.

"According to Subsector Aurelia's chrono-hymnals, it has been a month since we departed Saintsfall," she snorted before hocking out a wad of blood and phlegm to the ground. "By our count and chronos, it has been a year since the Gellar field shut down."

She bared a mouthful of bloody teeth at the Blood Raven Chapter Command.

The Ecclesiarchy of Meridian were more than happy to host the incoming Sororitas, and after their most direly injured had been or were in the midst of being seen to, more was learned of the harrowing journey to get to the Subsector. Of a cult amongst the lower decks, of mutations amongst the officer cadre, of sabotage and daemons alike. Very little of the original crew remained, and those few that did still live had largely been driven insane. By necessity, the Sororitas could do little else but walk the uneasy bridge between the faith of the Adeptus Mechanicus and the Ecclesiarchy proper, between Omnissiah and God-Emperor, in order to keep the ship even vaguely functioning and pointed in the right direction. Things had only grown worse the closer they got, as time stretched on within the Immaterium, and yet for a wonder they had not been able to crush the sisters of the Lost Rosetta, not utterly.

"I did not bring the whole of my Order, no," the Canoness declared after being taken out of the medically induced coma she had been forced into for a solid week. "The slaves of Ulkair have already begun their efforts, elsewhere in the Sector."

It was the most unwelcome news yet. Astropathic communication in and out of the Subsector had been growing more garbled and slower lately, but the full scope of it was only now revealed. Raiders bearing the marks of Nurgle had begun probing across the entire Sector, small in number but impossible to ignore. The Sector's battle fleet was already weakened after the disastrous attacks on the Saharduin Swells and the losses taken in defeating Vandis, they were ill-prepared to repel even this comparatively minor issues at the moment. Worse, there had been cult uprisings across the Sector as well, many of them sworn to Nurgle, or more specifically Ulkair. Not all of them, curiously, but most, and so the Lost Rosetta had seen fit to deploy much of their strength across Korianis in an effort to suppress them. A victory elsewhere, after all, might well end up empowering Ulkair further. And that was something that simply could not be allowed.

"But what I have delivered shall be enough," she had added, glaring about the medicae chamber to any and all who looked even slightly like they might contradict her.

To be fair to the Canoness, a shockingly high amount of Sisters had survived the ordeal, but then perhaps it shouldn't have been that shocking. For the Canoness had taken her most veteran of sisters with her from her entire Order, from across each of the commands of her subordinate Canonesses. Already, they were spreading tales through their after-action reports to the local Ecclesiarchy authorities, of their faith manifesting itself with great potency while trapped within the Warp. These were, after all, Seraphim and Celestians, no mere young recruits. That was not to say that there had not been losses, of course. But whether it was the favor of the God-Emperor, the favor and fury of the Lost Rosetta, or simple luck, of the thousand veteran Sororitas who had journeyed to Subsector Aurelia, eight hundred would be rendered combat ready within the next few weeks.

=======================================================================

The projected image over the actuality sphere accompanying the vox transmission was so thready and weak, all that could be seen of it was the vague shape of an astartes, a hood and cloak covering much of their armor.

"My thanks, Commander, for your prompt arrival," Osmadiel said calmly.

Aramus glanced at the Shield-Captain, only to frown and speak when the Shield-Captain remained silent.

"…of course, Master Osmadiel. We are glad to provide support," he said after a moment. "We only need your precise location."

"Transmitting now."

Only now did Aristos move, but it was only for the Custodian to point a single finger in total silence at Sarrelen who had been commanded to the communications console.

"…it is confirmed. These identification ciphers are very old, but they are correct. Coordinates inputted, Cap-…Commander?" The Tech-Marine stuttered only slightly as he tried to turn his head from Aristos to Aramus to make up for the near mistake.

Old codes were unusual, especially in the Cadian Gate when potential infiltrations and false flags were abundant. Nowadays, codes and ciphers could change within the hour, let alone the day or month.

"Duty has carried us far from the Rock, Commander. I would not expect most outsiders to comprehend the burden…but I have heard tales of the Penitent Blood Ravens. You, I suspect, would understand better than most."

There was a weariness there, and old pains, but a profound respect that nearly knocked Aramus to his knees. He was saved, if perhaps that could be considered it, by the barely audible snort from Aristos. It would not have been caught on the vox where the Dark Angel could hear it, not unless the Shield-Captain had desired it so.

"Perhaps I would. What is the foe we face here?"

"A foe you may remember well, Commander Aramus," Osmadiel grunted as several images were sent across the vox channels, depicting horrid heaving bio-ships.

"Tyranids," Aramus spat. "They seek to forge another corridor with which to plunge a Hive Tendril into the Cadian Gate!"

"Indeed, and across much of the Eye from the attentions of the Despoiler or Warmaster," Osmadiel noted. "If left unchecked, they could despoil this Sector and spread further, perhaps to Scarus and Scelus, to Belial, perhaps further."

"Then we must stop them, here and now."

No more needed to be said than that, not until the Retribution arrived over a shattered world. One with a dark and terrible history, but one that was not the main target of the enemy by virtue of that same history. The tyranids could feast on most anything, but there was little the Hive Mind desired within the broken remains of Caliban. Nevertheless, it was there that they met the fleet of Osmadiel, and a remarkable fleet it was. Three strike cruisers sailed there in the void, each of them larger than the Retribution. These, Sarrelen would declare, were ancient ships indeed, especially given how heavily equipped their weapon compliments were, far in excess of most standard allowances for modern strike cruiser construction. Their flagship, a battle barge, was much the same for its own kind.

"It hardly seems that you would need us at all," Aramus noted just as the first of the hive ships appeared on the auspex scans.

"Another ship, another compliment of warriors, another ally, all valuable things in combat," Osmadiel countered good-naturedly.

What followed was furious fighting indeed, but one that thankfully was without fatality. Casualties aplenty, yes, especially once the boarding began to strike the brains of the bio-ships, but none that were truly crippling. In two separate instances, Aramus even sighted the Dark Angels in the distance upon the larger Hive Ships, bolters booming and power swords flashing as they targeted the major organs within. Bio-plasma and living missile organisms evolved to chew through hull plating splattered on and smashed into the hulls of all five ships present, and while further repairs would be needed, none of the ships were too badly damaged. Indeed, the Dark Angels fought exceedingly well, deftly maneuvering their ships to allow void shields to regenerate, for crews to fight off boarders, presenting no weak points at all to the ravening hordes. They even incorporated the Retribution into their formation, allowing the battered ship the opportunity to contribute without risking itself overmuch.

Yet the Custodes did not deploy themselves, only seeing to defending the ship on the rare occasion when tyranids breached the hull.

Even so within a day it was done, the deed done far from most all eyes in the Cadian Gate, but one done in glory nonetheless.

"You have my thanks, Commander," Osmadiel said as their dead masses of meat and chitin were steadily burned apart by careful weapon's fire. "The Hive Mind will not try again for some time, I am sure. Your aid was greatly welcomed here."

"I…only-," Aramus began to speak before an Auramite-clad hand rose and cut him off.

"Master Osmadiel," Aristos said abruptly.

"…Who-,"

"I am Shield-Captain Aristos of the Adeptus Custodes. You will power down your shields, and I will come aboard your vessel."

There was a brief stunned silence.

"You-,"

"Do not waste my time with declaring me a liar. If you strike this ship down, there will be others. They will not be so patient, nor forgiving if you dared fire upon us."

There was something in the air as Aristos spoke. A weight. A pressure. Not quite the same as in the presence of significant psychic power, or a powerful Sororitas manifesting their faith into reality, but it was most certainly something beyond most mortal measures of intent. Whatever it was, the shields on the battle barge did indeed lower less than a minute later. Aramus did not follow, none of the Blood Ravens did. Instead, the Custodes headed as one for the teleportarium, and transferred themselves as a Shield-Host over to the battle barge. Warily, Sarrelen watched to see if the Dark Angel ships would target them, would react in any way at all, but they simply hung in the void.

Minutes passed.

Then an hour.

It would be three more before the Custodes returned, missing ten of their number. The ships of the Dark Angels would flare to life once more, turn as one, and immediately depart the battlefield without any further communications nor any aggressive moves towards the Retribution. The Shield-Captain, and his fellows, came back and returned to their original positions, with Aristos back on the Strategium. It was there that something within Aramus, well-suppressed, finally managed to bubble to the surface. A desire, a compulsion, weaker in him than in many in the Chapter, yet so tantalized that it could not fail to claw forth. He, quite simply, had to know.

"What…what was that about?" He finally asked, voice half-strangled.

Aristos glanced him up and down.

"A possibility, given form," the Shield-Captain said after a moment. "Osmadiel was not of the Dark Angels as you know them. Not from any of their current companies."

Aramus blinked.

"What? I don't…I don't understand."

The sigh that escaped the Custodes was like a blow to the chest, so potent was the disappointment.

"All that matters is that he, and they, are loyal to the Imperium. Now. Take the ship to Mordax Prime so it can be fully repaired so we can attend to the battlefield properly."

There would be many more questions, but none given voice, not that day. The conversation was quite clearly over. It would not be revisited once they reached the Forge World, nor in the weeks of hard fighting afterward. The Blood Ravens would fight alongside the Custodes, or more properly happened to be on the same battlefield as them, skirting around the sides as the Custodes went about their mysterious work. They did not fight in accordance with the battleplan of any general, any admiral, and simply did as they wished. The Retribution, and those who journeyed upon it, were simply caught up in the wake of the legends that had essentially put reins around their throats. At times, they fought to bring down enemy commanders. At others, they struck enemy bases. Depots. Boarded ships and left them sundered in the void. Often they targeted the xenos, not the forces of Chaos, but instead found themselves combatting necrons, greenskins, and tyranids, sometimes all three in the same day.

And yet, a month after the ship's full repair at Mordax Prime, they were commanded by Aristos back to the planet Cadia for a most unsettling meeting.

The most profound thing was the quiet.

Cadia was, for the most part, loud. Everywhere. All the time. There had not been a spare moment, a single spare second, that there was not a gun being fired, a blade swinging through the air, a cannon booming, a tank rumbling, and more somewhere on the planet's surface. The most cerebral of Khorne's servants and the most maudlin of Administratum adepts would both agree, if either were unfortunate enough to be in each other's presence, that there were higher gallons of blood spilled per moment statistically on Cadia than all but a handful of worlds within the galaxy. Screams of bloodlust. Screams of victory. Of righteous contempt. Of horror. Of pain. These were joined with the rhythmic and off-tempo thunder brought about by so many different artillery groups. Titans and Mega-Gargants and Bio-Titans strode across the surface, exchanging fire with each other and with entire armies. Entire Legios had come to Cadia, entire Legios had fallen on Cadia. Whole Knightly Houses, espousing either the Dark Gods or the God-Emperor, had done the same. Millions of metric tons of flesh and metal had been blasted, burnt, shot, exploded, melted, evaporated, sundered from reality itself, and yet more and more came to the world to join in the fighting.

Even in the most secure locations, there was noise. Fortified hospitals filled with the moans of the pained and dying, the shouting and whispering both of medicae staff, the hum and click of machines and servitors going about their own tireless work. Command bases were much the same, as officers shouted at one another, as quartermasters tore hair out and growled with peers and superiors both. Altars both plated in gold with pure white candles and those of twisted black metal and twitching sacrificed innocents were hunched over by the proud and desperate both. Adepts of the Mechanicus, both based at Mars and the Eye of Terror, constantly chanted in binary over their sacred machines. Snorting, chortling, smoking greenskin meks smacked and beat at their own creations with wrenches and screwdrivers. The tyranids, of course, were ever in motion, a chittering chitinous ocean that flowed across the world. Even the Necrons, normally so unnervingly quiet, were atypical to many of their kind. For these were the maddened Flayed Ones, as well as those who retained some measure of themselves even as the curse advanced through their memory engrams. Such gave rise to hideous alien shrieks as they demanded flesh, skin, their lives, their souls back from the C'tan who had long ago devoured such things.

It was, therefore, all the more disturbing for such a quiet to fall.

The forwardmost bastion of the Imperium on Cadia, the latest of its command centers, the absolute - and literally - bleeding edge of the war effort, should not have been so quiet. The lines of the enemy, the great enemy, was literally within viewing distance by the most mundane of mortal eyes. Potshots were, even now, being taken across more than a hundred miles of trench lines between cultists of Chaos and the ten latest Death Korps of Krieg regiments. If one could consider it potshots when tens of thousands of rounds were being exchanged every half hour.

It was was here, where the Warmaster herself led the war effort, where dozens of generals and their staffs were organizing the war across Cadia and the Cadian System, that there should never have been silence.

And yet there was.

It was a silence that was heralded by the most unsettling of feelings. The flesh prickled along the scalp and neck. The stomach dropped. A chill crept along the spine. Both of his hearts began to speed up, pulsing, as if battle was upon him, even though he knew it wasn't. Everyone in the strategium oriented, as one, towards the doors as the feeling grew worse and worse. The blazing light that emanated from within and around both the Warmaster and the Champion began to glow brighter, true, but almost as if it were defensive in nature. Like pressure increasing to compensate, came the whisper from the analytical part of his mind.

The Imperial Fist and Celestian Sororitas that guarded the door visibly shuddered as they turned towards the doors when they opened.

On the other side stood two Custodes, neither of whom Aramus did not recognize from those who had been aboard the Retribution for the past months. That alone brought several hearts to a temporary stuttering stop, at least in many of the officers of the Imperial Guard and a number of the Sororitas present. But the Custodes did not speak, and instead advanced several steps into the strategium before turning out slightly to reveal those behind them.

And these...were not Custodes.

Not at all.

That creeping dread, the roiling unease, that faint mounting disgust, all of it threw itself at Aramus like a physical weight that almost staggered him.

On the other side of the doors, numbering but thirteen, was the source of it all. Their power armor was a strange, shimmering grey and silver, of such masterful make that it put many such suits present to shame, save perhaps for the armor of the Custodes themselves. All of them bore concealing helms, strange two-handed blades that clung to their backs, and deadly looking bolters and knives. Though they did not crane their necks back and forth, it was impossible to not recognize the sheer otherworldly weight of their gazes as they swept the room. Especially as Aramus felt the weight leave him, somewhat, as whichever of the strange arrivals that had glanced at him looked away.

"Custodes," the Warmaster declared, the blazing beacons that were her eyes flaring as she spoke. "And so, these servants of the Emperor, too, have come to the crucible."

"Indeed," one of the Custodes said as he gave the slightest of nods. "The Captain-General has held to his promise."

He half-turned and gestured to the new arrivals.

"Knight-Centura Yukio and her most senior Oblivion Knights. There are others, but these are the first to arrive."

"So be it."

Then, in an act that made Aramus' skin crawl and bones itch, the Warmaster turned towards him.

"Aramus the Penitent. Kinslayer. Hero and Doom of Blood Ravens," she declared.

It felt like every single molecule that made up his being was being forced through the finest sieve, each resulting fragmented grain being examined one by one simultaneously.

"Warmaster," he bowed his head, unable to manage any further words and finding some small measure in relief in not having to look her in the eyes.

"You wish to die. You wish to live. You do not know which you desire more. You will decide before your reach your next destination. Your ship will transport the Oblivion Knights and Custodes."

"Of course, Warmaster. Where…where shall we go?"

A hand placed itself atop his head, and it felt like a burning sun being pressed against his flesh, yet it did not burn him.

"Where else?" There was a dry note to her voice, as well as the faintest bemusement. "To slay a daemon."

=========================================================================

They were only a few days out from their destination.

Possibly their final destination.

Apothecary Adrian Kogal slowly exhaled a puff of smoke from around the Lho-Stub between his teeth. Today, he stood dressed in nothing more than an off-white short-sleeved robe to garb his body, cinched at the waist with a simple rope cord. Which, in turn, did little to disguise his heavily muscled frame and the bulging yet sleek bionics which had replaced three of his limbs. It was with his right hand, the only hand he had still made of flesh and bone, that he drew the Lho-Stub out of his mouth and exhaled another cloud of smoke just to the left of the only other occupant of the Apothecarium for the moment.

"You're sure about this?" He asked, voice a graveyard's rumble.

Aramus nodded, face drawn tight with a determined grimace.

"I am."

Adrian pursed his lips and puffed on the Lho-Stub again.

"I only ask, because when you had me do the work all those years ago-,"

"I am aware, Adrian," Aramus shook his head. "Circumstances have...changed."

The Apothecary sharply exhaled through his nose, not quite a snort. Aramus wrinkled his nose as the smoke continued to fill the air before the air recycling kicked in again to waft it away.

"Must you 'honor the Lord-Castellan' in here, now, of all times?"

Adrian shrugged minutely.

"Firstly, it's my Apothecarium," he declared. "Secondly, I won't dismiss the gratitude of those Catachans. Thirdly, it's not like the smoke can harm either of us. Fourth,'" he jabbed the Lho-Stub at Aramus. "You bade me to never accept such a request. No matter what."

"I am aware."

"Had a whole speech and everything about it. About honor and penance and so on."

Aramus sighed again. Adrian Kogal had been one of the quietest Blood Ravens in the entire Penitent Crusade save for the one among their number who had sworn an outright Path of Silence. But somewhere in the past many decades, nearly a century now, that had been ground away to be replaced by a surly ill-tempered battle brother who partook in the same Lho-Stubs as Creed himself and carried a missile launcher and plasma gun into battle. Who had regularly leapt into the medicae tents of Imperial Guard and Sororitas detachments wherever they had been fighting, startling and saving in equal measure. He had been on the receiving end of stares by other Apothecaries hundreds of times at this point. For all of that, there was no Apothecary that Aramus could trust more.

"I know. But with what we are about to do..." Aramus trailed off, looking down at his naked and scarred body.

It was a gruesome tapestry, there was no denying that. Wounds remained that on most other Marines would have healed long ago. Scars from weapons mundane and monstrous covered him, lurid and terrible ones that had barely faded joining the latest additions. He clenched his left fist, the masterwork bionics whirring and clicking down the length of the artificial arm.

"My own self-loathing and failures cannot be allowed to harm our chances for success. Not this time." Aramus looked back up at Adrian with a glare that seemed to burn through the Apothecary. "I have no right, none at all."

Adrian clucked his tongue and popped the Lho-Stub back in, rolling it in his teeth before puffing out some more smoke.

"Very well."

Aramus blinked before he let himself be shoved to a supine position.

"So you'll do it?" He asked, surprised in spite of himself.

"Of course, I was always going to," Adrian snorted. "Been waiting for you to ask."

"What?! But-,"

Adrian clicked his fingers, causing the medical servitor to inject several doses of tranquilizing and painkilling solutions directly into Aramus' neck. The Force Commander jolted but was already rapidly approaching unconsciousness.

"This whole blasted Crusade, before we even got to Cadia, you made me put you to sleep," Adrian's voice was already growing distant. "Dampening glands, inducing dormancy to organs, bare minimum healing, so on."

There was another series of injections into Aramus' chest, all while the sound of saws and drills spinning up filled the air.

"Been waiting for you to ask me to wake you up again, Commander. Thaddeus has been doing his best, but I'd prefer two Heroes of Typhon than one."

=====================================================================

New astropathic reports only arrived long after the Lost Rosetta and scant Meridian Regiments did. The Sector was indeed under assault, multiple probing raids being performed as far as the sector's heart, though none of the ships were ever larger than light cruisers in tonnage. But even a smaller escort ship could cause untold damage to a planetary surface if it was allowed to use its weapons without interruption. Picket ships and system monitors were marshalled, pushing back and forth, while the ravaged Battlefleet Korianis did its best to repel such invaders. But these were things already known, just now with more detail. They came, these reports, amidst further astropathic communications near simultaneously through the curdling Immaterium surrounding Subsector Aurelia. The news, as ever in the seemingly ever-darkening day of the modern Imperium, was full of grim tidings.

In Segmentum Ultima, the 3rd Tyrannic War has finally spilled past the Realm of Ultramar. The Sons of Guilliman and their allies have purchased a most pyrrhic of victories. Too stalwart, too strong, too mighty, they have rebuffed the Hive Mind time and again. The alien fiends have found the Realm too strong for them to consume, at least as swiftly as they need to, and so tendrils and splinters have begun to flood past the unbroken lines to worlds left without. Deathwatch, ever more short-staffed and desperate, have been doing their best, but the valiant defense of Ultramar cannot so easily stretch and support these disparate other territories. Imperial forces throughout the Eastern Fringe are being called upon in great number to try and stem the tide that has managed to skirt around the utter dam that was and is Ultramar.

In Segmentum Pacificus, there have come rumors of a rabid expansion by a new xenos threat. Or, perhaps depending on one's knowledge, an old one. Wearied severely after the Night of One Thousand Rebellions, further depleted by forces called to holy crusade under the Warmaster Saint, the threadbare strength of the Imperium within Pacificus has been strained yet further. A xenos race, known as the Q'orl Swarmhood have begun rapidly expanding their territory into the Segmentum, overwhelming whole Sectors in their initial assaults. This Swarmhood possesses not only considerable numbers comparable to other insectoid species and most uncomfortably like the tyranids, they also possess notably advanced technologies of their own with only Warp-engines and the like previously having been apart from their technological base. This has evidently changed, with whole fleets of Q'orl dropping out of the Warp over Imperial worlds.

In Segmentum Tempestus, the Maynarkh Dynasty has continued to expand their territory. Three more Forge Worlds have been revealed as Tomb Worlds, all signs of existence of the Mechanicus upon them wiped out entirely, as well as a handful of other Imperial Worlds and some uninhabited planets as well. The total loss of the Orpheus and the Eurydice Sectors have been declared by the High Lords, with desperate efforts being put up to try and prevent further expansion into the nearby Argosa Sector. An effort which has been hamstrung both by the fact that the Imperial Navy cannot seem to even begin to challenge the Necron fleets with anything less than three to one numerical superiority and that another world within the Argosa Sector proved itself to be a Tomb World which has begun reactivating. Many, including the White Scars and Raven Guard, have been called upon to defend what may prove to be the greatest threat in the entire Segmentum if left to further grow its strength.

There are myriad threats elsewhere of course, but non so great as Armageddon in Solar and the 13th Black Crusade in Obscurus.

War continues to rage, as ever, in a darkness set aflame.

And yet these reports only serve to magnify what comes next, for the Blood Ravens cannot even begin to do their duty to the rest of the Imperium before they do their duty to their home.

===============================================================

It was not 'like' he had been deaf and blind before now. He quite literally had been deafening and blinding himself. His pain-dampening glands had been reactivated, and yet that barrier to the world made him feel all the more alive for it. The aches, the pains, scar tissue build-up, all of it carved and scoured from him. It was, if anything, as if he had been reborn again. Those of his organs that had been dormant now thrummed and pulsed in him, his being rejuvenated not just in body but in spirit. There was something completely and utterly freeing about what he was doing, here and now. In this ruined, wrecked ruin of a world, there was a peace in him he had scarcely imagined only a month ago that he could possess.

So high above as to be but a bright spot in the sky, the Retribution was trailing fire from a trio of near-mortal wounds, and was utterly surrounded by screeching tyranids, mostly obscured by clouds of ash and chitin. The Thunderhawks had been utilized to deliver their most precious occupants to the world below, as close as possible to their targets. Several had been shot down, and so the auxiliaries had been sent to seek them out and secure them. The drop pods had been emptied out, some as transports themselves, some as weapons. They were not alone, either. A company of the White Scars had come. Two companies of the Iron Hands. An entire Ordo Minoris of the Adeptas Sororitas, three hundred in number. Over a thousand space marines from various other Chapters. Three regiments of Catachan, another five of Elysian Drop Troops. It was these larger threats, ferried on more notable and larger ships, that had been targeted first and foremost by the twisted possessed tyranids who clung to the world and by the true Hive Mind that had come to enact retribution on the thief who had stolen the former. That the Retribution had gotten as close as it had yet had not yet been fully brought down was a testament to the skill of the Tech-Priests who even now desperately worked to keep it flying.

But none of that mattered right now.

They had, all of them, space marines and sisters of battle and guardsmen and skitarii, plunged into a true hellscape. Nothing of human habitation and existence remained anymore upon the ruined world. All was less than rubble, was dust, replaced solely by mountains of dead and rivers of alien ichor. Vast swathes, stretching out like grasping tendrils, had been transformed utterly into conduits into the Immaterium itself. Citadels of brass and blood-red metals forged out of hatred and fury sprouted up in these warped territories, and from them poured the daemonic hordes of Khorne. They, in turn, crashed and slammed into the swirling tides of tyranids, both the mindless puppets of the Lord of Shadows and the innumerable extensions of the Hive Mind, who in turn assaulted each other with just as much alien savagery. There was no quarter given, none even possibly imagined by any of the three great combatants who shook the planet down to its core with their fighting. The introduction of the Imperials into the planetary slaughterhouse had done nothing more than offer up different targets.

All strove now to reach a blood-filled caldera atop an unnatural mountain range, one forged both of billions upon billions of dead tyranids and the hellish protrusions of the Blood God's realm into the Materium. The Hive Mind had found the culprit it wished to examine and destroy. The inherent connection of Khorne's servants to warfare, bloodshed, and violence, all drew them forth without any other order required from higher minds within the hierarchy of those who served the Skull Throne. The First-Damned refused to surrender, not when he had come so close after so many years languishing. The Imperium could not allow any other victor other than themselves, but that was in truth simply an extension of their purpose and policy since their founding.

It was a slog, not just against the armies that thrashed about against one another, but from the very world itself. Subiaco Diablo was halfway to becoming a true Daemon World, slipping ever further into the embrace of the Blood God's realm. Subiaco Diablo was halfway to being devoured, punctured across its surface by gargantuan feeding tendrils skewering the world to feed the Hive Ships above. It shook, it trembled, it spewed blood and lava from chasms and crevices. Some geological, formed of cracking continental plates, others from fissures in crimson granite-flesh as the world's screams became that much more disturbingly human discounting the deafening volume.

But still they pushed on. They had to, or this would all be for nothing. All of the dead, their sacrifices rendered meaningless.

A titanic explosion from within the caldera nearly ended Aramus almost immediately after he thought that, his terminator armor stumbling and bowled over by the shockwave which followed. It was a thing of searing cold, a bow wave which spread for miles and miles around. He watched, stupefied, as the armor's readouts registered near absolute zero, thick layers of frost bursting into being across not just himself but everything around. His armor groaned with the effort it took to move once more, and the landscape itself had transformed from a dying world of heat and burning blood into one of frost and stillness. It did not last of course, but thick sheets of unnatural ice coated all things even as they began to move once more. Churning blood geysers began to push out frozen solid columns of blood from fleshy orifices. While tens of thousands of the closer tyranids had been so swiftly and powerfully affected by the cold as to die outright, there were a vast number more that continued to advance uncaring of said deaths. A great many daemons of Khorne were destroyed by the aftermath of what had just occurred, wiped back into the Immataerium as jumbled Warp essence. An entire regiment of Elysian Drop Troops was dead in the air, thousands upon thousands of thin needle-like spikes of ice marking their airborne graves. And yet they could not help but continue on, pushing through the slush and dead once more, the newborn tundra becoming a churning swamp of brass, chitin, and blood. Fully half of the tyranids they saw either collapsed, dead immediately, or else began to decay at impossible speeds. Only the greatest of their bio-forms, such as bio-titans, tyrants, hive guard, and the like managed to remain upright, and yet soon enough a horrid yet familiar intelligence began to spark and spread in their eyes once more.

"Come on!" Aramus yelled, hefting his thunder hammer high.

They reached the lip of the caldera and beheld but two things.

War.

And despair.

It was the latter that Aramus had scarcely felt in his life before, even at the worst of times. But the sight of Custodians, scattered about the Caldera, blood seeping from grievous wounds hacked into their no longer gleaming armor, shook him to his core. From beside him, Thaddeus let loose a ragged gasp, a sound echoed by the rest of the Blood Ravens, even Nereus. Their weapons lay covered in layers of ice and bodies alike, while daemons of Khorne cavorted over the weapons and their wielders. So, too, could the epicenter of the explosion be seen, a crater within the caldera, an afterimage flash from the destruction of Bel'akor's body and banishment of his essence. Even now, the afterimage flickered while decaying further and further, for now still showing the outrage and fury on the Daemon Prince's face as he was struck down.

The victor, even now, stood, snarling chain-axes held high to the sky. A multitude of bloodspattered cords ran and dangled from the scalp, one of the horns destroyed from some blow or another. Thick slabs of plate wept otherworldly essence from a number of heavy wounds, including one in the gut that had clearly pierced entirely through the torso. Many of the wounds bled heavily, dripping corrosive ichor upon the caldera floor, yet others were already beginning to heal as alien blood strewn across the battlefield began to swirl and creep in to fill them. One of the great wings was broken in multiple places, the other flapped still, buffeting crimson winds with every movement. The Daemon Primarch Angron, Fallen Son of the Emperor, roared his victory over Bel'akor for the universe to hear. He did not even glance at the arrival of the Blood Ravens or the handful of other Imperials who had managed to ascend the mountain with them.

And why would he?

For before him was much more enticing prey – none other than Shield-Captain Aristos, whose spear was cleft in twain and bolter was a stamped plate of metal. His legs had been twisted about, reversed, nearly torn off of his body entirely, with small craters around showing where he had been picked up and slammed back down again with absolute force and violence. Heavy gouges were evident across his torso and arms, blows that would have propelled any number of mere astartes far past the borders of death. Still, the Custodes struggle to lift himself with his sole remaining functioning limb, unsheathing a crackling knife in his belt that he weakly raised upwards. It was a feat repeated across the caldera, broken and scattered Custodes fighting on, despite what should have been mortal wounds, nevertheless staving off death just that little bit longer despite being surrounded by daemons. Tyranids, too, were pouring in all the while, targeting daemon and Custodes both.

Only one order could suffice for the Blood Ravens, one action that could be taken when confronted by such heartbreaking horror, such a morale-shattering sight.

"ATTACK!"

Sarrelen, slowest of them all while dragging his customized generator trailer behind them all, pushed to the fore, grunted once, and then unleashed himself. Two blinding spears of light hurled from his lascannons directly into Angron's face, while the combi-multi-meltas shot into the lines of daemons between them. Nereus fired off a round handed to him months ago by a member of the Deathwatch, a strange piece of xeno-archeotech of black metal and crackling green energies. Kogal fired up a charged shot from the Final Absolution of Caliban, a sphere of deadly plasma rocketing forwards. All of which impacted the Daemon Primarch, axes still raised high, a heavy cloud of dust and ash filling the air. The few remaining sororitas and other astartes began firing at the daemons of Khorne, desperately attempting to defend the remaining Custodes.

Thaddeus Rex took the air.

His jump pack screaming, pushed beyond all safety limits, he flew hard and fast forwards as the smoke just began to lift. From his left hip, haphazardly tied with combat webbing, he tore free a missile launcher that unleashed not just a krak missile but two melta charges crudely attached with adhesive. From his right hip, he pulled free his bolter pistol and began to unleash a torrent of advanced flux-core bolter rounds, the rare ammo a gift from the Mechanicus adepts of Mordax Prime. Growling Hate leapt to the instant he laid his hand on it and raised it up, all the while Thaddeus shouted a wordless cry as he hurled himself forwards.

Only for the smoke to not lift but be banished outright as a thunderclap rang out, a secondary shockwave effect brought about from a single absentminded blow. The Coronet of Honor, forged under the eyes of Azariah Vidya himself, shorted and melted as it was instantaneously overwhelmed. His relatively advanced MK-VIII power armor was parted and torn, and all could watch as the sheer concussive force of what struck him solidly in the midsection broke the jump pack he wore. Meat and organ and bone were churned and scattered, and Thaddeus Rex was bent almost in half as almost everything between his front and his spinal cord was removed, the white glistening bone visible amidst the viscera as he was thrown aside to land in a crumpled heap.

The Daemon Primarch had not looked away from the Shield-Captain, and only the most eagle-eyed of the astartes present were able to tell that he had even moved one of his axes at all.

"Adrien!" Aramus shouted before he half-knelt, a hand going to the forehead of his armor. "Get to him!"

"Aramus, don't! You heard what-,"

"Go!" He shouted before rapidly murmuring a benediction to his war gear.

He could not run there in time. Not in this armor. Not in these conditions, where the ground bulged and split open, where daemons and tyranids aplenty tread.

There was only one choice before him.

"Emperor guide me," he murmured as a crack opened up in the Warp and swallowed him whole.

To travel through the Warp was, at the best of times, a transit through a living hell. To do so here, on this world, was not the best of times. Aramus screamed, the noise unbidden, as he was buffeted by forces beyond his ken yet not necessarily beyond his hatred and contempt, felt the sound of waves crashing against cliffsides of bone, of billions of tumbling skulls falling from every direction towards a single centered point. A force mirroring gravity, yet infinitely darker, actively malicious in its purpose and desires, yet a force of un-reality all the same. All of this, he felt, he saw, he heard, rattling and shaken about as he plunged forward. Worst of all was not that distant crushing weight, like twin white stars erupting in infinity, but the towering inferno ahead of him. One that saw him coming all the same, and so Aramus raised his hammer and shield to meet the death that he approached.

The moment the teleportation completed they were torn from his grip so fast that his fingers were nearly broken from the sheer force of it.

Not grabbed, no, but simply knocked aside and out of his hands with sheer force from a single sweep the Daemon Primarch's left axe. The shield was a shattered mess that was sent flying past the lip of the caldera, the hammer a splintered broken pile of nothing. Something so massive, so bulky, should never have moved so swiftly, and yet it was done and over without a single heartbeat. There were no words exchanged, only hate and rage made utterly manifest as Angron opened his slavering maw and roared. The heat and sound which emerged over his knife-length fangs spilled out and forward, striking Aramus in his entire body. The Blood Raven found himself driven backwards and down into the volcanic soil, his armor enveloped utterly as if he were plunged into the heart of a star, nearly blinded outright to the point that his eyes within his sockets almost felt like they had begun to boil, as if every fluid in his body was set alight to nearly becoming steam inside of him. Something in his ears popped, and suddenly much of the world faded away. But not all of it. Not the scream of the daemon, which pierced past the physical and the organic directly into the soul into the soul itself. Even simply being this close, on sheer presence and closeness, the ceramite plate he wore was being heated beyond its capacity.

His venerable terminator armor was melting beneath the rage of Angron.

"A wretch dares to defend His dogs?! THEN YOU WILL DIE WITH HIM!"

Each word another body blow, a sonic cannon's burst.

And yet.

Mostly blinded, largely deafened, aflame in failing armor with his weapons obliterated, Aramus inhaled as deeply as his lungs could manage and did the only thing he could.

That which duty demanded and instinct supported.

===================================================================

Upon the Omnis Arcanum, an astropath was screaming, face contorting and reddened from the effort of receiving the message. Several other astropaths were gathered at their sides, and various librarians had joined as well. Justinius himself was present, crackling with psychic energy as he chanted in tandem with the others. He paused, but only for a moment, as Gabriel and the rest of the Chapter Command arrived. It had been ongoing for several minutes already, and even those without psychic abilities could tell that much effort was being made purely to keep the astropath alive as the message sought to outright burn through him.

"What is happening?" Gabriel said quickly.

A gesture from Justinius had one of the lesser astropaths toddle over, face dripping with sweat down a comparatively young face.

"A false…well perhaps," she stammered for a moment. "It carried the correct signatures and litanies of authority and identity, but the moment it was accepted it…," she gestured at the elder astropath as he grit his teeth. "A deadly trick, it seems, played upon us."

The straining astropath tilted his head back, veins pulsing in his neck, and opened his mouth. Blood and phlegm flew out of his mouth as his throat was shredded by otherworldly forces.

"BLOOD…RAVENS…"

It was killing the astropath to speak it, but the voice was unmistakably that of the Chaos Lord Mortirex.

====================================================================

Bones fractured, and in some cases had broken outright. Melting ceramite was compressed, with rivulets of it splattering about like putty. Stone and chitin beneath was cratered and smashed. A wave of sheer heat and force rippled outwards and bowled over daemons, astartes, sororitas, and tyranids alike. The ash and smoke from weapons fire and daemonic flames had been banished once more, allowing all with a mind and ability to see the result, there in the direct center of the caldera. The dissolving afterimage of Bel'akor's defeat had faded away entirely, and all the astral ice and frost left behind from his banishment had most definitely melted away entirely, with what little steam had resulted similarly removed. Violence still abounded, but so too was there utter surprise on many a face.

For there, Aramus of the Blood Ravens stood still, both arms outstretched. One hand each was clasped around the haft of a gigantic chain-axe, two enormous crimson hands opposite them. The axes whirred, snarled, almost heaved with nonexistent lungs, their forever blood-hungry teeth snapping and biting at the air. A few of them had tasted melting ceramite, and were even now scattering chips of pauldrons into the air. His arms shook, his entire body trembled with effort, and it was there he stood with two small craters around his feet.

Angron sneered and spat before pushing down harder, driving the axes down against Aramus and towards the weakly moving Shield-Captain behind and beneath him. The Daemon Primarch's strength grew further still as the slaughter continued across the planet against the aliens, as the fight within the caldera continued to rage, and Aramus was driven further down. Soon, within seconds, he was not simply trembling in place with effort, but practically vibrating as every part of him strained. Soon, the axes began to creep downwards, cutting further and further into his armor.

Until something firmed in Aramus and their progress was halted once more. Perhaps it was some of his broken bones shifting and settling in place. Perhaps the Machine Spirit of his armor had found some hidden reserve. Perhaps it was something else altogether. All that was certain at the time however was that to the growing infinite fury of Angron, once more the Blood Raven defied him and held the axes in place.

At which point Angron lowered his head and distended his jaw so that he could bite down at Aramus, ripping and tearing away the front of his helmet and much of the upper armor. Deep, burning, incandescently glowing ruin was left behind. Aramus, for his part could not scream, even as one of those hideous fangs grazed his face and nearly slew him outright. No, he could barely make any noise at all, so tightly grit were his teeth. It was not merely the heat which was reddening his skin across his entire body, but the strain, the effort. Blood and melted ceramite dribbled down Angron's chin, his baleful eyes blazing down at the defiant loyalist before him. The Lord of the Red Sands then simply began to push harder, tapping further into realms of strength beyond mundane reality. It would be recorded that first the upper back, then the shoulders, and finally the arms of Angron began to swell like balloons of flesh. They would swell and then all that ex nihilo mass would shift rapidly forward down towards Angron's hands forming a pair of blunt pile drivers daemonic fury, all in less than a second. This, finally, forced a quiet grunted breath from Aramus as the twin impacts slammed into him like artillery strikes. Armor and bone fractured once more, myomer and muscle tore, cables and ligaments ripped, and Aramus was forced further downwards, his knees beginning to bend.

Then Angron did so seven more times in rapid succession.

Teeth cracked. Joints were flattened. Phalanges were turned to powder in places. The solid plate of bone protecting his torso broke apart. Knees and elbows bent further and further. By the time the impacts stopped, Aramus was a solid two feet deeper than he'd begun, one knee a scant inch away from hitting the dirt and stone. All around the fighting was continuing, and in fact from beyond the bloodied tunnel that was Aramus' vision someone had begun firing on Angron directly from somewhere. Not that Aramus could hear any of it. He had truly gone deaf, and yet could perfectly hear every snarl, every whirl of a daemon's blade, every clink and rattle across Angron's frame. He was mostly blind, but could still somehow see as Angron leaned forward again, maw opening to end him.

Duty held but one course. One instinct demanded.

Defiance against the dark.

And so Aramus, neck nearly tearing off with the effort, firmed his grip an iota further, drew himself upright and forward with the axes and body of the Daemon Primarch as an anchor, and squarely headbutted Angron in his nose. The glowing remains of his terminator armor only helped, smashing against that much larger face and leaving droplets of molten ceramite behind.

Angron did not move, even as Aramus sagged back downwards. Several daemons had turned to look, even though it caused them to be cut down. Somewhere, a Blood Raven was shouting. The tyranids in the caldera were all but slain, and there was a pounding of power armor in the distance.
But Aramus could not hear it, could not perceive anything but the face of Angron. The infinite fury had faded, if only momentarily to be replaced with something almost vestigial in the Daemon Primarch's emotional arsenal: befuddlement. But then that was swallowed up by anger once more.

"You...you dare?"

Aramus, face tight and crimson, blood trickling down his nose and from his eyes, ears, and mouth, hauled himself upright...and headbutted Angron again. Angron's hooves did not move, but he reared his head back and let loose a cruel and incredulous laugh, cables sparking and scraping across his back. Then his entire body seemed to become suffused by sheer bloody weight as Angron forced his being and presence downward once more. What had seemed a mountain before was now but a puff of air compared to what Angron brought to bear now. This time, Aramus felt his pelvis and femurs crack apart, spilling marrow and blood within his armor. In that moment, it was but the armor holding Aramus up rather than anything else, the melting metal solidified into shape by sheer force. Organs throughout his body were nearly destroyed by the concussive force.

There, in the caldera, Aramus finally went limp as he was brought low after everything, bloodshot eyes still open. A bellowed scream echoed out from somewhere. Angron and many of his daemonic legion laughed as one, the petty defiance finally dealt with. Others had turned to fight new arrivals, only to be cut down themselves. The Lord of the Red Sands chortled in pleasure, the noise charnel and horrid to the ear, and lifted his axes to the sky once more so that he could properly claim the skulls of the Custodes. He paused, however, as he lifted his axes up, and stared at the limp red and black form that still clutched at them. Higher went the axes, and higher the body went.

Angron's eyes narrowed, then widened, for his ears and senses were more than enough to perceive the Larraman's Organ within the Blood Raven suddenly and superlatively activating. The faint dying sparks of brain activity erupted into a momentary lightning storm which rapidly normalized. In front of everyone at the caldera, and perhaps some beyond, Aramus of the Blood Ravens drew in a bloodied, ragged breath into squashed lungs and subsequently tightened his grip further with broken hands so that he could drag himself forwards to slam his entire upper body into Angron's face once more before his eyes had even refocused or blinked.

Angron's left hoof shifted backwards infinitesimally.

"What...?"

Blood and snot trickled down Aramus' broken face, chips of teeth spilling out from his split and burnt lips and broken jaw. A wet, determined gurgle escaped him as he drew himself forwards again, every part of his being screaming in pain. His battered hearts had been forced to beat once more after failing, and beat they did, squeezing blood out through compressed and crushed veins. This time, the impact was properly heard, for all that it was a muted thing compared to the fighting going on across the planet.

Angron's right hoof slid an inch, his wings twitching as if to make a beat before stilling. The Daemon Primarch's features twisted as he roared once more, but this time Aramus leaned into the otherworldly heat as he smashed himself into Angron again, cutting the roar off again. The Lord of the Red Sands shook his axes with hurricane strength, but Aramus clung still. To the axes, to his duty, to life itself, he doggedly clung. His grasp was beyond a death grip. It was a grasp of the duty laid down by the Emperor, and that precluded all things.

Death included.

Again. Again. Again.

Aramus threw his last weapon, his body, his spirit, again and again into Angron's face.

Rage ruled Angron, but surprise and outrage welled to the fore as well with each blow.

But more importantly, he was being, inch by impossible inch, pushed away from the fallen Shield-Captain. His wings had to beat to keep him forwards, his hooves dug into the stone and carved channels into it. Only then did Angron realize what had truly changed. No mere Astartes could do this. And that remained true still. But what Angron could sense was the mobile stillness that had been missed amongst the Tyranids, daemons, and loyalists. The blots of silence that had steadily ground up the slope of the mountain. That were now, this very instant, cresting the lip of the caldera.

The Sisters of Silence did not pause in their sprinting as they arrived, either. Beneath their feet, the Warp recoiled, was repulsed, was removed. Daemons raised their blades in one second and disappeared in the next as the Oblivion Knights passed them by. Tainted, screaming blood and mud was reduced to mundane volcanic ash. Onwards they came, and onwards they ran, and all the while Aramus, blind and deaf, continued his assault.

Every impact was louder and louder than before. A quiet crash, to a loud pact, to a thunderous slam. Peals of thunder rang out as melted ceramite and determined mortal struck the Daemon Primarch again and again. Angron stepped back, his wings beating harder to keep himself upright, his strength fleeing exponentially with every step the Sisters of Silence came closer, while the strength of Aramus was maintained by a will and strength all his own. A dozen of the Sisters flung silently crackling blades that flew straight and true, each puncturing Angron down to the hilt and drawing forth screams of true pain. The daemon flailed. He roared. But he could not dislodge, could not remove Aramus, until finally it was Angron's head snapping backwards as Aramus continued to attack him with his own head.

Again. Again. Again.

The few remaining bloodletters wailed in foreign despair as Angron was knocked onto is back by the growling, gurgling Blood Raven with one more titanic headbutt. Then the Sisters were there, three hundred of them. Their most powerful were towards the front, and so they plunged enormous two handed blades into the fallen Angron, reaching out and accepting the blades of their sisters. Seconds passed as Angron was filled with blades, surrounded by the nulls, his whole being fading away until it became a barely present outline of red shadow and cold burning stars.

"This..."

There was no explosion. Not even a muted pop. Aramus headbutted the foe one last time, metaphysical integrity failed, and abruptly he was falling the last several feet to the ground below to land on his already broken face. On all sides stood the Sisters of Silence, blinking as one. Beyond them stood the few surviving astartes and sororitas.

"OUT OF THE WAY!" Adrien Kogal roared.

==============================

"I know now where you huddle. Where you hide! But worry not - Ulkair has given me a gift to right the wrongs, to fulfill a debt of death!"

The astropath was dying every moment he was forced to transmit the message. The Chaos Lord's voice was weaker, very much so, but it remained his voice all the same. He could not possibly have regained his powers in totality, not so soon. But he had, all knew, escaped upon a ship.

"This...Trontiux...shall provide a fine sacrifice to the Dark Gods! The poor wretched dogs have left their larder unguarded!"

There were no audible shouts of disbelief. All knew what was being threatened. What was being implied. The Chapter had lost much, and now Mortirex threatened one of their remaining Recruiting Worlds. Not only that either, Gabriel realized immediately. The Knights of Trontiux had departed as well.

"Face me and defend them! Or flee, and let them die. Either way, there shall be a death debt paid!"

A final laugh came through the message before the astropath collapsed in a seizure. Justinius frowned as he walked over to the rest of the Chapter Command.

"The Tarot and our own rituals have borne out the same message, brothers," the Chief Librarian said tiredly. "The Warp is curdling, churning, as Ulkair grows stronger. Travel and messages are slowing ever more. Within a few more months..."

"What are you saying, Justinius," Apollo growled.

Gabriel only sighed, for he had already realized the problem.

"Any ships we send to defend Trontiux will not be able to return in time, whether we or the daemon is victorious," Justinius shook his head. "We can send a message to Sector Command, but when and whether they will respond given the chaos spreading across the Sector..."

"He seeks to weaken us further, before his own slaves even arrive," Cyrus growled.

"And yet, to leave a Recruiting World undefended...," Nero murmured.

All eyes turned to Gabriel.

Choose:
Either way, a message will be sent to Sector Command. Moratorium for 6 hours. Furthermore, the Knights of Trontiux have sworn oaths on their honor and names and legacies to defeat Ulkair here and now. They cannot depart the system before the battle is won or at least fought, by the words of their High King. The Lost Rosetta are not under Chapter authority, and you aren't telling Canoness Superior Tenenbaum to leave when UIkair is here. The Meridian Regiments are here to fight for Meridian and Subsector Aurelia, they aren't leaving either. Meridian is THEIR Homeworld and sole Recruiting World. Blood Ravens are being sent, or no one is. The Scarlet Lions specifically came here to fight Ulkair as well, but it is possible that they could be convinced to somehow abandon the main fight and their close allies, for they recognize the importance of a Recruiting World. However, if forces are sent, it could have dire consequences for Subsector Aurelia if the servants of Ulkair prove too strong.

[] Send Aid to Trontiux [Write-In Forces Sent]
[] Do Not, and Bear the Burden On Thy Souls Forevermore

Added Allies
Canoness Superior Margaret Tenenbaum of the Lost Rosetta
600 Elite Celestian Sororitas of the Lost Rosetta
200 Elite Seraphim Sororitas of the Lost Rosetta

1st Meridian Consolidated [Elite Heavy Infantry/Mechanized Regiment]
2nd Meridian Consolidated [Elite Heavy Infantry/Mechanized Regiment]
3rd Meridian Consolidated [Elite Artillery Regiment]

Turn 25 Results - 2482 - Part 3

Spoiler: Voting results [X] Battle: Surreptitious Intervention [X] Karak: Windherder [X] Personal: Xeno-Affinity Battle: Surreptitious Intervention Twice now, fate has thrust you into the position of commander. You, however, have no intention of respecting fate's opinion on the matter. You can do the most good placing your eyes and blades where they're least suspected and most useful, leaving matters of command and high-level strategy to those that have dedicated their lives to it. Added trait: Unseen - Unless specifically on the lookout for magical infiltration, active defences are no obstacle to you. +2 Intrigue. Master Infiltration (1/4) Karak: Windherder For Wizards of the Colleges, when it comes to using multiple winds in concert, the short version is 'don't', and the long version is 'no, really, don't, Articles 4 and 7, don't make us burn you'. This is because if you need to ask, the answer will always be no. For those with keen windsight, a solid grasp of the fundamentals, and the right contributors, the answer becomes a very cautious 'don't make us come over there'. Making the Winds work in harmony is still far beyond you, but if you're careful and give the Winds enough room, it is possible to make them work in symphony. Added Magic skill: Windherder - You've developed an intuitive grasp of how Winds interact, when they'll interfere with each other, and when they'll mix and curdle into Dhar. Makes basic multi-Wind Enchantment and Spellcasting possible, as long as other Wizards provide the other Winds. Personal: Xeno-Affinity Most citizens of the Empire hate and fear the unknown, from Wizards to Halflings to those that merely come from other provinces. Your experiences have broadened your horizons far beyond this. You've lived amongst the Dwarves, been a staunch ally to the Halflings, forged an alliance with the hive-mind of the We, and even somewhat befriended the Skaven known as Qrech. You are intrigued, rather than repelled, by the unknown. Added Diplomacy skill modifier: Xeno-Affinity - Basic and Advanced skills for non-Imperial cultures require 2/2 rather than 3/3. Blooded folded into Master Swordswoman. Advanced Colleges of Magic (2/3) Empire of Man (2/3) Halflings (2/2) Skaven (2/2) Strategy - Dwarf (3/3) Ulric (1/3) --- [Hunger Wood campaign: 77 vs 13] The past few months have been incredibly tumultuous, and though you've been doing your best to juggle matters, there's a couple of balls you've been forced to park in mid-air until you had a spare minute to process them. The EIC reports were an easy matter to shelve, but you're still slightly nervous when you finally snatch a few moments to process your backlog and are relieved to find the news is all good. Roswita may have shown her inexperience in the overly-ambitious three-pronged assault, but with the campaign devolved into a much more basic brawl the Army of Stirland has found its feet and stamped out the Strigoi, with one confirmed dead and interred at Siegfriedhof, one cannibalized by a rival and probably out of the picture for at least a while, and a third fled the Hunger Wood with its army shattered. The Battle Wizards put in a decent showing, avoiding any major miscasts while still providing solid contributions to each major battle, and the Stirland Repeater's first substantial deployment was an overall success, with maintenance and logistical concerns outweighed by the sheer weight of fire it was capable of putting out at a moment's notice. Closer to home, the Undumgi are jubilant with the full reclamation of the Karak, with the men looking forward to their peaceful retirement of patrolling a mountain pass dominated by friendly cannon and the Eye of Gazul. News has trickled north and you've begun to see the trend you've long predicted and hoped for: the beginning of significant human civilian immigration to the Karak, a majority of which are unmarried women. With the Karak no longer an active warzone and the Blood and Skull Rivers full of Barak Varr transports, there's a strong argument to be made that travelling to Eight Peaks is a fair bit safer than remaining in the Border Princes. You skim past a number of reports on the expanding demand for both staple goods and minor luxuries, and with the EIC and Karag Nar's Viceroy acting in harmony, all outsiders have been shut out of those developing markets as the EIC supply the raw materials and enterprising Undumgi lay down their pikes in favour of various tools. While increasing EIC dominance is good for you, your real concern here is that they maintain the strange hybrid culture of the Undumgi which you suspect to be vital to long-term close-quarters harmony between man and Dwarf. Finally, the Gunnery School has set up its foundational facilities in Karag Nar, providing formal artillery drilling to the Undumgi and the facilities to maintain the arsenal of weaponry watching over Death Pass. A clever investment on Nuln's part, considering this practically guarantees that artillery will be foremost in the minds of the Undumgi as they expand their stranglehold of the Pass, and you predict cannon at least atop Karag Zilfin and the entrance to the Ulrikadrin Underway. The Undumgi have tried to label it Karag Ulric, and though it might read as such in their patois, a Dwarven reader of the Klinkarhun runes they're using - ᛉ ᛞ ᚱ ᛉ ᛕ - would be more likely to pronounce it 'Alric'. You smile and pen a short note to your Magister Patriarch so he can let his Light College counterpart know of his inadvertent immortalization before moving on. --- [Communicating knowledge: ??+??+/-??=68.] [Communicating values: ??+??+/-??=42.] The We are your next major concern, and you check in with the Priestess who has been working amongst them for the past year. Her main concern and the first thing she reports is that although she hasn't quite managed to convert them to Esmerelda, she has managed to conceptually extend their fundamental communalism into an appreciation for more artificial collectives, and that based on this understanding it has requested to become part of the Karak-We. You're still not entirely sure how that would technically work, but you're pleased with the development nonetheless. What you see as a more significant development is that the Priestess has managed to communicate, in one form or another, the concepts required for them to enter into an informed trade relationship. From the understanding that the Karak-We-Not-We were unable to produce silk of their own, they were able to grasp the idea that the unique labour of their stomach and their spinnerets had added value to the protein they had digested, and therefore that silk was more valuable than the protein that eating it would provide. The obvious question from there is 'how much more valuable', and the We had considered and ultimately rejected a great deal of economic theory in favour of a much more easy to grasp 'twice as valuable'. Twice the weight in protein, or roughly eight times it in live animals. To your surprise, they've been keeping their own records, though not of silk supplied - instead, they've been recording the number of meals the Dwarves have provided, both from directing them to battlefields to have their pick of the dying and from the Rangers and their habit of turning over captives to the We. They're insisting on giving the Karak credit for these, as well as for any future enemies of the Karak-We turned over. They've also grasped the concept of a medium of exchange, though they see the gold coins more as an idiosyncratic method of recording debts than they do something with value of its own, and you have a quick word with Princess Edda, and a quick reconciliation later leads to a small pile of golden coins turned over to the We, who carefully weave it into a rather pretty tessellation on one of the walls of their hive. This opens up a few different options in the current problem facing them: that what was once an extremely rich hunting ground is now filled only with their allies. The We are currently surviving by preying on the rats left behind by the Skaven, but these are bite-size for the We and the Dwarves are doing their best to exterminate them, and they're starting to have to fall back on food stores. Under normal circumstances, this would call for a 'no-food' - a migration. These are, however, far from normal circumstances, and the We do not wish to bid farewell to their newfound friends. You sit down with the Weaver currently wearing the Ivory Circlet on one leg, and begin to discuss the possibilities. [ ] [WE] Hunt the Badlands Something that eventually translates as a 'Hunter's Highway' could be constructed through tunnels from the current nest to the Western Gate, allowing the Hunters to move swiftly and easily to the west and explore the Badlands. The prey concentration is low and there's less opportunity for ambushes, but a giant spider is still a giant spider and they'd make a terrifying addition to the nocturnal ecosystem of the Badlands. As a side-benefit, this would teach the greenskins of the Badlands to give the Karak a wide berth. [ ] [WE] Hunt the Mountains The sheer cliffs, gloomy valleys and dark caves of the mountains are no obstacle to the We, and there's enough wildlife in the surrounding mountains to keep the We fed. Though it means they wouldn't be feeding on enemies of the Karak, it could provide an early warning of any new neighbours moving into the area. [ ] [WE] Scavenge the Gauntlet Though it's become less of an attempted invasion and more of a source of entertainment to the greenskins forcing their less-favoured underlings to throw themselves against the Dwarven defences, the Underway passage from Black Crag to Karak Eight Peaks is still a constant flow of greenskins. Though they're unlikely to make any real contribution as the battle is one of logistics rather than martial ability for the Dwarves, it will keep them reliably and safely fed, and they will be crediting most of those meals to the Dwarves. [ ] [WE] Bounty System Not all the Undumgi are ready to settle down, and there's always mercenaries and glory-seekers coming and going. Apart from the obvious benefits of keeping the We fed and killing a lot of greenskins, this would bring a lot of mercenaries to the Karak while keeping them busy enough to stay out of trouble. [ ] [WE] Economic Integration Eight pounds of live animal becomes one pound of raw silk. This is an extremely simple problem to solve. Start importing live produce and paying the local hunters to start setting snares and digging pits. --- On top of the matter of the We and the debts they're owed, you also have your own debt to consider: a Boon from King Belegar that is practically limitless in scope. Spent well, this could catapult you in power, or influence, or comfort. Spent unwisely, this could beggar the Karak. You're torn between salivating at the possibilities and quailing at the responsibility. [ ] [BOON] I know just what to spend it on... If this wins, I will take submissions in one vote and have a final vote on what the boon will be after that. [ ] [BOON] Save it until the Karak is wealthy enough to afford my ambition. [ ] [BOON] Save it as a trump card to exploit an opportunity or address an emergency. [ ] [BOON] I have no idea what to spend it on. Put the matter aside for now. Penthouse The four with the most votes will win. [ ] [ROOM] Vault To keep safe your wealth, your secrets, and your miscellaneous esoterica. [ ] [ROOM] Shrine to Ranald The room where you mugged Mork with Him is all well and good, but something convenient and private might be nice. [ ] [ROOM] Explosives Laboratory A room with enough reinforcement and baffles to withstand all but the most inadvisable of experiments. [ ] [ROOM] Training Hall A room for mastering martial combat, including a sparring area. [ ] [ROOM] Firing Range A room for training and trialling firearms and ranged offensive spells. [ ] [ROOM] Provision Room A room filled with provisions and water sufficient to sustain a single person (and their dog) for a year. [ ] [ROOM] Armoury A room filled with mostly-ranged weapons, suitable to equip a substantial force to defend the Penthouse from attackers from below or from the skies. [ ] [ROOM] Trophy Room Your collection of mementos is growing large and impressive enough to deserve a room to itself, complete with tasteful little plaques describing the circumstances under which you acquired each piece. [ ] [ROOM] Guest Room For when you have visitors; can fit three comfortably, or up to six if enough of them are on good terms with each other. [ ] [ROOM] Wolf's Room He sleeps at the foot of your bed, but he'd probably appreciate a room of his own for midday naps and playing with the wolf-rats. [ ] [ROOM] Gyrocopter Hangar Includes a retractable landing pad and a reinforced outer door that cannot be easily distinguished from stone from the outside. The Eye is less accessible from here than it would be to a balcony landing pad. Library Purchases Budget: 300gc, 2 Dwarf Favour. Anything not spent will not accumulate. [ ] [LIBRARY] No purchase. [ ] [LIBRARY] Write-in. Dwarf Favour Purchases [ ] [DWARF] No purchase. [ ] [DWARF] Write-in. College Favour Purchases [ ] [COLLEGE] No purchase. [ ] [COLLEGE] Write-in. Other Purchases [ ] [PURCHASE] No purchase. [ ] [PURCHASE] Write-in. - There will be a four hour moratorium. If there's a room you think should be added, now's the time. - I know this format for the Boon vote isn't ideal, but nor would be the inevitable deadlock of people preference voting '[*] What I want [*] Don't spend it', or the rapid-fire tactical vote-switching if I disallow preference votes. The three 'don't spend it now' options are to determine when I will raise the matter again. - If there's anything else you think I might have forgotten, do remind me. I haven't forgotten the vaults; they will be part of the council meeting.

Turn 26 - 2482.5 - From Revanche to Revamp

Spoiler: Voting results [*] [BOON] Save it until the Karak is wealthy enough to afford my ambition. [*] [ROOM] Vault [*] [ROOM] Guest Room [*] [ROOM] Wolf's Room [*] [ROOM] Shrine to Ranald [*] [WE] Scavenge the Gauntlet [*] [LIBRARY] Linguistics (Dwarf Antiquarian), The Eonir of Laurelorn (Imperial Extensive & Esoteric, Dwarf Extensive), Waystones (Imperial Extensive, Dwarf Extensive) [*] [COLLEGE] 5 favors for a full translation of the Cathayan books [*] [DWARF] Have a Grandmaster Engineer have a go at the Stirland Repeater - 8 favors [*] [PURCHASE] No purchase. Eventually, you and the representative of the We decide on the Gauntlet between Karak Eight Peaks and Black Crag as their new primary source of food, which would let them retain their current habits as Hunters without depending on a barren and exposed hunting ground. You're torn on the matter of accounts, since part of you sees it as an advantage that the Karak will be credited for the deaths they'll be causing anyway and part of you feels like it's taking advantage of the We, but the price that's been set for their silk means even if they're unable to pick off any greenskins on their own and every scrap of food is credited to the Karak, they'll still be generating a profit for them to accumulate or spend as they see fit. With her task complete, the Priestess of Esmerelda is released from the Karak's payroll, but she mentions that she'll still be visiting them between her responsibilities to the Halflings because she feels there's still a possibility of making a conversion. It feels like something of an abandonment to you, but the We have the means at their disposal to take charge of their own education, and purchase books and the services of teachers as they see fit. They are sentient beings - or, arguably, one single sentient being - and they now have the freedom to chart their own course in life. --- After sending off the Cathayan books to be translated and sending word to Zhufbar via Prince Gotri about the Stirland Repeater, you turn your attention to your Penthouse. The third subbasement takes shape in a chorus of grumbling from Dwarven stonemasons displeased at leaving one room unfinished, but you're able to redirect the most unhappy to building the Vault which gives them a lot of satisfaction, and for the rest, Wolf's involvement in his own room makes it very easy to conceal the matter in a smokescreen of confusion as they act according to his whims and your direction. At first glance the room is a charming interior pond ringed with hardy Dwarven grass capable of surviving on reflected sunlight, and the elevation of the room above its neighbours is easy to assign to said pond. But underneath the soil is a warren of concealed chambers, some dedicated to comfort but one dedicated to a set of controls for Wolf to operate the Penthouse's defences from safety, and entrances to it are found not only hidden in the glade above but also concealed in adjoining rooms. You quickly become accustomed to him and his wolf-rat pack appearing and disappearing according to their whim, but you look forward to the effect it might have on anyone that braves your guest room in the future. The Shrine is tricky. Considering the security your Penthouse requires, you can't simply fill it with gamblers and cats and call it a day. But on what might be a whim, you asked a question or two of the local Rangers about the black-feathered and yellow-beaked birds you've seen alighting on your balcony to chirp at you and try to convince you to share your snacks and ale, and learn of the mountain chough, a cousin of the crow that makes its nests far higher than most birds can reach. A concealed opening is excavated with a thick steel grate just large enough to allow through these birds, and around a life-size wooden depiction of a crow carved by Qrech, the choughs cautiously begin to explore the sheltered little nooks and the trickling waterfalls of clean water that line the walls. A week later the first nest had begun construction, and taking inspiration from the mated pair, you send word and a few coins to the University of Altdorf's oft-neglected Division of Arts. After being startled by a few sketched proposals that lean hard into reinterpretations of the nature of Shallya's Tears and the Goblet they were drunk from, you commission a lovely painting of Ranald and Shallya sitting together in a field, surrounded by a mixed flock of crows and doves, and when it arrives you hang it across from the laudably fidelious choughs. You've heard several versions of the story of Ranald's ascension, and several of them don't sit very well with you. You'd very much prefer to believe the best of your oldest friend. --- For the first time, King Belegar sits at the head of a meeting of the Council with a completed crown. Once, you would have believed that this King Belegar would have been one reborn, with the four thousand year Grudge of his family finally righted. But if anything, King Belegar is more bound by duty now than he ever was. He is responsible for more citizens of the Karak every day, and he has a responsibility to the Karaz Ankor as well, to his seven fellow Kings and to his High King. With the War for Karak Eight Peaks won, King Belegar's duty has only become more complicated. The meeting takes place once more in what has come to be labelled the Room of Riven Stars, centered by the table built from the fragment of the former ceiling of the Hall of the Moon, which is no less meaningful for being a symbol of the abstract stakes rather than the immediate danger. "Needless to say," he begins, "the past months have been tumultuous. Everything changed in a single day, and thanks to every Dwarf and man and Halfling but especially thanks to Loremaster Mathilde, we did not only survive, but we have won. The Karak is ours." There is a circle of emphatic nods from everyone in attendance, and you bask in the understated but very real approval from your fellow councillors. "First things first: keeping what we've retaken. Thane Dreng?" "We have three immediate threats," he says. "The first is Black Crag, centered upon what is being called the Gauntlet. The greenskins have stopped attempting in earnest to storm the defences, but they still constantly probe it with those that end up on the losing end of internal squabbles. It will need to be guarded and fortified for the foreseeable future. Second, and much harder to defend against, are the Skaven. We don't know how likely they are to return, which Clans might make the attempt, or what direction they might come from. All I can do about it is set patrols through the lowest levels of the Karak. Third is the dragon, and now that it's awake I've asked for permission to take precautions against-" "We'll not provoke the beast if we don't have to," King Belegar says firmly. "As you say. Most of the rest of our efforts have been on restoring the Karak's overland defences." "Continue with that. The West Gate is going well, but don't neglect the Southern Sentinels or Morzund's Wall. When Karaz-a-Karak's Okral arrives, put them to work restoring them and turn your eyes downwards, start mapping out what needs to be dug and what needs to be filled in to minimize possible approaches and improve response times. Speaking of the dragon, Prince Kazrik?" "I've found a definitive match in the records of Barak Varr." "Blast. What did it do?" "Records, not Grudges. There's an archipelago off the coast of Araby they call the Sorcerers' Islands. A few centuries after Barak Varr razed Ulthuan's colony on them during the War of Vengeance, the dragon made its home there. For three hundred years, anything the Naggarothi had short of a Black Ark had to go all the way around the western side of Ulthuan, because if they passed between Ulthuan and Araby they'd either go too far east and be assaulted by the dragon, or too far west and run aground on the Shifting Isles. Eventually it either left or was driven out by Araby, but for a long time it was an important strategic advantage over the corsairs." "It never attacked a Dwarven ship? And that's all you can find on it?" "Only ever the Naggarothi. And there's not many Ice Dragons in any records of the Karaz Ankor, and they all tend to be fairly distinctive. That's the only time we've previously encountered it." "That takes away some of my misgivings. When the Okral arrives, concentrate on getting them settled in and to work, and make sure there's no trouble between them and us. Some of the major figures in Karaz-a-Karak's guilds have a sense of superiority towards the other Karaks. Prince Gotri, how went your project?" "It would have done a great deal to secure our parts of the Karak against the other forces within it," he says, only a slight grumble to his voice. "But it is absolutely unsuited for defending the entirely retaken Karak. So I've archived the blueprints." "Such is war," King Belegar says. "Are you happy with the defences of the Gauntlet?" He ponders that for a while, with an Engineer's natural distaste for declaring anything sufficient. "It would be more secure with flame cannon," he eventually says. "But I can't imagine a frontal assault succeeding against that weight of lead." "Good enough for me. Expand the Gyrocopter hangars, and when the Okral arrives, put the Engineers to work on building up it and the Aircorp. Maybe we won't need them against the dragon, but we'll soon be looking beyond our Karak and I want the tools to intervene quickly and effectively. Princess Edda?" "The Barrows are fully mapped and cleared, it had only the usual mountain beasts. We've begun to extract ore, which we're stockpiling." Her tone is not quite discontent, but there's a tone of a question in it. "The Okral will be restoring the smelters of Karag Mhonar. Take charge of the Miners and Prospectors amongst them, and plumb and restore the old mines - Flamestone and Ghuzhur first, Uzkul and Diamondhelm after. Nothing will draw settlers like ore waiting for picks. Gunnars, is the Temple of Grungni complete?" "Physically," he says. "The dedication ceremony is awaiting the arrival of a High Priest amongst the Okral." "Very well. Turn to Karag Mhonar, see if the old Temple to Smednir there can be restored, and if it can't, build one anew." "And Valaya, your majesty?" Gunnars asks carefully. "Valaya's flock currently resides in Grimnir's Karag. When Karag Rhyn is restored, so too will be Her Temple." "Valaya is patient," Gunnars says, in what would be approval if he hadn't very carefully avoided saying anything that could be considered a judgement of the King's decision. Finally, King Belegar turns to you. "Mathilde, a lot has changed of late, but the importance of your current task has not. Continue with it." Curiosity is plain on the faces of your fellow councillors, but everyone refrains from asking. --- While that's the end of the formal Council meeting, King Belegar announces that he will be breaking the seals on the surviving treasure vaults, and all present are welcome to come and watch. After that, it would take siege weaponry to pry any of the Dwarves away from King Belegar's side, and you're more than a little curious yourself. The Council seems to transform before your eyes into children on Sigmartag, as they enthusiastically speculate on the contents, passing on legends and rumours they'd heard. "The Hall of Ghosts was emptied during the Time of Woes," King Belegar says as you walk through the echoing halls of Karag Zilfin, "and the vaults of Karag Rhyn collapsed under what looks like an attempt to break in - our miners are working on it." "They say they're enjoying the novelty of taking a pick to stone and finding the contents already smelted and minted," Princess Edda says with a smile. "Someone - probably Clan Skryre - broke into Karag Zilfin's Treasure Vaults, but they didn't complete the job. Kragg theorizes that so many Skaven died while they were breaking through the layers of defences that by the time they got to the last few chambers, any attempts to use their Techno-Sorcery caused the dead to manifest and attack their former Clanmates, and without it they couldn't breach any further Runes." You consider the amount of ambient Dhar that the Skaven looters would need to be leaking for the souls of the restless dead to start manifesting on that scale, and wince. "It's been at least a few years since their last attempt, so since Morrslieb is waning and as long as no magic is used, it should be safe." The Hammerers flanking your procession don't seem to find that sufficient comfort, and they take some time sweeping the Vaults before giving you all the nod to clamber in over the rubble. The floor is black with old blood and bone fragments crunch underfoot, and here and there empty stone chests and shattered steel doors tell a clear story. But towards the back of the almost-emptied Vaults, a great deal of scorch-marks and the twin scents of scorched flesh and curdled magic show where Skaven avarice finally failed. Runes glow sullenly at your approach, but fade at a touch from King Belegar, and a muffled creak and whine within the walls tells of metal devices coming to life after millennia of dormancy. The door swings jerkily outwards, and under the collective stare of his Council, King Belegar walks inside. The romantic view of treasure is a chest haphazardly heaped with golden coins to the point of overflowing, but only the greenskins are so cavalier with storing their wealth, and everyone sensible keeps theirs neatly stacked and counted. Dwarves take it one step further, with shelf after shelf of carved grooves for cylindrical stacks of coins to nestle neatly within. At least half of them are empty, but the remainder still contain the gleam of gold, untarnished by the passage of time, in more than sufficient quantity to plump out the storage racks of the current treasury. King Belegar takes one of the stacks and considers it for some time, before returning to the doorway and passing a coin to each of you. Looking down, you find yourself returning the disapproving gaze of a Dwarf who, judging by the coin's inscription, is High King Gotrek Starbreaker. "Two hundred years of war, and still there were coins unspent," he says sadly. "We have so far to go to match the glory of the past." --- Gold is all well and good, but outside of the opinion of numismatists, the gold of the ancient past spends no better than one forged and stamped in Barak Varr yesterday. The Vault of Ancestors proves to be an equal disappointment, as you were hoping for ancient Runic weapons and instead found it full of furniture that was antique before the Karak fell, and though you understand that this 'wutroth' is important to the Dwarves you can't really match the excitement of your fellow councillors over carpentry. So as you make your way to the third stop, your expectations have been well and truly tempered and you're mentally planning for the rest of your day instead of getting worked up over what might be concealed in the hidden vaults of the Grand Urbaz - the trade hall that once played host to merchants from the rest of the world. The only thing keeping a flicker of curiosity burning is that King Belegar left the others to continue cooing over the antiques, so now it's only the two of you. "It was sealed two hundred years before the Skaven attacked," King Belegar says, "and they never unsealed it. I understand their reasoning, but..." he shrugs. "Do you know what it contains?" "Oh yes," he says. "I left it last for a reason. Didn't even suspect it would still be here until the Ranger I sent just in case reported back, I had assumed it would have been looted, as it didn't have nearly the calibre of Runic protections of the other Vaults, so it was a surprise to hear it was untouched. Nobody even suspected it was there, I suppose." You wait for him to continue and tell you what it contains, but when he falls silent again you refuse to take the bait, simply following him as he walks through the Hall that was still scattered with the remnants of Skaven occupation. You pass through a smaller hall that once might have been a foyer, then through a room still filled with enormous stone desks, and then through a narrow corridor with booths at either side you're pretty sure were once checkpoints. The corridor ends in a T-junction, but King Belegar ignores both branches in favour of considering the sigil of Clan Angrund. "Normally, trade is done by representatives of the Guild in question," he says, "but trade with non-Dwarves doesn't fit into that mould, so it was a matter for the Royal Clan. Kept second sons busy." He draws his hammer, and holds it against the larger depiction of it in the oversized sigil. For a long while nothing seems to be happening, but King Belegar's patience holds you there watching him, and eventually there's a click, and then a loud, echoing boom that shakes the ground beneath you. Slowly, the sigil rolls to one side, and with no ambient Dhar in the air you take the liberty of throwing out a Magic Light into the darkness within, and what you see freezes you in place. The wealth of Treasure Vaults was impressive, but you'd seen larger amounts - you'd slept on larger amounts. But the hall revealed is enormous and resembles a library, except with riches instead of books, and instead of uniform stacks of coins it takes every form imaginable - coins of all kinds of metal, ingots of a dizzying array of shapes and sizes and compositions, a rainbow of precious stones, each portion of wealth neatly demarcated from its neighbours. With every movement sending echoes through the long-empty hall, you walk towards the closest and consider the modest stack of gold, and the carved stone token in front of it. Ea-Nasir it says, using the stilted form it uses when phonetically spelling non-Khazalid words. Copper merchant. Tylos. Account opened 11.5.2702. "We were second only to Karaz-a-Karak, and we were much more welcoming to the humans," King Belegar says. "We gave them good prices for food and ore, and sold them weapons and goods at reasonable prices. Many of them came to think that Karak Eight Peaks was the most dependable and defensible place to store their money, from regular craftsfolk to some of their wealthiest nobles and traders. And, I suppose, history proved that trust well-placed." He picks up a coin with a gaunt, fanged face on it. "Strygos fell to greenskins. Tylos to Skaven. Nehekhara to their own Undead ancestors. In the end, we outlasted them all. So we sealed the Vault, and the debate over what to do with it all was put aside when the Skaven attacked us." "I take it you don't intend to rekindle that debate," you say, considering the Classical lettering on the coin. "There is no debate," he says firmly. "Shall I turn the wealth over to the Tomb Kings? To the Strigoi? Or worst of all, consider the Skaven inheritors of Tylos? No. Once the Okral have gone, we will use the smelters they will have built to reforge every coin and ingot, and none will think to question the rediscovered wealth of the Karak." You consider the reputation of the Karak, and of lost Dwarfholds in general, and you nod in agreement. You doubt there's a soul out there that would find anything amiss in the reborn Karak displaying mind-boggling amounts of wealth. --- Mandatory Actions: Pick one from each category. Journeyman Maximilian de Gaynesford, Gold Wizard [ ] MAX: Allow him to spend all his time on his metalworking studies. [ ] MAX: Learn a skill: specify what from who. You may pay for a trainer. [ ] MAX: Learn a spell: specify which. [ ] MAX: Study an artefact: specify which. [ ] MAX: Bring him into the classified study on Warptech and have him assist Johann with the Ratling Gun. [ ] MAX: Write a paper: specify which. [ ] MAX: Receive dictation: specify which. Must be taken with a 'dictate' action. Magister Johann, Gold Wizard [ ] JOHANN: Have him teach Adela what he knows of engineering. [ ] JOHANN: Learn a skill: specify what from who. You may pay for a trainer. [ ] JOHANN: Learn a spell: specify which. [ ] JOHANN: Study an artefact: specify which. [ ] JOHANN: Write a paper: specify which. Wizards of Karak Eight Peaks [ ] DUCK: Work with Panoramia for her to finally get around to investigating the greenskin mushrooms she found. [ ] DUCK: Panoramia's about ready to test for Magister, but she's putting it off because she doesn't have a lot of free time to prepare. Work with her to help make the most of every spare minute. [ ] DUCK: Help Johann train his rat-wolf children. [ ] DUCK: Johann's investigation into the ratling gun has hit a wall. See if you can help. [ ] DUCK: Each of your three ducklings can fight in melee. Spar with them, and teach them what you can. [ ] DUCK: Magical target-shooting is rough on normal targets. Set up a specialized target range for your ducklings, and for any other wizards at Eight Peaks. The Eastern Imperial Company Your outstanding debt: 450 crowns Your share of EIC profits: 175 crowns / turn Current Focus of the EIC: Handgun Factory in Blutdorf (Rollout to Army of Stirland) [ ] Put policies in place that local news should be collected and sent to you (rumour mill). [ ] Found an auditors division, to make sure the ledgers are in order. [ ] Start hiring handlers who can then start hiring informers and begin to collect non-public information. [ ] Reach out to Julia to find out if she's interested in being poached or passing on information. [ ] Reach out to Roswita, and have the EIC start passing on tips about any tax evasion or other naughtiness by the EIC's rivals. [ ] Start building a paramilitary river navy to ensure the coming trade explosion doesn't lead to a similar explosion in riverine banditry. [ ] Sell some of the Grand Urbaz Bank coins to collectors and museums on King Belegar's behalf. [ ] Bring in a Perpetual Apprentice to start grooming as a handler for intelligence matters of the EIC. (1 favour/turn) [ ] Look outside the Colleges for a candidate to start grooming as a handler for intelligence matters of the EIC. Personal Actions: you have four actions you can apply without engaging in overwork. Current overwork status: [ ] [ ] [ ] Each box will be filled by one action of overwork, and will take the two turns after that to fade as you recover. The first box incurs no penalty. The second will give a -10 penalty to all actions during the first turn of recovery. The third will give a -20 penalty to all actions on both turns of recovery. Overwork incurs no penalties on the turns taken, only on the turns recovering from it. You can take as many actions of overwork as you have unfilled boxes. When you use overwork it fills the left-most empty box, so [-][ ][ ] becomes [-][+][ ], not [+][-][ ]. All boxes recover in parallel and independent from one another, but second and third apply maluses on your actions during that cooldown period. Current Task: Queekish [ ] Seek to build a stronger rapport with Qrech, and provide enough sources of mental stimulation that you can turn your attention elsewhere. [ ] Try to convince him outright to teach you spoken Queekish. [ ] Try to deepen your understanding of Skaven warfare. [ ] Use King Belegar's pull to bring in some linguistics experts from the Empire's universities, though after proper vetting and swearing them to silence. Qrech Gambits: (one may be taken for free per action invested in the Qrech category above) [ ] Convince Qrech that you seek an arrangement with Clan Moulder, and that you will release him as an ambassador for that arrangement once you are satisfied he'll cooperate. [ ] Convince Qrech that the Under-Empire has no way of knowing he's even alive, and that he should prioritize the comfort with which he will live the rest of his life. [ ] Convince Qrech you're ambitious and loyal only to yourself, and you're willing to repay his cooperation in ways that will benefit the Under-Empire. [ ] Other (write in) Self-Improvement: [ ] Ask an acquaintance to train you in a skill: specify who and what. [ ] Attempt to learn a spell from scrolls (specify which, will be harder than studying it at the Grey College) [ ] Hire a trainer to come to Eight Peaks and teach you: specify what. (costs favours for Dwarf trainers, money for human ones) [ ] Travel to the Grey College and attend lessons there. (1 College Favour per class; 100gc can be paid instead for non-magical classes) [ ] Attempt to learn Battle Magic at the Grey College. (1 College Favour per attempt) [ ] Gain enough control of your unruly shadow to still it temporarily. [ ] Gain enough control of your attraction to smoke and gases to have it collect away from your face. [ ] Try to see through Pall of Darkness with your improved magical senses. [ ] Practice shooting while invisible. (applies to Substance of Shadow and Invisibility) [ ] Branulhune's ability to disappear and reappear at a thought allows entirely new forms of combat. Try to create them. [ ] Have one of Prince Gotri's pilots teach you to fly a gyrocopter. Research and Publishing: [ ] Study an artefact: select which. [ ] Write a paper: select which. Once per turn, you can write a paper without spending an action thanks to your Tower of Serenity. [ ] Dictate papers: select which two, must be taken with Max's 'receive dictation'. [ ] Investigate how the We communicates with... itself? [ ] Investigate the possibility of using one Wind to directly manipulate another. [ ] The Second Secret of Dhar teaches how to collapse it upon itself. Practice upon local Dhar taint, and very cautiously see if this works with Warpstone. [ ] Try to establish a relationship with the Cult of Verena, with the intent of offering them access to your rarer tomes in exchange for copies of some of their own. [ ] Record all the entries of the Grand Urbaz vaults and select a good-quality example of each minting to save from the smelters. (NEW) Aethyric Vitae (19 gallons): [ ] Investigate the exact circumstances required to induce a transformation. [ ] Investigate how the Vitae reacts to Dwarven magic-dampening Runes. (2 Dwarf favours) [ ] Attempt to interest one of the currently present Runesmiths in the interaction between Runes and Vitae. (Will start at the top and work your way down) [ ] Call in favours to get a specific Runesmith to examine the interaction between Runes and Vitae with you. [ ] Investigate how the Vitae reacts with Divine Magic. [ ] Investigate how the Vitae reacts to a power stone. [ ] Investigate how the Vitae reacts to being subjected to power stone creation methods. [ ] Instead of seeking the secrets of the blood, simply see if it can be weaponized in some way. Enchantment and Spell Creation: [ ] Enchant an item with a Moderately Complicated or easier spell (specify what and which) [ ] Attempt to deepen your skill with Enchantment (will be more difficult than studying it at the Grey College) [ ] Attempt to create a spell (see Approved Spells threadmark) Karag Nar Penthouse: each turn, you get ONE free choice in this category. Additional selections cost actions. [ ] Have a tower built atop Karag Nar: -100gc for 1 room, bonus to room's purpose. [ ] Have additional rooms excavated underneath your Penthouse: -125gc for 5 rooms. [ ] Have a gyrocopter landing pad built into your balcony. [ ] Your dungeon was built with a reasonable amount of paranoia. Apply an unreasonable amount of paranoia. [ ] Add security measures to your Penthouse to prevent forcible entry. Setting up rooms for specific purposes will have to wait until new rooms are constructed or excavated. Only one construction or excavation can take place at a time, but you can do one of each. Building downwards will increase by 1 each time; second set of excavated rooms will be 3 rooms, third will be 4, and so on. Building upwards can be added upon; towers can be added on to or additional towers can be built. The distinction between the two is entirely cosmetic. Foreign Relations: [ ] Join the war between Stirland and the vampires in northern Sylvania. Personal Relations: [ ] Spend time assisting with a fellow councillor's task: specify who and how. [ ] Spend time investigating a character without their knowledge: specify who. [ ] Wolf is fully grown and a Very Good Boy. Train him. (increases his intelligence, he may learn to speak Praestantia) [ ] Wolf is fully grown and very magical. Deepen your familiar bond. (may unlock a new familiar ability; risks obsession) Ranald's Coin - specify which face it will be set to [ ] The Gambler: specify an action this will apply to. A +20 bonus to up to two dice rolls resulting from a single chosen action. [ ] The Night Prowler As long as you are outside of private property and within a town or city, nobody will question your presence and nobody will be able to find you if you do not wish them to. [ ] The Deceiver: specify how this will be used. Lies you have developed beforehand will be delivered perfectly. The listener may believe you to be mistaken, but they will never believe that you are lying. Cannot be used to tell truths. [ ] The Protector When you act in a way that defends an individual or group from a danger that you did not cause, they will become aware of what you have done and will believe you acted selflessly in doing so. Spoiler: Artefacts to be studied Ranald's Coin Vampire skulls Unknown black gem, stolen from the Skaven. Preserved bodies of the Rat Mothers of Clan Mors. Eshin: Throwing star, still dripping venom. Eshin Sorcerer crystal sword. Eshin Sorcerer amulet, shattered. Moulder: Book on the Anatomy of Chaos Dwarves, partially translated. Electric whip, stolen from Clan Moulder. Vials, stolen from Clan Moulder. Captured Clan Moulder devices (as yet uninspected) Skryre: Firearms; jezzails, pistols, bullets, gunpowder. Ratling guns. Warp Lightning Cannon (misfired, possibly broken) Lighting mechanism, stolen from Clan Skryre. (shared project with Adela) Breathing apparatus, stolen from Clan Skryre. (shared project with Johann) Brass orb, stolen from Clan Skryre. Spoiler: Papers to be written Note: Fresh and Refreshed papers confer a +10 bonus; faded ones a -10 malus. Papers get one step less 'fresh' each turn: Fresh; Fading; Mostly Faded: Faded. Only the first and last have an effect on the diceroll. Brief observations on Eshin Sorcery (FRESH) Waaagh energy and magic witnessed during the Expedition. (FADED) The Black Orc Warboss' worship of Only Gork, and what you saw of the Rogue Idol ritual. (FADED) The physiology and venom of the We. (FADED) The psychology and social structure of the We. (FADED) Preliminary paper on Aethyric Vitae. (TIMELESS) Insight on Skaven tactics and strategy, acquired from the Liber Mortis but justified by your current encounters (TIMELESS) Basic Queekish: grammar, signs, common words (TIMELESS) Military lexicon of written Queekish (TIMELESS) Medical lexicon of written Queekish (TIMELESS) Technical lexicon of written Queekish (TIMELESS) Translated text on Chaos Dwarf anatomy (TIMELESS) Translated Eshin correspondence on the Skaven Civil War (TIMELESS) You can literally write the book on a topic for the same amount of effort as two papers; this can be split over multiple turns. You don't need to have all the pieces to do so, but it would be more efficient and impressive if you did. The We (missing: communication method) Queekish-Khazalid Dictionary Queekish-Reikspiel Dictionary - The Boon vote will take place soon after the departure of Karaz-a-Karak's workforce, at the end of Turn 32. Until that vote opens, I ask that everyone winds back debate on the topic. Things are getting more heated than I'd like. - Votes will be in plan format; there is a four hour moratorium. As always, if there's something I've missed or forgotten - and there probably is, because it's been a while since the last regular turn - let me know.

Turn 26 Results - 2482.5 - Part 1

Spoiler: Voting results [*] Plan: Spoken Queekish v4 with Better Max -[*] Contains one Overwork action -[*][MAX] Write a paper: Translated text on Chaos Dwarf anatomy (TIMELESS) -[*][JOHANN] Study an artefact: Unknown black gem, stolen from the Skaven. -[*][DUCK] Johann's investigation into the ratling gun has hit a wall. See if you can help -[*][EIC] Put policies in place that local news should be collected and sent to you (rumour mill). -[*] Seek to build a stronger rapport with Qrech, and provide enough sources of mental stimulation that you can turn your attention elsewhere. -[*] Try to convince him outright to teach you spoken Queekish. --[*] Deceiver: Continue with the Gambit that teaching you Queekish continues to cause discontent in the Grey Order and of course the Grey Order itself already has Queekish... -[*] Travel to the Grey College and attend lessons there: Waystones and Waystone maintenance -[*][AV] Investigate the exact circumstances required to induce a transformation. -[*] Wolf is fully grown and a Very Good Boy. Train him. (increases his intelligence, he may learn to speak Praestantia) -[*][PENTHOUSE] Have a gyrocopter landing pad built into your balcony. -[*][SERENITY] Translated Eshin correspondence on the Skaven Civil War (TIMELESS) -[*][COIN] The Deceiver: Skaven Gambit The coming months are going to involve a lot of time spent in the laboratories, and Max and Johann become the first guests to grace the new bedroom in your Penthouse as they prepare for a deep dive into some of the loot acquired from the Skaven, to the mutual delight of both Wolf and the wolf-rats. Though there's some moderate grumbling from Johann and Max who aren't quite close enough to be entirely pleased with sharing a room, they quickly find that Max's late nights and Johann's early mornings mean they only ever encounter each other in passing, and things quickly settle down into a harmonious peace. The Room of Serenity of late has become dominated by notes and papers in the jagged runes of Queekish and it will only become more so in the coming months, as Max looks to translate the tome on Chaos Dwarf Anatomy and you turn your attention to the correspondence of Clan Eshin. You take the time to sort through the various books captured from what was once Clan Moulder's territory in the hopes they'd be immediately relevant, but apart from a few books for your burgeoning section on Skaven society, the closest to potentially useful are a series on various types of small mammals and the terrible uses that Clan Moulder can put them to. The rest are clearly recreational in nature, and are split between those that give you an intriguing glimpse into what Skaven yearn for, and those that give you a horrifying glimpse into what Master Moulders apparently yearn for. You sort them into your library accordingly and turn your attention to your work. [Mathilde vs Eshin notes Part 1 - Translation: Learning, 70+27+13(Library: Skaven)=110.] [Mathilde vs Eshin notes Part 2 - Politics: Diplomacy, 33+13+13(Library: Skaven)=59.] [Mathilde vs Eshin notes Part 3 - War: Martial, 29+23+5(Strategy - Skaven)+13(Library: Skaven)=70.] The translation of the documents is simple enough, and you're able to construct the various documents into something resembling a single coherent timeline that gives an inside look into the events of the Third Skaven Civil War through a very unique lens, but any further examination is stymied time and time again as most of the letters are to and from individuals already intimately familiar with the names, places, and Clans involved. After using a few drafts to feed the Red Tower, you end up settling for delivering the translations in as accessible a format as you possibly can and leaving the digestion of the information to the diplomats, strategists, and anthropologists of the Empire - or at least to those with sufficient clearance. [The Clan Eshin Perspective of the Third Skaven Civil War. Subject: Rare, +1. Insight: Revolutionary, +2. Delivery: Dull, -1. Exotic, +1. Precious, +1. Alien, +1. Tactically Significant, +2. Classified, -2. Total: 5.] [Max vs Chaos Dwarf anatomy: Learning, 90+18+10(Patient)-10(lacks fluency)+9(Library: Anatomy)=117.] In contrast, Max flies through the tome on Chaos Dwarf anatomy, helped a great deal by having already searched through it and translated every piece of jargon involved. The work contains a wealth of knowledge derived from constant skirmishes between Clan Moulder and the Chaos Dwarves over Zorn Uzkul, and you shudder to think of the amount of test subjects Clan Moulder would have needed to determine the role of every single organ. All the subjects possess the tusks that physically distinguish them from the Dwarves you know, and some possess cloven hooves or horns as well. The most dramatic mutation is that of the Bull Centaur, which are well-documented in the tome, but of most interest to you is the record of the vivisection of a Sorcerer with special attention paid to the petrification that had begun upon his body. His feet and ankles were entirely of stone, and displayed evidence of grouting to repair cracks and chips, but the spread upwards was uneven, with blood vessels completely petrified to the knees and showing increased rigidity as high up as the thighs, even as the flesh above it appeared unchanged. But nothing above the waist showed any signs of the transformation, which provides you with quite a bit of food for thought. Magic as you know it flows primarily through the arms and chest, and under very few circumstances would it concentrate in the lowest extremities of the body. But you know next to nothing of the nature of the magic the Chaos Dwarves use. Is it Divine Magic that flows from below? Is their strange God physical, rather than ephemeral? Would that be related to their affinity for fire and molten rock and metal? If it is Arcane Magic of some sort, do they deliberately push what they cannot expel downwards? Or does something in the nature of it make it obey the call of gravity, rather than flowing through the air like the Winds? Or is seeking a logical answer a fool's errand when dealing with Dark Magic? Too many questions, not enough data. You give the completed translation and the attached metal printing plates your approval and have them sent north for printing and distribution. It's not quite sensitive enough to be classified, but as your colleague Lady Magister Grey has learned, the Chaos Dwarves are just as capable of holding a grudge as their uncorrupted cousins. So the true authors are classified, and anyone without the clearance to learn the truth of the matter from a College librarian will have to be satisfied with directing their gratitude towards Magister Grey and Journeyman Gold. [Anatomy of the Fire Dwarves of Zharr-Naggrund. Subject: Rare, +1. Insight: Revolutionary, +2. Delivery: Compelling, +1. Exotic, +1. Thorough, +1. Varied, +1. Tactically Relevant, +1. Anonymous, -1. Total: 7.] --- The second floor of the White Tower plays host to much less serene studies, as you and Johann turn your attention to your pile of Skaven artefacts. The Ratling Gun has been Johann's focus for years, and it bears the scars of several attempts at exploratory dismantling. You ring the workstation with Johann's stolen blueprints and books on engineering and warpstone, which certainly helped Johann rebuild it after his probings but focus entirely on how to assemble and maintain the devices without going into any of the underlying theory. First things first, you bring your well-developed Windsight to bear on the bulky machine, and immediately regret it. Though the ammunition for it has been removed and safely stored away, the device is dense with absorbed Dhar and immediately gives you the sensation of nausea centered in each of your eyes. You fight back the impossible urge to attempt to vomit from your retinas, double check that the Room is indeed whisking away and safely venting any radiating Dhar, and begin to study it more cautiously. To examine the entire Ratling Gun is a daunting prospect, but based on Johann's previous research, you're able to break it down into a collection of separate mechanisms. Reasoning it would make the most sense to follow the journey the ammunition itself takes, you begin furthest from the gun itself. The backpack mechanism is extremely complex due to the compartmentalization required to keep the huge amount of ammunition it contains from causing runaway reactions, and though it's not a difficult task to puzzle out the mainspring-and-flywheel mechanism, you quickly run into the first of the walls that Johann encountered - the amount of energy the backpack should be capable of storing would rotate no more than a quarter of its cargo out of their compartments, and much less when one takes into account that the flywheels appear to be cannibalizing the device's own motion to feed back into the mainspring. You compare your notes with Johann's, and find them in agreement. You scowl and move on to the next step. The hose that links backpack and gun is made of a black material unknown to you, which somehow has the properties of being both resilient and flexible. An exploratory cut reveals that the material is uniform all the way through, except for abrasions on the inside caused, you assume, by the passage of the balls the Ratling Gun fires. The impetus for the motion is part of the gun itself, where part of the mechanical energy of the crank being turned powers a pair of bellows as well as the gates that route the air; on the exhalation, the air blows down the revolving barrels, presumably to cool them and clear them of any blockages, while the inhalation pulls the shot up the hose. Again, all well and good, but a careful test of the mechanism - with the barrel pointed away from anything fragile, just in case - shows you that the suction is about what you'd expect from a hand-cranked bellows, and considering the weight of the warpstone-infused shot, nowhere near enough to account for the rate of fire. This is Johann's second stumbling point, and he has no more idea than you how to bypass it. The third link in this infuriating chain is the firing mechanism itself, where the hose delivers the warpstone shot to a mechanism twinned to the revolving barrels so that it drops it into a firing chamber as it arrives in the uppermost position. The third of Johann's walls is the most obvious of all: there's no mechanism for delivering gunpowder, just a holding mechanism for a piece of pure warpstone. It's the same sort of thing one often sees in the 'warplock' designs, where a fragment of pure warpstone reacts with warpstone-infused gunpowder, which causes ignition a lot more reliably than flint on frizzen. You're starting to understand how Johann could spend so much time on this and get nowhere. You spend some time watching Wolf and Skufit and the wolf-rats frolic through their park, and then return to the laboratory to grind away at the mystery. You use a freshly-laundered white handkerchief to rub down the interior of the firing mechanism, and do the same with one of the more conventional warplock weapons and a mundane flintlock weapon, and examine all three under a microscope. The handkerchief applied to the two more conventional weapons picked up faint black stains visible to the naked eye, and they looked fairly similar under a microscope, except for the sharp, angular fragments of refined warpstone dust mixed in with the warplock stain. But the handkerchief applied to the Ratling Gun came out clean to the naked eye, and the microscope reveals nothing but warpstone dust. You take the handkerchiefs a safe distance away from the eyeball hazard of the Ratling Gun, and to your Windsight it's quite clear that the dust from the Ratling Gun is of a significantly greater potency than that from the warplock, which suggests an answer. The next experiment is technically a breach of the Articles of Imperial Magic, but it's one covered by Johann's permission slip, so on a clear day with Morrsleib nowhere to be seen the two of you take the warpstone firing crystal and some of the bullets far out into the mountains. You have faith in Kragg's work, but you're also not an idiot, so you use extremely thick gloves to attach the firing crystal to an extremely long stick, and while sheltering behind a rock you clumsily do your best to bring it into contact with one of the bullets, and sure enough there's something almost like an explosion that shatters the stick in your hands and sends the bullet skittering away across the stone. With equal caution, you return the firing crystal to its holder and retrieve the bullet, noting the damage it has taken. Johann was watching its trajectory carefully, and points you towards the stone it rebounded from, none of which is anywhere near as marred as the bullet despite being significantly more fragile than warpstone-infused metal. "All the retrieved shots we've studied have similar markings, and nobody thought anything of it," you part-explain, part-vent to Johann on the way back. "Propelled by an explosion and into metal or bone or what have you, of course it would be damaged. But this one has the same markings even though it only bounced around the place." "So the shot itself explodes," he says. "Why only part of it?" "It's not..." You pause, and consider what an explosion technically can and can't be. "It's an explosion, but it's not an ignition explosion. The part of the shot closest to the firing crystal is flash-decaying into Dhar, and my best guess is when it transforms from solid warpstone to intangible Dhar, it goes through a gaseous phase, and the gas would have much more volume than the solid warpstone." "Like a steam mechanism," Johann says. "Except boiling warpstone instead of water." He frowns as he considers that. "That's insane." "Effective, though," you admit. "No wonder you couldn't figure it out. It's a warpstone reaction, and nobody's stupid enough to use Tale of Metal or Breach the Unknown on warpstone." "You'd be surprised," is his somber response. "We have a wing at Frederheim from that sort of thing. I had to serve six months there as an Apprentice." At your return, you work your way back through the machine based on this new understanding of the firing mechanism, and the firing chamber being horrifically dense with vaporizing warpstone provides the key to unlocking the other mysteries. Dhar calls to Dhar, and in sufficient quantities it would be more than enough to draw in warpstone-infused shot. The crank only needs to begin and sustain the reaction, not power it entirely, and after the first few bullets have been fed through the backpack mechanism, the magical draw on the rest can be tapped into to restore the flywheel to full power once more. It is an absolutely Skaven machine: cunning elegance built around a core of pure insanity. And, unfortunately, completely reliant on warpstone. You pen your notes and sketch a few charts of the full workings of the device, as well as jot down a few ideas on how one might throw a wrench into the works. [Learning, 54+27+20(Windsage)+9(Library: Warpstone)=110.] --- Johann's research into the gem hits an early stumbling block after he cast a spell on it, froze up, and staggered out of the laboratory. For the next week, he refused to do anything productive and had his wolf-rats fetch him food. "Just once," Johann says to you after emerging, "just once I'd like to cast Tale of Metal and find myself watching a master craftsman explaining the process to an apprentice or something. Not experience two hundred semisubjective years of the life of the world's most boring tree." You turn your gaze to the black gem. "It's... what, a fruit?" "Charcoal, I guess. It was growing at the base of a volcano, and the volcano eventually erupted. Immediately afterwards people appeared - Cathayan or Nipponese by the look of them - and dug the tree out of the solidified lava, found a piece of it they liked, and cut and shaped it like a gemstone, which is when the spell ended." He sighs and grimaces. "At least the birds were nice. I named them." An exchange of letters with the Natural Historians of the University of Altdorf confirms that no tree of that description exists within the Old World, but they strongly believe it to be a relative to the mulberry of Tilea. Without anything further to go on, your attention turns to the other spell at Johann's disposal, which he has to spend some time convincing himself to cast. "Oh," he says as the magic sinks into his brain, as he frowns and screws his eyes shut. "Oh, that's got a lot of foreign concepts tied into it. Oh, I don't like that." He stands up and walks around the room on shaky legs. "Emperor Luitpold is a person, right?" "Yes," you say cautiously. "Then I guess we can confirm this as Cathayan, because my brain is insisting he must be a dragon. Oh, that's going on the cognitohazard list. Okay. It's repellant antimagic, except for Divine magic." "Okay, Arcane antimagic. That's straightforward enough." "Except Divine is- no, it isn't, but according to the system of values that..." He takes a deep breath. "Are you okay?" "It's fine, it's temporary, it will pass, I was trained for this. Okay. Divine and Arcane are - by them - divided differently. They consider High Magic and Dark Magic to be Divine, and other magics to be Arcane." "Antimagic that doesn't work on Dark Magic," you say with a frown. "Yeah, I just scrambled my brain twice for the world's stupidest talisman. I'm going back to bed." You consider the nature of the pseudo-gemstone as Johann totters off, and run it through a few tests of your own, confirming its ability to disrupt Wind magic. Okay, it's effectively irreproducible, completely useless to a Wizard that wants to be able to cast spells, or to a Cleric that wants to channel the power of their God, and offers no protection against the magic used by most of the dark forces of the world. But it's very effective protection against Wind magic and what you think of as Divine magic, and that has value, right? --- What shall you do with the Cathayan Jet talisman? [ ] Gift it to someone as a protective talisman - [ ] Emperor Luitpold - [ ] Mandred von Holswig-Schliestein - [ ] Elector Countess Roswita van Hal - [ ] Governor Wilhelmina Hochschild - [ ] Baron Anton Kiesinger - [ ] Viceroy Francesco Caravello - [ ] Chief Bombardier Oswald Oswaldson - [ ] General Soizic [ ] Send it to the Colleges as a potentially useful trinket - Grants College Favour [ ] Keep it in case it comes in useful later - Feel free to suggest other potential recipients of the Cathayan Jet. Because of its nature, it is useless to Wizards and Divine casters. Because of cultural mistrust, it is unlikely to be appreciated by Dwarves.

Turn 26 Results - 2482.5 - Part 2

Spoiler: Voting results [*] Send it to the Colleges as a potentially useful trinket Pending actions: -[*] Seek to build a stronger rapport with Qrech, and provide enough sources of mental stimulation that you can turn your attention elsewhere. -[*] Try to convince him outright to teach you spoken Queekish. --[*] Deceiver: Continue with the Gambit that teaching you Queekish continues to cause discontent in the Grey Order and of course the Grey Order itself already has Queekish... -[*] Travel to the Grey College and attend lessons there: Waystones and Waystone maintenance -[*][AV] Investigate the exact circumstances required to induce a transformation. -[*] Wolf is fully grown and a Very Good Boy. Train him. (increases his intelligence, he may learn to speak Praestantia) -[*][EIC] Put policies in place that local news should be collected and sent to you (rumour mill). -[*][PENTHOUSE] Have a gyrocopter landing pad built into your balcony. The Empire has no small amount of magical trinkets of questionable provenance and niche purpose to adorn the more open-minded or desperate commanders for pivotal battles, and now the Cathayan Jet will join this arsenal. Perhaps it will make a difference on some battlefield of the near or distant future, or perhaps it will gather dust for your lifetime and beyond. [+2 College Favour] --- With Wolf as able to call upon your mental resources as you are to call upon his, teaching him is simply a matter of encouraging him to call upon those resources when he encounters a situation he doesn't understand, and over time his own understanding will expand from observation. You start with hiding treats, which quickly fails because you're unable to even think too long on the subject without Wolf and his motley pack materializing and swarming you. So you pass on the task to Max and Johann, and every day they conceal some within the Penthouse in little wooden containers that muffle most of the smell of them. So Wolf has to resort to looking beseechingly at Max and Johann, who obliging explain to him where it is - though they deliberately avoid giving any gesture that might indicate a direction. The result is rapid and effective, and every morning Max and Johann give more and more obscure and roundabout instructions that Wolf is forced to develop an understanding of before he can discover where the treats are concealed. [Learning Lingua Praestantia: Learning, 81+27=108.] The next step is significantly trickier. The throat and mouth of a canine is built for howls, growls and barks, not for spoken language, so teaching Wolf to speak any mundane language would have to find a way around that significant obstacle. Lingua Praestantia, however, is no mundane language. It is descended from the tongue of the beings the Elves say shaped the world, and it not only possesses words for concepts alien to Reikspiel, it also resonates with magic in such a way that chants and incantations in it resonate with magic and assist with the shaping of spells, rather than acting as a mere mnemonic device. A much lesser known property of the language is that it works the other way as well - just as Praestantia can shape magic, magic can form Praestantia. Theoretically, any creature with even a sliver of magical ability could learn the cantrips to turn magic into spoken word, but as it requires that creature to already have a solid grasp of the language, in practice it is only of use to Familiars, who have the intelligence and inclination to attempt it in the first place and can use their bond to accelerate the learning process. Normally, it would be a slow and painstaking process for a canine to learn even the simplest of cantrips. Without fingers to gesture or hold physical components or foci, and without a tongue to incant, all the usual crutches for those first starting to learn magic are incompatible and Wolf must leap straight to silent and practically still casting, with only the wagging of his tail to provide a very primitive approximation of a somatic component. But Link of Psyche allows you to transfer your understanding of magic directly from your mind to his and walk him through digesting the alien concepts involved, and a few patient weeks eventually leads to him being able to 'cast' words. He's never likely to be a chatterbox - it's just not in his nature to use words to communicate what a wagging tail or a warning growl could more succinctly encompass - but this does give him the very useful ability to nearly-instantly relay information for you. --- Perhaps Qrech has truly resigned himself to making the most of his situation, or perhaps he simply acts that way as he awaits an opportunity. Perhaps it doesn't make a difference. But as you look upon the room that was once a bare stone chamber and is now lined with shelves filled with the beings and beasts of the near east, and listen to him explaining the name and history of the newest additions, you feel confident that at least part of him is happy here, and you set yourself to the task of making that happiness sustainable without taking up a constant portion of your attention, and also without compromising the security he is to remain within. After a fair bit of thought, some correspondence with the College Secretariat, and a number of conversations with Qrech, you finally settle on something that will keep him occupied and engaged for at least the next few years - an enrolment in a series of University of Altdorf courses on Near Eastern Studies, to take place entirely through textbooks, lecture transcripts, and correspondence with a Professor and a handful of fellow students who have already demonstrated loyalty to the Empire. And just to be sure, Qrech's outgoing mail is to be written in Khazalid and translated by trusted Wizards to prevent the possibility of some hidden message being concealed within them. This would require him to learn Reikspiel to understand the coursework and responses from his pen-pals, but it just so happens you speak it, and this adds a layer of quid pro quo to the gambit you're about to attempt. With the Coin weaving believability into your words, you tell him of opportunities lost where you could have eavesdropped on Mors or Eshin and learned something that could be used against them, but could not comprehend the language well enough to understand, or even to transcribe it and have it translated later. You also bring back up the fictional power bloc within the Grey College, where those with the knowledge of Queekish keep an iron grip on it to maintain their income of influence from doling out translations, and tell of how you aspire to undermine them by learning the language for yourself, and then go on to undermine their monopoly and make them vulnerable to internal politics. Between the Coin and the Skaven worldview, this story is accepted without question by Qrech, who nods along thoughtfully as you tell him of it, and he scratches a dozing Skufit behind the ear as he considers your request. [Rolling...] "To teach you the High Tongue of Skavenblight would be blasphemy," he says at last. "To teach you the Moulder Tongue would be treason. But I would be willing to teach you the Low Tongue, used for Clans to talk to one another, and for the commanding of slaves." You consider this, and finally nod in acceptance. Qrech's mindset, you reflect, is almost entirely recognizable, as you understand his loyalty to his Clan and his Empire. But the part that you need to remind yourself of is that though he is loyal to the Under-Empire as a whole, he holds no loyalty towards any Clan but Moulder, and does not see his efforts to undermine other Clans as working against the interests of the Under-Empire. All resources on the Skaven describe them as treacherous, but perhaps it would be more accurate to describe them as having a different conception of what loyalty means, and holding a belief that internal strife strengthens the whole, rather than weakening it. [Learning Low Queekish: Learning, 72+27+11(Library: Linguistics)=110.] [Language Learned: Low Queekish.] It's said that Queekish relies a great deal on whisker motion, body language, and scents. What that fails to understand is that there is no one Queekish. Written Queekish is monolithic, a linguistic hegemony enforced from the top down by the Grey Seers of Skavenblight, but the 'High' Queekish dialect does not extend beyond the Blighted Marsh, with every Clan possessing its own variant on the language. And when one Clan has to speak to another, they do so in Low Queekish, a language stripped down to the bone for maximum mutual intelligibility - which means no tenses, no genders, no cases, and no nonverbal components. Once you wrap your lips and tongue around the pronunciation of the various sounds in it, learning it comes incredibly simply since you already know the much more complex written language. --- Of the forty or so Wizards attending the first lecture on Waystones, only five are above the rank of Apprentice: yourself, a Bright Magister who won't stop drumming their fingers on their desk, and three Journeymen who must be preparing for their final examinations. Of the Apprentices, Jades and Ambers are the most common, followed by the Amethysts, and only a single Celestial is present. Up at the board, the Gold Perpetual delivering the lecture begins by writing in letters taking up the entire chalkboard: DON'T. "If there is any option available to you that does not involve messing with a Waystone," she intones in a Talabeclander accent, "take that option, for the good of yourself and everyone in the area." The lectures you attend over the coming weeks hammer that point repeatedly, and involve a great many accounts of times this advice was not taken, and the terrible fates that befell everyone unfortunate enough to be in the general area. They also grudgingly give instructions on how to recognize when leaving the Waystone be is not an option, and how to resolve them using rote phrases of Anoqeyån. How to resolve a blockage between two Waystones, how to reconnect a Waystone that has been severed from the Leyline, how to vent an over-accumulation of energies in a Henge. All well and good, and suitable information for Apprentices who will soon be unleashed upon the world and told not to mess with the big magic rocks, but your need is greater and you're unable to get past the deliberate obfuscation built into the lecture. After being rebuffed at office hours, you have a quiet word to Algard, who apparently has already received a note warning him you might be Up To Something on the subject; he pens a reply that says that you are Up To Something with approval from the highest levels, and all assistance is to be rendered. After that, you receive a slightly less frosty reception from the Perpetual Professor, though she does increase how graphic the tales are of times things all went wrong. [Learning about Waystones: Learning, Breakpoints 50/80: 10+27+10(Windsage)+4(Library: Waystones)=51.] [Office Hours: 73+27+4(Library: Waystones)=104.] [Magical Skill added: Waystones and Henges.] Between the now more helpful Office Hours and a set of one-woman field trips to the Henge of the Jade College and the Waystones of the Amber Hills, you manage to grasp the very basics of what Waystones are. The world is criss-crossed with natural channels along which magic flows, and the Waystones act as embankments to contain and deepen those channels. Where multiple Leylines meet, Henges are built to direct the magic towards its ultimate destination - supposedly, but perhaps not necessarily, the Great Vortex of Ulthuan. With your higher clearance, you're also told in private the incantations for tapping into a portion of the power flowing through Waystones, which comes with even more dire warnings as to how terribly that can go wrong. Also passed along is the amount of raw explosive power necessary to destroy a Waystone or Henge, which has been unfortunately necessary from time to time when a blockage has curdled into Dhar somewhere the Empire is unable to hold for long enough to restore the proper flow. Better a one-time Dhar explosion than a permanent and self-restoring font of Dark Magic for the many enemies of the Empire. --- It is all well and good to know that something is flammable, but scientific rigour demands to know the exact flashpoint. Similarly, you are not satisfied with knowing in general terms what can cause the disintegration of Aethyric Vitae. You need to know the exact circumstances under which it will transform. So you settle in for a long and tedious chain of experiments wherein you do the same thing at very slightly different levels over and over until you get a different result. It certainly isn't thrilling, but it is a requirement to be able to engage in future projects with the substance with any degree of safety or confidence. So hour after tedious hour, you find new entries to add to the list. First, the most dangerous and least desirable transformation. Pure warpstone gives a range in yards, refined warpstone in inches. Morrsleib with a clear sky can still trigger it while waning, while an overcast night is only dangerous when Morrsleib is full. A trip into the formerly Skaven territories confirms that ambient Dhar can trigger the transformation, but only at levels equivalent to recent Battle Magic use. You spend some time on equations trying to reconcile these numbers, and confirm that if one assumes Morrsleib is 'merely' a source of ambient Dhar, it should not be anywhere near sufficient for the transformation. But then, Morrsleib has never been merely anything, as the fact that its phase can sometimes be visibly different in places mere miles apart can attest. Now for the more desired transformation. Petty and Lesser Magics are insufficient, even when physically touching the Vitae, which surprises you. The simplest spells require the direct touch of the caster, while the strongest spells you know can trigger it at mere proximity - though seemingly anything that would block line of sight would prevent this. You dutifully calculate and note the exact range for a selection of spells. Magical artefacts only cause the transformation when active, at ranges equivalent to the spells they contain, which simplifies the bookkeeping. Ambient magical energy causes transformation only at significantly higher levels to that of Dhar, which means it should be safe in any mundane situation short of something along the lines of being surrounded by particularly inspired astronomers during a lightning storm. It may not be particularly glamorous work, but the resulting notebook filled with the exact circumstances under which the Vitae will transform is quietly satisfying nonetheless. --- [Rolling for Cathayan Books: 1, 2, 3.] You'd considered the possibility of a full hangar built into the side of the peak, but in the end you decided on adding a landing pad directly to the balcony, which would shave off a few seconds in case of someone needing to reach the Eye of Gazul in a hurry. As local masons and architects freed up by the arrival of Karaz-a-Karak's Okral get to work on that, you turn your attention to incoming correspondence from the Empire, most suspenseful of which is the translations of the Cathayan books. What you find, to your great disappointment but some curiosity, is that the books were apparently a geographic encyclopedia of Cathay, and while some things like their Three Great Rivers and the mountains to the west and oceans to the east are much the same as you're used to, some things raise your eyebrows - the Great Maw, the Baleful Deserts, the Castles in the Sky, the Dragon's Spine. Still, the world is full of curiosities and most of them are a great deal closer than that of Cathay, so you add a new shelf to your library and put them from your mind. [Rolling for Grandmaster Engineer examining the Stirland Repeater: 1, 2] The correspondence from the EIC raises eyebrows as well, as contained within the first trickle of local gossip you've ordered to be collated and passed on, you find the reports from the Gerber-Kiesinger Repeating Rifle Factory as they phase in the recommendations from a Grandmaster of Zhufbar's Engineers Guild. Though he didn't pass on any truly revolutionary information, he did apparently decide that it breached no vows of secrecy for him to get the manlings to stop blowing themselves up quite so damn often while they did what they were already doing, and he introduced the design and some of the tools for smoother-working mechanisms and more reliably airtight seals within the Repeaters. The resulting weapons are no less prone to fouling or resistant to battering, but you suppose to a Dwarven point of view, it's the fault of the Umgi for using substandard powder and not treating their weapons with sufficient care. --- Thus concludes the work Mathilde performed these past months, but not every waking moment was filled with work. With whom did she spend her free time, this past year? The four with the most votes will be chosen, not counting those locked in. [+] The Wizards of Karak Eight Peaks (locked in) [+] Social interaction initiated by someone else (locked in) [ ] Gretel, who's apparently spending her newly-earned wealth to make herself at home. [ ] Adela, to see where she's at in deciding her future. [ ] Hubert, to go deeper into discussion on Ulrican matters. [ ] Elder Hluodwica, High Priestess of Esmerelda and civilian leader of the Eight Peaks Halflings. [ ] Francesco Caravello, proud leader of the Undumgi and possible future Thane. [ ] Oswald Oswaldson, newly-minted Chief Bombardier of the Undumgi. [ ] Soizic, military leader of the Undumgi. [ ] Sir Ruprecht Wulfhart, leader of the frontier town of Ulrikadrin. [ ] The We, to check on how they're settling in to the new arrangement. [ ] Barak Varr, to watch the progress of the canal. [ ] Karak Hirn, to satisfy your curiosity about Prince Ulthar. [ ] Roswita, as she campaigns through Hunger Wood. [ ] Kasmir, to see how he's keeping himself busy in Sylvania. [ ] Wilhelmina, to see how she's going when she's not a terrifying financial juggernaut. [ ] Julia, to see what she has gotten up to as Stirland's most experienced spy master. [ ] The Amber College, to see how your donation of Lustrian eggs is going. [ ] Follow up on your donation of the Skaven organ-vat, and see what has been made of it. [ ] Other (write in) - There will be a one hour voting moratorium. - Feel free to suggest other candidates for social actions, especially any I may have forgotten about.

Turn 26 Social - 2482.5 - Part 1

Spoiler: Voting results [*] The We, to check on how they're settling in to the new arrangement. [*] Wilhelmina, to see how she's going when she's not a terrifying financial juggernaut. [*] Oswald Oswaldson, newly-minted Chief Bombardier of the Undumgi. [*] Roswita, as she campaigns through Hunger Wood. To the surprise of her subjects, the Elector Countess is once more in residence in Eagle Castle, and it takes an examination of the news from the EIC to understand why. Hunger Wood is being constantly patrolled by the Second Division, Tempelhof is firmly under the control of the Black Guard of Morr, and the First, Third and Fourth Divisions are garrisoned in Pfaffbach, Eisigfurt and Regrakhof respectively. The final openly-operating Vampires in Sylvania are hemmed in on all sides. To an amateur eye, it makes no sense that the campaign would be put on hold right when victory seems so close. But it makes perfect sense to those who know a little more about war against practitioners of necromancy. "Sieges are supposed to be a science," Roswita says, frustration thick in her voice as she stares down at a map of the County of Waldenhof. "Food, water, defenders. Circumvallate and wait. They either surrender, or they get slaughtered by their own populace for not surrendering. But that doesn't apply here, not against them. Suffering strengthens them. Casualties reinforce them. They would grow stronger while a besieging force grows weaker." You nod sympathetically, running your eye over the map. Judging by the force estimates, the forces of Mihnea in Mikalsdorf has suffered a great deal of casualties since you made off with a handful of his magical trinkets, while Ioana in Waldenhof has had her forces grow, possibly as a direct result. "Stockpiling, then?" The Army of Stirland grew dramatically in its number of cannon thanks to Anton's actions during the Purge of the Haunted Hills, but it's no simple thing to supply gunpowder to that many hungry guns. "And starving them in the meantime. Metaphorically, of course. 'Of the known Bloodlines, only the Strigoi are content with subsistence; the rest are dependent upon the existing economies of the Empire to supply their needs. The Von Carsteins seek to act as a Nation-State, and have the expenses to match. The Lahmians move within the upper strata of society, and rely upon money to smooth their way. The Necrarchs are forever hungry for new specimens, old tomes, and fragments of Wyrdstone to fuel their experiments. And the Blood Dragons are forever in need of replacements for their arms and armour, and demand the highest quality.'" It has the ring of quotation to it, but you don't recognize the words. "Who said that?" She hesitates, a touch of pink coming to her cheeks. "I did," she says at last. "I was writing a dissertation on it for the Order before all this." You smile as a few things make sense. "Your Steward, the exciseman. You've been putting the theory to practice." She nods, but there's a stiffness to her expression as she does. "It worked. Better than I expected." "Alkharad." She nods. "You weren't just cutting off his hobby materials. You inadvertently undermined his entire project in Teufelheim." She nods. "Until we examined his books, I had assumed it was Vampiric megalomania, an overreaction to an inconvenience. But judging by the prices he was being forced to pay for the luxuries that must have been going towards..." She glances around the room. "The others involved in the project, we were hitting him hard and costing him dearly." The personal meeting room of the Elector Countess of Stirland is possibly the most secure place in the province, but the Templars of Sigmar are almost as thorough at inculcating paranoia as the Grey College. "So now we apply the same to those two Lahmians." You frown and try to recall. There was a time when you could recite the Gazetteer of Greater Stirland from memory, but nowadays that same part of your brain was occupied with more southerly concerns. But Hel Fenn on the map jogs your memory. "Peat," you say. While burned as fuel in some places, most of it ended up in Nuln or the Karaks, where it would be subject to a careful process that, if done correctly, would transform it into peat-coal, a substance that burns as hot and clean as the finest charcoal, but for significantly longer by volume. "Who's buying?" "The roads are ours, but the Stir is not so easily blockaded. The Margravine of Essen has already been pressured by the Chancellor of Hertwig, as he has no desire to see all the hard work in the Dead Wood go to waste, and I know they're not coming as far downriver as Wurtbad. But that still leaves four major cities on the other side of the Stir. So the current battlefield is in Talabeclander courts, not Sylvanian moors." You grimace in sympathy. "Still, if I am defeated there, it will be because they expended some of their dwindling resources on bribes. By the time that plays out, I'll have stockpiled enough gunpowder for us to march on Mikalsdorf and resolve the siege through bombardment instead of starving them out." You nod thoughtfully. "Even then, you must be cautious," you say, in the tone of one imparting sage advice. "The walls of Mikalsdorf will be able to withstand cannonfire better than you might expect, as it is certain that the Vampire will rampire." By the time your words register you're already out the door and halfway through the corridor, but her sigh is still clearly audible, and you can't keep yourself from giggling all the way to your next meeting. --- When you arrive at your scheduled meeting to catch up with Wilhelmina, you're surprised to see a second person waiting for you, and doubly surprised that it's a girl of perhaps eight, dark hair in a neat ponytail and her simple yellow dress only slightly marred by inkstains. "Mathilde," Wilhelmina says, "I'd like to introduce you to my granddaughter, Eike Hochschild." You conceal your surprise with long practice and give the girl a short bow. "Good day, Miss Eike." The girl has an expression of intense concentration on her face as she curtsies. "At your service..." Then she frowns and closes her eyes as she mumbles to herself, then she turns and looks up at Wilhelmina beseechingly. "Context, Eike," Wilhelmina says gently. "She is here as a partner in the EIC, so her title in Stirland is foremost." "At your service, Dame Weber!" She says in a rush, as if trying to catch up. "Good girl. Go help Reinecke with the filing." As the girl patters away at a pace just short of a jog, you give Wilhelmina a searching look. "Didn't think you'd take a second run at motherhood." She takes a seat at the table and you follow suit. "Me neither. After I decided against snatching up Anton for myself, I'd resigned myself to the EIC passing on to him and you and Stirland when I passed. But sometimes, the Gods provide." "And I didn't know you were a grandmother." "Neither did I, until just recently. Her mother was apparently the kept woman of my third son. They fell out and she moved on to a new patron, with Eike on the way. Last year she was caught in a pox outbreak in Nuln, and with the scars she got, she didn't have any beauty left to sell. She came to my son looking for an arrangement, and did so in public, and it was the talk of the town for weeks when he rebuffed her. I had her brought to me, and sent her on her way with some money and no Eike." "You bought her?" you ask, keeping your voice neutral. She nods once, not a trace of shame on her face. "If she'd said no to my offer, I'd have set her and Eike up in a house here in Wurtbad. But she didn't. Maybe she thought Eike would be better off with me, or maybe she was fine with the idea of selling her own flesh and blood. I don't know her well enough to judge." "You're sure she's your son's?" She shrugs. "As sure as anyone can be in such matters. She's got my late husband's hair." You consider the matter, and decide to let it rest there. Not the most conventional arrangement, but hopefully the girl would grow up to be better than her father and uncles. So you move on to receiving and processing the usual stack of accumulated information from the past year, as well as getting Wilhelmina's take on it all at the same time. News here in Stirland matches what you heard from Roswita, and Karag Nar continues to be in sky-high spirits with no trace of any problems brewing. The information the EIC is absorbing from further afield makes it clear that the major gossip in this part of the Empire is about canals - specifically, the one being built by Ostermark and Karak Kadrin to bridge the Stir and the Talabec. "Still no firm date of completion," Wilhelmina says as she broods over a river map with the future link marked. "Anyone else, I'd be sure that they'd get sick of it or run out of money, but Dwarves don't do either of those. At this point it looks like there's no major obstacles left. Talabecland got burned trying to disrupt the canal, now they're just hoping to ride it out as best they can." "They've gotten complacent from only having Stirland to compete with on the Stir," you say thoughtfully, "hence their gambit, I suppose. I doubt anyone else will try anything. Most Stir traders - us included - are looking forward to cheaper access to Ostermark, Ostland, and Kislev, which should more than outweigh the cost of added competition." "And with all eyes there, nobody's paying attention to the real game-changer in the Aver Reach." "Except us." Wilhelmina grins. "Except us. My next target is an old acquaintance of yours - Count Maksim von Stolpe of Leicheberg." - Writing on the remainder of the social turn will resume tomorrow.

Turn 26 Social - 2482.5 - Part 2

Johann arrived in Altdorf a few days before you did, to report his progress to his superiors and see to other internal matters of the Gold College. But the night before you were to arrive, he began a long and arduous process that was one of the most precious secrets of the Gold College: the distillation of magically-attuned Conceptual Gold, all you know of which is that it begins, in this case, with about six pounds of pure gold. The Gold College is not just the wealthiest of the Colleges of Magic, but one of the wealthiest organizations in the entire Old World. The structure of the College itself is not hidden in any way, nestled into the corner of the city walls and the Reik for all to visit, or at least those wealthy enough to afford the products of modern alchemy, from pigments and dyes to medicines and poisons to magical elixirs. It might seem strange that the exterior of such a wealthy organization is so plain, boxy, and utilitarian. But as Altdorf learned during the fifteen-year siege of the Colleges during the reign of Deieter IV, the College being built beside and partially upon the Reik was not just to turn waterwheels and cool forges, as the low-lying streets that surround it were flooded by hidden sluices, turning the College into a formidable fortified position. But the impression of defensibility evaporates as soon as one enters the College itself, as the reception area of the College is luxurious enough to make the wealthiest of clients feel at home, with thick carpets, velvet curtains and gilded statues displaying as little subtlety as the average Gold Wizard. Most clients would have a well-dressed attendant sidle discreetly up to them within moments of entering, but one wearing the robes of a sibling College merits a longer wait as a more qualified figure is sought to recieve you. When they do finally arrive, you tell them your business here, and are led deeper into the College and down flight after flight of stairs. The ground floor is for books and business, and it is below that the real work happens, where the forgiving earth can absorb the consequences of any missteps. The laboratory you are led to is far from the stereotypes, as it is clean, well-ventilated, well-lit, and empty of clutter, as alchemists that tolerate distractions and variables tend not to last too long. Johann looks up from a crucible as you enter and closes the lid on a chest of tools of some sort before rising to greet you. "Thank you for being here," he says, and there's a moment of awkwardness where he hesitates between holding his hand out to shake and going in for a hug, and you resolve the dilemma by stepping in. From touch alone, it's impossible to tell that the skin beneath his robes is at all abnormal. "Of course," you say. "But I'm still not sure why. It's far from the first time you've done this." "Arms and legs are one thing," he says as he turns back to the crucible, keeping a close eye on the simmering molten metal it contains, "and I had my former Master with me for my lungs. But she's busy siccing Golden Hounds on ghouls, and this was the only timeslot for the- for some of the tools." You nod. "Alright, so what are you gilding? Another organ?" You glance around the room for surgical tools, and are relieved not to spot any. "My eyes." Scratch the relief. "Your- how?" "It's a slightly different process. The vitreous fluid is replaced, and only the iris is gilded." You grimace as you try not to imagine exactly how that occurs. "And you want me to be your spotter? What do I have to do?" "No, the part of the ritual that contains the potential damage also makes any intervention impossible. I just..." He looks up at you, and you can't help but notice the bags under his eyes before he turns back to the metal. "Someone to be here, and to get me back to the Karak if it goes wrong." --- Fifteen minutes of awkward small talk later, punctuated by the occasional bursting bubble of slowly boiling metal, the last of the preparations are complete and Johann has wheeled out a horrific-looking pair of metal funnels on a stand, which he adjusts to match the distance between his eyes. "Both at once?" you ask. "Might as well," he says with false bravado. "The ritual encompasses the optic nerve, so if I do one and it goes wrong, the heat will still radiate from one to the other." You offer to help set it up, but you're quite relieved when he rebuffs you, and after filling the funnels with alchemically-altered gold, bolting them onto the bench, and fitting himself with a truly horrifying-looking headset that straps his eyelids open, he climbs atop the bench top and aligns himself under them. "If all goes well, this should only take ten minutes or so," he says. "And if it doesn't?" "Oh, we'll know right away," he says with a tense little laugh. [Rolling...] You know right away. Johann squeezes the bulb on an end of a pipe that opens the funnels, and somehow manages not to flinch as twin strands of gold with the consistency of honey stretch towards his held-open eyes, but though screaming is entirely appropriate given the situation, you've heard more than enough screams in your time to tell between terror and agony. The funnels snap shut as Johann drops the bulb, and you pull him out from under the mechanism by his feet so that the still-suspended gold can splash against the bench instead of Johann's face. But after that, all you can do is hold him as he thrashes and screams and his eyeballs boil away in his head. --- "That could have gone better," he says to you again. He's said it several times that morning. "It could have," you agree again. "Could have gone worse, though," is the next line, and you nod in agreement, before remembering that he can't see you nodding. The magic to bind the Conceptual Gold to his eyes had failed, but the magic to contain the effect to his eyes had not. "What's the plan from here," you ask, as he seems to be a little more sure of what he's saying, and you hope that means he's come to terms with it. "Jade College?" "No point turning back on gilding," he says, holding a hand up to touch his blindfold. "It would be years before the Chamon fades enough for another Wind to heal the damage. Once the scarring is complete, I can attempt it again. I've got enough savings for a second attempt once the failed batch is salvaged. Assuming it succeeds, it will be like it never went wrong." It's clear he's as much reassuring himself as he is telling you. You consider reaching over to pat his hand, but you don't want to startle him. So instead you murmur agreement, and lead him to the waiting gyrocarriage to take him home. --- Though he should definitely be taking it easy, Johann insisted on being present for the usual meeting of the Wizards. And though they're much too big to ride atop him these days, his wolf-rats haven't left his side since he returned from Altdorf and insist on following along. So your meeting room is rather crowded, and all those present are fairly distracted with shooting sympathetic looks at Johann. "Okay," you say with forced cheer. "Johann and Max and I have been occupied with classified projects, which just means the rest of you are going to have to carry this meeting. Panoramia, you're the most industrious of us, how goes pulling food out of the ground?" "The Eastern Valley is still going to take a lot of time and attention, but it's all work the Halflings can take care of themselves, so we're starting to draw up plans for the Caldera itself," she says. "The whole..." she waves a hand in a vaguely upwards direction, "death tower thing seems to have dealt with the worst of the spore infestation, but it's a lot of earth that's suffered a lot of neglect." "Don't you ever get sick of just... preventing everyone from starving to death? Ever want to branch out into some sort of dubious megaweapon?" "Duty comes first," she says primly, "and there's a sense of satisfaction to a thriving topsoil." "Speaking as someone who enjoys not starving, thank you," Max says with a nod. "You're quite welcome," she says, giving you a smug look. "Moving on to what I hope is more interesting levels of megalomania, Adela, how has your past few months been? Have you reached a decision on your future?" She looks quite proud of herself. "The Gunnery School here settled it, I managed to get one of my brothers in and I'm looking to get some cousins into the next intake." "You're from Nuln, right? Like Oswald is." "His..." she screws up her face, thinking. "Great-uncle was the mentor of my first cousin once removed. I think." "I'm picturing an entire platoon of Burgstallers and Oswaldsons and it is terrifying. Going to throw yourself back into engineering, then?" She shrugs, looking self-conscious. "I wanted to, but apparently the visiting Dwarves are a lot touchier about that sort of thing than Prince Gotri's lot." "Oh, they would be. See me about that later, I've got a book or two that might give you some direction. Hubert, how about you?" "I've been spending a lot of time at Ulrikadrin lately," he says. "Training and praying with them. I'll stay for now." "And with Soizic," Gretel says with a smile. "Okay, yes, and I've been training under General Soizic." "Training under?" Adela asks, her smile a mirror of Gretel's. "Drilling, then," he corrects himself, a tinge of red to his cheeks. "Drilling," Gretel says thoughtfully. "Okay, leave him alone," you say, and Hubert is foolish enough to shoot you a grateful look. "Whatever form of dismounted swordplay he practices with the General is between him and her." Gretel and Adela dissolve into laughter, and Max and Johann are both fighting back grins. Panoramia, to your surprise, is blushing almost as much as poor Hubert. Weren't Jades supposed to be more worldly? "Gretel, though it's certainly within your power to retire to a life of shiftless debauchery, I doubt you'd still be attending these meetings if you didn't aspire to more. What's on your horizons?" She seems like she wants to speak up in defence of shiftless debauchery, but she apparently decides against it. "I've been talking to the Besiegers, and while they'd be happy to have a Wizard amongst them, they'd be doubly so to have someone who can perform Morr's rites. If they get a contract that's not too far away, I'll go with them." "You want to be a mercenary?" you ask doubtfully. "I want to see more battlefields," she corrects. "Ah." That, you suppose, makes more sense. You've never had to look too far for shadows and mists, but the Amethyst Wind wasn't quite so omnipresent. "Well, there's never too long between trouble in the Border Princes or Tilea. Just make sure to come back in one piece." "As you wish, esteemed Magister," she says with a sarcastic little bow. --- While most of Karag Nar's facilities are close to ground level, the new branch of the Gunnery School of Nuln is not that far below your penthouse, built level to the firing platforms of Karag Nar's cannon and mortars overlooking Death Pass. Not only does this give easy access to said cannon for teaching and maintenance, it also provides a fantastic view. It's out on one of these platforms that you find the Chief Bombardier of the Undumgi, who's focusing most of his attention on the slate in his hands, though with regular glances out at the view. Following his gaze, you see flickers of colour far below as tiny marker flags flap in the breeze. You know that the entirety of the firing arc of these guns has been ranged and mapped in advance, but that doesn't remove the need for the Gunnery School to teach trajectories and trigonometry to their students, and it seems the master of those students is a believer in keeping his skills honed. "This is my magic," he says proudly, looking up at you and tapping his chalk against the slate. "We follow the ritual of cleaning and loading, we do the arcane calculations, we make an offering of fire, and if we did it all just right, thirty-six pounds of iron travelling at a mile every four seconds goes exactly where I want it to." "That would make for a handy spell," you say with a smile, "though most Wizards tend to prefer more portable foci." "Seen a Battle Altar or two in my time that would disagree." He squints at you thoughtfully. "You know, I was a bit put out after you chose Frank over me, but I should have realized a Grey Wizard would be playing the long game. Generations of Oswaldsons have dreamed of having an arsenal, and now I have one, and the perfect perch to fire it from. And now I teach the joy of firepower to new generations of worthies. So! What brings such an august figure to my pied-à-terre, as the Bretonnians say?" "Wanting to get to know a figure of near-comparable augustness. The Gunnery School is a real coup for the Karak, and though it's not my job to ensure it's in good hands, it is my responsibility." "No better hands than those of an Oswaldson," he says with a smile, holding them up, charcoal stains and all, for inspection. "I don't have the powder-tattoos of my father as my eyes were deemed insufficient by the Nuln Ironsides, hence my sojourn with the Nuln 2nd Halberdier Regiment. Leverage is almost as good an equalizer as gunpowder, after all. But the joy of command is that you can draw on the eyes and minds and muscles of those below, and it's not hard to arrange it so you have at least one good set of each in a gun crew." "Speaking of, how goes their formation?" you ask, taking a seat beside him on his bench. "Tricky, tricky," he says, waving a hand. "Aloof and aloft would come all too natural, with these cannon perched up here. A separate class of professional artillerists is the natural answer, but that dragon of yours has me nervous." "My dragon?" you ask. "You're the one that made friends with it, aren't you? Same as that one in Sylvania." You open your mouth, and then mentally shrug. "Sure." "Not many dragons around, but there's wyverns and manticores and fell bats in these mountains, and that's just the start of it, and you can't make friends with them all. And it would be a terrible waste to leash the gyrocopters to us. So every gunner, says I, must be as adept with steel as the rest of the Undumgi, and I turn them over to Soizic on the regular for them to be terrorized into competence. So they can defend themselves against flying gribblies, and so they can march shoulder-to-shoulder with the rest of us if we must fight outside the shadows of the Karags." You consider his words. Specialism as a doctrine reigns supreme over the Empire's modern military theory, but modern military theory is based heavily on a core of semiprofessional regiments stiffening up a largely untrained militia. The Empire's few truly professional soldiers are specialists to balance out the huge supply of effectively generalist amateurs. There's an argument to be had here that the Undumgi as an entirely professional force should break with traditional thinking. But even if there wasn't, interfering now would do more harm than good, undermining the existing command structure and breeding resentment where currently there is harmony. "The Dwarves would likely agree," you say. "Every Dwarf that marches to war is trained to a standard at least equal to that of the Empire's swordsmen, even the gun crews and Thunderers and Quarrellers." "Sensible lot," he says. He peers down at his slate, then nods to himself in satisfaction. "Have you ever had cause to learn the art of ballistics?" "Indirectly," you say. "Trigonometry comes in handy in some esoteric corners of Wizardry." He grins sideways at you. "If you ever wish to learn to apply it to this second form of magic, it would be my honour to teach you." --- The Gauntlet is not a place of glory, not any more. It is a place of endless mechanical precision, where the regular rabble of greenskins forced down the Underway path are mown down as dispassionately as water is pumped out of a mine below the water table. The passage itself is harshly illuminated by a series of polished bronze mirrors redirecting the light of several constantly-burning bonfires, and though the Dwarves keep the passage clear of solid remains to deprive would-be invaders of any cover, no amount of cleaning would manage to clear away the layer after layer of bloodstains that have formed. Only a cunning series of bellows to force the airflow towards Black Crag prevents the smell from being overpowering. But it's still far from pleasant, and you find yourself breathing through your mouth as you consider the sign in Khazalid mounted above one of the watchposts. KEEP YOUR DISTANCE FROM THE SPIDERS IF YOU MUST APPROACH, BE SURE THEY HAVE SEEN YOU FIRST DO NOT MAKE SUDDEN MOVEMENTS NEAR THEM Considering the Hunters here would be operating on instinct and instruction, rather than a live connection to the We, it's a sensible set of precautions. Looking up at the roof, you can see the lines of webbing that allow the Hunters to move even faster than they usually would towards their unconventional hunting ground. "How have they been doing?" you ask the Longbeard currently in command. "They stay up there, we stay down there, and everyone's happy," he says with a shrug. "They wander up the Gauntlet to try to pick off greenskins when it's quiet, and seem to be doing alright at it. Half the time the first warning we have of an incoming assault is a bunch of them coming back at once and all the rest of them darting into side tunnels to wait until the shooting stops. Then they pick over the battlefield and take away any of them still wriggling, then the Halflings show up for the rest, then we wait for the next lot." "No problems?" "Some idiots that don't read signs," he says with a shrug. "The venom mostly wears off, and what's left over is a cheaper lesson than most in doing what you're told on a battlefield. There's some grumbling, but no more than normal." --- "Karak-We-green-food is five-eighths sufficient," the We spokesspider relays to you from its position of pride on one of the We's golden walls of tesselated coins, "Hunting in..." it pauses as it considers the phonetics, which is no mean feat for a species that communicates non-verbally. "'Black-Crag' is two-eighths sufficient. Final one-eighth from Karak-We-gold-food. This is a suitable many-food." "Are the Black-Crag-green-four-legs becoming more sometimes-not-food?" You'd consulted your notes on the speech patterns of the We in preparation for this meeting. "Green-four-legs-sometimes-food are very sometimes," it says, and though the circlet does not relay tone, you can sense the frustration with greenskin unpredictability that is common to so many of their enemies. "But the We have hunted green-four-legs for many-Echo. If they become more sometimes-not-food, we will learn how to make them more sometimes-food. We do not wish a no-food." "Nor do we," you say with a smile, and mean it. The We are undeniably strange beings, but under their alien mindview was a charming and unselfish simplicity of being. "Into what are you growing your not-food-gold?" They'd stumbled onto the concept of accounts, by splitting their Karak-We-gold into food-gold and not-food-gold. You're starting to wonder how the economists of the University of Altdorf would react to the creatures. "We wish to know of not-We-Wes," it says, with a happy chitter of its mandibles. "The Karak-We is part of the Karaz-We, which is in a many-food with the Empire-We, which itself is made up of smaller-Wes which are made of smaller-Wes which are made of smaller-Wes. And each not-We is alone in its We, but it still seeks bigger-We. It is frightening and inspiring. Any other-We with a single Egg-Layer would be frightened, would seek only the safest food. But not-We are only ever one not-We, but they still hunt, and they hunt such that if they were other-We, we would consider it mating-suitability. Even you hunt, and you are the most-Echo of the not-We, who must know how only one you are." You take a moment to digest that. "I do know how only one I am," you say. "But I will never not be only one. So I would rather hunt well, than not." It chitters again. "We are glad to be in a many-food with your Karak-We." --- You prepare a report for King Belegar on your progress with Queekish, including what you've learned of its dialects and that you should be ready to begin work on something distributable very soon. You're quite certain he'll leave you on that assignment, as if there was anything urgent enough to require your immediate attention you'd have heard about it. Library Purchases Budget: 300gc, 2 Dwarf Favour. Anything not spent will not accumulate. [ ] [LIBRARY] No purchase. [ ] [LIBRARY] Write-in. Dwarf Favour Purchases [ ] [DWARF] No purchase. [ ] [DWARF] Write-in. College Favour Purchases [ ] [COLLEGE] No purchase. [ ] [COLLEGE] Write-in. Other Purchases [ ] [PURCHASE] No purchase. [ ] [PURCHASE] Write-in. - There will be a two-hour moratorium.

Turn 27 - 2483 - Paving with Good Intentions

Spoiler: Voting results [*] [LIBRARY] Rune Magic (Imperial Extensive), Powerstones (Imperial Extensive), Waystones and Henges (Dwarf Antiquarian) [*] [COLLEGE] Ulgu Powerstone (5 Favour), A Collar for Wolf with a move enchantment (2 Favour) [*] [DWARF] No purchase. [*] [PURCHASE] No purchase. You put in a pair of relatively straightforward commissions: one for a collar enchanted with the Move cantrip for Wolf, and another for a single piece of Crystal Mist, the Power Stone of Ulgu. The latter might come in handy for your future experiments with Aethyric Vitae, and assuming said experiments don't go terribly wrong, it would remain usable for enchantment afterwards. --- "As most of you would be aware," King Belegar says as the seven of you climb the spiralling central staircase of Karag Lhune, "the Okral have not integrated well, despite our best efforts at extending hospitality." The undercurrent of hostility in his voice is well-concealed, but definitely there if you're looking for it. "I've had them build barracks near each of their main job sites just to cut down on clashes with locals," Prince Kazrik says gloomily. "They expected to take over their respective guilds here for the duration of their stay, and those guilds don't appreciate it." "Some of their lineages rival those of the eldest Clans of Karaz-a-Karak, they'll not be disrespected by outsiders," King Belegar says firmly. "Tell me of the Masons first." "Clan Stoneback, returned originals, and Clan Ikrokri, formerly of Karak Izor," Dreng says. "The Stonebacks worked throughout the Grey and Black Mountains, and have strong ties to the Younger Holds. So it's an old irritation that the Okral are making worse. I've moved the Durokral off the defences and onto the other tasks. It is our blood that will be spilled on those defences, so it should be our picks and hammers that shape it." "What are the Durokral doing now, then?" "Restoring Karags Rhyn and Mhonar." King Belegar doesn't look happy, but after a moment of relative silence broken by the footsteps as you climb upwards, he lets it pass. "And the mapping?" "We're focusing on the upper levels for now, how the original passages have changed and been added to. If need be the deeper sections could be cut off, but we need to know the upper levels to defend them. We should have begun pushing deeper before mid-year." "Very well. Prince Gotri, the Endrinokral?" "They've declared that they can't work on Gyrocopters without breaching Guild Secrets of the Engineers Guild of Karaz-a-Karak," he says bitterly, "which is a ridiculous insult, considering that they wouldn't be able to build one in the first place without the knowledge of the Engineers Guild of Zhufbar. So I've put them to work on components and," he waves a hand upwards, "this elevator, which even in their arrogance they can't declare Guild Secrets." King Belegar sighs. "Princess Edda?" "The gears are turning. The Norgrimlings and Ironbacks are hard at work in the the Barrows while the Grungokral have been working on Flamestone Mine, so there's been no clashes, and we've not any smelting clans so the Azulokral don't have any beards to tug." "Makes for a nice change, though I'd rather the Okral could get along, rather than need to operate alone. Very well. Gunnars, how goes your work in Mhonar?" "The Azulokral is providing the expertise and the proper rites, but we'll need to attract a proper smelting Clan or at least a few priests once they leave. Apart from that, I'm happy with the pace of progress." King Belegar nods in response to that, and after a few moments of silence a grumbling conversation picks up between Dreng, the Princes and the Princess about handling the Okral which consumes the remainder of your climb. The elevator you finally arrive at is certainly impressive, being large and strong enough for six gyrocopters or a full score of cannon in a single trip, but if it weren't for your ability to magically reinforce your muscles, you'd have a lot more objections to climbing all the way up a mountain just to ride an elevator back down again. The other Councillors seem to be used to you not always being called upon in these meetings, and you take that you aren't taken aside for a one-on-one meeting with Belegar as approval to continue. --- Mandatory Actions: Pick one from each category. Journeyman Maximilian de Gaynesford, Gold Wizard [ ] MAX: Allow him to spend all his time on his metalworking studies. [ ] MAX: Learn a skill: specify what from who. You may pay for a trainer. [ ] MAX: Learn a spell: specify which. [ ] MAX: Study an artefact: specify which. [ ] MAX: Write a paper: specify which. [ ] MAX: Receive dictation: specify which. Must be taken with a 'dictate' action. Magister Johann, Gold Wizard [ ] JOHANN: Have him teach Adela what he knows of engineering. [ ] JOHANN: Allow him to take it easy until his eyes recover enough for a second attempt at Gilding. (NEW) [ ] JOHANN: Attempt to take advantage of his temporarily blindness to improve his Windsight. (NEW) [ ] JOHANN: Learn a skill: specify what from who. You may pay for a trainer. [ ] JOHANN: Learn a spell: specify which. [ ] JOHANN: Study an artefact: specify which. [ ] JOHANN: Write a paper: specify which. Wizards of Karak Eight Peaks [ ] DUCK: Work with Panoramia for her to finally get around to investigating the greenskin mushrooms she found. [ ] DUCK: Panoramia's about ready to test for Magister, but she's putting it off because she doesn't have a lot of free time to prepare. Work with her to help make the most of every spare minute. [ ] DUCK: Help Johann train his rat-wolf children. [ ] DUCK: Spend time with Hubert in an attempt to find him a purpose. (NEW) [ ] DUCK: When Gretel makes her foray into being a mercenary, go with her to supervise and, if necessary, intervene. (NEW) [ ] DUCK: Each of your three ducklings can fight in melee. Spar with them, and teach them what you can. [ ] DUCK: Magical target-shooting is rough on normal targets. Set up a specialized target range for your ducklings, and for any other wizards at Eight Peaks. The Eastern Imperial Company Your outstanding debt: 275 crowns Your share of EIC profits: 175 crowns / turn Current Focus of the EIC: Handgun Factory in Blutdorf (Rollout to Army of Stirland) [ ] Found an auditors division, to make sure the ledgers are in order. [ ] Start hiring handlers who can then start hiring informers and begin to collect non-public information. [ ] Reach out to Julia to find out if she's interested in being poached or passing on information. [ ] Reach out to Roswita, and have the EIC start passing on tips about any tax evasion or other naughtiness by the EIC's rivals. [ ] Start building a paramilitary river navy to ensure the coming trade explosion doesn't lead to a similar explosion in riverine banditry. [ ] Sell some of the Grand Urbaz Bank coins to collectors and museums on King Belegar's behalf. [ ] Bring in a Perpetual Apprentice to start grooming as a handler for intelligence matters of the EIC. (1 favour/turn) [ ] Look outside the Colleges for a candidate to start grooming as a handler for intelligence matters of the EIC. [ ] Integrate the Gong Farmers and the Niter Factory into the EIC, and expand production. (NEW) Personal Actions: you have four actions you can apply without engaging in overwork. Current overwork status: [+] [ ] [ ] Each box will be filled by one action of overwork, and will take the two turns after that to fade as you recover. The first box incurs no penalty. The second will give a -10 penalty to all actions during the first turn of recovery. The third will give a -20 penalty to all actions on both turns of recovery. Overwork incurs no penalties on the turns taken, only on the turns recovering from it. You can take as many actions of overwork as you have unfilled boxes. When you use overwork it fills the left-most empty box, so [-][ ][ ] becomes [-][+][ ], not [+][-][ ]. All boxes recover in parallel and independent from one another, but second and third apply maluses on your actions during that cooldown period. Current Task: Queekish [ ] Use King Belegar's pull to bring in some linguistics experts from the Empire's universities, though after proper vetting and swearing them to silence. [ ] Despite him considering it treasonous, push Qrech to share the Moulder dialect of Queekish. (NEW) [ ] Despite him considering it blasphemous, push Qrech to share High Queekish. (NEW) Qrech Gambits (can be taken for free alongside pushing him for additional dialects or 'ask an acquaintance to train you' action targeting Qrech): [ ] Convince Qrech that you seek an arrangement with Clan Moulder, and that you will release him as an ambassador for that arrangement once you are satisfied he'll cooperate. [ ] Convince Qrech that the Under-Empire has no way of knowing he's even alive, and that he should prioritize the comfort with which he will live the rest of his life. [ ] Convince Qrech you're ambitious and loyal only to yourself, and you're willing to repay his cooperation in ways that will benefit the Under-Empire. [ ] Other (write in) Self-Improvement: [ ] Ask an acquaintance to train you in a skill: specify who and what. [ ] Attempt to learn a spell from scrolls (specify which, will be harder than studying it at the Grey College) [ ] Hire a trainer to come to Eight Peaks and teach you: specify what. (costs favours for Dwarf trainers, money for human ones) [ ] Travel to the Grey College and attend lessons there. (1 College Favour per class; 100gc can be paid instead for non-magical classes) [ ] Attempt to learn Battle Magic at the Grey College. (1 College Favour per attempt) [ ] Gain enough control of your unruly shadow to still it temporarily. [ ] Gain enough control of your attraction to smoke and gases to have it collect away from your face. [ ] Try to see through Pall of Darkness with your improved magical senses. [ ] Practice shooting while invisible. (applies to Substance of Shadow and Invisibility) [ ] Branulhune's ability to disappear and reappear at a thought allows entirely new forms of combat. Try to create them. [ ] Have one of Prince Gotri's pilots teach you to fly a gyrocopter. Research and Publishing: [ ] Study an artefact: select which. [ ] Write a paper: select which. Once per turn, you can write a paper without spending an action thanks to your Tower of Serenity. [ ] Dictate papers: select which two, must be taken with Max's 'receive dictation'. [ ] Investigate how the We communicates with... itself? [ ] Investigate the possibility of using one Wind to directly manipulate another. [ ] The Second Secret of Dhar teaches how to collapse it upon itself. Practice upon local Dhar taint, and very cautiously see if this works with Warpstone. [ ] Try to establish a relationship with the Cult of Verena, with the intent of offering them access to your rarer tomes in exchange for copies of some of their own. [ ] Record all the entries of the Grand Urbaz vaults and select a good-quality example of each minting to save from the smelters. Aethyric Vitae (20 gallons): [ ] Investigate how the Vitae reacts to Dwarven magic-dampening Runes. (2 Dwarf favours) [ ] Attempt to interest a prominent and knowledgeable Runesmiths in the interaction between Runes and Vitae. (will start at the top and work your way down) [ ] Attempt to interest a young Runesmith with ambition and flexibility in the interaction between Runes and Vitae. (will give a selection of candidates) (NEW) [ ] Call in favours to get a specific Runesmith to examine the interaction between Runes and Vitae with you. [ ] Investigate how the Vitae reacts with Divine Magic. [ ] Investigate how the Vitae reacts to a power stone. [ ] Investigate how the Vitae reacts to being subjected to power stone creation methods. [ ] Using the secrets you already know of the Vitae, attempt to weaponize it. (NEW-ish) Enchantment and Spell Creation: [ ] Enchant an item with a Moderately Complicated or easier spell (specify what and which) [ ] Attempt to deepen your skill with Enchantment (will be more difficult than studying it at the Grey College) [ ] Attempt to create a spell (see Approved Spells threadmark) Karag Nar Penthouse: each turn, you get ONE free choice in this category. Additional selections cost actions. [ ] PENTHOUSE: Have a tower built atop Karag Nar: -100gc for 1 room, bonus to room's purpose. [ ] PENTHOUSE: Have additional rooms excavated underneath your Penthouse: -125gc for 5 rooms. [ ] PENTHOUSE: Your dungeon was built with a reasonable amount of paranoia. Apply an unreasonable amount of paranoia. [ ] PENTHOUSE: Add security measures to your Penthouse to prevent forcible entry. [ ] PENTHOUSE: Have firing platforms built around the Penthouse so that it can be defended from flyers or climbers without granting access to it. Setting up rooms for specific purposes will have to wait until new rooms are constructed or excavated. Only one construction or excavation can take place at a time, but you can do one of each. Building downwards will increase by 1 each time; second set of excavated rooms will be 3 rooms, third will be 4, and so on. Building upwards can be added upon; towers can be added on to or additional towers can be built. The distinction between the two is entirely cosmetic. Foreign Relations: [ ] Join the war between Stirland and the vampires in northern Sylvania. Personal Relations: [ ] Spend time assisting with a fellow councillor's task: specify who and how. [ ] Spend time investigating a character without their knowledge: specify who. [ ] Wolf is fully grown, very smart, and a Very Good Boy. Train him further. (specify what he will be taught) (NEW-ish) [ ] Wolf is fully grown and very magical. Deepen your familiar bond. (may unlock a new familiar ability; risks obsession) Ranald's Coin - specify which face it will be set to [ ] The Gambler: specify an action this will apply to. A +20 bonus to up to two dice rolls resulting from a single chosen action. [ ] The Night Prowler As long as you are outside of private property and within a town or city, nobody will question your presence and nobody will be able to find you if you do not wish them to. [ ] The Deceiver: specify how this will be used. Lies you have developed beforehand will be delivered perfectly. The listener may believe you to be mistaken, but they will never believe that you are lying. Cannot be used to tell truths. [ ] The Protector When you act in a way that defends an individual or group from a danger that you did not cause, they will become aware of what you have done and will believe you acted selflessly in doing so. Spoiler: Artefacts to be studied Ranald's Coin Vampire skulls Preserved bodies of the Rat Mothers of Clan Mors. Eshin: Throwing star, still dripping venom. Eshin Sorcerer crystal sword. Eshin Sorcerer amulet, shattered. Moulder: Book on the Anatomy of Chaos Dwarves, partially translated. Electric whip, stolen from Clan Moulder. Vials, stolen from Clan Moulder. Captured Clan Moulder devices (as yet uninspected) Skryre: Firearms; jezzails, pistols, bullets, gunpowder. Warp Lightning Cannon (misfired, possibly broken) Lighting mechanism, stolen from Clan Skryre. (shared project with Adela) Breathing apparatus, stolen from Clan Skryre. (shared project with Johann) Brass orb, stolen from Clan Skryre. Spoiler: Papers to be written Note: Fresh and Refreshed papers confer a +10 bonus; faded ones a -10 malus. Papers get one step less 'fresh' each turn: Fresh; Fading; Mostly Faded: Faded. Only the first and last have an effect on the diceroll. Ratling Gun mechanism and countermeasures (FRESH) (can be written by Johann) Brief observations on Eshin Sorcery (FADING) Waaagh energy and magic witnessed during the Expedition. (FADED) The Black Orc Warboss' worship of Only Gork, and what you saw of the Rogue Idol ritual. (FADED) The physiology and venom of the We. (FADED) The psychology and social structure of the We. (FADED) Preliminary paper on Aethyric Vitae. (TIMELESS) Insight on Skaven tactics and strategy, acquired from the Liber Mortis but justified by your current encounters (TIMELESS) Basic Written Queekish: grammar, signs, common words (TIMELESS) Low Queekish, the common tongue of the Skaven (TIMELESS) Military lexicon of written Queekish (TIMELESS) Medical lexicon of written Queekish (TIMELESS) Technical lexicon of written Queekish (TIMELESS) You can literally write the book on a topic for the same amount of effort as two papers; this can be split over multiple turns. You don't need to have all the pieces to do so, but it would be more efficient and impressive if you did. The We (missing: communication method) Queekish-Khazalid Dictionary, including spoken Low Queekish Queekish-Reikspiel Dictionary, including spoken Low Queekish - Votes will be in plan format; there is a four hour moratorium. - As always, suggestions for new additions to the list are welcome.

Turn 27 Results - 2483 - Part 1

Spoiler: Voting results [*] Plan Snek, Spider, and Squeak -[*] MAX: Receive dictation: Queekish-Khazalid Dictionary, including spoken Low Queekish -[*] JOHANN: Attempt to take advantage of his temporarily blindness to improve his Windsight. -[*] DUCK: Work with Panoramia for her to finally get around to investigating the greenskin mushrooms she found. -[*] EIC: Bring in a Perpetual Apprentice to start grooming as a handler for intelligence matters of the EIC. (1 favour/turn) --[*] Gambler -[*] Travel to the Grey College and attend lessons there. --[*] Practical Diplomacy -[*] Dictate papers: Queekish-Khazalid Dictionary, including spoken Low Queekish -[*] Investigate how the We communicates with... itself? -[*] Investigate how the Vitae reacts to Dwarven magic-dampening Runes. (2 Dwarf favours) -[*] PENTHOUSE: Have a tower built atop Karag Nar: -100gc for 1 room, bonus to room's purpose. -[*] SERENITY: Write a paper: Queekish-Reikspiel Dictionary, including spoken Low Queekish (1/2) -[*] COIN: The Gambler Panoramia's priority is the fields of the Eastern Valley, and considering it was a lifeless desert when you arrived and is now lush with life and growing more so with every year, you can't entirely fault her on that. But the strange magic-absorbing mushrooms she discovered being farmed by the Night Goblins within Karag Lhune have received only enough attention to confirm they can be grown from spores, and ever since have been tucked away somewhere in her sleeping quarters while the original field has been razed. Well, enough is enough. You've finally found enough spare time to pry her away from her crops and assist in her figuring out the fungi she's tentatively named 'Waaaghsoak Mushrooms'. The mushrooms, from the quick look-over you and Panoramia gave them back when you discovered them, absorb ambient magical energy as they grow, and are then consumed by greenskin Shamans in the blithe assumption that the energies will act entirely predictably and be able to be channelled directly into their spellcasting. It would be possible to write an entire book on the myriad ways that could go terribly wrong, but you're hoping there are non-stupid applications for the mushrooms that you and Panoramia could discover. Planting beds are set up, one in Panoramia's quarters for her to closely monitor, one in the fields outside, one in the Grey Tower, and one deep below Karag Nar to act as a control, and every day a portion of the growing mushrooms are plucked from their beds for study and dissection inside your laboratory within the White Tower. [Studying the mushrooms: Learning, 46+27+20(White Tower)=93.] Though it's not her speciality, Panoramia is much more educated in the ways of the mushroom than you are, and you quickly learn that the parts you recognize are merely the delivery mechanism for its spores, and the majority of a fungus remains underground. The first few days are spent dissecting and examining fungal roots, which prove stubbornly mundane under even the closest of magical examination, showing only as much magical energy as any living thing would have absorbed from their respective surroundings. It's not until the button stage when the fruiting body begins to form that you begin to see anything of interest, and magic begins to be actively absorbed and stored within the flesh of the mushroom. Despite a great deal of study, including transplanting some samples into your White Tower for hours of mind-numbing observation, you can't see any active use that the Winds are being put to within the growing mushrooms. The mushroom is simply a more natural conductor of the Winds than the air, and so magic flows in and lingers there. You suspect this is advantageous for the mushrooms growing in the fields outside, as they would be most likely to absorb Ghyran and be subject to the beneficial effects of ambient life magic, though their larger size might be due to richer soil. But cave mushrooms would be most likely to encounter Ulgu, not Ghyran, and the Crooked Moon Night Goblins were definitely growing these underground. Are they native to caves, and perhaps Ulgu-rich mushrooms are more likely to be overlooked by those that might otherwise feed upon them? You borrow the services of a particularly gluttonous goat from the Halflings, and the creature proves the defensive hypothesis incorrect by being just as able to spot and consume the Grey Tower mushrooms as it is the control mushrooms. Perhaps the mushrooms originally grew in a more Ghyran-rich environment and were transplanted by the Night Goblins, possibly via trade with Forest Goblins, or perhaps they cultivated the ability in the fungi from scratch somehow. After careful observation of the test goat, you move on to stage two, and the only negative side-effects noted from consumption of the control mushrooms is a great deal of complaints about their rubbery texture. Stage three has identical results, and none of the subjects show any unexpected effects from a sudden boost in their ambient levels of Ghyran or Ulgu, only mild elation in the former and slight confusion in the latter. So you finally subject yourself to stage four, and you and Panoramia consume some of the mushrooms yourselves and are able to confirm previous reports - the texture is like a slug, except somehow able to become stuck in your teeth. But shortly after you force it down, you can feel the slow trickle of energy as the mushroom is digested and the magic freed to flow through your body. Okay, maybe the idea of consumption isn't completely off-base, but before you credit the greenskins with a good idea, you'll want to see what happens if the process is performed under less-than-ideal conditions. You leave Panoramia to write up the paper introducing the species to the scholarly world, and she agrees to leave out the trait that drew your attention to it until you're able to provide further testing. [A Novel and Edible Species of Psalliota Found Cultivated by the Night Goblins of Karak Eight Peaks. Subject: Rare, +1. Insight: Revolutionary, +2. Delivery: Dull, -1. Exotic, +1. Thorough, +1. Secondary Author, -2. Total: +2.] --- To call Johann skeptical about improving his Windsight would be an understatement, as it apparently sounds to him like some of the more esoteric parts of the arts of the Pick of Grungni that he tried and failed to reach an understanding of. But either out of respect for you or gratitude for the company, he barely puts up a fight and allows you to drag him into the White Tower, and you don't protest at the pack following him - both because you doubt you'd be able to separate them without a lot of trouble, and because they'd work quite nicely as subjects for observation. Magical senses are tricky things, right down to appropriately naming them. Current convention amongst the Colleges is 'Windsight', which is misleading on two levels as it isn't restricted to the eight Winds, nor does it always manifest as sight. In the recent past 'Magesight' was preferred, but one does not need to be a Mage to possess it - many people can perceive magic without any ability to manipulate it. Some more mystical types say 'Spirit-Sight', which might be the most correct of all if certain theories about the nature of magic and souls are correct. And in the common parlance it's 'Witchsight', which is just plain rude. Whatever name it goes by, the fact is that it's not a single sense at all, but a label applied to however a person perceives magic, and there's as many ways to perceive magic as there are people capable of doing so. To you, Windsight is mostly sight, though Dhar has an accompanying smell and the Waaagh is more of a mingling of taste and sensation. The sense Johann describes to you is very different to conventional senses, and he haltingly does his best to explain a constant awareness of his surroundings, and eventually settles on describing it as being able to know where a fire is by the sensation of heat on your skin. To this sense, open air feels different enough to inert stone walls that he's still mostly able to make his way around, and various types of magical energies are sensed as a sort of once-removed emotion. But, naturally enough, it is various metals that his magical sense is most able to perceive, including the ability to discern alloys and roughly gauge purity at a touch. It does present something of a stumbling block for direct study, but you're still hopeful. [Mathilde's teaching: Learning, 33+27+10(Windsage)+2(Library: Chamon)=72.] [Johann's learning: Learning, 90+14+10(White Tower)-10(Inflexible Magic)=104.] It goes a lot better than you expected. Your own magical sense manifests omnidirectionally, so after some trial and error you're able to find common ground and develop a good understanding of how he's perceiving the world. From there, you take him through some of the more basic meditative exercises of the Grey College, which is a lot better received when you tell him that absolute stillness is not required, nor is refraining from playing with his wolf-rats. Under your thoughtful gaze, he quickly and unknowingly hones his senses on the nimble and energetic creatures, and it's not long until there's no hesitation at all in his reaching out to rub ears, scratch shoulders, and tickle bellies. From there, it's simply a matter of escalation, starting with simple sorting exercises and quickly moving on to more energetic pursuits, from throwing sticks for his wolf-rats to making his way carefully through the sprouting cabbage fields without crushing too much of the crop underfoot. Eventually you reach the point where you're throwing an ovular ball wrapped with iron wire back and forth, hindered to no small extent by the wolf-rats and their ability to jump higher than a man when they feel they're being left out of the game. By that point, Johann has regained his old confidence, and only the blindfold over his eyes indicates that he's not currently able to see. --- Ever since Chieftain Qrech Anuvongeni of Seventh-and-Final-Combe fell into your hands two years ago, you've spent no small amount of time working on building an understanding of Queekish, and the final chapter of the efforts you have made will be no less difficult than the others as you and Maximilian endeavour to distil everything you've learned of this alien tongue into a pair of tomes. [Mathilde's efforts: Learning, 32+27+11(Library: Linguistics)=70.] [Max's contributions: 76+18+10(Amanuensis)+10(Patient)+11(Library: Linguistics)=135.] [Groundwork for Reikspiel edition: Learning, 54+27+11(Library: Linguistics)=92.] Maximilian, as you're well aware, is fairly middling compared to some of the scholars of the Colleges you've encountered, but what he lacks in raw talent he more than makes up for with a willingness to dedicate himself fully to the insights of others, and to persevere at it long after others would have given up. It's no small task to build a dictionary from scratch and mistakes and ambiguities seem to spontaneously arise in your shared manuscript, but Maximilian runs each and every one into the ground, tracing back the source of each word and finding the original cause of the confusion as your towering stacks of translated documents sprout hundreds of multicoloured tags. Most of your attention turns towards the appendix dedicated to spoken Low Queekish, the lingua franca of the Under-Empire. You suspect the other dialects would put up much more of a fight, but Low Queekish has been deliberately stripped of complexity and adapted so that it can be shared not just amongst Skaven from every corner of the world, but by their slaves of innumerable species and possibly their allies as well. So it doesn't require whiskers or musk, and it doesn't dip above or below what human ears are capable of hearing, and doesn't contain any other linguistic complications that the other dialects might have. The end result, you feel, would give a dedicated student at least a fighting chance at being able to develop an understanding of the spoken language. The end result of your work is a single handwritten tome given the title Rakilid un Thaggorhun, ready to be presented to King Belegar and then on to either scribes for copying or to carvers or etchers for creating printing blocks. But while there's no question that it will be quickly distributed throughout the entire Karaz Ankor, when it comes to something this substantial, how it is presented will make a major impact. And while the decision would be King Belegar's, after the whole 'you never sent to Karaz-a-Karak for help' thing, you're almost certain that your own recommendation will carry an immense amount of weight in the matter. [ ] From one King to his Fellows A personal gift from King Belegar to his Brother-Kings and Sister-Queen. [ ] From an Old Hold A symbol of the re-emergence of Karak Eight Peaks as a major power in the Karaz Ankor. [ ] From a Young Hold A symbol of new kinds of thinking for a new time. [ ] From the Karaz Ankor Sent by the King to his High King, and from the High King to the Empire, to be a unifying force in the Karaz Ankor. [ ] From a Very Impressive Loremaster All efforts will be made to emphasize your role in the creation of the tome. [ ] Make no recommendation Leave it entirely in King Belegar's hands, and hope for the best.

Turn 27 Results - 2483 - Part 2

Spoiler: Voting results [*] From an Old Hold A symbol of the re-emergence of Karak Eight Peaks as a major power in the Karaz Ankor. Unfinished business: -[*] EIC: Bring in a Perpetual Apprentice to start grooming as a handler for intelligence matters of the EIC. (1 favour/turn) --[*] Gambler -[*] Travel to the Grey College and attend lessons there. --[*] Practical Diplomacy -[*] Investigate how the We communicates with... itself? -[*] Investigate how the Vitae reacts to Dwarven magic-dampening Runes. (2 Dwarf favours) -[*] PENTHOUSE: Have a tower built atop Karag Nar: -100gc for 1 room, bonus to room's purpose. -[*] COIN: The Gambler Grey Wizards have a reputation as spies and diplomats, and while your abilities as a spy have served you well, you'd have to admit you're not quite as diplomatic as you could be. So with pride firmly swallowed, you make your way to Altdorf and enrol yourself in some of the foundational courses on practical diplomacy that you never got around to completing during your apprenticeship, and try to ignore how many ways you're leagues beyond the other Wizards in the room, including the lecturer. You're reminded almost instantly why you did your best to avoid these classes as an Apprentice as you are bombarded with terminology and minutiae from every corner of the Empire, each of which insists on doing things differently entirely, you're sure, to frustrate everyone else. Why can't they just all go by the title of Elector Count? Why does there need to be Grand Dukes, Grand Counts, a Grand Baron, a Grand Prince, and a Chancellor, all of which are equivalent to each other? Your question was confined to the inside of your mind and rhetorical besides, but the lecturer must have picked up on it anyway, because over several excruciating days the exact differences between the titles are enumerated and explored. You find it slightly easier than your younger self to force yourself to pay attention as you have some context as to why those differences can be important in the form of Stirland's relations with its neighbours, as well as the conflict between Middenland and Nordland, so despite your distaste you're able to force yourself to pay attention throughout. A vast set of power structures is sketched out, from the nobility to the military to the burghers to the cults, and where they overlap, interlock, and conflict with each other, and where the Colleges fit into them and how a member of the Colleges can make those power structures work for them - for the greater good of all, of course. Once the lessons on the Empire is complete, a much less detailed description is given of the more important neighbours of the Empire, and though the lessons on the Dwarves are all things you already know, you do your best to take mental notes as the most prominent neighbouring human realms are described, just in case you might need it some day. [Practical Diplomacy: Diplomacy, 92+13=105.] [Skill: Diplomacy / Empire of Man advances to Basic.] [Skill: Diplomacy / Bretonnia advances to 1/2.] [Skill: Diplomacy / Kislev advances to 1/2.] --- You've extensively tested the reaction of Aethyric Vitae to both the Winds and to Dhar, but you've yet to test how it reacts to Runecraft, and the most basic test is how it reacts to the closest thing the Dwarves have to magic-manipulating Runes: those that repel it. You don't need full-power masterpieces capable of deflecting battle magic, so you gather a trio of examples from Thorek's apprentice swarm: the Rune of Valaya which repels magical energies, the Rune of Sanctuary which confers magical inertness, and the Rune of Spellbreaking that disrupts magical energies. All broadly similar in objective, but all very different in how they go about it. The Rune of Spellbreaking is the one that worries you the most, so you set to it first to get it out of the way. The Runes are normally only usable by Runesmiths as they require... some sort of control that they refuse to elaborate on to target it, but this one is stripped down and will target a 'spell' directly above it. You place a very small vial of Aethyric Vitae above the slab of granite bearing the Rune, then do your best to retreat to a safe distance as the Rune activates. As you pick glass out of your hair, you do your best to interpret the very rapid process that had resulted in the disintegration of the Vitae, and conclude that the Rune of Spellbreaking - or at least this basic version of it - counters a spell in the most straightforward way possible, by projecting very thin blades or spikes of some sort of magic-repelling energy to disrupt it. Unfortunately, you're unable to tell whether this energy itself triggers the transformation, or whether it's a result of mere magical turbulence. Perhaps a Light Wizard with very keen Magesight using Speed of Light and some very thick goggles could, but then, perhaps not. With the causing explosions portion of the experiment hopefully behind you, you turn to the Rune of Sanctuary. Testing it proves very difficult, as the effect is distributed throughout an area instead of being concentrated on a single subject. A series of long, frustrating tests later confirms that however the Rune of Sanctuary works, its effects do not have any effect that you can notice on the Vitae itself, as it remains just as reactive as ever. But on the bright side, it doesn't show any negative effects from its exposure to the Rune, and you confirm that it does add an additional layer of resistance to storage vessels, which you make a note of as a way to reduce the likelihood of inadvertent reactions. The Rune of Valaya is a particularly infuriating Rune to study, as it is one that almost all Runesmiths know but none will speak much of, including the myriad forms it apparently comes in - from the Runes of personal protection, to the Banner Runes, to the massive Hold-Runes that protect entire Karaks, to the variation upon your belt. And, as Gunnars revealed to you, there's the Rites of Valaya performed upon every Dwarf shortly after birth to grant them their magically-repellent nature, and there's no doubt in your mind that the Rune and the Rites are related. So it's near certain you're not going to get any straight answers from the Dwarves about the nature of Valaya's repelling of magical energies, so you go directly to experimentation. Dwarven magical resistance extends to all known forms of magic, including Chaos Sorcery, so you've high hopes that the Rune of Valaya will work on the Vitae, but you're not quite sure what form it 'working' will take. So in a now-familiar routine, you begin with the contents of a tiny vial from a safe distance, and you're just able to make up the minute amount of Vitae oozing upwards to distance itself from the Rune it is held above. Your next experiment denies its desire to escape from the Rune, as with a system of pulleys you force a stoppered vial to make contact with the granite upon which the Rune is carved, and sure enough, another vial is added to the toll as rapidly expanding magical energy bursts its way free. You're not sure if that's the result from overexposure to the Rune, or simply from the compression as it is forced against the side of the vial, but it amounts to the same. Out of curiosity, you get your hands on two more of the Runes and after some time spent calculating angles, you manage to prop up the three Runes in a triangle and suspend a blob of Vitae in midair as the repellent force of the Runes proves stronger than the pull of gravity. It's certainly a striking effect, but you suspect that with more powerful and permanent Runes, the same effect could be used to suspend a much larger amount in mid-air in the centre of overlapping repellent forces to keep any rogue magical energies at bay. Overkill, perhaps, considering the 'put them in a barrel and lock them away' storage plan has thus far proven quite sufficient, but something to keep in mind for if you ever need to transport them to a more at-risk location. --- How does the We communicate? Well, it communicates with you via the magics of the Amber College with a little help from some enthusiastic pedipalp gesture, but its internal communication is a lot more mysterious. You don't think you quite managed to communicate what it was you were trying to achieve, but they're happy for you to spend time inside their nest while they engage in their habitual internal communication, and you turn your Magesight onto the Karak's strangest allies. It's easier said than done, of course. If their communication method was easily visible, you would have seen it already, and the We were unable to describe it without making the chirping noise they make when the translation magics fail. So after double-checking that there weren't hitherto unnoticed packets of magical energies flowing back and forth, you settle in to get a good, long look at their souls, which is also easier said than done. Magesight is often described as the ability to see souls, but what is usually seen is the ambient energies given off by souls, and the traces of Winds swirling about inside them. Seeing the soul itself is like trying to see the wick of a burning candle, both in difficulty and in likelihood to result in headaches. The fundamental question you first seek an answer to is the nature of a We soul, and what you piece together over long days punctuated by headaches in your soul is that the answer is in a grey area. The We in their colony share a single soul, but it is a shapeless and amorphic one compared to that of the beings you're used to, and when a Hunter leaves a fragment of the greater oversoul breaks off to go with it. It's not dissimilar to theories you've seen referenced on the nature of the souls of other eusocial insects. So that means that internal communication via the soul is quite possible, and with the help of the bemused but cooperative We, you set to work testing for it. Which itself wasn't that difficult, because all it takes is a tunnel adjoining the Hall of Pillared Iron that the We call home, where a Web-Weaver carried in your arms rejoins the oversoul of the We but remains unmoving, as per the last set of instructions it received before leaving in the first place. So, sound. Perhaps higher pitched than you can hear, perhaps lower, it doesn't matter terribly much. Either way, the We appear to be entirely non-magical, despite how alien they are from sentient life as you know it. You must admit a little disappointment that the answer is so mundane, but it does fill in the few remaining gaps in your knowledge of the We. --- Ask a citizen of the Empire of the Colleges of Magic, and they'd likely picture a wise Wizard Lord or a powerful Battle Wizard. But for each graduated Magister there's at least five Perpetuals, those with just enough magical ability to be a danger to themselves, but for whatever reason forever unable to cast anything but the most basic of spells. Some lack power, others lack control, and some unlucky few are too traumatized by early miscasts to continue their education, but despite their lack of power they are still subject to the Articles Of Imperial Magic. Some are given magical dampeners and allowed to return to their former lives, and through them the Colleges have an Empire-wide network of information-gatherers and safehouses, but the majority remain within the Colleges, performing the myriad tasks required for the Colleges to operate but don't actually require feats of magic. Many work as servants and assistants, but many more act in more trusted and important roles, as guards and bureaucrats and librarians and lecturers and, yes, as spymasters. [Rolling...] You send a request in, and the turning gears of the College process it and eventually a single encrypted scroll is returned to you, and the number of applicants takes you by surprise. Their names are false and their particulars are less detailed than you'd like, but the Grey College is always very careful about the amount of biographical data that is allowed to leave the grounds, no matter who it's directed to. [ ] Hochlander The first possibility is a recent transfer from the Hochland College of Sorcery, who proved to be an excellent candidate for Grey Wizard in every way except for magical power. He has strong affinities for cryptography, languages, and intimidation, as well as being a fair woodsman and an excellent marksman. [ ] Nordlander A recent wash-out from her apprenticeship, the second candidate has been dampened after a nasty series of escalating miscasts, which you can definitely sympathize with, considering your own experience with Wisdom's Asp. Though her education has been very limited so far, she has been judged as possessing very strong loyalty and willpower. [ ] Stirlander A middle-aged woman with a work history as long as it is classified, fresh from a recently-concluded long-term project somewhere in your home province. She boasts significantly more experience with spycraft and espionage than you do, but she's likely to have her own ideas about how things should be run, and you're a little put out that there was apparently a Grey College operation happening in Stirland that you never heard a whisper about. [ ] Marienburger A young man who passed up the College of Navigation and Sea Magicks in favour of the Empire's Colleges, this candidate has an unsurprisingly nautical background and an apparent familiarity with those Ulthuani that leave their island home to trade amongst the wider world. He also has an impressive knack for mists. [ ] Tilean A lady from the crowded streets of Verezzo, this candidate has twin talents for mathematics and intrigue, and apparently had a rather successful career as a wandering charlatan before her modest magical gifts manifested and she made her way to the Empire. Undoubtedly skilled, but you've got the feeling that her name being put forward to you was more a vote of confidence in your ability to keep an eye on her, rather than in her loyalty to the Colleges or the Empire. [ ] Wissenlander A bandit that earned some infamy when they mugged a travelling Reiksguard Knight, and then even more when they used their fragment of magical ability to escape their cell and lead the Witch Hunters that the local authorities called in on a merry chase across Solland. Apparently their brush with the pyre caused them to rethink their life, as they made their way to Altdorf to present themself to the Grey College. A talented criminal, and one who still has a bounty on their head in Wissenland, which makes for quite a sturdy leash. [ ] Middenlander A long-time resident of Middenheim's Guild of Wizards and Alchemists seeking a posting as far away from the City of the White Wolf as they can possibly get until unnamed circumstances blow over, this candidate is one of those rare few Wizards that has contacts within the Cults of the Empire, and he also has a knack for inspiring loyalty in others. All of them seem useful in their own way, but as much as you might want to, you can't hire them all. You're expected to somehow pare this list down to three candidates, and their schedules will be made to align with yours for interviews before you make your final choice as to who to hire. Perhaps a blank slate will be desired so you can imprint on them the required skills and make sure that proper loyalties are instilled, or perhaps you should lean towards a more experienced candidate and count on your own canniness to keep them in line. - The three with the most votes will be interviewed in the next update. There will be a two hour moratorium for discussion. You can vote for as many candidates as you like.

Turn 27 Results - 2483 - Part 3

Spoiler: Voting results [*] Hochlander [*] Stirlander [*] Nordlander You interview the Hochlander in one of the College's less hostile meeting rooms. He's a young man with a short and wiry build, with a handsome face slightly marred by pockmarks. He listens intently to your explanation of the role you're seeking to fill, and thinks carefully before responding to you asking if he had any questions. "No," he eventually replies. "Very well. Tell me how you'd go about it." Again, he takes his time considering it. "The position of authority means that cooperation can be assumed," he says slowly, "so it is a matter of infrastructure. Of creating avenues for the information to flow to you without being intercepted. The job will necessarily be a highly mobile one at first, travelling wherever the EIC reaches to embed institutional knowledge of encryption amongst the clerks and managers. After that, it will be largely reactive." You nod thoughtfully, having expected an answer like that. Show a tree to a lumberjack, and he'll assume the job is to fell it. But it may be that he is simply putting his best foot forward. "The job will also likely involve troubleshooting for the EIC on occasion. I'll run you through a few hypotheticals, let me know how you'd go about the shooting of those troubles." Bandits in Talabecland was first, and it was a trap, but instead of saying that he would descend upon the forests with gun and axe he explains that the only major overland route where a traveller can't put their back against a river was along the Old Forest Road between Uckrofurt and Lieske, which meant the Farlic Hills, which meant the hill tribes. The EIC should seek a good relationship with the Roadwardens of Lieske, not just in this scenario but in general, in order to secure overland trade, and if the hill tribes are getting up to enough mischief to challenge the Roadwardens then it's serious enough to take all the way to the Grand Duke. You nod along, making mental notes. You posit the same question in Averland, which is much further than his native Hochland. Heideck is his eventual answer, and for a moment you think he means the Priest of Ranald before you remember the town located in the heart of Averland. It is also, you are told, a hotbed of competing elements as the local nobles seek a Charter to elevate it to an semi-autonomous city-state, rather than being subject to the whims of the infamously unreliable Leitdorfs, and those appointed by the Leitdorfs to oversee it seek to thwart these ambitions. An accord sought here would be swift and firm, as either side would seek to lock down a potential partner before the others could get wind of the opportunity. After a few more questions, the general impression you get of the Hochlander is that he is simple in the sense that is far from stupid. He thinks carefully, knows his limits, and seeks to lean on the existing power structures of the Empire wherever possible, instead of trying to reinvent the wheel whenever a novel problem is encountered. You thank him for his time, and let him know you'll have an answer for him before long. --- The Stirlander is old enough to be your mother, and is likely not one to be swayed by your titles, reputations, and an official setting. The best way to deal with a battle you can't win is to not fight it in the first place, so you instead interview her in a much more casual setting: a cozy little tavern in a dubious neighbourhood that Regimand controls, and possibly outright owns. Wizards in Altdorf are treated with cautious respect by anyone that knows what's good for them, and this close to the slums, Grey Wizards are treated with terrified deference, so you have no trouble making sure that nobody's near enough to your booth to overhear your interview with the experienced spy. She arrives exactly on time, has the barkeep bring over a succession of large drinks, and every moment that her mouth isn't occupied with drinking or talking, she's puffing on a pipe that wreathes the two of you in smoke, which seems as drawn to her as it is to you. "What would you like to know," you lead, doing her the courtesy of assuming she's already done her research. "D'ye have a goal in mind with this EIC, or are ye letting opportunity court ye?" Her accent and mannerisms make it clear that she's either from one of the most remote corners of Stirland, or doing her best to seem like it. "It is largely reactive," you admit frankly, "but I do want to use it to have more of an ear to the ground in the Empire at large." "Is the EIC to prop up the van Hals?" You consider the question. Under the Articles, Wizards are to be obedient to the Emperor second only to the ideals and laws of the Empire, but only required to 'render service to the ... Electors of the Empire upon request'. Understandable, considering it was written right after the end of the Time of Three Emperors, and Magnus the Pious would not want the Colleges able to throw their support behind over-ambitious Elector Counts. So under the letter of the law, one could say that there is no duty for a Wizard to provide unasked-for assistance to an Elector Count. "Yes," you say at last. "Sylvania being brought to heel benefits the Empire and everyone in it." She gives you a piercing look, and you return it as best you can, and she apparently decides against any follow-ups. "Better than the Haupt-Anderssens," she concedes. "Ask your questions, then." "If you can, tell me of your most recent experience." You can't not ask. She considers that. "The last Haupt-Anderssen sought help where he oughtn't've, though he botched it in the end. His help let them get their claws in deep. Been working towards dismantling it. Got enough information that having to run was worth it, and soon enough there'll be pyres aplenty in Thalheim." You nod, frowning as you remember your time in Stirland. Western Stirland was under the watchful eye of the Elector Count, Southern Stirland was subject to your intervention a time or two, and 'Eastern Stirland' was, of course, the subject of much attention. Central Stirland was often left to take care of itself. Perhaps that was a mistake, or perhaps the Vampires were the more immediate threat. The Stirlander's much-redacted work history is enough that you don't feel the need to test her with hypotheticals, and simply have her fill in what gaps she can to get a better idea of who she is. She's been dismantling enemies of the Empire since you were in diapers, and is now moving up to managing the escapades of others. She could take the entire EIC in hand and form it in her own image tomorrow if you handed the reins to her. But that's the thing - it would be her image. She has her own ideas as to how things should be done, and is quite eager to put those ideas into practice. And you're unlikely to ever be able to make her more personally loyal to you than she is loyal to the Grey College and the Empire - assuming, of course, that that's where her loyalties lie. You're not sure if that's a problem. You thank her for her time, and let her know you'll have an answer for her soon. --- The Nordlander is... a woman. You're fairly sure. You can recall her voice, husky and thick with the Nordland accent that sounds something like an angrier and faster Dwarven one, but the moment you take her eyes off her face all memory of it evaporates. Whatever the nature of her magical mishaps, they so marked her features with Ulgu that they can't be recalled by others. It takes little prompting to get her to speak of her history, and she tells of the tiny fishing village of Kreideklippe, and of the Cult that grew within it like a tumour, and of the brutal battle when it rose up and tried to take control of the village by force. According to the reports passed on by the Grey College, she accounted for at least three cultists with her trident and was holding off some sort of blue-skinned, many-handed demon when the militia arrived. The Witch Hunters winnowed through the villagers to separate the loyal from the heretical, and though the Nordlander passed the conventional trials, the Warrior-Priests spotted the gift of magic within her, either awoken or perhaps instilled by the workings of the Cult, and she was turned over to the Grey College for further testing. Those, too, she passed, and she elected to join the ranks of the College. It would have been a wonderful origin for a future Grey Wizard, but fate or chance or darker powers had other plans, as her magical ability firmly outstripped her ability to control it, and you can't help but raise your eyebrows at some of the destruction that she inadvertently caused - including, you're slightly upset to hear, to what had been your favourite reading nook when you were an Apprentice. It eventually culminated in every orifice above her neck being sealed shut by a miscast, and only the intervention of her former Master's knife prevented her suffocation, and she decided then that wielding magic was beyond her, and that her service to her College lay in more mundane means. Her voice cracks a little as she says that; she reached that decision less than a month ago, and you can't tell if it's the terror of the miscast or the loss of her future that still haunts her. In all fields except spearfishing, she is easily the least trained and experienced of all the candidates, but what she boasts is moldability. She's a sharp young woman and is very obviously searching for a new purpose, and if you were to provide it, you're fairly confident you could count on her to die for you. You thank her for her time, and with the interviews concluded, you start to contemplate which of the three candidates you'll be entrusting the EIC to. [ ] [EIC] Hochlander [ ] [EIC] Stirlander [ ] [EIC] Nordlander --- Thus concludes the work Mathilde performed these past months, but not every waking moment was filled with work. With whom did she spend her free time, this past year? The four with the most votes will be chosen, not counting those locked in. [+] The Wizards of Karak Eight Peaks (locked in) [+] Social interaction initiated by someone else (locked in) [+] EIC Reports (does not cost a choice) Fellow Wizards [ ] Johann, as he once more tries to gild his eyeballs. [ ] Maximilian, who has been especially invaluable lately and is still neck-deep in translations. [ ] Panoramia, as she goes about her business in the fields of the Eastern Valley. [ ] Gretel, who's apparently spending her newly-earned wealth to make herself at home. [ ] Adela, to see where she's at in deciding her future. [ ] Hubert, to go deeper into discussion on Ulrican matters. Karak Eight Peaks Notables [ ] Elder Hluodwica, High Priestess of Esmerelda and civilian leader of the Eight Peaks Halflings. [ ] Francesco Caravello, proud leader of the Undumgi and possible future Thane. [ ] Soizic, military leader of the Undumgi. [ ] Sir Ruprecht Wulfhart, leader of the frontier town of Ulrikadrin. Foreign Relations [ ] Barak Varr, to watch the progress of the canal. [ ] Karak Hirn, to satisfy your curiosity about Prince Ulthar. Friends Abroad [ ] Kasmir, to see how he's keeping himself busy in Sylvania. [ ] Julia, to see what she has gotten up to as Stirland's most experienced spy master. [ ] Eike Hochschild, to get to know your future business partner. Following Up [ ] The Amber College, to see how your donation of Lustrian eggs is going. [ ] Follow up on your donation of the Skaven organ-vat, and see what has been made of it. [ ] Other (write in) Furthermore, with relative peace descended upon the Karak, now might be a good time for Mathilde's thoughts to turn towards her love life. Do they? [ ] [ROMANCE] Yes [ ] [ROMANCE] No - There will be a two hour voting moratorium. - Feel free to suggest other candidates for social actions, especially any I may have forgotten about. - This is not the time for Waifu Wars or Husbando Hostilities; the question is whether you wish to see romance in Mathilde's life at this time, not specific candidates. - If a romance vote is held, it will not be a lock-in for romance, but for which person or persons Mathilde may be interested in, and who Mathilde will seek to get to know better.

Turn 27 Social - 2483 - Part 1

Spoiler: Voting results [*] [EIC] Hochlander [*] [ROMANCE] Yes [+] The Wizards of Karak Eight Peaks (locked in) [+] Social interaction initiated by someone else (locked in) [+] EIC Reports (does not cost a choice) [*] Johann, as he once more tries to gild his eyeballs. [*] Maximilian, who has been especially invaluable lately and is still neck-deep in translations. [*] Soizic, military leader of the Undumgi. [*] The Amber College, to see how your donation of Lustrian eggs is going. --- Of the three candidates for EIC handler, you end up deciding on the Hochlander, and as they are officially recorded as entering into your employ you receive their full file from the Grey College. Rudiger von Bechafen is his full name, his family once burghers of Ostermark that were pushed out by the influx of more wealthy and influential notables fleeing the destruction of Mordheim. Like many Hochlanders, he has spent a significant portion of his life hunting the forests of eastern Drakwald with a long rifle, a hobby he was able to maintain through his education at the College of Sorcery in Hergig, and since his 'graduation' to Apprentice-in-Perpetuity due to his relative lack of magical power, he has been acting as a messenger for the Grey College, and has proven his loyalty, tenaciousness, and adaptability by getting messages quickly and safely to some of the most dangerous places in the Old World. He then transferred to Altdorf in search of a greater challenge, and may have found it in what is to be his new task. You introduce him to his quarters and to the local representatives of the EIC and leave him to settle in. --- Once more, Johann has gone ahead to perform the ritual preparations forbidden to anyone outside the Gold Order. Gold Perpetuals will be assisting him with everything that requires eyes, Johann apparently not being the first to seek to apply Gilding to blind eyes. You had nudged him to perhaps get some sleep beforehand, but apparently the ritual doesn't allow for it, so all you can do is cross your fingers and hope for the best. He's succeeeded at least six times that you know of, so hopefully the mishap last time was merely a freak accident, not to be repeated. So while Johann sees to that, you make your way to the Imperial Zoo to check up on the donation of Lustrian eggs you made four years ago, after you found and bought them in the marketplace of Barak Varr. Seija had told you that the creatures inside were predators with sharp senses, though neither apex nor especially bright, which hopefully meant that they would be tamable. You'd donated them to the Amber College rather than the Zoo itself, but with Supreme Patriarch Dragomas having firmly ensconced himself within the Zoo, the two were growing less separate by the day. Though that little fact was kept from the general public, lest ticket sales take a dive. Your robes get you into the secure areas and your rank into the high secure areas, but only your name gets you past the skeptical guard outside the insecure areas, where the beasts weren't even a little bit tamed and armour was very strongly suggested. Clad in Aethyric Armour, you follow a twitchy and leather-clad zookeeper past high walls and steel doors towards your own potential contribution to the arsenal of the Empire. And then, in a deep pit carved into the rock and lined with stone parapets like an inverted castle, you spot them, perched atop rocks sticking out of a large, central lake - blue lizards the size of a horse, with red fins and frills and long, vicious claws. And as you cautiously approach the edge, four heads swivel to look directly at you, and you can almost see them considering their chances of somehow getting their teeth into you. "Don't get too close, ma'am," the zookeeper warns. "They spit fire. I'll go get the Magister that's been raising them." To your surprise, the Magister that arrives isn't from the Amber Order, but a Bright Magister who introduces himself as Hans Scheunacht. He's overweight, twitchy, and radiates heat like a furnace, but he speaks with confidence as he walks fearlessly to the edge of the enclosure and waves a hello at the lizards within. "Stroppy things," he says, fishing a chunk of unidentifiable meat out of the bucket he brought with him and throwing it in a lazy arc towards the nearest, who snaps it out of the air with surprising speed. "And lazy. They spit something that ignites on contact with the air, but whatever it is, it's hot when it's inside of them too, so they spend a lot of time trying to keep cool. They can run pretty fast when they're of a mind, but prefer to ambush, which is why we have them in here, so you can do a headcount and make sure they're not hiding." "Chance of weaponization?" you ask hopefully. He shrugs. "If we needed to we could cage them up and point them at an enemy today, but we're not going to get people killed trying to control them beyond that unless we can establish a breeding population. Right now, the immediate possibilities are in the saliva, and there's a preliminary paper on its way through the usual channels now. The Asur Navy use something similar to great effect, and if we can harvest or recreate it, it could be a great boon to our own efforts at sea." As you watch, he lowers a ladder into the enclosure and walks among the lizards, who eye him thoughtfully but make no attempt to make a meal of him. He tries to encourage you to come down and give them a pat, demonstrating on one that ruffles its frill in either enjoyment or agitation at his attentions, but you're quite happy to leave him to it. Perhaps in a decade or so there'll be teams goading these creatures into battle, or riders atop their backs, or their saliva or something derived from it will be burning the enemies of the Empire at sea, but for now it's one curious creature amongst many. [Chemical Properties and Possible Applications of the Autoignitive Saliva of the Lustrian Salamander: +4 College Favour] --- You're shown into a different but near-identical laboratory, where events echo themselves eerily, from Johann's greeting to the final preparations to the funnels to apply the boiling gold to Johann's eyes. This time he does accept your help in setting it up, as the air is too thick with Chamon for him to be entirely confident in aligning everything using only his Magesight, and you hope you're not contributing to another horrible maiming. "On the bright side," he says distractedly as he concentrates on the crucible, "even if things go wrong in the same way, it can't do any more damage than has already been done." Evidently his mind is running along similar lines to yours. "You said you had enough savings for one more try last time, though," you probe. He shrugs. "The Order has very competitive moneylending rates for just this sort of occasion. Or I still have the Boon from King Belegar I could call in." You consider that, at wince at the idea of an overambitious Wizard getting himself deep into debt to his own College as they try over and over to restore a crippled limb. While the Gold and Grey Orders get on fairly well, bonding over being more practical types than the more airy and mystical Orders, they still do things very, very differently. Johann removes the blindfold he's been wearing for the past six months, and you're glad you're not able to see you wince at the sight of the fleshy pink and cloudy grey that the previous attempt left of his eyes. He lifts himself atop the bench and you place a hand on the side of his head to direct him exactly under the two funnels, and then guide his hand to the bulb that will open the valves. "Wish me luck," he says half-jokingly, and though this is far from his jurisdiction, you think a quick but fervent prayer to Ranald. [Rolling...] An awful sense of deja vu sweeps through you as golden strands stretch towards Johann's eyes, but this time there is no screaming or thrashing as the molten gold makes contact, just the click of metal on metal as Johann releases the bulb and the funnels snap close, and the sound of boiling flesh underpinning the silence. For a terrible moment you think he might be dead, but his trembling arm lifts towards his face, then hesitates before dropping to his side. Just as last time, there's nothing that can be done, and the only mercy is that anything near his eyes capable of feeling pain burned away in the previous attempt. All you can do is take his hand as he stares upwards and waits for the terrible heat to fade as magically-altered gold melts into his ruined eyes. --- "That could have gone better," you say to him later as the two of you sit in a quiet room somewhere closer to ground level, and he gives a sad little smile. "Could have gone worse, though," he says. But he doesn't sound like he believes it. "You're still among the living," you say gently, "and we can try again, in another few months." He lifts a hand to touch the blindfold he's once more wearing. "I was watching it the whole time," he says. "From a very close perspective. Last time, the integration failed. This time, the cohesion failed too. The gold is supposed to remain contiguous, which made it simple to remove last time. Now, it's... throughout." You look at him through Magesight, and though he's the big ball of Chamon he always is, you can also see it shining brightly in his eye sockets. "Can't it be removed?" "Throughout," he says simply. "There'd be so much removed there'd be nothing left to gild." "And you can't gild if there's residual Chamon," you say, remembering. He nods. The two of you sit there in silence for some time. "Silver lining," he says suddenly. "There's a hell of a paper in this." --- When you first met him, Maximilian was an ambitious and slightly pompous creative type with a penchant for drama. Now, he is... still those things, admittedly, but also a patient and thoughtful partner in your scholarly pursuits, having so far joined you in the writing of five papers and two books, with a third well on the way. It would be easy to let him fade into the foreground as simply an extension of your will, but even if you were okay with doing that to someone you've grown to consider a friend, the Grey College taught you that highly-skilled but underappreciated underlings are one of the most common and vulnerable weak links there are. So you make the time to show some appreciation to the more junior of the Gold Wizards under your authority. He is a man with two lives right now, and when he is not wrestling with Queekish grammar in your Tower, he is bending metal to his will and soaking up every scrap of metallurgical secrets his Dwarven teacher deems fit to pass on. When you find him, he's labouring over a workbench in the massive communal smithy of Karag Lhune, that the Dwarves consider a shoddy temporary set-up and many human smiths would give limbs to have access to. "Evening, Magister," he says distractedly as you approach, marking a flattened piece of iron with a piece of charcoal. "Everything alright?" "Thought I'd pay you a visit," you reply, trying to work out what he's up to from the many oddly-shaped pieces of scrap metal covering his bench. "See what you're up to when you're not writing." "Practice right now," he says, picking up a file and starting to grind away at an errant protrusion. "I need to get better with the fiddly bits, so I'm building a crossbow for myself." "Isn't that an engineer thing?" "That's what my teacher said," he says with a smile, "but me using it with Silver Arrows makes it Zhufokri nonsense instead of a breach of guild boundaries." He pauses, thinking. "I've read that some Wizards manifest a magical bow, instead of just the arrows. I'm not actually sure if this would disrupt the conceptual framework. Guess I'll find out." His progress, he explains distractedly as he carefully shapes the metal, is nearing a solid foundation for him to start introducing his magic to the process, using Enchant Item and Law of Logic to enhance his own abilities to create, thus turning the temporary transfigurations of Chamon into something permanent, including a suitable Masterpiece. After that, he's not so sure. Once he dreamed of a very upper-class blacksmith in Altdorf or Nuln or Talabheim, but he admits he's found a liking for his part in pushing back the boundaries of what is known. There is, you reflect, something of a magnetism to Karak Eight Peaks. You suppose it's hard to turn your back on history in the making, and a new chapter being added to a story thought finished three thousand years hence very much qualifies. So far, Esbern and Seija are the only Wizards to have spent much time here without putting down roots. The two of you chatter as he puts the crossbow together, resulting in something that does seem at a glance to be similar in shape to what the Quarrelers use, but closer examination reveals as having no actual mechanisms, and the two of you make your way out into the Eastern Valley to some archery butts near the base of Karag Lhune. "Who was Arha, anyway?" Maximilian asks as he fiddles with the crossbow. "An Elf, probably. It sounds Eltharin." "Figures," he says, and lifts the crossbow to his eye and takes aim. "Oh, that's a lot easier to aim than a bow. Let's see..." He concentrates, and Chamon flows from his hands and through the crossbow into the notch, and a silvery bolt forms and flings itself out of the crossbow and towards the earthen butt. "Huh," he says, surprised. "That was new," you say. "With the bow, the arrows just sort of appeared near your hands, not actually in the implement." "Maybe because it's metal?" he says, unsure. "The bow was wood, maybe its nature meant it didn't interact with the magics. Or maybe it's a matter of visualization? Because I made the crossbow myself?" He runs a finger down the bolt notch, then takes aim once more, and again the bolt forms in the notch before firing itself forward. This time he maintains the pose, and a moment later another appears and fires, and then another. You've seen better rates of fire, but only from your revolvers and the most skilled archers. "Silver Bolts of Maximilian," you say, and he grins broadly. --- With the Karak secured and the future more or less calm, Mathilde's mind is turning to the possibility of romance. There are a number of possibilities of varying suitability, some of whom Mathilde knows well, some she's only met once or twice. Vote for the person or persons you wish Mathilde to spend more time with to see how romantically compatible she might be with them. Wizards [ ] Supreme Patriarch Dragomas [ ] Magister Patriarch Algard [ ] Magister Johann [ ] Magisters Esbern and Seija [ ] Journeywoman Panoramia [ ] Journeyman Maximilian de Gaynesford [ ] Journeywoman Adela Burgstaller [ ] Journeyman Hubert Denzel [ ] Journeywoman Gretel Maurer Humans [ ] Viceroy Francesco Caravello [ ] General Soizic [ ] Chief Bombardier Oswald Oswaldson [ ] Sir Ruprecht Wulfhart [ ] Empress Heidi Haupt-Anderssen [ ] Elector Countess Roswita Van Hal [ ] Baron Anton Kiesinger II [ ] Governor Wilhelmina Hochschild [ ] Brother Kasmir Heinz [ ] Julia Antionette Massif Dwarves [ ] King Belegar Ironhammer [ ] Prince Kazrik and Princess Edda [ ] Prince Gotri [ ] King Kazador's sons Other [ ] Field-Marshal Titus Muggins [ ] Vicereine Cadaeth [ ] Ambassador Daroir [ ] Asarnil the Dragonlord [ ] Chieftain Qrech Anuvongeni [ ] The Ice Dragon of Karag Zilfin [ ] The We - This vote is not a lock-in, it is who Mathilde will be attracted to and seek to explore the possibilities with. - Whether Mathilde pursues one person or plays the field with multiple depends on the result of the vote; the exact details I will leave unsaid to prevent attempts at gaming the system. Vote for who you want to see Mathilde with instead of attempting anything strategic. - Similarly, don't vote for some of the more unusual possibilities just to see if I'd do it. I absolutely would. Don't vote that way unless you want the story to go that way. - Yes, there are power imbalances in several of the possible relationships. This is a time period where such imbalances come standard. While it's valid to not like a given pairing because of that, you can trust in the power of GM fiat to know that nobody will be under any duress. - If there's any candidates you feel are missing and wish to vote for, feel free to suggest them. - I will have zero tolerance for any sort of malarkey. Keep it civil. - There will be a one hour moratorium.

Turn 27 Social - 2483 - Part 2

Spoiler: Voting results 372 voters 177 for Journeywoman Panoramia 177 for Magister Johann 119 for Elector Countess Roswita van Hal 114 for Baron Anton Kiesinger II 103 for The Ice Dragon of Karag Zilfin 95 for Chief Bombardier Oswald Oswaldson 75 for Vicereine Cadaeth 47 for King Kazador's sons 46 for Empress Heidi Haupt-Anderssen 44 for Asarnil the Dragonlord 36 for Journeyman Maximilian de Gaynesford 35 for Viceroy Francesco Caravello 33 for King Belegar Ironhammer 31 for The We 27 for Magisters Esbern and Seija 18 for Journeywoman Gretel Maurer 17 for Ambassador Daroir 14 for Chieftain Qrech Anuvongeni 14 for Sir Ruprecht Wulfhart 13 for Prince Gotri 12 for Prince Kazrik and Princess Edda 11 for Journeywoman Adela Burgstaller 11 for Magister Patriarch Algard 8 for Julia Antionette Massif 7 for Supreme Patriarch Dragomas 6 for Governor Wilhelmina Hochschild 6 for Ranald 6 for Journeyman Hubert Denzel 5 for General Soizic 3 for Brother Kasmir Heinz 3 for Field-Marshal Titus Muggins 1 for Asarnil and Deathfang According to the few historians bold enough to have travelled to the newly-reclaimed Karak, the great hall at ground level in Karag Nar was originally a Mustering Hall, but when Karag Nar was turned over to non-Dwarven residency during the Golden Age, it was transformed into a great market that grew to rival that of Barak Varr. Now the hall has returned to its original purpose, and it once more rings with the clack of wood on wood as sparring Undumgi fight back and forth. Overseeing it all is Soizic, standing a head below many of her soldiers but projecting an aura of being the tallest in the room as she moves from spar to spar, distributing advice and encouragement freely. You take a moment to watch her, and how the men react to her. As a Wizard, you're treated by most as a Wizard first and a woman second, which bypasses a lot of prejudices - often, admittedly, in favour of worse ones. But Soizic exists within a more martial world, and you have to wonder how many of the men of the Undumgi might object to being led by a woman. You don't see any evidence of that here and now; perhaps she has proven herself to them, or perhaps she is in the process of sidelining those objectors and none of them are currently present. Either way, that's not your business, it's hers and Francesco's. At least as long as they stay on top of it. The Undumgi are accustomed to your comings and goings, but you still draw a few curious looks, and it doesn't take long for Soizic to follow one of those looks and notice you. She doesn't immediately break off from what she's doing, but her trajectory through the room does curve in your direction, and it doesn't take long for her to stand before you. She's wearing an unadorned quilted doublet and woolen hose, the simple but hardy clothing of a currently-unarmoured knight, with a sword upon her waist that you recognize as one of the seven brothers of your own. "Dame Weber," she greets you with a bow. "Sir Soizic," you reply, and you return it with a slightly shallower bow, due to your higher place in the Karak's heirarchy. Her current title is General, but your own is Loremaster. If she wants to speak to you as one Knight to another, then you're happy to cooperate. As for 'Sir', Bretonnian Knights are always Sir, and a Bretonnian Knight she claims to be. "To what must I thank your gracing of my training hall?" she asks. Her melodic accent makes her easy to listen to, even if the phrases of Bretonnian manners sound roundabout and evasive to an ear accustomed to the more straightforward speech of the Empire. Around you the training continues, though those closest to you are clearly straining to overhear. "Courtesy and curiosity," you reply, though in truth the latter was definitely the foremost. "You've become a prominent woman in the Karag I call home, and I've yet to greet you as General of the Undumgi." You'd met her briefly when the candidates for Karag Nar's Viceroy were being considered, but not since her elevation to her current title. "Honesty compels me to admit that I am unaccustomed to considering those blessed with magic as so near to a peer to myself," she says slowly. "In truth, had I not come to count Freiherr Denzel as a friend, the thought would still be alien to me." It takes you a moment to realize she must be referring to Hubert - in Middenland, sons share the title of their father. You consider this as an avenue to ask about the Damsels, but decide against it as you've heard that Bretonnians are touchy about them. "How fare the Undumgi?" you venture instead. She half-turns and runs her eyes over the training. "A difficult time. The enemy is not quite so close now, so they must become new. They are Knights Errant, bringing a specific foe to battle, but they must become Knights of the Realm, watching over their land against all who may trespass." From what little you know of Bretonnia, her meaning is easy to guess. "From Swordsmen to Roadwardens," you say. She nods. "Patrols and sentries are not so glorious as pitched battle, but they are necessary. The greenskins and the ratmen, it is not enough to shatter their ranks and drive them from the field, as they will have returned and restored their numbers before the victory feast is concluded. You must hold what you have won, or you have won nothing." The two of you speak a while longer, and you find yourself impressed by how seriously she is taking her new role. From her words, it seems she has taken personal responsibility for the safety of all travel east of Death's Crossing and west of the Badlands. More generally, you're reminded that though she joined the Expedition as a vagabond warrior, she was raised and educated amongst Bretonnia's nobility. She seems as skilled an orator as she is a swordswoman, and you've no doubt she could be quite charming and convincing if she wanted to be. Part of you is uneasy that you don't have a good grasp of her motivations - she seeks the Grail, and you know little enough of what that means normally, let alone what it means when the seeker is quite happy to play games with the exact wording of the Grail Vow. You thank her for her time, and watch as she turns back to her men, transforming in an instant from one noble talking to another, to a stern taskmaster teaching discipline to her charges. --- The Citadel's North Tower is atop a spiralling staircase that would be quite daunting to anyone that doesn't live atop a mountain, which is why in the centre of that spiral there is a newly-restored system of pulleys and counterweights to lift residents, visitors and cargo to the lofty peak. The room awaiting you at the top is a chaotic jumble of a room, being part kitchen, part reading room, and part shrine, with the windows on each wall firmly blocked by thick curtains to keep the heat in. Thick rugs cover the floor, cushions are strewn about in place of chairs, and a softly glowing ball of Shyish provides illumination. You give a carefully respectful bow to the shrine - a haughty-looking raven perched atop a skull, carved from stone - and busy yourself investigating the half-filled shelves. The books on Morr and Shyish you expected, but you do raise an eyebrow at the books on ritual magic, as you do at the ones on Tilean history. There's a creak as a trapdoor in the roof opens and you turn to see Gretel climbing down the ladder on the wall next to it. "Magister," she says to you in greeting. "Journeywoman," you reply with a smile. "You've made the place quite homey." "Easier said than done," she says, shooting a glare at the nearest window. "I don't think Dwarves even feel temperature." The two of you make small talk as the rest of the wizards begin to arrive. Most of them arrive via the elevator in ones and twos, but Hubert's entry through a window is impressive enough that you suppress your initial instinct to treat it as completely mundane. As Gretel fussily refastens the curtains and everyone prepares their own pile of cushions to recline in, you call another meeting of your Duckling Club to order. "First of all," you say, "my thanks to Gretel for hosting us today." The other Wizards murmur variations on thanks and admirations for her home, and Gretel is visibly delighted. It's likely she's never had a home to call her own apart from the spartan quarters of the Amethyst College, and she had leapt at the chance to show her tower off when you asked her. "Second, my congratulations to Hubert for learning what I assume is Wings of Heaven." "It is, and thank you, Magister," he says, smiling with pride. "It's quite exhilarating." "I imagine it must be. Unfortunately, I've not been engaging in anything quite so grand of late - most of my time has been spent in the laboratory or writing papers, none of which are quite ready for publication. But I have faith in the rest of you to bring excitement to this meeting." Johann, Maximillian and Panoramia fail to supply excitement, as most of their time has been spent on ongoing projects or engaged in research with you. Adela has been making her way through some of the more accessible books in your library on the subjects of engineering and chemistry, which has kept her busy when she hasn't been spending time with her newly-arrived brother. Thankfully, Hubert has some more interesting news. "I've entered the employ of Prince Kazrik," Hubert says proudly, "as the official delegate to Ulrikadrin from Karak Eight Peaks." "Impressive," you say, but you frown internally. It's definitely an impressive and important task, but it could also mean he's cleaving to his background as a noble and an Ulrican, rather than a Wizard of the Celestial College. A person can't always serve every facet of who they are equally, but Hubert definitely seems to be favouring every part of himself that isn't magical. If it weren't for his newfound ability to fly, you'd start to wonder if he was on a path to becoming Perpetual, rather than proceeding towards graduation. "It's a sign the Dwarves are taking Ulrikadrin seriously," Johann says thoughtfully. "And respecting their faith. Which is good, since they're sitting atop our only safe link to the rest of civilization." The conversation gets sidetracked into talk of geopolitics and travel routes, but as Gretel seems to be getting more and more fidgety, you don't take long to bring matters back on topic and turn attention to her and her recent activities. "I had my first contract with the Besiegers," she says proudly. "Some dispute between a few different Princes between the Khyprian Road and the Hvargir Forest, which just needed us to stand around and look intimidating, and then protecting the local lumberjacks from Forest Goblins while they harvested a grove of old oaks, then escorted the wood to Barak Varr for shipping." "Can Border Princes afford mercenaries?" Adela asks dubiously. "Of course not, it was on behalf of some Bordeleaux merchant. Bretonnia needs oak for ships and the merchant was offering a good price, but the Border Princes kept fighting over it instead of actually cutting down and shipping trees. So they paid us into strongarming them into cooperating with each other." Perhaps not the most glorious of tasks, but undoubtedly a well-paying one. You smile and join the others in congratulating her, glad that she's found an acceptable way to afford the comforts she was fond of. --- Baronet Willus Husserl, of the Menshenfresserhoffen Husserls of Ostermark, wiped the sweat off his brow and felt sorry for himself, the activity that had consumed most of his time this past week. When he had been sent on this mission he had been filled with pride, convinced it was at least partially for his good showing at the First and Third Battles of Mordheim, rather than entirely a sop for his father, the Baron of Menshenfresserhoffen, and his objections to the League's over-emphasis on riverine trade at the expense of overland. But that had been back in Ostermark at the start of a great adventure, and after leaving the boats he'd had a long trip through the dark of the underground highway and now had the baking sun high overhead, and the whole time he'd had nothing but Ulricans for company. So Willus was deep within a well-cultivated sulk. He hadn't even been able to bring his horse, since so much of the trip had been by riverboats. Wizards, he mused, staring up at one of the dozens of seemingly-identical mountains that surrounded the cart he was riding in. What business did he have getting involved with wizards? Apart from that charming Druidess he had pined over from afar during the Mordheim campaign, the closest he'd come to dealing with wizards was a visit to the Tomb of Loremaster Yrtle when he was a child. Now he was supposed to interrogate one about some trade rivalry? He'd pictured some half-crazed Alchemist or an inscrutable Astrologer, but when he had been told exactly who and what he was to seek, his blood had run cold at the idea of an encounter with a Shadowmancer. Most citizens of the Empire would, when something went bump in the night, fear the Beastman or the Undead, but to those with noble titles who grow up surrounded by stone walls and armed guards, fear takes on different shapes. Every noble family has secrets; the least of which would be of great interest to the Excisemen, the more middling to spies from rival families, and the worst of all must be protected at all costs from the agents of the Imperial Spymaster known as the Emperor's Eyes. And should one of those most terrible of secrets be uncovered and the powers-that-be didn't wish to make a spectacle of it, the sword that prunes errant branches from even the most ancient and respected of families were the Shadowmancers, the Illusionists of the Grey Guardians, the wielders of the Sword of Judgement who answer only to the Emperor. Or so the stories go, anyway. And he was to probe one of them for trade information. And not just any anonymous cowled figure, but the Dämmerlichtreiter of Stirland. Hushed whispers at dances and balls recite a list of her most prominent victims: Marshal Verezzo of Stirland, Count Petr of Leicheberg, Baron Alexis of Teufelheim, Countess Gabriella of Nachthafen, and all the burghers of the ill-fated Stirlandian League. They say that during the Sylvanian campaign she struck down a Ghoul King with her shadow, burned a quarter of Drakenhof with mystical fire, and summoned a dragon to battle the winged vampires of Castle Drakenhof. Some whisper that when Grand Count Abelhelm died, she disguised herself as his daughter to finish the job, which is why nobody had even heard of 'Roswita' before, and the wizard has been seen so little since. Others say the Dwarves were so impressed with her assault on Castle Drakenhof that they hired her on the spot for the Reconquest of Karak Eight Peaks, and she was so respected by the Army of Stirland that six entire regiments deserted to join her. "Well spotted, young lord," said the wagon driver, and Willus blinked as he was shaken from his thoughts. "Had many a passenger on edge on account of not having seen them, worrying about greenskins and the like." Willus refocused his eyes on the mountain he had been gloomily staring at. Even with the hint, it took him a few moments to spot the pattern in the chaos, the rounded parapets amongst the unworked stone. "Watchposts?" he hazarded. "Those are what puts the Und in Undumgi. Not just those pretty halberds they've got, any unwelcome visitors'll also have to deal with their cannon and mortars. Makes this road as safe as a Reikland highway." Willus looked up at the mountain with new interest, pleased to have something to occupy his thoughts for at least a while on this interminable voyage. --- By the time he entered the mountain he was told was called Karag Nar, Willus was already rattled. Instead of a gate in the side of a mountain he'd been expecting, a gate between two mountains had opened into a idyllic farm valley dotted with cottages and filled with Halflings, giving him the momentary but terrifying thought that he'd gotten turned around at some point and ended up at the Moot. In the Karag he saw the grand underground passages he had expected, but the overwhelming majority of those going to and fro were human and the passageways echoed with conversation, only some of which was in Reikspiel. He'd resorted to wandering until he'd found some of the 'Undumgi' to ask directions, and had dismissed what they'd said until the next two sets had said the same. So he reluctantly followed the advice and found himself back outside, weaving through the fields and following the directions of halflings until he found a field lying fallow, where it seems two teams were playing some sort of ball game - one team consisting of Halfling children, the other of wolves. On closer inspection, most of the wolves were actually rats the size of wolves. Resolutely refusing to think too much about what he was doing, Willus politely interrupted the game and explained his purpose to the terrifyingly shrewd gaze of the wolf, who cocked his head at him thoughtfully for a moment before nodding, yipping a farewell at his rodent teammates, and trotting back towards the Undumgi mountain. In something of a daze, Willus followed. --- You read through the letter of introduction, then read it again more closely to check for any hidden messages, then read it a third time to make sure it follows the mind-bendingly intricate protocols for addressing someone of your muddled status, which must have taken some poor courtier several hours. The tone is very much respectful, but just shy of being obsequious, as they technically are, to a certain point of view, a competitor to the company you own just over a third of. Then you turn your gaze to the well-dressed but severely rumpled young man who has been alternating between drinking water to recover from his hike to your front door and nervously side-eyeing the pillar in the center of the room. "Very well," you say. "What business does the League of Ostermark have with the Eastern Imperial Company?" The lad opens his mouth to reply, and you interrupt mercilessly. "That is, what business that couldn't much more conveniently be taken to the Governor." He hesitates before trying to respond and you gesture for him to go on, noting with some satisfaction that he flinches away from the tendril of woodsmoke that the motion sends wafting towards him. "I assume you know of the Ostermark League's interests in the Stir?" "Of course," you say. You're going to have to double-check the gazetteer later, but you're pretty sure Menshenfresserhoffen is landlocked somewhere in the moors, and thus wouldn't have any interest in the Stir unless they were made to. One of that family being sent on this matter would have to be a statement that Ostermark is united on this - though you can't be sure whether that statement is targeted at you or at Menshenfresserhoffen. "Ostermark is likewise aware of the Eastern Imperial Company's interests in the Aver of late." You wonder if that's true. Does he mean the incorporation of the West Stirland Riverine Company, which everyone would know about, or the Black Water canal-and-lock project that Wilhelmina and Barak Varr are attempting? "There's currently no overlap between our interests, but that's likely to change in the near future as we extend westwards. What we'd like to know-" he pauses and licks his lips nervously, a stark contrast with his confident and likely practiced speech. "-is what competition between Ostermark trade interests and Stirlandian ones would represent, precisely. Considering that..." he pauses again, and you keep your gaze level on his as he fumbles his words. "Considering the, uh. Considering." Considering that you are a terrifying snarl of competing powers and limitations, he might have been about to say. Or words to that effect. You lean back in your chair and consider him while you digest the question, trying to decide whether it represents a nervous query or a cunning threat. The - what was he, a Baronet? In the sense of the son of a baron, or as an honourary non-landed title? You can't remember which Ostermark uses. Whatever he is, he's clearly very nervous, but you can't tell whether it's the nervousness of someone who hasn't seen their comfort zone for months and is now talking to a wizard, or it's the nervousness of someone who's delivering a veiled threat to a being that could obliterate him. The naive read on the situation is that a trade interest - which the nobles of Ostermark often cooperated as - might be nervous about going up against a rival backed by a Grey Wizard, and are asking permission to start competing without it being treated as interfering with an obscure wing of the Empire's intelligence apparatus. A slightly more thoughtful analysis might consider their question to be asking whether to lock swords with Shareholder Mathilde would also earn the enmity of Dame Weber, or whether competing with Loremaster Weber might by extension be working against Karak Eight Peaks, which might jeopardize Ostermark's relationship with Karak Kadrin. But the sufficiently paranoid wizard might take the question as a veiled but very real jab at Magister Weber, who is bound by the Articles of Imperial Magic and the oaths of the Grey Order. A warning shot to say that Ostermark is coming downriver, and if the EIC stands in their way, to a certain point of view that could be seen as a Grey Wizard interfering with the legitimate business of an Elector Count for their own personal profit. Which is the sort of thing that gets the Bursar very tetchy indeed. There's a whole shelf of maps that Wolf could fetch for you, but you instead use a sliver of concentration to call to your aura of woodsmoke and gather it in your hand, and then cast it forward like a fistful of dice. As the Baronet's chair clatters against stone, the smoke shapes itself into the familiar contours of the eastern Empire. For the sake of your audience - who is very resolutely trying to continue looking serious while picking his chair back up - you concentrate a moment longer, and helpful labels form, hovering above towns and rivers. "The Eastern Imperial Company has no concerns upriver of Wurtbad," you note, as if to yourself. "And we are not seeking any at this time. Ostermark has a free hand to develop what looks to me like three quarters of the Stir unimpeded. Marburg, Thalheim, Siegfriedhof, Ossino, Gersdorf, Krugenheim. Two counties, three baronies, and a chapterhouse. It seems to me that any competition between Stirlandian and Ostermarker traders is some time off, and if and when it comes, there'd be enough prosperity to go around that said competition would take the usual customary forms, rather than anything exotic." You hope that serves to thread the needle. If they came with an innocent question, that should reassure them that business can continue as usual; if there's a threat, then it costs nothing to let them think the upper Stir is a concession. Wilhelmina's fixated on the Aver-Reik to try to claim as much as she can of what will hopefully be the new Altdorf to Barak Varr trade route, so the Stir will be all but free for the taking anyway. And in either scenario, a veiled threat of your own: if Ostermark gets too Marienburg-y with their trade tactics, it will be taken as an escalation and responded to accordingly. Grey Order diplomacy at its finest: Don't Make Me Come Over There. You allow the clearly rattled young man time to memorize what you said, as he will be asked to repeat it word for word when he returns to Ostermark, and then engage in the usual pleasantries that nobles always demand. When he leaves, he's collected enough of himself to take it with grace when you tell him that Wolf will see him out, but not so much that he doesn't jump when you appear to vanish from your seat. --- That's as good a reminder as you're likely to get to go through the latest from the EIC. Count Maksim von Stolpe was only too happy to sign beneficial trade deals with the EIC, and Wilhelmina now only needs an accord of some sort with Count Robert Toppenheimer of Hornau to have complete dominance over the Stirland side of the Aver. The project itself is still in the opening stages, Dwarves not being ones to rush at the best of times, let alone when building on a lake notoriously full of terrifying monsters, but at least that means nobody else has gotten wind of it yet. Moving on to less direct reports, the military of Stirland remains garrisoned as their stockpiles grow and Roswita seeks to cut off the peat trade that is financing the remaining vampires. That's how it's described by those reporting from Stirland, but those coming from Talabecland are much more detailed, and much more entertaining. Roswita's first attempt at dealing with the nobles of Talabecland was diplomatic, which went poorly, then her second pass consisted of a great deal of threats, none of which were taken seriously. The notes from this time give a general impression of her returning to Stirland in failure. The tone of those reports change quite drastically a few weeks later, when the Holy Order of the Templars of Sigmar descend in force upon Talabecland. You're quite disappointed when you get up to date on the latest reports when their investigation has only just begun and nobody important has yet to feed the pyres. The only other piece of information that catches your attention is rumours that the Moot is in negotiations with various powers to acquire riverboats. Most are taking this as an indication that the Halflings are looking to get involved in trade; you take it as a strong indication that Elder Hisme Stoutheart knows about the Black Water project and wants to be able to take full advantage of it to keep close ties with their colony. --- [ ] [TOWER] Oh Dear With a series of very prominent buttons easily accessible from anywhere in the room, be able to drain all magical energies in three heartbeats. Near-complete immunity to miscasts and any other conceivable magical threat. 100gc, 3 College favours, 3 Dwarf favours. [ ] [TOWER] Grey Battery Seek to expand the capability of the Grey Tower to absorb and store power, whether for firing the Eye of Gazul or other purposes. 50gc. [ ] [TOWER] Protection (COLOUR) Build a tower to magically reinforce or protect the others. Specify wind. 5 College favours. [ ] [TOWER] Anti-Air (COLOUR) Build a tower to magically attack any airborne enemies. Specify wind. 5 College favours. [ ] [TOWER] Smoke and Mirrors Build a tower to enable longer-range teleportation. Will require an action to set up, exact implementation will be determined by rolls and choices with that action. Library Purchases Budget: 300gc, 2 Dwarf Favour. Anything not spent will not accumulate. [ ] [LIBRARY] No purchase. [ ] [LIBRARY] Write-in. Dwarf Favour Purchases [ ] [DWARF] No purchase. [ ] [DWARF] Write-in. College Favour Purchases [ ] [COLLEGE] No purchase. [ ] [COLLEGE] Write-in. Other Purchases [ ] [PURCHASE] No purchase. [ ] [PURCHASE] Write-in. - There will be a 24 hour moratorium, to allow people time to notice the quest is back, to refresh their memory, and because I left things on a complicated vote. - Feel free to suggest other towers. - If there's anything I've forgotten, please let me know. - On the subject of the romance vote: Panoramia and Johann are the foremost candidates with a clear lead, and as such will have an effect on her internal monologue in the future. Roswita, Anton, Oswald, and the Ice Dragon all have at least a quarter of the vote, and as such will be options for social actions intended to get to know them better and investigate the possibility of a deeper relationship. You can consider this a 'soft lock' on those candidates. If those possibilities fizzle out, then the candidate list could be revisited in the future.

Turn 28 - 2483.5 - What Could Be A Very Large Problem

Spoiler: Voting results [*] [TOWER] Oh Dear [*] [LIBRARY] Esoteric Imperial Ranald (150gc), Esoteric Imperial Sevir (50gc, 2CF), Antiquarian Dwarven Dragons (100gc, 2DF), Dwarven Romance (50gc), Bretonnian Romance (50gc) [*] [DWARF] No purchase. [*] [COLLEGE] No purchase. [*] [PURCHASE] Post a bounty of 300 gold at Barak Varr for enough dragonbone to make two staffs. Of all your towers, the Tower of Calamity is possibly the least groundbreaking. Everything it does is a technique already used in one of your other towers, just applied differently, so it takes very little work on your part to set the construction in motion. But though the construction isn't of much interest, the possibility of investigating dangerous phenomenon with some modicum of safety is one you find very intriguing. Your other new expenditure is a bounty posted at Barak Varr, with word also spread into the Empire by the EIC: intact dragonbone wanted of any variant, with enough of a prize attached to interest anyone who might have some but not so much to inspire anyone to actually go hunting a dragon, or so you hope. It will take time for news to spread and the results to reach you, but if all goes well you should have some very intriguing magical material to work with in the near future. --- The Council meeting is a litany of grumbled complaints about the Okral, intermixed with grudging admission that once they do set their minds to working instead of tugging the beards of the Karak's clans, they're certainly industrious. Most effort is currently focused on Karags Rhyn and Mhonar, the two linked Karags that were once home to the majority of the Karak's population, and though reversing three thousand years of neglect is no small task, it seems well apace. Personally, you think it's misspent effort when the entire population can fit comfortably inside Karag Lhune, but it's a fool's errand to try to talk a Dwarf into a half-measure. Your own report is not quite as well-received as you'd hoped - sure, everyone makes the suitable impressed noises, but you can tell that none of them quite grasp what you've accomplished. Most Dwarves just aren't wired to grasp the sort of tactics that this tome will make possible - after all, it doesn't make it any easier to strike a Skaven down with an axe or a quarrel, so how much of a difference could it possibly make? You have a feeling Kazador would get it once Kazrik passed on a copy to him, as would Prince Ulthar when one reaches Karak Hirn. It might not be quite as dramatic as destroying a charging Waaagh with the fires of a Dwarven God, but you think that of all your accomplishments, Rakilid un Thaggorhun could, in the end, have the strongest cumulative effect on the fate of the Old World - if it's used properly. --- Finally the last of the court files out of the Great Hall, their footsteps echoing through the vast empty space. High King Thorgrim Grudgebearer allows himself to relax fractionally in his chair, his shoulders slumping slightly. Another day over, another day closer to- Well. Not anymore, perhaps. His eyes flick sideways to a readout only he could see. Vala-Azril-Ungol, functional. As if summoned by his thoughts, an attendant hurries in, still young enough to be in a hurry to get everywhere. A Gunnisson, he recalls. His Ancestors were once Kings of Mount Silverspear, and now they are mere warriors in Karaz-a-Karak. "What is it, lad?" he asks. "Package from Karak- from Vala-Azril-Ungol, your Highness," the beardling says, laying a weighty bundle atop the desk in front of the High King. "Marked for your eyes only." "Very well, take a step back," Thorgrim says, leaning forward to examine it. Plain cloth, wrapped in twine. Boxy, so likely not a head, which he sometimes received from his more rowdy subjects as proof a Grudge has been settled. The twine easily parts to a knife usually used to sharpen quills, and he unfolds the paper to see a book - leatherbound, good and sturdy. Rakilid un Thaggorhun, he reads. Some report on the Skaven? He opens it, and turns a page. Then two. Then flips through the pages, his eyebrows rising. "Good news, your Highness?" the lad asks. "You could say that," Thorgrim replies thoughtfully. "Get me... well, let's start with my Loremaster." --- Deep underground, under the lowest official level of the vast archives of Karaz-a-Karak, the air stirred for the first time in years as a door swung open, creaking on hinges older than civilizations. The light that fell upon it was not the flicker of lamplight, as no flame was allowed deeper than the second level of the archives - this was runelight, and save for the sun itself, no steadier illumination could be found. In stark contrast to the neat and orderly shelves above, these were dotted with a chaotic mess of assorted writings, from tattered books to half-torn scrolls to individual scraps of paper, each kept in a custom-made compartment to keep it safe from the ravages of the years. "All of it, your Highness," the Loremaster says, his voice still strong despite his centuries. "Every book, every scroll, every letter, rubbings of wall carvings, even the warpstone-tainted ones are around here, in runed crates. Not quite as glorious as skulls and captured weapons, but it still does the heart good, to gaze upon it all." High King Thorgrim Grudgebearer nodded in thought. "Is that why they've been collected? As trophies?" "Mm, perhaps. The decree itself is from High King Morgrim, and I suspect it would be Morgrim Ironbeard because Morgrim Blackbeard would have specified. Blackbeard, I think, would have been the type to seek trophies, but Ironbeard strikes me as more likely to be looking for answers." "And have any been found?" The Loremaster sighs. "Many have tried, but it's like mining through mud. They have two separate alphabets of thirteen letters which we believe to be formal and informal variations, and numerous logographs besides, some of which seem to be morphemes and some whole words. There's also a great deal of inconsistency, which we believe to be due to differing dialects of the language. Every generation there's one or two that will sink years into pursuing it, but all have failed. Lost a promising linguist to it after he swore a Slayer Oath, though he did find a suitable death to a war mammoth in the far north." "Right, then." Thorgrim lifts his hand, bringing the book he is carrying to the Loremaster's attention. "A new addition?" the Loremaster asks, peering down at the book as the High King hands it to him. "No, that's proper writing. Rakilid... maybe not. Never saw the purpose in making up new words, the old ones served our ancestors fine." He falls silent as he opens the book, and then his mouth opens slightly as he flips the pages, though no sound comes out. "Will this help?" It takes a moment for the Loremaster to find his voice again. "Assuming this is all correct..." he pauses as he flips through some more, his brow furrowing. "We will need many more hands..." "You'll have them. Send to Zhufbar and Barak Varr for all the scholars they can spare, in my name. And keep me apprised of everything of interest that you uncover." --- Your assignment for the remainder of this year is a light one, as Belegar knows you've still got to finish the Reikspiel version of the translation - to create, commission, devise, or otherwise see to some sort of plan for if the Ice Dragon turns hostile, ideally something that could also come in handy against other dragons or any other variety of enormous flying beast. A number of possibilities immediately leap to mind, and it's up to you to decide upon the best of them. Mandatory Actions: Pick one from each category. Journeyman Maximilian de Gaynesford, Gold Wizard [ ] MAX: Allow him to spend all his time on his metalworking studies. [ ] MAX: Learn a skill: specify what from who. You may pay for a trainer. [ ] MAX: Learn a spell: specify which. [ ] MAX: Study an artefact: specify which. [ ] MAX: Write a paper: specify which. [ ] MAX: Receive dictation: specify which. Must be taken with a 'dictate' action. Magister Johann, Gold Wizard [ ] JOHANN: Have him teach Adela what he knows of engineering. [ ] JOHANN: Learn a skill: specify what from who. You may pay for a trainer. [ ] JOHANN: Learn a spell: specify which. [ ] JOHANN: Study an artefact: specify which. [ ] JOHANN: Write a paper: specify which. Wizards of Karak Eight Peaks [ ] DUCK: Work with Panoramia to try to implement the Waaaghsoak Mushrooms as an aid to spellcasting. (NEW) [ ] DUCK: Panoramia's about ready to test for Magister, but she's putting it off because she doesn't have a lot of free time to prepare. Work with her to help make the most of every spare minute. [ ] DUCK: Help Johann train his rat-wolf children. [ ] DUCK: Spend time with Hubert to try to ensure a good relationship between him and magic, and between him and his identity as a Wizard. (NEW-ish) [ ] DUCK: Tag along on one of Gretel's mercenary contracts. (NEW-ish) [ ] DUCK: Each of your three ducklings can fight in melee. Spar with them, and teach them what you can. [ ] DUCK: Magical target-shooting is rough on normal targets. Set up a specialized target range for your ducklings, and for any other wizards at Eight Peaks. The Eastern Imperial Company Your outstanding debt: 100 crowns Your share of EIC profits: 175 crowns / turn Current Focus of the EIC: Expansion along the Aver EIC Handler: The Hochlander [ ] Completely hand over management of the EIC intelligence apparatus to the Hochlander. Will remove this section from future turns and regain the half-turn invested in it. (NEW) [ ] Have the Hochlander introduce a series of ciphers to the EIC to allow it to communicate internally in much greater security. (NEW) [ ] Lend the services of the Hochlander, and the EIC's intelligence and contacts, to Roswita to help track down the Talabeclanders buying peat from the vampires. (NEW) [ ] Found an auditors division, to make sure the ledgers are in order. [ ] Start hiring handlers who can then start hiring informers and begin to collect non-public information. [ ] Reach out to Julia to find out if she's interested in being poached or passing on information. [ ] Reach out to Roswita, and have the EIC start passing on tips about any tax evasion or other naughtiness by the EIC's rivals. [ ] Start building a paramilitary river navy to ensure the coming trade explosion doesn't lead to a similar explosion in riverine banditry. [ ] Sell some of the Grand Urbaz Bank coins to collectors and museums on King Belegar's behalf. [ ] Integrate the Gong Farmers and the Niter Factory into the EIC, and expand production. Personal Actions: you have four actions you can apply without engaging in overwork. Current overwork status: [-] [ ] [ ] Each box will be filled by one action of overwork, and will take the two turns after that to fade as you recover. The first box incurs no penalty. The second will give a -10 penalty to all actions during the first turn of recovery. The third will give a -20 penalty to all actions on both turns of recovery. Overwork incurs no penalties on the turns taken, only on the turns recovering from it. You can take as many actions of overwork as you have unfilled boxes. When you use overwork it fills the left-most empty box, so [-][ ][ ] becomes [-][+][ ], not [+][-][ ]. All boxes recover in parallel and independent from one another, but second and third apply maluses on your actions during that cooldown period. Current Task: Anti-Dragon (NEW) [ ] Commission a suitable magical artefact from the Colleges of Magic, and train some dubious Dwarven volunteers in its use (specify what; does not cost favour). [ ] Build a new tower with anti-dragon capabilities (specify Dwarven Rune or College spell it would be based on; does not cost favour). [ ] Other (write-in; material and favour costs will be paid by Belegar) Current Task: Queekish [ ] Use King Belegar's pull to bring in some linguistics experts from the Empire's universities, though after proper vetting and swearing them to silence. [ ] Despite him considering it treasonous, push Qrech to share the Moulder dialect of Queekish. [ ] Despite him considering it blasphemous, push Qrech to share High Queekish. Qrech Gambits (can be taken for free alongside pushing him for additional dialects or 'ask an acquaintance to train you' action targeting Qrech): [ ] Convince Qrech that you seek an arrangement with Clan Moulder, and that you will release him as an ambassador for that arrangement once you are satisfied he'll cooperate. [ ] Convince Qrech that the Under-Empire has no way of knowing he's even alive, and that he should prioritize the comfort with which he will live the rest of his life. [ ] Convince Qrech you're ambitious and loyal only to yourself, and you're willing to repay his cooperation in ways that will benefit the Under-Empire. [ ] Other (write in) Self-Improvement: [ ] Ask an acquaintance to train you in a skill: specify who and what. [ ] Attempt to learn a spell from scrolls (specify which, will be harder than studying it at the Grey College) [ ] Hire a trainer to come to Eight Peaks and teach you: specify what. (costs favours for Dwarf trainers, money for human ones) [ ] Travel to the Grey College and attend lessons there. (1 College Favour per class; 100gc can be paid instead for non-magical classes) [ ] Attempt to learn Battle Magic at the Grey College. (1 College Favour per attempt) [ ] Gain enough control of your unruly shadow to still it temporarily. [ ] Gain enough control of your attraction to smoke and gases to have it collect away from your face. [ ] Try to see through Pall of Darkness with your improved magical senses. [ ] Practice shooting while invisible. (applies to Substance of Shadow and Invisibility) [ ] Branulhune's ability to disappear and reappear at a thought allows entirely new forms of combat. Try to create them. [ ] Have one of Prince Gotri's pilots teach you to fly a gyrocopter. Research and Publishing: [ ] Study an artefact: select which. [ ] Write a paper: select which. Once per turn, you can write a paper without spending an action thanks to your Tower of Serenity. [ ] Dictate papers: select which two, must be taken with Max's 'receive dictation'. [ ] Investigate the possibility of using one Wind to directly manipulate another. [ ] The Second Secret of Dhar teaches how to collapse it upon itself. Practice upon local Dhar taint, and very cautiously see if this works with Warpstone. [ ] Try to establish a relationship with the Cult of Verena, with the intent of offering them access to your rarer tomes in exchange for copies of some of their own. [ ] Record all the entries of the Grand Urbaz vaults and select a good-quality example of each minting to save from the smelters. Aethyric Vitae (21 gallons): [ ] Attempt to interest a prominent and knowledgeable Runesmiths in the interaction between Runes and Vitae. (will start at the top and work your way down) [ ] Attempt to interest a young Runesmith with ambition and flexibility in the interaction between Runes and Vitae. (will give a selection of candidates) [ ] Call in favours to get a specific Runesmith to examine the interaction between Runes and Vitae with you. [ ] Using what you've learned of how it reacts to Runes, create new means of storing and moving the Vitae in complete safety. (NEW) [ ] Experiment with integrating the Vitae into enchantments. (NEW) [ ] Investigate how the Vitae reacts with Divine Magic. [ ] Investigate how the Vitae reacts to a power stone. [ ] Investigate how the Vitae reacts to being subjected to power stone creation methods. [ ] Using the secrets you already know of the Vitae, attempt to weaponize it. Enchantment and Spell Creation: [ ] Enchant an item with a Moderately Complicated or easier spell (specify what and which) [ ] Attempt to enchant an object to translate Windsight into a visual image. [ ] Attempt to deepen your skill with Enchantment (will be more difficult than studying it at the Grey College) [ ] Attempt to create a spell (see Approved Spells threadmark) Karag Nar Penthouse: each turn, you get ONE free choice in this category. Additional selections cost actions. [ ] PENTHOUSE: Have a tower built atop Karag Nar: -100gc for 1 room, bonus to room's purpose. [ ] PENTHOUSE: Have additional rooms excavated underneath your Penthouse: -125gc for 5 rooms. [ ] PENTHOUSE: Your dungeon was built with a reasonable amount of paranoia. Apply an unreasonable amount of paranoia. [ ] PENTHOUSE: Add security measures to your Penthouse to prevent forcible entry. [ ] PENTHOUSE: Have firing platforms built around the Penthouse so that it can be defended from flyers or climbers without granting access to it. Setting up rooms for specific purposes will have to wait until new rooms are constructed or excavated. Only one construction or excavation can take place at a time, but you can do one of each. Building downwards will increase by 1 each time; second set of excavated rooms will be 3 rooms, third will be 4, and so on. Building upwards can be added upon; towers can be added on to or additional towers can be built. The distinction between the two is entirely cosmetic. Foreign Relations: [ ] Join the war between Stirland and the vampires in northern Sylvania. [ ] Personally search for the Talabeclander buyers of peat from the vampires. (NEW) [ ] Throw your reputation, and that of the Grey College, behind Roswita as she tries to browbeat the Talabeclanders into submission. (NEW) Personal Relations: [ ] Spend time assisting with a fellow councillor's task: specify who and how. [ ] Spend time investigating a character without their knowledge: specify who. [ ] Wolf is fully grown, very smart, and a Very Good Boy. Train him further. (specify what he will be taught) [ ] Wolf is fully grown and very magical. Deepen your familiar bond. (may unlock a new familiar ability; risks obsession) Ranald's Coin - specify which face it will be set to [ ] The Gambler: specify an action this will apply to. A +20 bonus to up to two dice rolls resulting from a single chosen action. [ ] The Night Prowler As long as you are outside of private property and within a town or city, nobody will question your presence and nobody will be able to find you if you do not wish them to. [ ] The Deceiver: specify how this will be used. Lies you have developed beforehand will be delivered perfectly. The listener may believe you to be mistaken, but they will never believe that you are lying. Cannot be used to tell truths. [ ] The Protector When you act in a way that defends an individual or group from a danger that you did not cause, they will become aware of what you have done and will believe you acted selflessly in doing so. Spoiler: Artefacts to be studied Ranald's Coin Vampire skulls Preserved bodies of the Rat Mothers of Clan Mors. Eshin: Throwing star, still dripping venom. Eshin Sorcerer crystal sword. Eshin Sorcerer amulet, shattered. Moulder: Electric whip, stolen from Clan Moulder. Vials, stolen from Clan Moulder. Captured Clan Moulder devices (as yet uninspected) Skryre: Firearms; jezzails, pistols, bullets, gunpowder. Warp Lightning Cannon (misfired, possibly broken) Lighting mechanism, stolen from Clan Skryre. (shared project with Adela) Breathing apparatus, stolen from Clan Skryre. (shared project with Johann) Brass orb, stolen from Clan Skryre. Spoiler: Papers to be written Note: Fresh and Refreshed papers confer a +10 bonus; faded ones a -10 malus. Papers get one step less 'fresh' each turn: Fresh; Fading; Mostly Faded: Faded. Only the first and last have an effect on the diceroll. Ratling Gun mechanism and countermeasures (FADING) (can be written by Johann) Brief observations on Eshin Sorcery (MOSTLY FADED) Waaagh energy and magic witnessed during the Expedition. (FADED) The Black Orc Warboss' worship of Only Gork, and what you saw of the Rogue Idol ritual. (FADED) The physiology and venom of the We. (FADED) The psychology and social structure of the We. (FADED) Preliminary paper on Aethyric Vitae. (TIMELESS) Insight on Skaven tactics and strategy, acquired from the Liber Mortis but justified by your current encounters (TIMELESS) Basic Written Queekish: grammar, signs, common words (TIMELESS) Low Queekish, the common tongue of the Skaven (TIMELESS) Military lexicon of written Queekish (TIMELESS) Medical lexicon of written Queekish (TIMELESS) Technical lexicon of written Queekish (TIMELESS) You can literally write the book on a topic for the same amount of effort as two papers; this can be split over multiple turns. You don't need to have all the pieces to do so, but it would be more efficient and impressive if you did. The We Queekish-Reikspiel Dictionary, including spoken Low Queekish (Half Completed) - There will be a two hour moratorium. - If there's anything I've forgotten - and that's quite likely - please let me know. Similarly, speak up if there's anything you think should be added. - The exact favour payoff for the translation into Khazalid is pending, and will depend on whether and how it is put to use in other holds. - The dragon task has a huge amount of latitude, and creativity is encouraged.

Turn 28 Results - 2483.5 - Part 1

Spoiler: Voting results [*] Plan: Fight Dragon with Dragon -[*] MAX: Receive dictation. -[*] JOHANN: Write a paper: Ratling Gun mechanism and countermeasures -[*] DUCK: Spend time with Hubert to try to ensure a good relationship between him and magic, and between him and his identity as a Wizard. -[*] EIC: Lend the services of the Hochlander, and the EIC's intelligence and contacts, to Roswita to help track down the Talabeclanders buying peat from the vampires. -[*] Commission an altar based on (boosted) Transformation of Kadon. --[*] Able to transform non-wizards. --[*] Optimized to reduce destructive consequences in case of miscast. --[*] Can only be activated by a Dwarf not currently being transformed. --[*] Can only be activated with one of three keystones. --[*] Transportable but heavy and unwieldy enough that even the resulting dragon can not just carry it away. --[*] COIN: The Gambler -[*] Travel to the Grey College and attend lessons there: Staff Turning -[*] Attempt to interest a prominent and knowledgeable Runesmiths in the interaction between Runes and Vitae. (will start at the top and work your way down) -[*] Dictate papers: --[*] Queekish-Reikspiel Dictionary, including spoken Low Queekish --[*] Insight on Skaven tactics and strategy -[*] PENTHOUSE: Have a tower built atop Karag Nar -[*] SERENITY: Write a paper: Brief observations on Eshin Sorcery You brief the Hochlander - he has a name, but it sounds so very mysterious to just call him the Hochlander - in a gyrocopter headed north, telling him his task is to provide what support he can to Roswita in the matter of tracking down whoever is bankrolling the remaining land-holding vampires in Sylvania by buying peat from them. Not only is it a worthy task, but it will also give you a better idea of how he operates, whether he works through the EIC, establishes an entirely new network, or tracks the merchants personally. You drop him off in Nuln for him to make his own, less attention-getting way to his task from there, and then move on to Altdorf. You have a massive commission on behalf of King Belegar to drop into the laps of the Amber College, one the result of a great deal of thought on your part. You spent a great deal of time consulting your library, trying to decide which piece of battle magic would be most helpful in a fight against a dragon, but in the end you realized you were coming at it from the wrong direction. The Dwarves are entirely capable of directing a bewildering and varied barrage at a dragon, should the need arise, and it makes no major difference to add a magical shot to that volley. What is needed is a reason for the dragon to expose itself to that barrage in the first place, and though you spent some time considering mental trickery to accomplish that, eventually you decided you needed a genuine motivation, one that did not require directly influencing the foe. In the end, you settled on Transformation of Kadon. How better to counter a dragon, than another dragon? Through the process of internal requests that the Colleges operate on, you've received word that the person to talk to on this matter is Lord Magister Luuk Schild, as well as allowing you to arrange a meeting. It is oft said that the Amber Order has no College in Altdorf - you may have said it a time or two yourself - but while that is true, they do have a tower, if something so squat and festooned with gargoyles can be described as a tower. Built before Teclis reached an accord with the shamanic brotherhood that is the ancestor to the modern Amber Order, it exists today solely as a letterbox and very occasionally as a meeting room. It is said that the door appears only when the Amber Wind blows strongest, but that would be extremely impractical. Lord Magister Luuk is a squat and muscled man, hairless except for bushy eyebrows and exuding an aura of Ghur that puts your teeth on edge. He is a man of few words, and when you explain to him the specifics of what you want, he furrows his brow and says a single word: "Why?" "To fight other dragons," is your wonderfully succinct answer. "What sort?" "Our main concern is ice." He wrinkles his nose, and then nods. "Come back at midwinter." You're quite pleased at how simple that was to commission, but you can't help but go over the final words he said as he walked out: "It'll be uglier than you think it'll be." --- Staff turning, you quickly discover, is all the most boring parts of enchantment made even more boring. Everything needs to be perfect, because it is to have every ounce of power a wizard wields run through it, as well as helping absorb ambient energies to cast those spells in the first place. There's no creativity, no cleverness, no puzzles. You make it as conductive to the Wind in question as you possibly can, and the only variation in results is in imperfections. There can be more to staffs than this - the Bright Order in particular delights in ones able to amplify specific spells - but that's not covered by the class. Day by tedious day, you rote memorize the various ways to attune materials to a Wind. If you hadn't already spread word of the bounty on dragonbone, you might be tempted to drop the idea altogether and be satisfied with your sword and guns. But at long, long last, the day finally comes that there's nothing more for them to torment you with, and you flee before they change their mind. [Skill added: Turning] --- Returning to the sanctuary of your home, you settle in for a just as quiet but infinitely more interesting task. Once more Max and Johann are calling your Room of Serenity home while a bevy of papers are prepared, with only minor hitches as Johann experiments with different types of metallic inks to allow him to proofread his own work. This time, however, you're not quite able to fully lose yourself in the comfortable routine of academia, as you have to be careful exactly how your insights are presented. All three of the papers currently being written use understandings that you owe to the Liber Mortis, either directly in the case of Skaven strategy or indirectly via the understanding of Dhar it gave you that allowed you to puzzle out both the Ratling Gun and Eshin magic. You do have very good alternate explanations for how you could have come by that knowledge, but you'd much rather not have to explain in the first place. The Ratling Gun paper is simple enough, as you have to rewrite a set of your notes for Johann anyway in inks visible to his Windsight; you simply leave off some of the more exact details of the firing mechanism, leaving it explained as a Warpstone-induced explosion instead of explaining precisely the flash-decay that the Warpstone firing crystal induces. The rest requires no more than an Apprentice-level understanding of magic's nature, as the attraction between Dhar and other magics is warned against early and often. The second part of the paper is trickier, at least for Johann: countermeasures. He gets as far as Fault of Form and speculates on whether Law of Gold would be applicable, and runs out of steam. You take a break from your own papers to sketch out a few ideas, then a few more, and next thing you know the sun's gone down and you're looking at half a manuscript that spells out exactly how anyone with a modicum of magical talent can turn a firing Ratling Gun into a rapidly expanding cloud of shrapnel. Johann is more than happy to append it to the end of his effort and call it a day. [Ratling Gun paper: Learning, 11+16+10(Breach the Unknown)+15(mostly thorough notes)=52.] [Ratling Gun countermeasures: Learning, 6+16+9(Library: Warpstone)=31.] [Mathilde interrupt: Learning, 100+27+5(Tactics: Skaven)+9(Library: Warpstone)-20(multitasking)=121.] [Internal Mechanisms of the Ratling Gun, and How to Foil Them, 2483. Subject: Rare, +1. Insight: Revolutionary, +2. Delivery: Dull, -1. Precious, +1. Thorough, +1. Tactically Significant: +2. Classified, -2. Total: +4.] Your work with Max quickly falls into a rhythm of surging forward with the paper on Skaven warfare when inspiration strikes, and falling back to the Queekish-Reikspiel Dictionary when it flags. There's no lack of information to draw from, ranging from your own experience, to that of human and Dwarven authors in your library, to the precious few texts on the subject you have from Skaven writers, to the insights provided by Qrech. And, of course, most precious of all, the war diary of Frederick van Hal, containing not only his own keen intellect but a few pearls of wisdom that must have come from he who would become Vlad von Carstein. (You're distracted from your task by a while by an unexpected pang of regret that you levelled Castle Drakenhof. How much could you have learned from but a single book written by him?) The paper does, you feel, suffer from the need to conceal the greatest source of your knowledge, as you're forced to reverse engineer plausible chains of logic of how you could have derived that information from your experiences or from more suitable texts. But Max once more rises to the occasion, and he manages to wrestle many a clumsy passage into submission where you were on the verge of excising it completely. The final product isn't as great as it was in your imagination, but so very little is, and it's readable, accessible, and delivers a lot of very useful information in a way that doesn't, you hope, raise questions. That's enough. [Skaven strategy and tactics paper: Martial, 58+23+5(Strategy/Tactics: Skaven)+13(Library: Skaven)+10(Amanuensis)=109.] [Winning the War Below, 2483. Subject: Uncommon, +0. Insight: Confirming, +1. Delivery: Competent, +0. Thorough, +1. Varied, +1. Alien, +1. Accessible, +1. Tactically Significant, +2. Classified, -2. Total: +5.] Writing the lexicon is, in comparison, no effort at all. Every possible stumbling block has already been encountered and defeated in the process of writing the Khazalid equivalent. You do spend some time on the side trying to come up with a better pronunciation guide, as well as spending a fair bit of effort on excising the text of any linguistic flourishes that you feel are identifiably yours or Max's, but it's more to keep your mind occupied while doing the long and dull task of cataloguing an entire language than anything that has much of an effect on the final product. After some discussion you label it simply: Queekish. [Queekish, 2483. Pending.] The final paper is more of a report than a full essay as you distil your lingering memories of the Eshin Sorcerer, and the notes you took at the time, into as much raw data as possible. Grey Seers are notorious and feared, as are the Warlock-Engineers of Clan Skryre, but the existence of an Eshin-specific brand of warp magic was known only by a few dubious accounts and mostly thought to be fictional. You saw proof to the contrary, and saw one wield magic that seems to be to Ulgu what necromancy is to Shyish, and thus is completely distinct to the magic of the Grey Seers, and disproving theories that the possibility of such a hybrid with Dhar was unique to Shyish. So even with its brevity, and even with the necessity of secrecy, you've no doubt that even this short a paper will turn some heads. [Eshin Sorcerer paper: Learning, 37+27+10(Windsage)+4(Library: Skaven Warp Magic)=78.] [An Eyewitness Account of a Distinct Variety of Skaven Sorcery, 2483. Subject: Rare, +1. Insight: Shattering, +3. Delivery: Competent, +0. Exotic, +1. Precious, +1. Classified, -2. Total: +4.] When you return to Altdorf, not only will you be collecting a Battle Altar, you'll be dropping quite a payload of intelligence upon the Grey College. You can barely wait. The only question is: who will you present this linguistic coup to? [ ] Emperor Luitpold [ ] The Imperial Spymaster [ ] Supreme Patriarch Dragomas [ ] Magister Patriarch Algard [ ] Other (write in) - There will be a two hour moratorium. - The identity of the Imperial Spymaster is unknown to you, as they officially do not exist. But this could get you a meeting. - Whoever is chosen, it will be kept as secret as the Empire is capable of keeping it, and it will get to where it needs to go.

Turn 28 Results - 2483.5 - Part 2

Spoiler: Voting result [*] Magister Patriarch Algard Spoiler: Unfinished business -[*] DUCK: Spend time with Hubert to try to ensure a good relationship between him and magic, and between him and his identity as a Wizard. -[*] Commission an altar based on (boosted) Transformation of Kadon. --[*] Able to transform non-wizards. --[*] Optimized to reduce destructive consequences in case of miscast. --[*] Can only be activated by a Dwarf not currently being transformed. --[*] Can only be activated with one of three keystones. --[*] Transportable but heavy and unwieldy enough that even the resulting dragon can not just carry it away. --[*] COIN: The Gambler -[*] Attempt to interest a prominent and knowledgeable Runesmiths in the interaction between Runes and Vitae. (will start at the top and work your way down) With all the tests and experiments you've performed with the Aethyric Vitae, it's come time to bring in a Runesmith to examine the interactions between Runes and Vitae, foremost of all your hope that it could be used to rapidly charge Runes dependent on absorbing ambient magic. You've decided to start at the top and work your way down, and though there could be much debate on the matter of which Runelord could be considered the greatest of all, you start with Kragg on the grounds that the two of you have worked together well in the past. Rolling... You find Kragg in his workshop, as expected, tinkering with an axe while shooting surly looks at Bok looming in one corner. The glare he levels at the vial of Vitae you brought threatens to detonate it as it shrinks away from his gaze, and though he does you the courtesy of hearing you out, he eventually declines, citing that the future of Runecrafting will always lie in the greatness of the past, not in material oddities from the Warp. But he does suggest you take it to someone who isn't doing anything useful with their time so they can see if it might be of some use, and though he doesn't specify, it's more than clear who he means by that. Thorek Ironbrow doesn't spend much time at Karak Eight Peaks of late, but he does pass through it quite regularly as he travels to every corner of the extant Karaz Ankor to establish his status in person. Your status as Loremaster means you're able to secure a meeting with him when next he passes through, and he spends some time inspecting the vial. "The undifferentiated substance of the Polar Realm," he says slowly. "It can be contained safely?" You hand over your design for a runic array to keep it suspended and isolated, and he spends even more time studying that. "And division can be reliably induced. If the repellent fields could ensure a specific amount is dropped onto a catalyst..." It's clear he doesn't care much for the substance, but the idea of being able to supply large but precise amounts of magical energy on demand intrigues him, and after much grumbling he concedes it wouldn't be a complete waste of time on his part to pursue the project. A week later the more portable portions of his workshop arrive and he establishes himself deep within the largely-unoccupied Kvinn-Wyr, and the two of you get to work - he reluctantly concedes that your senses are much sharper than whatever equivalent Runesmiths use to feel the movement of magical energy. He gets to work on experimenting, and you're given a chance to see how his approach differs to Kragg's. Kragg, from what you've seen, knows exactly what he is doing at all times. If a Rune is to be struck, he strikes it in utter confidence that it will work as he demands. Thorek is very different, starting each step with filling a large block of slate hung on the wall of his workshop with notes in chalk, and then he acts with extreme care and precision. A few prototypes are laboriously created and rejected until he settles on a simple design for a containment vessel - a steel bowl with a hole in the base and inscribed with the Rune of Valaya forms the base, and another inscribed with the Rune of Sanctuary to sit atop it. The Rune of Valaya suspends a portion of Aethyric Vitae in the centre of the sphere the two bowls form, while the Rune of Sanctuary keep any errant magical energies from interfering with it. The sphere is suspended above a steel ingot with a Rune of Spellbreaking, and then from a safe distance the Rune of Valaya is deactivated. The suspended blob of Vitae drops through the hole, falls upon the Rune of Spellbreaking, and detonates, filling the room with magical energy that is siphoned away into Runic collectors Thorek had set up. This success prompts Thorek to return to the drawing board, and he designs a more self-contained system, calculating precisely how much energy could saturate a specific area until the Winds are forced to intermingle and form Dhar. Eight vents are built on each side of a precisely-measured cubic detonation chamber, one for each Wind, and the energies are funnelled into an adjoining hinged octahedron, which can be opened to place an Anvil Rune inside - or a newly-made absorption Rune, for Thorek won't risk an Anvil Rune on this just yet. A mechanism is added to empty a flask into the containment chamber from above, Thorek observes the detonation in action several times, and then he returns once more to the drawing board, and you have to bite your tongue to refrain from commenting. After weeks of work, the final prototype is shown, and you have to admit to being impressed. The uppermost mechanism allows for a row of sealed containers to be held ready a safe distance from one another, and then delivers them at precise intervals into the containment chamber. After enough time has passed for the Vitae in the containment chamber to have formed a sphere from the semi-spherical repellent field that suspends it, the Rune of Valaya is deactivated and the Vitae drops into the detonation chamber, with a metal lid sliding over the hole a heartbeat before the Vitae reacts to the Rune of Spellbreaking. The energies are siphoned out of the chamber and delivered not just to the charging chamber, but also to the other Runes that control the process, ensuring it could run indefinitely with the only intervention needed being to refill and replace the Vitae containers. And with Thorek's face lined with concern, you watch as for the first time a precious Anvil Rune is placed into the charging chamber, one of the ones exhausted during the rebuffing of Waaagh Birdmuncha, and then the mechanism begins its work, with the gentle noises of metal sliding over metal only interrupted by the splash-THOOMF of the Vitae being dropped and detonating. And after a number of containers are emptied, Thorek gingerly opens the charging chamber to stare at the Anvil Rune within, which now glows with contained power. "I've no doubt," he says slowly, "that your manling craft has uses for the substance. But every drop you could spare would be of great value to the descendants of Thungni." [1 gallon of Vitae expended on experimentation] --- Hubert is a bit of an odd duck. To be an Ulrican and a Wizard is an untenable position in the first place - Ulric dictates self-reliance, and a Wizard is by necessity reliant on the whims of the Winds of Magic - but to be an Ulrican and a Celestial Wizard is particularly so, as it would be difficult to find two groups more different in temperament. And on top of that he's from a noble family, and they rarely react well to finding the gift of magic amongst their offspring. So it's no surprise to you that he often seems rootless and irresolute, torn in mutually exclusive directions. If there's a glimmer of hope, it's that he's recently added Wings of Heaven to his magical repertoire. Consulting your books on Azyr, you find that the spellbook of the Celestial Order is split neatly between those that look to the sky for the portents in the stars, and those that look to the sky and weaponize it. Hubert does seem to be a poor fit for astrology and scrying the future, but he may very well be a good fit for throwing lightning around, even if that doesn't fit the approved mold of the Order. So you spend some time with him when he's not off dealing with his coreligionists of Ulrikadrin, to feel out where his mind is at and, if necessary, try to nudge it in a better direction. The easiest way to nail him down is with sparring - he's often to be found in the sparring chambers, even when Soizic isn't there to keep him company - so in between bouts, you turn the topic to the history of the Empire and his order to try to determine what it is he admires and aspires to, and after the usual suspects of Magnus the Pious and his companions, and Teclis and Yrtle and Finrier, you hear an unexpected name - Casandora, the Seeress of Mordheim, one of the Sisters of Sigmar in their efforts to prevent the tainted bounty of the comet from falling into the wrong hands. Sigmarites say that her foresight was a gift from Sigmar, but some of the Celestial Order theorize that she was channelling the power of Azyr instead, and the powerful Battle Magic to call a comet down from the heavens is said by some to have been named for her. "A member of a cloistered order who nevertheless crossed blades with the enemies of the Empire," you muse. He opens his mouth to reply, then frowns and shrugs. "Okay, when you put it like that..." You raise an eyebrow, and he sighs. "Look, I'd have been okay with the Bright Order. Or the Golds or the Greys. But I dreamed of the stars at night and I could feel a change in the weather coming three days off, so I ended up stuck with, well..." "The Celestials," you say, nodding in understanding. "Stargazers and fortune-tellers." You nod again, thoughtfully. "Just as the Greys are diplomats, and generally work completely unseen." "Right," he says, and then frowns. "And the Brights are unthinking fire dispensers instead of aspiring mechanics, the Amethysts are ascetics, and the Golds are cold and analytical and definitely don't take up punching and puppy rearing as hobbies..." He sighs. "Okay, point made." "And I'm going to keep making it," you say, prodding him with your wooden sparring blade. "I'm sure your Apprenticeship was astoundingly tedious, but now you're clear of it you can blaze your own trail. If you want, you can make the choice to never set eyes on Altdorf again, and be able to throw lightning and flit around the sky for the low price of one coin in ten. Or if you really want, I can write a letter and get you a full set of dampeners, and you can go back to Middenland and do whatever it is Middenlander nobles do, or go to Ulrikadrin and join the Winter Wolves, or stick around and join the Undumgi. But if you really set your mind to it, you can be whatever kind of Wizard you want to be and still find success and respect among the Colleges, even if you don't fit the archetype of your classmates." [Pep talk: Diplomacy, 71+14+2(Library: Azyr)=87.] For a moment you think you might have pushed him a bit too far, but after a long moment he looks down at his hands as lightning crackles along his knuckles. "I never wanted to be a Wizard of the Celestial Order," he says quietly. "But I find I've liked being a Wizard of Karak Eight Peaks." You smile, and reach out and ruffle his hair. "If that's what you want to be, that's what you can keep being. You've got it in you to achieve greatness whatever path you end up taking, but not if you never pick a path." He doesn't reply, but he does look thoughtful. And over the coming weeks, you do seem to notice him flitting about the sky more often. --- When you return to Altdorf as the nights grow long, it's with a fair bit of anticipation and a touch of trepidation. Lord Magister Luuk's words echo in your imagination, and you can imagine quite a few different ways he could have meant 'uglier than you think it'll be'. But you definitely weren't imagining what you found when you approached the Amber Tower on the appointed day and found it almost dwarfed by a massive pillar of stone propped up against it, heavily splattered with the dark stains of old blood. "You know what Herdstones are?" Lord Magister Luuk says after you enter the tower, not looking up from the battered kettle he was patiently watching. "Gathering points for the Beastmen," you say. They'd come up a time or two in tales of Regimand's travels. "They're also the complete opposite of Waystones, which scares the shit out of anyone with sense." He scratches at his shoulder, where the angry red of a new scar is visible under his leathers. "If you can interrupt them while they're setting one up, and drag the thing away before they summon reinforcements, you've got a menhir attuned to Ghur but not yet tainted by their rituals. It was a stroke of luck to find one just as you asked for this." You suppress a smile. "I carved out a recess in the side of this one, and you need to fill it with heart-blood of wild animals spilled by the blade I left in it, that's the 'key' you asked for. Wild, mind - nothing domesticated. Once it's full, the chosen subject drinks it, and as long as they drink most of it the transformation should take hold. Tea?" "Yes, please." He busies himself, and a minute later hands you a chipped stone mug of surprisingly pleasant dandelion tea. "When one of us transforms, we hold what we truly are inside of us, and so when the spell ends we revert. Someone else does not have the training to hold who they are within them, so the transformation sinks deeper into them until nothing remains untouched. So the menhir also imbues a second spell into them, which does the remembering of what they were." You nod along, but are struck by a sudden suspicion. "Imbues how?" He shrugs. "Some strange tangle of energies one of the other Colleges came up with a few years back." You repress a sigh. Ambers. Sometimes it seems like they keep more secrets by accident with their disdain for the trappings of civilization than the Greys do on purpose. "Assuming nobody dispels it, it should activate when the subject sleeps. Ideally that will be when whatever emergency they were transformed for is dealt with, but I figured if they were rendered unconscious they're probably done for anyway." "And if someone does dispel it?" "That would be a problem, and it's not an unlikely one, because someone might figure that would get rid of the dragon. If that does happen, might be kindest to wait until they sleep and then give them a quick death. They won't have the training we have to retain our selves when in the form of another, and it won't take long for them to lose themselves, and then you've got a feral beast on your hands. I recommend you don't use it if there isn't an immediate problem for them to address, because there being an enemy in the here and now should keep them concentrated for long enough. Assuming they get back to their old form in a timely manner, there shouldn't be too many long-term effects." You grimace at the thought. "What sort of dragon? Great Fire? Horned?" He sips his tea to conceal a grimace. "A dragon. Definitely a dragon. You'll see what I mean. One more reason not to let anyone get trapped that way." You thank him for his time and expertise, and he thanks you for the ephemeral promise of repayment that will likely be traded a half dozen times or more before Belegar is ever called upon to make good. And he leaves you with the not inconsiderable problem of transporting tens of tons of stone halfway across the continent. --- You're quite pleased with yourself as you enter Algard's office, as filled with anticipation as your arms are brimming with papers. He looks up as you enter, takes in your expression and your cargo, and slides his paperwork off his desk and into a sideways dimension. "Last time you came in here with that expression, we cleared the Skaven out of Ubersreik," he notes. "Funny you should mention them," you say, and slide your trio of papers across his desk to him. "There's a process for publishing these and this isn't it," he gripes, but he picks up the first anyway and winces. "Ever been on the receiving end of one of these things?" "Not personally, though I've shared a battlefield with them." The closest you came, Johann punched the operator out before they had a chance to get it operating. "Do your best to keep it that way." He skims through it, comes to the simple cantrip that will guarantee a very bad day for anyone within the blast radius of an exploding Ratling Gun, and his eyebrows rise as he mumbles and does a few experimental gestures. "That easy?" "There's a shocking amount of mechanical energy in the storage mechanism. It only takes the right nudge for a failure cascade, and that sets off the Warpstone." "This could... no, this will save lives. Probably a lot of them. Do you have other copies of this?" "Yes, and one's on its way through the system." "Good." He makes a series of gestures that does strange things to the shimmering aura of sideways dimensions in his office, and the paper disappears somewhere into his storage system. "An Eyewitness Account... You're sure? The more skilled ones can certainly look like they're using magic, but..." he opens the paper and skims through it, then stops abruptly. "Oh fuck. You're sure of what you saw?" You nod. "Never thought I'd be thankful for the Eshin ability to keep secrets. The Amethysts have a devil of a time with Necromancy, if an Ulgu equivalent got out it would be an utter nightmare. You dropped this one in the classified pile, right?" You nod again. "Good. Bloody rats." A few more gestures, and that report disappears. "And a third... Winning the War Below? I suppose you've earned some hubris," he says with a smile, but the smile slips away as he gets deeper into it. "I do think I've got some insights to share," you say with clearly false modesty. "This is... very detailed. Just a moment." He opens a drawer, rummages through the clutter inside, and then underhand lobs something to you. "Think fast." You catch it, and frown as the crystal orb glows with a shocking amount of Hysh, a tendril of pure light extruding to wave lazily through the air. "What in the-" you grimace as the Ulgu inside you rebels at so much Light magic in close proximity, and there's a crashing flutter as one of Algard's paperwork dimensions collapses. "Seriously? Did you seriously just daemon-check me?" "If any of your underlings drop three different flavours of extremely convenient and extremely unlikely insight on you in a row, I'd be very disappointed if you didn't do the same." The orb subsides, the energy tendril retracting back into its depths. "What are your sources with this one? Sudden flashes of inspiration in your dreams? Whispers on the wind? A conveniently insightful underling that appeared out of nowhere?" You begin to rebut, but then you frown. He's kind of got a point, considering the order you're delivering these in. Maybe you shouldn't have saved the best for last. "My sources," you say, standing and dropping your freshly-printed tome on his desk with a dramatic thump, "are primary." He stares down at the single word on the cover: Queekish. With slow and careful movements, he lifts the cover and begins to flip through page after page of laboriously catalogued pictograms and phonetics. "We've lost more than one to Frederheim in their attempts at unpicking their tongue," he says. "How? Your captive?" "I convinced him that we already had it translated, but internal politics meant that my requests for translations were getting stonewalled. Then I fed him a great deal of papers stolen from the Clans that were present in the Karak. He thought he was helping me defeat just those Clans, since his own was already defeated there." "This..." He frowns. "In the wrong hands, this would obliterate the Conspiracy of Silence. Who knows?" "Johann and Maximilian de Gaynesford of the Gold Order. King Belegar and his council. By now, a Khazalid version would have reached the High King of Karaz-a-Karak." "A Khazalid version is no threat, the Dwarves have been in open war against them since time immemorial. Johann... he was given dispensation, wasn't he? I'll have a word with Feldmann. Would you vouch for Maximilian?" "Completely." He looks at you, then nods. "Your security?" "Dwarves consider it sufficient to guard a holy superweapon." He snorts a laugh. "How could I forget. Very well, consider me mollified, for now. But find the time in the coming year to go through anti-Chaos training. That's an order. I'd be surprised if you hadn't already drawn the attention of at least the Changer." He turns his attention back to the book. "This is astounding work, Magister. And it's about to make the War Below a lot more interesting. Most will never learn of this, and even fewer will know that it was done by you, but those that matter will." As you make your way out of the College, you find yourself unable to stop from smiling. Your papers were so good he thought you were cheating, which is quite a compliment. Though to be fair, for some of it you were, it's just that your source was necromantic rather than daemonic. [GREAT DEED performed.] --- Thus concludes the work Mathilde performed these past months, but not every waking moment was filled with work. With whom did she spend her free time, this past year? The four with the most votes will be chosen, not counting those locked in. [+] The Wizards of Karak Eight Peaks (locked in) [+] Social interaction initiated by someone else (locked in) [+] EIC Reports (does not cost a choice) Romance Any victors from this category will trigger a subvote for how you'll spend time with them. This isn't a lock-in, this is getting to know them better to see how compatible you might be. [ ] [ROMANCE] Journeywoman Panoramia [ ] [ROMANCE] Magister Johann [ ] [ROMANCE] Elector Countess Roswita van Hal [ ] [ROMANCE] Baron Anton Kiesinger II [ ] [ROMANCE] The Ice Dragon of Karag Zilfin [ ] [ROMANCE] Chief Bombardier Oswald Oswaldson Fellow Wizards [ ] Gretel, who's apparently spending her newly-earned wealth to make herself at home. [ ] Adela, to see how she's going with her mechanical aspirations. Karak Eight Peaks Notables [ ] Elder Hluodwica, High Priestess of Esmerelda and civilian leader of the Eight Peaks Halflings. [ ] Francesco Caravello, proud Viceroy of the Undumgi. [ ] Sir Ruprecht Wulfhart, leader of the frontier town of Ulrikadrin. Foreign Relations [ ] Barak Varr, to watch the progress of the canal. [ ] Karak Hirn, to satisfy your curiosity about Prince Ulthar. Friends Abroad [ ] Kasmir, to see how he's keeping himself busy in Sylvania. [ ] Julia, to see what she has gotten up to as Stirland's most experienced spy master. [ ] Eike Hochschild, to get to know your future business partner. [ ] Empress Heidi, to pay her a social visit and see how Mandred is growing. Following Up [ ] Regimand, to finally get the full story behind the Lahmian plot you were both ensnared by. [ ] The Amber College, to check in on the salamanders. [ ] Follow up on your donation of the Skaven organ-vat, and see what has been made of it. [ ] Other (write in) - There will be a two hour moratorium. - If you have ideas for other people to spend time with, let me know. - The results of the Hochlander's actions will be part of the EIC reports. - You get four options total. This can mean you take multiple romance options, or none. - The Coin did apply, the action just took place off-screen. - The exact method for how Vitae can be translated into Runesmith gratitude will be determined in coming turns.

Turn 28 Social - 2483.5 - Part 1

Spoiler: Voting results [+] The Wizards of Karak Eight Peaks (locked in) [+] Social interaction initiated by someone else (locked in) [+] EIC Reports (does not cost a choice) [*] [ROMANCE] Magister Johann [*] Empress Heidi, to pay her a social visit and see how Mandred is growing [*] [ROMANCE] Journeywoman Panoramia [*] Karak Hirn, to satisfy your curiosity about Prince Ulthar. You first visited Karak Hirn five years ago, shortly after joining the Expedition. Since then, you've visited most of the surviving ancient holds that date back to the Time of the Ancestor Gods, and the differences are many and obvious. Though its population is significantly smaller than the Old Holds, Karak Hirn is filled to the brim with Dwarves, as its population has never been significantly bigger than it is right now, and parts of it ring with the sound of excavation and construction as more room is dug out for their still-growing population. It was never connected to the Underway, so any enemies it might face must approach overland or tunnel through untouched rock to reach them, and if anything does manage that feat, a warning and call to arms is sounded through the massive caverns that give the Hornhold its name. And situated where it is high in the mountains between Wissenland and the Border Princes, it does not face the constant threat of nearby enemies that the World's Edge Mountains so often crawl with. It's a tragic contrast, and you hope one that Karak Eight Peaks can begin to change - though thinking of Kragg's seemingly doomed obsession with the ancient elemental Bok, and how the Dwarves of the Karak are already spreading themselves thin trying to populate the same halls as their ancestors instead of more practically calling a single mountain home, it might be that your hopes are already in vain. The ancient masterpieces from before the Time of Woes are a source of great pride for the Old Holds, but also a constant reminder of how far they've fallen. You shake your morbid thoughts as you enter the Hornhold, your name alone being enough to grant you entrance, and see to the tedious task of making your way up the chain of courtiers and officials before you can gain access to the heir apparent. In contrast to how this usually goes, the higher you climb the faster it goes, as the more important Dwarves in this process are more familiar with events in the distant south, and do not doubt your claim to having reason to meet with the Prince you once fought alongside. At last you're led through the bustling passages, and you find your lips quirking in a smile as you finally set eyes once more on Ulthar, who could not be more different from the last time you saw him. Though he's still wearing the universal Dwarven 'casual' outfit - leather and chain, with a hand weapon on his hip - the small differences you've learned to spot are the equivalent to a particularly vain Altdorf noble. The chain is a silvery colour, not gromril but pretending to be, an expensive and militarily pointless variation on the silversteel of Karak Eight Peaks, his axe glints with jewels instead of Runes, and instead of braids, his sable-black beard bears silver rings, dotted with sapphires. He looks up from the table overflowing with accounts and reports, and takes a moment to blink in shock before leaping up and hurrying forward to greet you, clasping your arm in his. "Utkazakali!" he roars in delight. "Grimnir smiles on this day. What brings you to these mountains?" He waves a hand dismissively at the courtier who brought you here, who hesitates a moment before scurrying off. "Mostly a social call," you say, returning his smile. "I hear the Head Ranger of the Karak Eight Peaks Expedition has gone up in the world." He barks a grim laugh. "You could say that, but I'd disagree. Chains of gold still chafe, and I'd kill to be back on the open road." "Nobody would give me a straight answer about this whole..." you wave a hand vaguely. "Of course they won't. Some shames are too great to speak aloud in polite company." He sighs, and runs a hand over his face. "Good thing neither Rangers nor Zhufokri are polite company. I was third in line, and had my differences with my father besides, and in my rebellious youth I joined the Rangers to aggravate him further. And found astounding success in doing so - I was disinherited. Which at least meant he'd stop hounding me to get married. Then during the Expedition, my two more traditional and favoured brothers went out hunting together, and were found days later with their axes tangled in each others' guts, and their bodyguards similarly slain by one another. The only surviving bodyguard blamed the paranoia of the elder before his execution, but some dubious evidence was uncovered in their quarters that suggested the ambition of the younger was the cause." You wince. Such a tale wouldn't be out of place in human histories, but to Dwarves these events would feel as shameful to them as the reign of Dieter IV was to the Empire. "So you were reinherited?" "No such thing exists, except through forgetfulness and destroyed records. But I'm now my father's only child, and if you trace back the lineage to find the next in line - and my father did - the result is a Salkalten shipwright who has never seen the mountains. Apparently I'm preferable to that. So records were destroyed and forgetfulness was induced, and everyone who knows better stays silent, and in the privacy of their own minds their respect for my father diminishes with every day he does not travel to Karak Kadrin and take the Oath." Ulthar's face is stony, disgust thick in his tone. There's not much that can be said to that, so you place a hand on Ulthar's shoulder in comradely commiseration. "Could be worse," you eventually say. "How so?" "Let me tell you about my parents..." --- On a gyrocopter is possibly the worst place to nurse a hangover, but you do your best to recover as you make your way to Altdorf several days later, while also trying to remember how old this heir presumptive is. You were there for his first birthday, which was almost a couple of years ago, which makes him almost three, which means he's... still fairly helpless, you're pretty sure. Ridiculous. Wolf was fully grown and capable of killing a man by the age of two. You've mostly recovered by the time you touch down in Altdorf, and you pass through the security of the Imperial Palace without trouble after handing over your pistols - they don't know about Branulhune, but they do know you're a Wizard and thus capable of summoning a variety of forms of magical death if so inclined, so it's entirely a matter of being polite instead of a security measure. You make your way through the massive building until you enter the part of the palace that is the domain of the Empress, and from there you are pointed towards her current location within the gardens, a surprisingly small patch of green sandwiched between the bulk of the palace and the sprawl of the Imperial Zoo, and pause to consider your formidable coreligionist as she holds court amongst her coterie of retainers and ladies-in-waiting. The Empress looks not a year older than when you first met her as Gabriella, and is half-dressed in furs that she's partially removed as the early winter sun provides some heat, giving her a chance to also show off the silks beneath. Some of the crowd around her hold drinks and light snacks for their mistress, but others hold paper and slates, and every now and then one is dispatched to send or retrieve a document for some obscure purpose. Heidi is not resting on her laurels, and though her official station begins and ends with the creation of the heir that is currently charging around the grass waving a wooden sword at imaginary foes, the position can allow immense amounts of unofficial influence, and Heidi appears to be taking full advantage. As you approach, a wave of nudges spreads through the small crowd and you find yourself facing an array of speculative looks. They part at your approach, and Heidi makes a delighted noise and unceremoniously unseats the previous favoured who had been sitting beside her on the bench. A rapid-fire series of orders scatters the coterie with a series of tasks, including fetching drinks and snacks for you, and the two of you are very quickly left alone. "So," she says with a smile, "I hear you're making a wave or two amongst the Colleges." "There's been a bit of interest in my research," you say, matching her airy understatement. "How goes the business of Empressing?" She smiles with what seems like genuine fondness at the boy currently menacing at swordpoint the statue of Emperor Jürgen the Opulent. "It gives new meaning to 'long con', but it's not without its charms. Especially now that the northern troubles have faded to a dull roar. There's always something somewhere, but that just means there's something to keep the mind occupied." She scratches her chin thoughtfully, looking sideways at you. "Do you think you could take on Dragomas?" "What?" You consider that for all of two seconds. "No. Absolutely not. He went off the edge of the map to the 'here be dragons' and came back with the ability to turn into one. And it's even stronger than the ones the other Ambers can turn into." "That's a shame. He's a surprisingly difficult nut to crack." You shake your head in exasperation. "Be that as it may, he's very good at his job and the Battle Wizards adore him. I don't envy anyone that succeeds him." "Any idea who that might be?" You consider it. "Elspeth von Draken probably could if she wanted to, but she only took up leadership of the Amethyst after whatever happened to Hexensohn and there were no better candidates. Paranoth might be able to, he was Supreme Patriarch for a few years, but that was years before I was even an Apprentice. Algard likes him too much, No-Relation Reicthard doesn't seem the type... I think the most likely candidate to try is Feldmann of the Golds, he's said to be ambitious and he's very good at getting along with non-Wizards... but to me, that suggests that he's not dipped enough into his Wind to stand a chance." You shake your head. "I think Dragomas is going to be a fact of life for the foreseeable future. And though that might not be ideal for your ambitions, I think he's good for the Empire." "Oh, fine. It was just a passing thought, anyway." "If your palms are getting itchy, watch the rivers." "Is this about the peat thing? The Grand Theogonist will not shut up about it." "No, no. The channels." "Ostermark's project?" "And between the Aver and the Black Water." "Oh, that." She frowns. "Isn't it a series of locks?" You sigh. "It will have both. My point is, it's going to stir things up for trade throughout the southern Empire. There's going to be plenty of opportunities for you to get up to mischief without causing another Night of a Thousand Arcane Duels." "Trade is just fencing for the boring," she says loftily, but you can see her considering it. "Mandred darling," she calls out, and the lad turns from tormenting the former Emperors. "Come and say hello to your Godmother." "Speaking of," you say as the boy approaches, "what's the cover story for how we know each other?" "The truth told sideways is the best lie. We met in Stirland and hit it off, and I've decided you'd make a suitable protector for the lad if anything were to happen." "Hit it off? I seem to recall giving serious consideration to hauling off and whacking you with my sword," you grumble, and turn to the child. With a look of great concentration on his face, he gives you a solid attempt at a courtly bow. "Pleasedtomeetyoufairlady," he recites in a practiced burst, then smiles, pleased with himself. "Quite charming, isn't he?" Heidi says, ruffling his hair. Mandred lifts his arms up at her, and she obliging picks him up and perches him on her lap, and he snuggles against her happily. "Fairly," you concede, watching the future Emperor pluck at loose hairs on Heidi's stole. You refrain from mentioning that Wolf is capable of talking in complete sentences. You suppose teaching someone to talk is harder when they're not directly linked to your mind. --- As you make your way out of the Palace some time later, you find yourself tailed by someone that's so overflowing with nervousness that you can feel them coming. You seriously consider summoning Branulhune as they finally summon their courage enough to approach, but instead of coming at you with a knife, they bow nervously and stutter, "Dame Weber! I am Baronet Holzkrug, in the service of the Chamberlain of the Seal. He would like to meet with you, and talk of matters of state." Though you keep from showing it, you're quite surprised. The Chamberlain of the Seal answers directly to the Emperor and is responsible for foreign relations, and the current holder of the role is Graf Otto von Bitternach, who despite his youth has been able to cultivate a reputation for fair and straightforward dealing with the allies of the Empire. "What matters, specifically?" "He would like your insight into the inner workings of our steadfast allies of the Karaz Ankor." Though the young man is clearly a bundle of nerves, you can't see any misdirection in him, so you give the only answer one can give when called upon by the Imperial Council - you accede. And as you follow the man into the part of the palace dedicated to the bureaucratic warrens that do their best to run the Empire, you consider what you will say. You owe loyalty to the Empire, but also to King Belegar, and there's likely to be questions put to you in the following meeting where your answer cannot fully serve both. [ ] Speak honestly of everything you're asked about, even outright secrets of the Karaz Ankor [ ] Speak honestly of everything not explicitly secret, including rifts within the Karaz Ankor [ ] Conceal matters you know the Dwarves would prefer you conceal --- You have also resolved to embark on the first tentative steps of romance, starting with getting to know Johann and Panoramia better. How exactly will you go about this? Johann: [ ] You've got a puppy, he's got several. Easy. Spend time with him as your pup plays with his. [ ] Though you both use your magic to cheat, you both have an interest in personal fitness. Work out with him. [ ] There's a festival to Grungni coming up, and Johann has taken to observing the Holy Days of the Ancestor-God. Join him in this. [ ] Other (write in) Panoramia: [ ] Though you rarely think of those days, you did grow up on a farm and know something of the soil. Spend time with her as she goes about her work. [ ] The Halflings are renowned chefs, and several restaurants have opened clustered around the base of Karag Nar. Share a meal with her. [ ] Panoramia currently calls a small cottage somewhere in the Eastern Valley home, help her expand it into a proper tower. [ ] Other (write in) - There will be a two hour moratorium. - If you have a different set of criteria in mind with the meeting with the Chamberlain, please suggest them. - The suggestions given for romance are off the top of my head. Write-ins are absolutely valid here.

The Chamberlain of the Seal

Spoiler: Voting results [X] Speak honestly of everything not explicitly secret, including rifts within the Karaz Ankor [X] The Halflings are renowned chefs, and several restaurants have opened clustered around the base of Karag Nar. Share a meal with her. [X] There's a festival to Grungni coming up, and Johann has taken to observing the Holy Days of the Ancestor-God. Join him in this. The nervous Baronet leads you through the bureaucratic sprawl and then out the other side again into the more sumptuous portions of the palace, finally leading you to a room you recognize by reputation - the room that houses the Great Chart. In it, most of the floor is inlaid with various materials making up a massive scale model of the Empire, with rivers of pearl, lakes of silver, and forests of ebony, with ivory buttons representing individual cities. The man you are here to meet is sitting on a stool, staring thoughtfully down at the flowing rivers of the southern Empire, and he turns to meet you as you enter and the Baronet flees. Graf Otto von Bitternach is a serious-faced and prematurely balding man with a very neat beard, and has risen to the Council of State due to possessing the rare gift of somehow managing to reach accords with Dwarves and Elves, Royarch and Tzar, and every variety of despot and demagogue known to the southern realms. "Magister Weber," he says, inclining his head toward you. "An honour." "Chamberlain von Bitternach," you reply, bowing. "The honour is mine." "When I heard you were gracing the Palace, I could not miss the opportunity to draw on your knowledge." He speaks with the practiced tones of a trained orator, and from his reputation, you've no doubt his words are chosen carefully. "How can I assist the Council of State?" "I have at my disposal a dozen experts on the Karaz Ankor, but all draw what they know from the same teachings, and none can give me a satisfactory answer. You have lived amongst them, and serve the King of one of the greatest of the Old Holds." He gestures at the map, towards where Karak Kadrin is symbolized in steel. "My envoys all tell me that High King Thorgrim cares little for trade, and my own personal meetings with him reinforce that. And yet everywhere I look there are channels and locks being constructed, and the trade companies of the East and South maneuver to purchase boats and docks, and Barak Varr is fundamentally restructuring their navy for construction. What conclusion am I to draw from this?" Ah. "You described Karak Eight Peaks as an Old Hold. Is that what your experts tell you?" "Some believe they may be strongly influenced by the Young Holds, but King Belegar was raised in Karaz-a-Karak and their closest ally is Karak Azul." You take a moment to consider how to put this. "When I first started living with the Dwarves, I was struck by the cultural divide between the Young Holds and the Old Holds. It's an easy impression to reach, and one that few Dwarves will discourage. But the truth is..." You pause, trying to find the best way to tell him what he needs to know without speaking ill of those you live amongst. "I know a radical engineer who once told me that the only Old Hold is Karaz-a-Karak, and the more I see of the Karaz Ankor, the more truth I find in his words. Set aside Karak Azul, which has been isolated for generations. Karak Kadrin is pragmatic, Zhufbar is progressive - at least by Dwarf standards - and Barak Varr is cosmopolitan. And to assuage the guilt they feel for veering from the path of their ancestors, they speak a great deal of their admiration for the Old Ways, and allow themselves to be labelled an Old Hold, and allow Karaz-a-Karak a certain level of cultural primacy." He considers your words. "So you're saying they're no different to..." He waves a hand vaguely at the Empire, with its borders picked out in rosewood. "There's never been a recorded Civil War amongst the Dwarves," he says dubiously. "Not quite. They don't think like we do. A human is very good at convincing himself that he's in the right. A Dwarf will obsessively dwell on them being in the wrong. I suspect they find it literally impossible not to. So an Elector that is upset at the Emperor will convince himself why it's okay for him to divide Sigmar's Empire, but a Dwarven King upset at the High King will brood endlessly on how they are failing Grungni's Karaz Ankor. So instead of rebellion, you have a growing silence, until the King succumbs to despair and relations are normalized with the heir's ascension." You think of Belegar and suppress a wince. "So Karaz-a-Karak is able to project an image of unity because those that disagree are silenced by the shame of failing their Ancestors." "And any Dwarf I ask about the matter will clam up instead of acknowledging the fiction. How independent are they, truly?" "They have the same values and the same enemies, but differ in how they go about things. So while Karaz-a-Karak cares nothing for trade because it is astonishingly wealthy, mostly self-sufficient, and relatively isolated, the other 'Old' Holds care very much. Barak Varr is a trade port, Karak Kadrin taxes Peak Pass and trades with Ostermark, and Zhufbar relies on trade for the components of gunpowder." "That explains why nobody in Karaz-a-Karak had much to say on the topic of canals, even when so many Dwarves and resources are being applied to them." He sighs. "Could they be convinced to stop?" You blink in surprise. "Stop? But this would be hugely to the Empire's advantage. Shortening trade with the Southern realms would-" "Yes, everyone loves to cut out the middleman," he interrupts you, "but then are so often taken by surprise at the middleman cutting back." You turn your eyes to Marienburg, still depicted here as an Imperial province. "Ah." "They're threatening an embargo, and these canals won't be functional soon enough to stop it from biting. And the Chancellor says that would do unacceptable things to our budget. So we'd have no choice but to try to force the issue. The Battle of Grootscher Marsh was a disaster for the Empire, and though some are keen for a rematch, the timing is terrible. Stirland is locked in combat with Vampires, Wissenland took heavy losses against..." he hesitates, eyeing you and frowning. "Skaven," you supply. "Oh, good. Against Skaven. And the trouble in the north over..." He hesitates again. "The Eonir." "Right, Grey Wizard. And Ostland's still nervous about spillover from Kislev and their Ogre problems, and we're not fully sure we've stamped down the latest from Drachenfels here in the Reikland. So that leaves two provinces ready for war." He pauses, frowning. "Three. Forgot Hochland. Against every mercenary the bloated coffers of Marienburg can lure, and if history charts the same course as last time..." "Ulthuan," you say grimly. "They've done quite well out of their partnership with Marienburg, and they're even less willing to give a straight answer than usual on the matter. So I put it to you - can the Dwarves be convinced to stop building the canal between the Aver and the Black Waters?" Under the piercing gaze of the Chamberlain of the Seal, you consider your answer carefully. [ ] The High King could make it so This is likely to cause discontent within the Karaz Ankor. [ ] For sufficient concessions This would weaken the Empire. [ ] They can make up for the loss in trade This would weaken the Karaz Ankor and the Empire until the canals are complete. To clarify: this would involve the Karaz Ankor paying the Empire for what they lose in trade income, as well as arranging alternate routes for crucial goods. [ ] No, but they could help break the blockade Barak Varr is the main force behind the project, and would not hesitate to deploy their navy in support of the Empire's to reopen trade routes. To clarify: this would involve destroying Marienburg's navy and any chains, booms, and gates capable of blocking the river. [ ] No, but they would fight beside you This could easily be spun as Elven sabotage of a Dwarven project. Dwarven pride would have the Throngs march alongside the Imperial Army, and Marienburg could be reclaimed. [ ] No, they cannot be dissuaded It's hard to say what this would result in. [ ] I don't know Wash your hands of the matter. - There will be a two hour moratorium. - Most of the Empire's rivers flow to the Reik and meet the sea at Marienburg. By refusing to allow foreign vessels to pass, they effectively blockade the Empire without having to project power outside their territory.

Turn 28 Social - 2483.5 - Part 2

Spoiler: Voting results and unfinished business [*] No, but they could help break the blockade [*] [ROMANCE] Magister Johann -[*] There's a festival to Grungni coming up, and Johann has taken to observing the Holy Days of the Ancestor-God. Join him in this. [*] [ROMANCE] Journeywoman Panoramia -[*] The Halflings are renowned chefs, and several restaurants have opened clustered around the base of Karag Nar. Share a meal with her. [+] The Wizards of Karak Eight Peaks (locked in) [+] EIC Reports (does not cost a choice) "Not without doing significant damage to relationships between the Dwarfholds involved and the Empire," is your eventual response. "They would see it as cowardice, that the Empire is having terms dictated to them by a city-state. They'd question why the Imperial Navy doesn't simply sail into Marienburg and break the blockade - in fact," you continue, as though you'd only just thought of it, "Barak Varr would be almost certain to be willing to aid such an effort with their own naval forces." Otto von Bitternach's expression turns calculating as he considers that. "A potent threat to be able to level," he muses, "and if matters do escalate, even Ulthuan would have to think twice before engaging with the combined navies of the Empire and Barak Varr. The First is hemmed in here, but if we had the Second go find some Reavers or something to loudly clash against, they would have to either let our fleets combine or give us a credible charge against them of aiding and abetting piracy and the Ruinous Powers, which could peel off Ulthuan, or it might bring in Kislev and Bretonnia..." He stares intensely down at the ivory button representing Marienburg before seeming to remember your presence. "The Emperor's thanks for providing your insight on the matter. Pass on his regards to King Belegar." --- When you return to the Karak, the first thing you do is go through your reports from the EIC to check for any signs of Marienburger mischief. You're quite relieved to find that everything appears normal, and the EIC's grip on the northern bank of the Aver almost complete. Since you've got all the paperwork out anyway, you move on to checking through the rest of the reports from up north, starting with the Hochlander's adventures in Talabecland, and find yourself quite surprised. You'd expected the Templars of Sigmar to descend upon the innocent populace of Talabecland like a Khornate Beastherd on the warpath, but all indications are that they quickly and efficiently winnowed through the citizens of note with no more threats than necessary and systematically narrowed the suspects down until they identified the culprits as a loose collection of allied burghers in Krugenheim and Ossino, who thought they could avoid suspicion by pointing investigators back and forth between the two towns until they gave up. They thought wrong, and ended up answering to the pyres. The Hochlander's contribution to the project was minimal, though if his reports are accurate you can't find fault with his attempt, it was simply a matter of the Witch Hunters having both more manpower and a larger information network in the form of the Church of Sigmar. But he did manage to keep up with the investigation and give every appearance of helpful cooperation, as well as aiding the Witch Hunters with transportation upon EIC wagons and boats, and has come away from the project with a significant list of contacts within the Templars of Sigmar. Which is the sort of thing that might come in very handy in the future, even if you're not their biggest fan. Reading through the reports from the rest of the EIC, it seems the Army of Stirland is making ready to break camp and tighten the encirclement of the vampire-controlled towns with the Spring thaw. Personally, you'd think it would be best to allow the lack of income time to really wear on them, but Roswita has demonstrated a definite preference to act quickly in Sylvania, and so far it seems mostly to be working out for her. The only other oddity is reports from Talabecland that there's been a fairly significant increase in the worship of Karnos, the local God of the Hunt. Unusual, but as he's not proscribed and seems relatively harmless, it's probably not anything to worry about. --- Most of Karagril remains empty, with mining and masonry Clans currently in residence filling only a tiny fraction of its capacity. The majority of its passages are lonely, eerie stone corridors full of echoes and shadows. But there is one major exception: the Temple of Grungni, finished last year and a destination for anyone wishing to venerate the Ancestor God of Mining and Stoneworking. Some humans might consider this an unusually minor niche for such a prominent God, comparing him to such regional godlings as Gargali of Wissenland or Vallich of Nordland. But it was Grungni's teachings that allowed the Dwarves to survive the coming of chaos as they dug deeper and deeper into the protective embrace of the mountains, and it is the bounty of those mountains that puts weapons in the hands and wealth in the vaults of the Dwarven people. So they venerate him as one of the three foremost Ancestor Gods, sometimes calling him the Father of the Dwarven race or the first High King of the Karaz Ankor. And every hundred days when it is time to celebrate the Festival of Grungni, only the most vital of work or dire of illnesses will prevent any given Dwarf from participating. That Johann is joining the festivities is something of a surprise. Not the fact that the Dwarves allow it - Grungni has a number of followers in the Empire as the God of the Forge, and you've read of a Temple to him in Nuln - but the fact that a Gold Wizard would adopt any God, as they're usually the least religious of the Colleges, both by tradition and the influence of Chamon. "That's usually the case," he says quietly as the gathered Dwarves file out of the Temple and towards the Underway. "But there's a standing order amongst the Gold Order to make whatever overtures possible towards Dwarven religion." You frown. "To what end?" "Nothing specific, at least as far as I'm aware. We're just aware they're the foremost crafters of the Old World, and anything we can do to get in their good graces is to our advantage. But besides that, I've had a lifetime of hearing tales of the great deeds the Gods have supposedly done, but you'd be amazed at how many 'slivers of Sigmar's armour' or 'weight from Verena's scales' have origins in a local blacksmith when you hit them with Tale of Metal. So it never really rang true for me." "So what makes the Ancestor Gods different? Is it the Disciple of the Pick business?" He hesitates, and you brace yourself. "What did you do?" He hesitates a moment longer. "The First Mine, under the Citadel? The Priest took me to visit it as part of my training. I was supposed to meditate in there, but I was curious, and it turns out trace amounts of gromril left behind by a miner counts as 'creation'. I only got the split second of the pick striking the stone, but... it was Them. All three of Them. One mining, one smelting, and one striking down the greenskins. I don't know if they were Gods, but what I saw of Them was more than enough to justify worshipping Them." Though part of you is aghast at how Johann had apparently been systematically ensorcelling supposed divine artifacts, you can understand the effect that must have had on him. During the quiet parts of the Battle of the Caldera, you saw Dwarves fall to their knees in numbed awe simply from standing in a mineshaft dug by Grungni's own hand. To have caught a glimpse of the Ancestor Gods themselves as they performed one of their greatest acts must have been overwhelming to someone that had never felt the touch of divinity. --- The Barrows are the most secure of the mines that the Karak is currently working, and the procession splits off as it works its way deeper underground. The topmost levels have been exhausted, but small nuggets of ores and native metals have been secreted around the place for the youngest of children to discover as they swing their tiny picks at piles of loose rock. Below that, the miners have carefully uncovered minor veins without excavating them and marked the path to them for youths strong enough to do some actual mining, but not yet knowledgeable enough for prospecting. All the adults - including you and Johann, though a number of Dwarves hinted that you might be better off sticking to the shallower tunnels - are to strike the earth and genuinely discover metal for yourself. Perhaps not the most romantic setting, but that might just be a matter of perspective - it is a religious obligation to leave your fellow miners be unless they're actively threatened by enemies or cave-ins, even if the sounds coming out of their side branch sound nothing like metal on stone. It's apparently an unspoken tradition for courting couples to venture into the mines together and return with a suspicious lack of ore. You're not sure if Johann knows about that part. You went forward on the assumption that he didn't, otherwise asking to join him for this would have been even more awkward than it was. As it goes deeper, the procession splits off over and over until you and Johann are left alone with your borrowed pick-axes and your very own side branch, with a single bobbing Marsh Light to cast illumination. To anyone else, it would be a tiny spot of illumination in a sea of darkness, but to you it does just enough to turn pitch black into the shadow in which your magical senses thrive. And Johann has no need of light at all, with his Magesight not only able to show him the stone around him, but making the seeking of metal-bearing ore trivial. "Do you know anything about mining?" you ask, weighing the pick in your hands. "Hit the rock until metal comes out," Johann says. "Or ores, I suppose. Let's see..." He stops walking and tilts his head as he reaches out with his Magesight. "On the left, about an arm's length in. It's shining like a beacon." He walks over to the spot, seems to peer at the wall through his blindfold, and taps it with his pick. "Right here." "Shining? Is it magical?" You're not sure what sort of omen it is to find Warpstone during a Festival to Grungni, but it can't be good. "No, wrong sort of shining. I think it's lodestone." He takes an experimental swing at the wall, and a small cloud of rock-dust bursts forth, along with a few sparks. "That's a good sign, right? Sparks means metal?" You take a moment to summon Ulgu into your muscles, then step up and swing alongside him, raising a second cloud. "I have no idea," he says frankly. The two of you quickly fall into a rhythm, your Ulgu-infused muscles keeping pace with his golden ones. "They don't teach properties of metals in the Gold College?" "Probably do to most, but you need to be at least theoretically capable of Alchemy to take the class." He keeps his tone light, but it's clearly artificial. "Ah." You remember a few of your classmates who ran into similar roadblocks. Most of them are still Apprentices to this day. "Yeah. I was lucky that my Master gave me the chance to prove myself instead of dropping me right into Perpetual. I decided if I was going to be stuck at one third of a Gold Wizard, I'd have to be three times as good to break even. Eventually I had begged, borrowed, and stole enough coin for my first Gilding. Got made Journeyman on the spot. Who needs alchemy?" "Better to do one thing well than be mediocre at everything," you say. "My Master told me that, then got annoyed when I skipped Diplomacy class." He gives a brief laugh. "I suppose you're as typical a Grey Wizard as I am a Gold." "Never developed the habit of sticking to the shadows. My first grown-up assignment was to the Council of Stirland. Made it difficult to act innocent." He pauses mid-swing. "Wait, the whole Stirland thing was your Journeying?" "It was definitely educational." You take a step back from the wall to take a breath of clear air. "Damn dust. This must be why Dwarves have beards." "I haven't noticed any dust," Johann says with a smile, and you wonder if his Magesight can see enough to notice someone rolling their eyes at him. --- The two of you emerge from the Barrows not long after with an egg-sized chunk of lodestone and about ten times its weight in dust clinging to each of you. You think yearningly of your bathroom, but part of the festival is to eat and drink still covered in onk - the dirt and grime of honest work underground. Apart from the Dwarves seeing to food and drink, everyone else is at least as dirty as you, from the smallest child to the most wizened Elder. You lead Johann to a serious-faced Dwarf with a massive ledger and a very tall pile of small sacks, who carefully records and labels the lodestone - a sensible precaution to prevent the unearthed minerals from being lost in the drinking to come - and then over to a wagon stacked high with barrels. You walk away from it with two large flagons of good ale, and you take a seat on a bench freshly hewn from rock. "What happens to the ores?" you ask Johann. "They'll be either smelted or cut to an appropriate size, usually by someone doing penance. Dwarf merchants always make sure they have plenty of rings and pendants and whatnot they can be mounted in, or you can just drill a hole in it and wear it on a string. It brings good fortune. Shavings and off-cuts are all smelted together and given to anyone that didn't find anything." "What, a sort of pot-luck alloy?" "I thought it was odd too at first, but it's a moral teaching. The Hold will look after you if you need it, but it's better to be self-sufficient." You nod in understanding. Dwarves usually don't trust metaphors, but the exception is when it's about mining or metals or both. "You know, when I joined the Expedition, I never expected anything like this," Johann says, looking out at the growing, sprawling crowd of feasting and drinking Dwarves. "It's so... normal. I mean, everyone's a Dwarf, but it's not that different to Sigmartag or the Festival of Light or the Day of Folly. I thought it would be like the stories of Karak Azgal, where there was a tiny oasis of peace atop a massive sprawling warren of monsters to kill and treasure to loot. I'd grab some Skaven-y bits and write a few papers and prove that I deserved my Magistership and get out before a Waaagh or something wiped the foothold off the map. But we did it. We took back Karak Eight Peaks. And we're sitting on enough Skaven artifacts and technology to pump out papers for the next decade." "We did it," you echo with a smile. - Remainder of social turn to come.

Turn 28 Social - 2483.5 - Part 3

The community inside Karag Nar has come a long way since it was first conquered, and a great deal of this is due to the fact that most of its founders had fifty crowns worth of silver in their pocket, a generous and reliable pay-packet for their continued work securing Death Pass, and no rent to pay. A number of veterans of the Expedition opted to open taverns and small businesses of their own rather than join the ranks of the Undumgi, and they were soon joined by ambitious travellers seeking to acquire some of that silver for themselves. First came the merchants, then came the tinkers, then came craftsmen of every imaginable type, and now you can get your shoe repaired, your knife sharpened, your clothes laundered, and top it off with a nice cup of Arabyan coffee or Cathayan tea, all without leaving the gallery. And amongst the most popular of these are the ones you have to leave the Karag proper for: the cluster of taverns and restaurants built around the base of Karag Nar and operated by the Halflings. A few offer their own brews, but ever since the Dourback Clan arrived, most offer an identical array of Dwarven beers and ales, and do their best to draw customers with the foods they offer alongside these drinks. Many of those who frequented Halfling establishments were attracted to the serving sizes, but to those more gourmet than gourmand, the destination of choice was Josias' Arms, possibly because one had to walk halfway to the Citadel to reach it. The operators had expected to cater entirely to their fellow Halflings, and to capitalize on this unexpected popularity and prevent their customers from banging their heads on the low ceiling or getting lost in the fields on the way home, they've just opened The Rest of Josias much closer to Karag Nar. It seems the perfect setting to get to know Panoramia better, as she has an affinity for the Halflings and you have an affinity for obscure puns and eating meals someone else has prepared. Making the invitation is easier said than done. With Johann you just sort of invited yourself along to something he was already going to, but this isn't so simple and Panoramia is, well, trickier than Johann. Johann and Max have grown accustomed to a certain level of inscrutability on your part, but Panoramia has developed something of an ability to see through at least some of your usual facades through the years. You consider and reject a number of different approaches over a few weeks, and just as you were closing in on a perfect plan, Wolf gets fed up and goes and asks her on your behalf. She accepted, and called Wolf a good boy. He was insufferably smug for days. --- You'd fretted about what to wear for a few minutes because it seems the customary thing to do, but you knew all along you were going to wear the same thing you always wear, and as Panoramia would be coming straight from the fields she's unlikely to have dressed up for it anyway. As your training demands, you arrive early to get a feel for the place and secure an advantageous position, which turns out to be a table in one corner where you could put your back to the wall, and with a window close enough to dive through in case of attack or awkward silences. Being built and furnished with non-Halflings in mind, The Rest of Josias is quite navigable, but everything's still slightly lower down than human construction and it gives it a rather cozy atmosphere that you find yourself rather liking. You cloak yourself in Take No Heed and catch up on your reading while waiting for Panoramia to arrive. "The Most Noble Art of the Sky," comes an unexpected voice some time later, jarring you out of the book. "Thinking of changing Orders?" "To the Celestials?" you reply with a grimace, letting the part of your concentration that was keeping your spell sustained dissipate. "Too lofty for my liking. I'm hoping it will help me get inside Hubert's head." Panoramia slides into the seat across from you. As you'd expected, she's wearing robes similar to your own except in shade, and though there's dirt on her robe and under her nails there's none on the rest of her hands or on her face, and some lingering dampness to her hair leads you to suspect she washed off in an aqueduct on her way here. "He's the least Celestial Celestial I've ever even heard of," she says, looking aside for a moment to say a few words in what you assume to be Mootish towards a server who's looking at your suddenly-occupied table with some confusion. "That's the problem. He was - still is, I suppose - a Noble. He was going to either inherit or end up in a Knightly Order or Ulric's priesthood, then some time in his teenage years that was snatched away. I can't even begin to imagine what that would do to a person." "Your family were farmers, right?" "Peasants," you correct. "Magic was certainly preferable. You always knew you were destined for the Jade Order, right?" "In one way or another," she says with a nod. "Two Wizard parents made magical ability likely, but even if it hadn't bloomed in me I'd still serve the Order. There's always work to be done." "What was it like, always knowing?" She laughs. "Embarrassing, in the end. I had fretted so much about never getting it, then when it pulsed in such a way that it was undeniable I realized it'd been there for years. I didn't realize that most people can't feel the rhythm of the seasons or the slow-soul of a tree." "You've got tactile Magesight?" "Most Jades do, that or emotive. What's it like for you?" "Mostly visual, except for Waaagh and Dhar." "Ooh, what colour am I?" You barely have to concentrate. "You're pure green. Wizards always stick out like that. Makes it hard to know what they're feeling." "Wow, that must be useful. Especially for a Grey Wizard." "Sometimes. It shows me what they're feeling but not why they're feeling that way. I almost drew steel on a courtier the other week because he was so nervous I thought he was about to try to attack me, but he just had a message. I guess he was intimidated." "Grey Wizards do have a reputation, and so do you. And you don't exactly go out of your way to dispel it." You smile. "It's fun. And most people are taken in by it. Why aren't you?" "Wolf," she says simply. You sigh. "He told you?" "No, this was long before he was talking. Familiars are tricky, but he's a dog, and dogs are what their masters make them. You could have made him sneaky and sly, or you could have made him vicious and intimidating. But you didn't. Even after he was fully grown, he stayed a happy, playful puppy." "Maybe I use him to throw people off," you say, but it's clear she's not buying it. "Okay, fine. It's true, and it doesn't take much more than basic Wind theory to spot it. Ulgu doesn't make for terrifying ethereal assassins unless you really put your mind to it. It makes mystics and showmen." She snaps her fingers. "So that's the other half." She pauses thoughtfully, giving you a long, considering look as the server takes advantage of the quiet to step in with tall mugs of freshly-drawn small beer. Well, small beer by Dwarf standards. Some taverns in the Empire sold ale with less of a kick than this. "Mystical Ulgu. Boundaries, right? Between light and dark, between day and night. Ambiguities and edge cases. That's the side of you that builds hell towers and experiments on mushrooms." "I suppose you could see it that way," you say, not entirely convinced. "What about you? The farms would be your Elemental side, right?" "Everyone makes that mistake at first. Most of the plant stuff is Mystical. Though come to think of it..." She frowns, tapping her fingers against her mug. "I guess I have been focused pretty hard on the crops and the soil. Though that could qualify as both, as supplying food would fit under Elemental. Or maybe I'll exercise my Elemental side more after we turn the Caldera into pastures and bring in more livestock." You consider the amount of work she's already dedicated to, combined with this new addition. "It all seems fairly..." You try to think of a non-critical way to put it. "Encompassing?" "Hah. What are you doing next month?" "Experiments and business in Altdorf, I suppose," you answer, taken a little by surprise. "You know what I'm doing?" She leans back in her chair with a smug smile. "Nothing. And the month after that? Nothing. And the month after that, I think I'm going to get around to catching up on my nothing." She grins, then turns serious. "But yes, it is intense for three seasons a year. But this valley means I can do something nobody else in the Order has been able to even try: to create arable land from a complete blank slate. No variables, no surprises, no fires, no floods, no droughts. Just dead soil and water and the Halflings and me, creating something from nothing. If I succeed, it's because of me. If I fail, it's because of me. Not because some broken Waystone farted on the far side of the horizon. Oh! And speaking of, that's another thing to take on once I'm done with the soil. Never even heard of a circular Waystone cluster anything like this big before, there's a paper or two in that." You are a Wizard of the Grey Order, and Wizards of the Grey Order don't spit their drinks across the table. You finish your draw on the beer calmly and place the mug carefully back down. "You know much about Waystones?" She looks at you oddly. "Jade Order, remember? I've been pulling Ghyran out of them ever since they woke up last year." "Right. Of course." You make a mental note to look into this further later, and mentally underline it several times. "It's tied into the Druid thing, right?" "Ugh, the Druid thing. If nothing else, I'm glad to be half a continent away from all of that. 'Should we still worship the Earth Mother', 'should we switch over to Rhya', 'is Rhya the Earth Mother', 'is Shallya the Earth Mother', 'is there even an Earth Mother', 'is Taal the Green Man'... honestly, at this point I couldn't care less. The Gods can do what they do and I'll do what I do and we don't have to bother each other. What about you? Is the Grey College really a hive of secret Ranald cultists?" "Wouldn't be much of a Ranald cultist if I told, would I?" you say, holding up a pair of crossed fingers. She examines you carefully, then turns wide-eyed in surprise. "Wait, really? You actually worship Ranald?" "We have an understanding. Where do you think I got Wolf?" "Wolf? Wolf was... wow." She blinks, and frowns. "The God of sneakiness and deceit got you a puppy?" "It makes sense in context." She gives you an expectant look, and you acquiesce. "Well, it started soon after I arrived in Wurtbad and was looking for a place to live..." The story of Wolf and Heideck and the shrine to Stromfels lasts until the food arrives, and what food it is. Fresh meat is a rare luxury in the Karak, as it has to either come from hunting - not the safest of activities in the World's Edge Mountains - or be transported all the way from the Border Princes or Averland. But the Halflings have risen to the challenge and come up with an array of techniques and sauces to make salted meat almost as good as a fresh roast, and the conversation trails off as you both give the meal the full attention it deserves. After the plates are whisked away, the two of you engage in pleasant small talk as you perform the Halfling religious obligation of refraining from strenuous activity after a meal, and wash it down with a mug or two of a very pleasant ale. After enough time has passed, you say your goodbyes and part ways. The sun has fallen, but Panoramia's as able to navigate through the fields as easily as you are through the twilight. --- The next meeting of Wizards is taking place in your penthouse once more, as you've got something very special to show off: your very own copy of A Modest Treatise into the Nature of Magic, written by the former Magister Patriarch of the Gold Order. An enormous, massive, and very expensive tome filled with theories on the nature of the Winds and their origin, the tome has arguably made Puchta second only to Teclis in influence on the Collegiate understanding of magic. Every College has a substantial waiting list for access to their copy, and the weight and expense means that only a handful of copies exist in private hands. And now you have your own copy, a worthy capstone to your growing collection of books on magical theory. Though it's always good to catch up with the citizens of your little empire, there's not a lot of interest said in the meeting. You've spent so much time with your fellow Wizards these past few months that only Gretel and Adela have any news for you. Gretel's is interesting, as it seems the Besiegers have been put on retainer by Barak Varr and advised that they should practice shipboard manoeuvres. Though you quiz Gretel quite closely, there's no indication as to whether Barak Varr might have them in mind for a voyage to Marienburg or to defend the Black Water project. Adela, meanwhile, has been at something of a loose end ever since her projects with the local engineers have been put on the backburner, and she's mainly been studying, practising, and trying to grow her influence over the Karag Nar Gunnery School, and her new spell Inextinguishable Flame causes a good-natured bicker session between her and Johann over the relative merits of it and Stoke the Forge, with Maximillian occasionally lifting his head from the pages of A Modest Treatise to join in. As the year comes to a close, two deliveries arrive in close succession: the unnerving menhir finally arrives from Altdorf, and a massive spike of bone, purported to be a trophy from a slain storm dragon that has been gathering dust on the wall of a noble Tilean family for generations. You believe the claim as soon as you take it out onto your balcony and the ambient Azyr of the high winds change course to flow through the horn. You tuck it away safely inside your vault, considering your options for making use of it. The accompanying letter informed you that half of your bounty remains posted. With that business seen to, you prepare your report for Belegar and consider what tasks to suggest for your attention. When you last did so, the Karak was still mostly in enemy hands and many of the prospective projects were focused on that, so it takes a fair bit of revision from last time. [ ] PROJECT: Aethyric Vitae You're reasonably confident that there's a great deal of potential yet to be unlocked in the Vitae. [ ] PROJECT: Dragon You've supplied one weapon for the possibility of a hostile dragon, perhaps now you should see to securing the possibility of a peaceful one. [ ] PROJECT: Cartographer Your maps have made significant differences to several battles, and could prove just as useful in its ongoing defence. You could map the entirety of Karak Eight Peaks and enchant a map room so that it would forever display your findings, and could be updated as needed. [ ] PROJECT: Waystone The Eonir have asked to work with you on a research project into the Waystones. Though you doubt you can reverse-engineer a product of the Dwarven Golden Age in partnership with the greatest Wizards of Ulthuan, you might be able to uncover something useful. [ ] PROJECT: Enchanted Engineering Experiment with applying enchantments to gyrocopters and gyrocarriages. [ ] PROJECT: Western Gate The Eastern Gate and its approach is entirely dominated by the Eye of Gazul, but its angles to affect the Western Gate are more limited. If you consider this insufficient, you can suggest to King Belegar that you lend your efforts to bolstering its defences. [ ] PROJECT: Black Waters Though you're unlikely to be able to contribute to the construction yourself, you might be able to indirectly aid the ongoing construction of the canals and locks between the Black Waters and the Aver. [ ] PROJECT: Marienburg Marienburg is threatening a blockade, and the Empire is threatening to break it. You could be of some use in cowing Marienburg or paving the way for a short decisive war. [ ] PROJECT: Karag Dum Though at the opposite end of the continent, no Dwarf is disinterested in a reclamation attempt, and that goes double for those living in a reclaimed Hold. Perhaps Belegar would be willing to assign you to aid the preparations of Expedition. [ ] PROJECT: Nagarythe Dwarves don't really believe in things like 'vacations', but you're pretty sure they'll happily make an exception for a vacation dedicated to tormenting the Druchii. [ ] [TOWER] Grey Battery Seek to expand the capability of the Grey Tower to absorb and store power, whether for firing the Eye of Gazul or other purposes. 50gc. [ ] [TOWER] Far Sight Filled to the brim with refraction cantrips, this tower would allow anyone in it to see in detail any point within line of sight. 2 College Favours. [ ] [TOWER] Protection (COLOUR) Build a tower to magically reinforce or protect the others. Specify wind. 5 College favours. [ ] [TOWER] Anti-Air (COLOUR) Build a tower to magically attack any airborne enemies. Specify wind. 5 College favours. [ ] [TOWER] Smoke and Mirrors Build a tower to enable longer-range teleportation. Will require an action to set up, exact implementation will be determined by rolls and choices with that action. Library Purchases Budget: 300gc, 2 Dwarf Favour. Anything not spent will not accumulate. [ ] [LIBRARY] No purchase. [ ] [LIBRARY] Write-in. Dwarf Favour Purchases Aethyric Vitae can be spent instead of favour at an exchange rate of 3 favour per gallon; for Rune-related purchases, this will also guarantee the cooperation of Runelords who may otherwise be disinterested. To use this, simply add 'paid by Vitae' or similar to an item you are voting for. [ ] [DWARF] No purchase. [ ] [DWARF] Write-in. College Favour Purchases [ ] [COLLEGE] No purchase. [ ] [COLLEGE] Write-in. Other Purchases [ ] [PURCHASE] No purchase. [ ] [PURCHASE] Write-in. - There will be a three hour moratorium. The Project section is in plan format. Remember to do all your voting in the same post. - Project: Karag Dum would involve only scouting and preparation at this time. Joining it yourself would be an option in later turns. - Feel free to suggest alternative projects or tower ideas for me to add to the list.

Turn 29 - 2484 - They Go to the Land of the Ice and Snow

Spoiler: Voting results [X] Plan Red -[x] PROJECT: Cartographer -[x] PROJECT: Waystone -[x] PROJECT: Black Waters -[X] PROJECT: Karag Dum [X] [TOWER] Anti-Air: Azyr [X] [LIBRARY] Enchantment: Imperial Antiquarian (100gc, 2CF), Divine Magic: Imperial Antiquarian (100gc, 2CF), Ranald: Bretonnian Extensive (100gc), Engineering: Imperial Esoteric, Bretonnian Extensive, Dwarven Extensive (350gc), Waystones and Henges: Dwarven Esoteric (50gc, 2DF) [X] [DWARF] Rooms of Calamity for eight colleges (10DF + 10 gallons AV) [x] [COLLEGE] No purchase. [X] [PURCHASE] Firkin of dwarven ink for Grey College Docent (5gc) After some thought and a great deal of correspondence with the Colleges, you strike a deal with Thorek: he and his numerous Apprentices travel to Altdorf to install Rooms of Calamity in each of the Colleges, and in exchange you turn over half of your accumulated stockpile of Aethyric Vitae to him. Though there are no immediate benefits to you, the benefits to the Karaz Ankor and to the Colleges make it worth it. The Karaz Ankor being able to use their most potent Anvil-Runes on demand will no doubt be of use when under threat in the coming years, and the Rooms of Calamity will, you hope, ensure that more College Wizards survive their educations. And it won't exactly hurt your own reputation to be responsible for both of those. Before Thorek leaves, you have some nicely understated plaques commissioned to be placed by the entrances to the rooms, bearing your name and the names you've come up with for each of them. The Maze for the Grey College, the Alcove for the Golds, the Tomb for the Amethysts, the Hall for the Celestials... it may be that nobody will ever set eyes on every one of the rooms and put the pieces together, but that just makes it all the more satisfying. The only part you're not entirely sure of is the Enclosure for the Amber College, not entirely sure if it was worth building, and whether it could be built somewhere more appropriate for them. But in the end you put your doubts aside and have it built as a second story on the small, squat tower that the Ambers possess in the city. They may not be fond of civilization, but that doesn't mean they aren't sensible people, and you're sure they'll see the value in being able to more safely learn the most dangerous of magics, and will likely consider having to do so in Altdorf a small price to pay. In comparison, your own new construction is relatively modest, consisting of a new floor on the Blue Tower and a series of crystals and metallic cross-joints, along with a series of instructions that allow Hubert to assemble them. At first you're a little annoyed at how little effort the Celestials put into the matter, until you read through the instructions and find a caution to avoid working on a certain day, as Hubert will be distracted with personal matters and the mistake he would make could be dangerous. You suppose prognostication means never having to double-check your work. Once the Dwarves have built another floor onto your Blue Tower you turn the matter over to him, and it takes only a couple of weeks for it to come together. It absorbs and contains the lightning strikes that the Blue Tower already feeds upon, and that energy can be unleashed at the press of an activation glyph, either in a specific direction or just to ground the energy through anything nearby that isn't already grounded. When you're done seeing to all that, you also organize a small gift of a firkin of high-quality Dwarven ink for the Docent. Whoever they are - their identity is kept a secret for fairly obvious reasons - they're responsible for collating, organizing, and cross-referencing the College's records of captured and intercepted enemy communications, and the book on Queekish would have dropped what you're sure is a substantial task into their lap as they turn it on however many Skaven books and documents the Grey College may have amassed over the years. --- You'd explained the operation of the Menhir to King Belegar, and though his expression spoke volumes, he refrained from commenting until Kragg, Thorek, and Gunnars had all given it a thorough inspection, and all had declared it free of corruption. "I hate this," he finally says, glaring at the pool meant to be filled with heartsblood. "I hate it almost as much as I hate the idea of an unchecked Ice Dragon. Good work. I'll have it secured within the Citadel, and hope it never sees use." After that is the Council meeting, which of late are starting to blur together, and there's a definite sense of rising tension, even as the Council grows more and more adept at handling the complaints and provocations of the Okral. Two more years is a common refrain, sometimes in relief and sometimes in resignation. If all goes according to plan, the departure of the Okral will be soon after the completion of the restoration of Karags Rhyn and Mhonar and the construction of Temples to Valaya and Smednir within them, as well as the defences both above and below that will hopefully keep the Karak secure for generations to come. And then everyone can move on to their pet projects instead of being full-time Grumbaki-wranglers. "Karag Dum," Belegar says, drawing the attention of all present. "What do we know about the Expedition there? All I know is that if every Dawi that claimed they wanted to help my own efforts but were already invested in the other were truthful, they could conquer every mountain from Karak Kadrin to Kraka Drak." "Zhufbar is supplying a convoy of Steam-Wagons," Gotri says. "Which means it's able to carry an incredible amount of supplies and weaponry, but limits the terrain it's able to cross. It's to set out from Karak Kadrin in the coming years, with the exact time and route to depend on weather and circumstance." You'd memorized a map in preparation, and with a moment's concentration silvery-grey light seeps out from your fingers and forms a map on the table, outlining the lands of Kislev, the Northern Dark Lands, and the Western Great Steppes; your fellow Councillors are used enough to this that none react with anything but interest. "The High Pass and the Skull Road was once one of the safer routes to the East, but now most traders flock to the more southern passes." "Karag Dum once marked the threshold to the lands ruled by Chaos," Gunnars notes. "Now it's stretched as far south as Praag." "Still, you said 'most'," Kazrik notes. You nod. "It must still be passable to an extent, but at some point the path of the Expedition will have to leave the Skull Road and turn north, driving further into the Wastes." "Most acknowledge it as untenable," Gotri says, "so the goal of the Expedition is to evacuate any remaining survivors, artefacts, and treasures, not to retake or reinforce. The tales of Thorgrim Grudgebearer give many hope that like the Norse Dwarves did, the Dwarves of Karag Dum still hold out, and the fate of the Norse Dwarves has convinced many of the dangers of the Wastes." "There is value in that," Belegar says, patting the hammer on his hip. "The Hammer of Angrund performed many mighty deeds while exiled from here. Very well. Loremaster Weber, lend what assistance you can to the preparations of the Expedition. I've no doubt Karak Kadrin has supplied them with all the conventional weaponry it can carry, but you've shown quite a talent for the unconventional." Spoiler: Planned route Mandatory Actions: Pick one from each category. Journeyman Maximilian de Gaynesford, Gold Wizard [ ] MAX: Allow him to spend all his time on his metalworking studies. [ ] MAX: Learn a skill: specify what from who. You may pay for a trainer. [ ] MAX: Learn a spell: specify which. [ ] MAX: Study an artefact: specify which. [ ] MAX: Write a paper: specify which. [ ] MAX: Receive dictation: specify which. Must be taken with a 'dictate' action. Magister Johann, Gold Wizard [ ] JOHANN: Have him teach Adela what he knows of engineering. [ ] JOHANN: Learn a skill: specify what from who. You may pay for a trainer. [ ] JOHANN: Learn a spell: specify which. [ ] JOHANN: Study an artefact: specify which. [ ] JOHANN: Write a paper: specify which. Wizards of Karak Eight Peaks [ ] DUCK: Work with Panoramia to try to implement the Waaaghsoak Mushrooms as an aid to spellcasting. [ ] DUCK: Panoramia's about ready to test for Magister, but she's putting it off because she doesn't have a lot of free time to prepare. Work with her to help make the most of every spare minute. [ ] DUCK: Help Johann train his rat-wolf children. [ ] DUCK: Attempt to recruit Gretel and the Besiegers for the Karag Dum Expedition. [ ] DUCK: Each of your three ducklings can fight in melee. Spar with them, and teach them what you can. [ ] DUCK: Magical target-shooting is rough on normal targets. Set up a specialized target range for your ducklings, and for any other wizards at Eight Peaks. [ ] DUCK: Study an artefact with one of the Journeymen: specify who and which. The Eastern Imperial Company Your share of EIC profits: 175 crowns / turn Current Focus of the EIC: Expansion along the Aver EIC Handler: The Hochlander [ ] EIC: Completely hand over management of the EIC intelligence apparatus to the Hochlander. Will remove this section from future turns and regain the half-turn invested in it. [ ] EIC: Have the Hochlander introduce a series of ciphers to the EIC to allow it to communicate internally in much greater security. [ ] EIC: Found an auditors division, to make sure the ledgers are in order. [ ] EIC: Start hiring handlers who can then start hiring informers and begin to collect non-public information. [ ] EIC: Reach out to Julia to find out if she's interested in being poached or passing on information. [ ] EIC: Reach out to Roswita, and have the EIC start passing on tips about any tax evasion or other naughtiness by the EIC's rivals. [ ] EIC: Start building a paramilitary river navy to ensure the coming trade explosion doesn't lead to a similar explosion in riverine banditry. [ ] EIC: Sell some of the Grand Urbaz Bank coins to collectors and museums on King Belegar's behalf. [ ] EIC: Integrate the Gong Farmers and the Niter Factory into the EIC, and expand production. [ ] EIC: Have the EIC keep tabs on mercenaries so that they can be more easily hired if needed. Personal Actions: you have four actions you can apply without engaging in overwork. Current overwork status: [ ] [ ] [ ] Each box will be filled by one action of overwork, and will take the two turns after that to fade as you recover. The first box incurs no penalty. The second will give a -10 penalty to all actions during the first turn of recovery. The third will give a -20 penalty to all actions on both turns of recovery. Overwork incurs no penalties on the turns taken, only on the turns recovering from it. You can take as many actions of overwork as you have unfilled boxes. When you use overwork it fills the left-most empty box, so [-][ ][ ] becomes [-][+][ ], not [+][-][ ]. All boxes recover in parallel and independent from one another, but second and third apply maluses on your actions during that cooldown period. Current Task: Karag Dum Expedition preparations (NEW) [ ] Collate useful information on the northernmost Dark Lands from Qrech and Lady Magister Grey. [ ] Seek out merchants who have travelled the Skull Road to learn what they know of it. [ ] Trawl around the bars and brothels of Tilea, looking to talk to the actual mercenaries that have walked either the Skull Road, or the Great Steppes. [ ] Seek volunteers from the Colleges to join the Expedition. [ ] Seek mercenaries to join the Expedition (optional: specify who/where). [ ] With the help of a gyrocarriage, personally scout part of the route (specify: High Pass, Road of Skulls, Western Great Steppes, Karag Dum vicinity) [ ] Try to contact the Ice Witches of Kislev in the hopes they can provide clement weather for the Expedition. [ ] Attempt to learn the Greenskin tongue to communicate with the Hobgoblin Khanates of the Steppes. [ ] Attempt to learn Kurgan to communicate with the Kurgan of the Steppes. [ ] Learn what you can of dealing with the Hobgoblin Khanates of the Steppes. [ ] Learn what you can of dealing with the Kurgan of the Steppes. Spoiler: Qrech Qrech [ ] Despite him considering it treasonous, push Qrech to share the Moulder dialect of Queekish. [ ] Despite him considering it blasphemous, push Qrech to share High Queekish. Qrech Gambits (can be taken for free alongside a Qrech option): [ ] Convince Qrech that you seek an arrangement with Clan Moulder, and that you will release him as an ambassador for that arrangement once you are satisfied he'll cooperate. [ ] Convince Qrech that the Under-Empire has no way of knowing he's even alive, and that he should prioritize the comfort with which he will live the rest of his life. [ ] Convince Qrech you're ambitious and loyal only to yourself, and you're willing to repay his cooperation in ways that will benefit the Under-Empire. [ ] Other (write in) Self-Improvement: [ ] Ask an acquaintance to train you in a skill: specify who and what. [ ] Attempt to learn a spell from scrolls (specify which, will be harder than studying it at the Grey College) [ ] Hire a trainer to come to Eight Peaks and teach you: specify what. (costs favours for Dwarf trainers, money for human ones) [ ] Travel to the Grey College and attend lessons there. (1 College Favour per class; 100gc can be paid instead for non-magical classes) [ ] Attempt to learn Battle Magic at the Grey College. (1 College Favour per attempt) [ ] Gain enough control of your unruly shadow to still it temporarily. [ ] Gain enough control of your attraction to smoke and gases to have it collect away from your face. [ ] Try to see through Pall of Darkness with your improved magical senses. [ ] Practice shooting while invisible. (applies to Substance of Shadow and Invisibility) [ ] Branulhune's ability to disappear and reappear at a thought allows entirely new forms of combat. Try to create them. [ ] Have one of Prince Gotri's pilots teach you to fly a gyrocopter. Research and Publishing: [ ] Study an artefact: select which. [ ] Write a paper: select which. [ ] Write something else: write in. Once per turn, you can write a paper or a 'something else' without spending an action thanks to your Tower of Serenity. [ ] Dictate papers: select which two, must be taken with Max's 'receive dictation'. [ ] Investigate the possibility of using one Wind to directly manipulate another. [ ] The Second Secret of Dhar teaches how to collapse it upon itself. Practice upon local Dhar taint, and very cautiously see if this works with Warpstone. [ ] Try to establish a relationship with the Cult of Verena, with the intent of offering them access to your rarer tomes in exchange for copies of some of their own. [ ] Record all the entries of the Grand Urbaz vaults and select a good-quality example of each minting to save from the smelters. [ ] Attend anti-Chaos training at the Grey College. (NEW) Aethyric Vitae (11 gallons): [ ] Experiment with integrating the Vitae into enchantments. [ ] Investigate how the Vitae reacts with Divine Magic. [ ] Investigate how the Vitae reacts to a power stone. [ ] Investigate how the Vitae reacts to being subjected to power stone creation methods. [ ] Using the secrets you already know of the Vitae, attempt to weaponize it. Enchantment and Spell Creation: [ ] Enchant an item with a Moderately Complicated or easier spell (specify what and which) [ ] Attempt to enchant an object to translate Windsight into a visual image. [ ] Attempt to deepen your skill with Enchantment (will be more difficult than studying it at the Grey College) [ ] Attempt to create a spell (see Approved Spells threadmark) [ ] Turn a staff from mundane materials. [ ] Turn a staff from the horn of a Storm Dragon. Karag Nar Penthouse: each turn, you get ONE free choice in this category. Additional selections cost actions. [ ] PENTHOUSE: Have a tower built atop Karag Nar: -100gc for 1 room, bonus to room's purpose. [ ] PENTHOUSE: Have additional rooms excavated underneath your Penthouse: -125gc for 5 rooms. [ ] PENTHOUSE: Your dungeon was built with a reasonable amount of paranoia. Apply an unreasonable amount of paranoia. [ ] PENTHOUSE: Add security measures to your Penthouse to prevent forcible entry. [ ] PENTHOUSE: Have firing platforms built around the Penthouse so that it can be defended from flyers or climbers without granting access to it. Setting up rooms for specific purposes will have to wait until new rooms are constructed or excavated. Only one construction or excavation can take place at a time, but you can do one of each. Building downwards will increase by 1 each time; second set of excavated rooms will be 3 rooms, third will be 4, and so on. Building upwards can be added upon; towers can be added on to or additional towers can be built. The distinction between the two is entirely cosmetic. Foreign Relations: [ ] Join the war between Stirland and the vampires in northern Sylvania. [ ] Involve yourself in the Marienburg affair (specify how) (NEW) [ ] Involve yourself in the Black Waters project (specify how) (NEW) Personal Relations: [ ] Spend time assisting with a fellow councillor's task: specify who and how. [ ] Spend time investigating a character without their knowledge: specify who. [ ] Wolf is fully grown, very smart, and a Very Good Boy. Train him further. (specify what he will be taught) [ ] Wolf is fully grown and very magical. Deepen your familiar bond. (may unlock a new familiar ability; risks obsession) Ranald's Coin - specify which face it will be set to [ ] The Gambler: specify an action this will apply to. A +20 bonus to up to two dice rolls resulting from a single chosen action. [ ] The Night Prowler As long as you are outside of private property and within a town or city, nobody will question your presence and nobody will be able to find you if you do not wish them to. [ ] The Deceiver: specify how this will be used. Lies you have developed beforehand will be delivered perfectly. The listener may believe you to be mistaken, but they will never believe that you are lying. Cannot be used to tell truths. [ ] The Protector When you act in a way that defends an individual or group from a danger that you did not cause, they will become aware of what you have done and will believe you acted selflessly in doing so. Spoiler: Accumulated Artefacts Ranald's Coin Vampire skulls Preserved bodies of the Rat Mothers of Clan Mors. Eshin: Throwing star, still dripping venom. Eshin Sorcerer crystal sword. Eshin Sorcerer amulet, shattered. Moulder: Electric whip, stolen from Clan Moulder. Vials, stolen from Clan Moulder. Captured Clan Moulder devices (as yet uninspected) Skryre: Firearms; jezzails, pistols, bullets, gunpowder. Warp Lightning Cannon (misfired, possibly broken) Lighting mechanism, stolen from Clan Skryre. (shared project with Adela) Breathing apparatus, stolen from Clan Skryre. (shared project with Johann) Brass orb, stolen from Clan Skryre. Spoiler: Potential Papers Note: Fresh and Refreshed papers confer a +10 bonus; faded ones a -10 malus. Papers get one step less 'fresh' each turn: Fresh; Fading; Mostly Faded: Faded. Only the first and last have an effect on the diceroll. Waaagh energy and magic witnessed during the Expedition. (FADED) The Black Orc Warboss' worship of Only Gork, and what you saw of the Rogue Idol ritual. (FADED) The physiology and venom of the We. (FADED) The psychology and social structure of the We. (FADED) Preliminary paper on Aethyric Vitae. (TIMELESS) You can literally write the book on a topic for the same amount of effort as two papers; this can be split over multiple turns. You don't need to have all the pieces to do so, but it would be more efficient and impressive if you did. The We - There will be a three hour moratorium. Voting will be in plan format. - To see the current plans, click on Thread Tools in the top right, then Vote Tally. - If you have ideas for alternate ways to help the Expedition, please suggest them. - The Karag Dum Expedition is currently planning to leave some time from late next year to three years from now, which means between three and seven turns from now. You'll have a better idea of exactly when as it gets closer. - Background information that Mathilde would know: the northern Dark Lands along the Road of Skulls is uninhabited, but between two major Chaos Dwarf strongholds. The Western Great Steppes is populated by the Hobgoblin Khanates and the horse nomads known as Kurgans.

Turn 29 Results - 2484

Spoiler: Voting results [*] Plan Keep It Classy -[*] Contains one Overwork action -[*] MAX: Study an artefact: Captured Clan Moulder devices (as yet uninspected) -[*] JOHANN: Have him teach Adela what he knows of engineering. -[*] DUCK: Magical target-shooting is rough on normal targets. Set up a specialized target range for your ducklings, and for any other wizards at Eight Peaks. -[*] EIC: Start hiring handlers who can then start hiring informers and begin to collect non-public information. -[*] SERENITY: Write a paper: The We book (1/2) -[*] PENTHOUSE: Have a tower built atop Karag Nar: -100gc for 1 room, bonus to room's purpose. -[*] Collate useful information on the northernmost Dark Lands from Qrech and Lady Magister Grey. -[*] Attend classes at the Grey College: --[*] Anti-Chaos Training --[*] Runes and Runecraft --[*] Enchanting -[*] Study an artefact: Ranald's Coin --[*] COIN: The Gambler The Expedition to Karag Dum is one you have a lot of misgivings about, but you're somewhat reassured by the fact that at least most of them intend to evacuate survivors and retrieve treasures and artefacts, rather than trying to reclaim a Dwarfhold in the middle of the Chaos Wastes. Most of the route is along the Road of Skulls, which... well, the name does indicate a certain amount of danger, but it's one that is semi-regularly travelled by merchants and enough of them make it back for others to consider the risk worth taking. And a properly prepared and equipped expedition would surely fare better than merchant caravans. Speaking of proper preparation, there's a fair bit you need to do yourself before you'll feel happy about venturing into the Chaos Wastes, even on a scouting mission. You've got ideas for a number of possible enchantments that could help, you're considering finally crafting a staff of your very own, and not least of all, there's the anti-Chaos training that Algard insisted you take. When you arrive at the Grey College, you're delighted that Regimand is there to greet you, and quite glad that he seems to have gotten his new beard somewhat under control. Instead of being blown away with every errant breeze, it has thickened enough to stay in place, and now almost looks like normal hair unless he moves his head too quickly. He claims to be in retirement again, which you treat with the scepticism it deserves, and then tells you he'll be managing the first part of your training. "First off," he says after you've moved into one of the private reading rooms, "tell me what you know of the Four." "The Plotter, the Excessive, the Diseased, and the Violent," you say. "I know Their general spheres, but just what you taught me way back during my Apprenticeship. Apart from a brief glimpse of one of the Plotter's schemes, I've not brushed with the Four." "That you know of," he says. "I'm glad you're still not using Their names. Opinion is still divided on whether that does draw Their attention, but I've always felt that calling Them by name leads someone to underestimate Them." Over the next few days, he takes you through a more advanced description of the Four and how They operate, focusing on what They offer and what They tend to want in exchange. You can see why it's not taught earlier on, as it's quite an array of abilities, traits, and knowledge They can supposedly grant, and nobody is entirely immune to the full array of temptation spread out before you. How many Journeymen would be lost if you planted these ideas into their mind, and in the arrogance of youth, they decided they had it in them to snatch away the tainted gifts of Chaos and turn them to noble ends? After all, is that not what Wizardry itself is? After Regimand has exhausted what he's confident enough in to teach, you're passed along to a rather more intimidating figure - the Porter of the Grey Order, Reiner Starke. His unassuming title hides the truth of his power in plain sight - it is he that decides who the doors of the Grey College do and do not open to. The youngest current Lord Magister, his ambition is as well known as his loyalty to the Empire. "Magister Weber," he says, his grey eyes betraying the touch of Ulgu as he tries to stare you down. "Lord Magister," you reply calmly, returning his gaze. "Your ascent through the ranks has been meteoric," he says, consulting a sheet of encoded notes, "but unlike most who could be described that way, there seems to be no doubts as to your loyalty or worthiness. Your service to the late and lamented Hunter-Count was impeccable, as has been your assistance to his daughter, even when you had every reason and excuse not to. And your continued aid to the Dwarf-folk has been quite the exemplar. Tell me, are you a woman of faith?" You have no idea where he's going with this, so you hedge. "I can't claim to compare to people such as Chaplain Kasmir Heinz or Sir Ruprecht Wulfhart, but yes, I consider myself to be." He smiles, seemingly quite pleased. "I had thought you to be. I've no doubt you'll continue to prove yourself a worthy addition to the Grey College in the coming years, and I look forward to working alongside you." That unnerving conversation concluded, he spends parts of the coming days giving you short, terse lectures on the resonances of the Four, and you spend the rest of those days locked in rooms with shackled grimoires that cannot be allowed to leave the College. The information you gain is quite disturbing, considering how many symbols, animals, phrases, and even numbers are said to be associated with one of the Four. But by the time you've finished, you've got a reasonable idea of how to avoid inadvertently attracting the attention of the Chaos Gods - or, if you were so inclined, an encyclopedic knowledge of how to invite it. It's quite the double-edged sword. [Piety Skill gained: Chaos: You know how to avoid - or to invite - the attentions of the Chaos Gods, and of the curses and blessings they gift and inflict.] --- Runes and Runecraft, it is reiterated several times by Choirmaster Stephen on the first day and regularly after, is not in any way related to the Runesmithing of the Karaz Ankor. The simplest reason is the runes are much more closely related to Eltharin than Khazalid, though it is its own distinct pseudo-alphabet after two centuries of iteration by the Colleges. Over the years it has integrated fragments of Druidic glyphs, Shamanic symbology, High Nehekharan hieroglyphs, Alchemical and Astrological notation, Hedgewise markings, and Thieves Cant. And maybe a little Khazalid, but only indirectly via Old Reikspiel. Definitely nothing straight from Khazalid. Please don't say otherwise to the Runesmiths. It does not have direct effects on the item the Runes are drawn or carved or otherwise integrated into, it simply makes them more suited to hold or channel specific Winds under specific circumstances, making it quite helpful for enchantments and staff-turning, especially ones using esoteric components that are often used more for their power than for being perfectly attuned to the right Wind. The reason the Runes work is immaterial to the fact that it does work, but Choirmaster Stephen seems to be largely unable to keep himself from being sidetracked into the theories and implications of the different resonances all these different symbols of varied origins have. The Apprentices taking the course delight in prodding the Choirmaster into these digressions so they can nap or talk amongst themselves, but you and the other Magisters present pay close attention and are able to glean a number of intriguing insights above and beyond what you learn of Runecraft. In contrast, the lessons on Enchantment itself are completely free of digression, both because of the potential danger and because of the teacher, Magister Hugo Bann of the Bright College, the giant of a man who you previously met during his work on the Red Tower. He has proven himself to have a better grasp of safely binding magic into items than Lord Wizards twice his age, and in fact some of those very Lord Wizards are alongside you in the classroom, trying to improve their enchantment skills to encompass everything short of Battle Magic. Every one of the lessons takes place in a building owned by the Gold College with thick stone walls and a flimsy wooden roof which is usually home to the more ambitious adventures in chemistry, and though none of the mishaps that take place during the lessons are quite serious enough to blow the roof off, they do come close enough to show the wisdom of the setting. Magister Bann's lesson plan is very straightforward: you can pick up the theory of materials and ritual and thaumaturgic equations elsewhere, but nowhere else will you find someone who can teach you to find the exact limit of how much magic you can handle without taking a step over it. Magic does not like the process of enchantment, and given the ghost of a chance will wriggle free from a novice enchanter's grasp and do something rather drastic to show its displeasure. It takes total control to force it to take a static and permanent form, and while Magister Bann does not teach you how to achieve that control - it's unlikely he would have useful insight on the matter for anyone but his fellow Brights anyway - he does teach you how to recognize when you are approaching your limit, and when it's time to redouble your focus and when it's time to ground the magic and start again from scratch. It's certainly an atypical lesson plan, but the lessening rate of magical mishaps in the classroom over the weeks speaks for itself. [Runes Class: Learning, 75+27+10(Enchanter)=112.] [Enchantment Class: 84+27+10(Enchanter)=121.] [Magic Skill improved: Enchantment: Able to enchant objects with Fiendishly Complex spells and below.] [Magic Skill gained: Runecraft: You know the eclectic variety of runes and symbols used by the Colleges to improve their enchantments, and a lot of the theory behind them. +1 Learning.] --- When Qrech first introduced himself to you, it was as Chieftain Qrech Anuvongeni of Seventh-and-Final-Combe. While you take careful notes, he explains to you - haltingly, as he mentally searches every sentence for information that might be useable against Clan Moulder and excises it - what that means. "In the southern face of the Great Skull Land, there are fourteen major combes west of the Falls of Doom. The Seventh-and-Final-Combe is the front line of Clan Moulder. From it, we raided the East-Dwarves for weapons and materials and slaves, and they raided us for test subjects and sacrifices and slaves. Have done so for many generations. No changes. Very confusing for new Clanrats. Two is war, yes? But for us, there is our superiors, and for they, it is theirs. So we fight enough that we get interesting new slaves to keep Hell Pit happy, and they fight enough that they get interesting new slaves to keep Zharr-Naggrund happy. Two threes overlapping. War, but peace." He chitters his teeth in amusement. "Those that cannot understand, they try to push proper fight, end up killed by East-Dwarves. Self-correcting, very balanced." Though you'll never say so to a Dwarf, having gotten used to their way of seeing the world means it's easy to understand the Skaven perspective of Zorn Uzkul, where the surface exists primarily as a source of danger. But just underneath Skaven cowardice is Skaven ambition, and the eyes that watch the surface do so not only for enemies, but for opportunity, so their eyes are all the sharper. The Road of Skulls is known to the Empire as the road from Kislev to Cathay, but to those that call the Dark Lands home, it is the only accessible route from Zorn Uzkul to the Great Steppes. It is not only frequented by ambitious traders from Kislev and the Empire, but also warbands and trading parties from the top of the world: the Chaos-worshipping horse nomads of the Kurgan, the wolf-riding clans of the Hobgoblin Khanates, and the rare but much-feared warbands of the Tong. Some push further west to raid Kislev, others travel to the Chaos Dwarf citadel of Uzkulak to trade captured slaves and pillaged treasures for arms and armour forged by the Chaos Dwarves. Overall, a well-trodden and very dangerous highway, watched from below. Over a series of interviews, you extract every pertinent memory from Qrech. The map you're working from is from the University of Altdorf, and though it does have some details near the Road of Skulls, it is almost blank to either side, and you manage to fill a fair amount of that blankness with rough details on the terrain and whether below it dwells Skaven or Chaos Dwarves or neither. But though Qrech has given you a fair amount of information about the plateau itself, he's not actually able to give you much information on the Chaos Dwarves, as what he does know about them is mostly about raiding the Plains of Zharr to the south. So you turn your attention to another, equally valuable source of information: Lady Magister Grey. Lady Magister Grey is the closest thing the Colleges have to an expert on the Chaos Dwarves, who earned quite a bit of their enmity by exploding one of their very few Hellcannon foundries. For the rest of her career, Hobgoblin assassins would manage to find her in the most unlikely of places, and though she defeated all of them and gained quite a bit of renown with the level of information on Hobgoblin anatomy she published, they only needed to get lucky once to settle the score. After it became clear that the Chaos Dwarves were using some sort of bizarre underwater vessel to deliver Hobgoblin assassins throughout the Empire with impunity, she retired to Altdorf, where between the First Imperial Fleet and the defences of the Colleges, she was reasonably safe. Even so, Hobgoblin corpses are often found bobbing down the river after having been fatally mugged by Altdorf's oddly patriotic criminal underworld, which is completely unaffiliated with the Grey College. "In their way," she says thoughtfully as she rummages through her storage closet, "they're as reclusive as their untainted kinfolk. When they venture out, it's generally for slaves, and they much prefer for the slaves to be brought to them. A great many of mankind's enemies know that if you take enough slaves to the Chaos Dwarves, you can walk away with weapons and armours of astounding quality - especially if you don't mind that their puissance comes from demons bound within them." She pulls out a scroll tube, peers into one end dubiously, then shrugs and drops it back into the clutter. "That's where the Hellcannons came from. The Great War Against Chaos was a win for us in the end, but plenty merely raided their black hearts out instead of throwing themselves entirely behind the Everchosen, and they walked away with untold thousands of slaves, both from Kislev and from the infighting amongst them afterwards. Not to mention the opportunistic raids from greenskins and Ogres and Dark Elves and whatnot. This flooded the metaphorical market with enough slaves that even the foundries of Zharr-Naggrund couldn't purchase them all, and many ended up sacrificed or eaten after the entire tribe or clan or Waaagh or what-have-you was armed and armoured." "So the Hellcannons were the equivalent of luxury goods?" you say dubiously. "It's tough to wrap your mind around, but that's what it comes down to. They don't need them for their own defences, they need them to be able to secure as many slaves as possible, to fuel their industry and sate their God. Aha!" She pulls a severely squished roll of parchment out from under a chest festooned with padlocks, and does her best to unroll and flatten it on her desk to show to you. "Most of it's Zharr-Naggrund, but see at the top there, the Falls of Doom? They've excavated an enormous tunnel under it, all the way to Uzkulak. Ever since they finished it, Uzkulak has been their Barak Varr. On top of the existing 'customers' coming from the Great Steppes, there's Norscans and Dark Elves and Sartosans and Corsairs and Zombie Pirates that all make their way through the pack ice. And some of the 'traders' that claim to go east to Cathay simply stop at Uzkulak and buy stolen cargoes that the Chaos Dwarves have no use for. Uzkulak doesn't care where you come from as long as they get first refusal and a cut." You trace the line of the artificial underground river. "I've seen pictures of Zharr-Naggrund, I'd assumed they didn't have the same compulsion to stay below ground." "They do, it just comes second to the desire to dominate, and you can't do that in the mountains. Too many nooks and crannies. A tower on an open plain means there's no escape and no surprises." She smiles, looking quite pleased with herself. "Present company excluded, of course." Over the coming days, you distil the useful information from her copies of the papers she wrote back then into a series of notes and some extra details on your developing map. Between your two sources, it seems that the Expedition might be more likely to succeed than you first feared. Sure, there'd the chance of unfriendly traffic coming from the Great Steppes, but your primary concern was that the area seemed to be dominated by the Chaos Dwarves, seeing as it was sandwiched between Zharr-Nagrund and Uzkulak. But if they travel underground, just as the Dwarves did before the Underway was shattered, then the surface would go mostly unthreatened by them. --- Ever since you received it, Ranald's Coin has been hanging from your neck, providing aid in a wide variety of ways, some of which you could only guess at. The most obvious unusual element about it is that it has two sides but four faces, and as you roll the coin across your knuckles, four different symbols of the four different facets of Ranald are visible. Despite the intense amount of magic within the Coin, this doesn't seem to be a magical effect. It just has four faces, and that fact takes precedence over things like limitations of the physical world. Windsight is the ability to not just see the unseen, but to glimpse into the immaterial world that is parallel to the material one, where souls and daemons and Gods reside. But 'parallel' can be a misleading term, as the Aethyr does not map neatly or consistently onto the mundane world, save for when the border between the two is ruptured, as is supposedly the case at the poles and, briefly but disastrously, during the very worst of miscasts. For one very pertinent example, if you use your Magesight to 'look' in the right direction - one that has nothing to do with the three conventional dimensions - you can see the presence of Ranald, and the link between your soul and Him. But if you look at the Coin, you can see the link from it to Ranald, and it is not running alongside the one between Him and you, despite the fact that you hold the Coin in your hands. There are countless theories to try to make sense of the Warp, one of the most popular being that it is impossible to make sense of the Warp. Your first foray is to examine the Coin as if it was possessing of an Arcane enchantment, rather than a Divine one. This is easier said than done, as if this was Arcane, it would have to be the work of a lunatic or a genius to have been fit into such a small object. As you do your best to train your Magesight onto such a small object, you're reminded of your finicky work with the Shyish-infused swords, and of your efforts to reverse-engineer the Dhar matrix used by the self-proclaimed Countess of Sylvania. Even with your very finely-honed Magesight and the Room of Utter Neutrality to guarantee a clear view, hours turn into days peering at the Coin and sketching out the strands of energy that fill it. Making the task much more difficult is that the sacred symbol of Ranald is a simple cross, which means it's impossible to say where it's deliberately present and where it's simply the intersection of two strands. It's on the fourth day that energy pulses through the Coin, originating from the strand that extends away from it and towards Ranald's aethyric presence. The strands writhe and unfold, extending into the world around you and disappearing from view. You can feel reality ripple gently, but it's the gentle ripple that comes from something very, very large moving beneath. As you watch, the tendrils ensnare probability and bend it into a new shape... And then they stop, and withdraw into the coin, folding back in on themselves until they're contained once more within it, and reality settles down once more to its normal function. You look around the bare room for any indication that anything has changed, but as far as you can tell everything is as it was. But the power of the Coin as it is currently set is to tip the odds at a key moment, so surely it must have done something. Though come to think of it, you did entreat its aid for the task of examining itself. And you suppose it is rather lucky that you just so happened to be watching it as it activated. Is that what it did? Intervene so that when it did intervene, it would be when you were watching? You're starting to develop a headache. You suppose this sort of recursiveness is what you get when you turn an artefact against itself. Your second approach is to use the Coin as a locus to examine Ranald Himself, which is technically something you could do using your own link with him, but looking inwards like that requires a lot of meditation and focus to get good results and being completely centered gets in the way of reaching conclusions. Even with the Coin, it's an effort to give the Aethyr a proper study rather than snatching a glimpse at a time, as even though Magesight is not restricted to the normal three dimensions, your brain tends to insist that it should be, and doesn't like to interpret the information it garners. But over a series of prolonged meditations on the Coin, you start to gather impressions of what it connects to. A God, it is sometimes said, can be compared to a mortal being in the same way that the sun can be compared to a smouldering ember. You doubt that it was meant literally, but from looking Ranald-wards, you start to think it might be on to something. The fragment of the being you can see does not look materially different from the soul of the beings around you, just - 'just'! - astonishingly greater in size and intensity. Though you suppose you can't be sure that you're looking at Ranald Himself, you could be looking at the outermost edge of Ranald's domain within the Aethyr. Though you must admit you don't even know enough to say whether that's a meaningful distinction. Then, one morning as you mentally prepare for another day spend gazing into the Warp, someone hands a letter that's come all the way from the Empire to Wolf to bring up to you. It's not the same stationery the College uses, the handwriting is atrocious, and it seems that at some point it had an unfortunate encounter with a puddle. You carefully unpeel the brittle envelope and extract the letter within. To my very dear friend, it begins, and most of the ink after that has smeared beyond recognition. One single word, left miraculously untouched in the middle of the mess of stains, remains legible: don't. And at the very bottom, it is signed Yours most sincerely. The name below that, you're quite sure, is Ronald. But the handwriting makes it very, very easy to mistake that O for an A. Your first reaction is a blend of surprise, disappointment, and perhaps just a touch of fear. You'd embarked on this course of action honestly believing that Ranald wouldn't have a problem with your explorations, though to be fair to Him, a polite letter is possibly the gentlest form of divine disapproval imaginable. And the more you think about it, the more clear His message seems: He objects specifically to your study of Him. Which is odd, because you shouldn't be able to get that from a single word. You're pretty sure Ranald is cheating. You're also pretty sure that He could have had the letter spell that out for you, instead of somehow communicating a subconscious suggestion as to the full meaning. Ranald does like to be dramatic from time to time, and don't is quite memorably laconic. Message quite received, you double-check the envelope, decipher the handwriting, and have the letter sent back to the Empire to return to its correct course to one Matilda Wesser. --- Back during the Battle of the Caldera, anything from Under-Karagril that survived first it being conquered by Clan Mors and then by the Dwarves was piled up and put aside for your attention. The only piece of attention you've been able to spare it was skimming through it to make sure none of it would decompose or detonate, and ever since it's been piled up and waiting for a spare moment. And now, through the magic of delegation, it will finally be seen to. [Rolling...] The final report is largely a long list of bizarre junk more suited to a carnival's freak show or a dilettante's cabinet of curiosities than any serious laboratory, but after the trash is discarded the more valuable items show themselves. It seems Clan Moulder demanded the best of equipment and their tendrils stretched far and wide to achieve this, as a shocking amount of equipment bears the marks of smiths, factories, and glassblowers from human nations throughout the Old World. They require thorough cleaning, then purification in fire, then a close examination on your part to determine no taint has slipped through, but after you're satisfied with their cleanliness you pick out the few choicest parts for your own laboratory and then allow the remaining to be shipped north in a slightly precariously-piled wagon. In the coming weeks, you receive a note of thanks from the College's Archivist thanking you for the pieces that the Colleges decided were of use, as well as a small purse from the sale of the remainder, helpfully pre-tithed for your convenience. You're a little disappointed that there weren't fresh tidbits to add to your research burden, but considering how cluttered your vault still is, perhaps that's for the best. [Profit from Clan Moulder devices: 4 College Favour, 114 crowns.] Your second piece of delegation was having Johann take Adela under his wing and teach her what he knows of engineering, as she's been cut off from the informal education she'd been receiving by the presence of thousands of curmudgeonly traditionalists. Johann might not be an engineer, but he did receive a firm education in the basics from the Gold College, who have quite the grasp of things like metallurgy and chemistry and their many applications. From what you pick up when you visit your library, Johann might not be the best teacher but Adela is an eager student, and hungry for any scrap of knowledge she can get. Between the scraps the Dwarves allow her to pick up and the information she's picking up from the Gunnery School and from Johann, she might be able to achieve a truly unique insight. [Teaching: Johann's learning, 35+16+2(Library: Chamon)=53.] [Being taught: Adela's Learning, 62+19+14(Library: Engineering)=95.] [Getting along: Johann's Diplomacy, 33+19=52.] [Adela's trait upgraded: Adaptable Mechanic: Adela has begun to fuse the engineering knowledge of the Dwarves and the Empire with the insight of the Gold Wizards.] The rest of your time is spent split between two projects, switching between them whenever one begins to grow tiresome. The first is the complete book on the We, your notes finally completed after having determined by process of elimination how they communicate amongst themselves. Well begun is half done, or so they say, and in that spirit you properly collate and cross-reference the notes of yourself and Esbern and Seija, as well as the previous papers on the subject. You spend some time searching for a book to act as a template, deciding against taking inspiration from bestiaries in favour of ones on foreign but not necessarily hostile sentient species. Thanks to Qrech's taste in reading materials, you find an ideal template in one of the more sympathetic titles on the physiology and society of the Ogre Kingdoms, and the skeleton of the title takes rapid form. The other project is the establishment of a proper 'firing range' for the Wizards of the Karak. The first step would normally be a survey of the Winds to find an appropriate place, but with the Karags doubling as Waystones, the local Winds are as steady and uniform as one could hope for. So with your pick of locations, you try to balance accessibility with proper distancing from the local population, both for safety and to avoid disquieting them with some of the more esoteric spells. You eventually settle on a small rocky valley between Karag Nar and one of the lesser peaks that surround it, not too far a walk from the Halflings' paths but not visible from their fields. It takes shockingly little Dwarf labour to level a long section of the valley and set up a gravel butt at the end, and though you envisioned some man-shaped targets, possibly with inverted buckets for heads, you consider how long they'd last against some of Adela's more rambunctious displays and instead settle for simple and easily replaceable wooden targets. That part takes very little of your time; what takes more of it is being a good example for your Ducklings and hoping they follow suit, and firing off a barrage of pointed invitations to that effect. Adela shrugs them off completely, and it might be that you're not going to be able to get her away from your library without a crowbar, but Hubert and Gretel prove more amenable. Hubert's still sticking to Lightning Bolt, but he's developing extremely good aim with it, and if he is going to be a one-trick pony, that's one hell of a trick. But it's Gretel that really impresses you, as she uses the target range to learn, practice, and swiftly master a spell that coats an area in frost that wraps itself in tendrils around anything in the area. And as you volunteer to experience, it also comes with a rather shocking sensation of impending doom that has you fighting against the encroaching frost to summon Branulhune before you remember it's only a test. You're sure it would be quite devastating to anyone without a Wizard's mental discipline, especially since they won't know it's coming, and you also imagine that Gretel's comrades in the Besiegers would be able to take advantage of the induced paralysis to fulfil the doom that the spell promises. All in all, you're very happy with the result of your efforts. [Hubert target-shooting: Hubert's Martial, 57+18=75.] [Adela target-shooting: Adela's Martial, 2+17=19.] [Gretel target-shooting: Gretel's Martial, 100+18=118.] [Gretel learns and masters spell: The Icy Grip of Death.] --- Thus concludes the work Mathilde performed these past months, but not every waking moment was filled with work. With whom did she spend her free time, this past year? The four with the most votes will be chosen, not counting those locked in. [+] The Wizards of Karak Eight Peaks (locked in) [+] Social interaction initiated by someone else (locked in) [+] EIC Reports (does not cost a choice) Romance Any victors from the below will trigger a subvote for how you'll spend time with them. For everyone but Panoramia and Johann, this is getting to know them better to see how compatible you might be. For Panoramia and Johann, it will be a first tentative expression of interest. While this would not be a soft-lock, it could be awkward to walk that back if Mathilde decides her heart lies elsewhere. [ ] [ROMANCE] Journeywoman Panoramia [ ] [ROMANCE] Magister Johann [ ] [ROMANCE] Elector Countess Roswita van Hal [ ] [ROMANCE] Baron Anton Kiesinger II [ ] [ROMANCE] The Ice Dragon of Karag Zilfin [ ] [ROMANCE] Chief Bombardier Oswald Oswaldson Fellow Wizards [ ] Gretel, who's apparently spending her newly-earned wealth to make herself at home. [ ] Hubert, as he settles in to his niche with Ulrikadrin. Karak Eight Peaks Notables [ ] Elder Hluodwica, High Priestess of Esmerelda and civilian leader of the Eight Peaks Halflings. [ ] Francesco Caravello, proud Viceroy of the Undumgi. [ ] Sir Ruprecht Wulfhart, leader of the frontier town of Ulrikadrin. Foreign Relations [ ] Barak Varr, to watch the progress of the canal. [ ] Karak Kadrin, to get to know the leaders of the Expedition. [ ] Stirland, to see for yourself how the war against Sylvania is progressing. Friends Abroad [ ] Kasmir, to see how he's keeping himself busy in Sylvania. [ ] Julia, to see what she has gotten up to as Stirland's most experienced spy master. [ ] Wilhelmina Hochschild, to check in on her and see how she feels about the Marienburg situation. [ ] Eike Hochschild, to get to know your future business partner. Following Up [ ] Regimand, to finally get the full story behind the Lahmian plot you were both ensnared by. [ ] The Amber College, to check in on the salamanders. [ ] Follow up on your donation of the Skaven organ-vat, and see what has been made of it. [ ] Pay a visit to your fief, to see if anything has changed. It probably hasn't. [ ] Do a round of the Colleges to check how the Rooms of Calamity are being received. [ ] Other (write in) - There will be a two hour moratorium. - If you have any ideas for other potential social actions, please feel free to suggest them. - I have made some changes to how many enchanted items Mathilde can have on her person. The details of these can be found at the top of the Collection of Important Information threadmark.

Turn 29 Social - 2484 - Part 1

Spoiler: Voting results [*] Regimand, to finally get the full story behind the Lahmian plot you were both ensnared by. [*] Karak Kadrin, to get to know the leaders of the Expedition. [*] Do a round of the Colleges to check how the Rooms of Calamity are being received. [*] Wilhelmina Hochschild, to check in on her and see how she feels about the Marienburg situation. [+] The Wizards of Karak Eight Peaks (locked in) [+] Social interaction initiated by someone else (locked in) [+] EIC Reports (does not cost a choice) -[*] EIC: Start hiring handlers who can then start hiring informers and begin to collect non-public information. The Grey College has a number of nooks for private conversation, each with a slightly different level of security. The one you find yourself in is the least used of them all, the one that would be used if Teclis arrived and wanted to have a quiet word with the Emperor. You and Regimand take the opportunity to rifle through the drinks cabinet, and though it would be in poor taste to pull the cork on something that's sat untouched since the College's founding, anything that's already open is fair game. In deference to the current situation with Marienburg you help yourself to a generous measure of Westerland brandy, while Regimand lingers over the wines before settling on a Morceaux white. "So," Regimand says, glancing over to double-check the door was still closed even though it would take a lot of dispelling and a team of sappers to shift it. "The Conspiracy. Hmm. Ever seen a Waaagh form?" You recall the infighting between the Orc tribes that once called Karak Eight Peaks home. "Never gave them the opportunity to finish, but I've seen them trying to sort things out amongst themselves." "They could take lessons from the way things work in the shadows here. Any given network of low-level dupes can change hands three times in a year without any of them catching on that there's someone new behind the mask or under the hood. We try to encourage this to keep any one group from accumulating enough momentum to become dangerous, but every now and then one of them can start snowballing without us catching on fast enough to stop them, and then you've got a new player on the board. Or an old player returning to it." He sighs. "I don't know who dropped the ball on the Lahmians, or if they're just sneakier than we give them credit for, or if they just got a few lucky breaks in rapid succession, but almost overnight they went from one faction amongst many to one of the major players." "How'd they snare you?" "If you want to play the game, you have to ante up. And there's no ante better than yourself." You can see where this is going. "And you ended up a chip in someone's stack. The Lahmians' stack." He looks embarrassed. "Like I said, snowballing. I made sure the metaphorical chip ended up in the hands of a loose network of Black Magisters up north. They blackmail me into assisting them, over time they grow to know me, I act a little interested and a little reluctant and a couple years later they're either recruiting me fully or at least comfortable enough to start slipping up. But they were warring for influence with a local cult - Khaine or the other violent one, never did figure out which - and they were both too focused on each other to keep from being swept up by the Lahmians." "And let me guess, to really sell your illusion, nobody knew about it." "You know what they say, 'three can keep a secret if two of them are dead and buried in a properly sanctified Garden that you've checked on recently'. Besides, even if I could wriggle out, that would mean there's one less angle of attack on this new juggernaut. I couldn't possibly have been placed to target them specifically, so that gave me legitimacy in their eyes. And in the end, the risk paid off. I'm sure that by now, you've done things you wouldn't have been able to get permission for if you'd asked." Well, you'd have to concede that point. "And through you, they put pressure on me. Presumably because they had enough dirt on you to get your Apprentice in hot water." He takes a drink. "I do think if it did come down to that, you would have been okay. A few uncomfortable debriefs and closer scrutiny for a while. That's part of how the Grey College works - we project an aura of being so harsh on our own that people think we're easy to blackmail, and that leads to us finding a lot of blackmailers. But I had to let it play out, so I told you what they thought the consequences would be for you. So you got placed on the board as a piece in their scuffle over Sylvania." "Countess von Carstein," you say, giving a grim smile at the memory of her end. "She's our best guess for the one that had been chewing through Haupt-Anderssens, though it turns out they did miss at least one. The Lahmians were rather nervous about the whole situation. They never did manage to find out whether 'Countess von Carstein' was a true inheritor to the title, or merely a pretender. They used part of their influence to ensure that the Elector Count title would pass to someone they thought would bring the fight straight to this von Carstein, and weaken both Sylvania and Stirland in the process. There's another useful reputation for you - the Witch Hunters. Everyone thinks they see the witch, they burn the witch, and to be fair there's plenty that do, but at the core of the Templars of Sigmar are thinkers and plotters. Van Hal didn't just throw Stirland's army at Sylvania, he built up and prepared first, and while doing so the Templars were performing their own investigations." "They were positioning themselves to make a play for greater Stirland," you guess. "They had a lot of it. Outside of Drakenhof, most of the Counts and Barons of Sylvania were either Lahmians or in their pocket, and they had a lot of influence in Southern Stirland. Even if they couldn't sweep everything, if things turned out differently Sylvania could have easily swallowed it up in the chaos. But van Hal took the most prominent collaborator out of the picture and then made demonstrations of power in the Ghoul Wood and the Hunter's Hills, which caused a lot of rethinking of allegiances. And while the Lahmians were arguing amongst themselves whether to make their play or pivot to trying to get hooks into the new Van Hal, you dropped a list into my hands." "I've wondered about that, since then. The Templars could have acted themselves. The only reason they wouldn't have done so directly..." "Was one little name on the list. No wonder the Lahmians had so much influence, when they could whisper into the Emperor's ear at night. The Templars are almost never shy about getting their hands dirty, but when the succession of Sigmar's Empire is at stake..." He shakes his head. "Even if they were willing to act, it would cost so much of the influence of the Cult of Sigmar. Influence they've spent generations accumulating." "So they find themselves wondering if they're loyal to the Empire, or the Emperor, or the Church. And wondering how many of their fellows would share their answer." You smile sadly. "But Abelhelm knew one group that had the answer set in stone for them. 'The first obedience of every Magister must be to the ideals and laws of Sigmar's Holy Empire'..." "Thank the Gods for the foresight of Magnus," Regimand says, raising his glass in a toast. "To the foresight of Magnus," you echo, draining your drink. Regimand eyes his now-empty glass thoughtfully, clearly contemplating a refill. "So I added their list to my list, and I, of course, sorted it all out on my own. Or so official history will record if it ever gets out. The rest, as you know, is murder." "And one set of 'natural causes'. How'd you manage that?" He smiles. "Let's just say there was an Amethyst looking to shore up their position." --- It would be entirely self-indulgent to go on a grand tour of the Rooms of Calamity you had commissioned, but you feel you've earned a bit of self-indulgence, especially after you went to check up on the one you'd called the Maze in the Grey College and found it had disappeared between one day and the next, absorbed into the Battle Wizard cloister. Your first stop is the Ambers and their Enclosure, as it was the one you were least sure of. The Tower is just as abandoned as it usually is, and after you climb up into the Room itself it's accumulating its own layer of dust to match downstairs, but you do find a set of clawmarks in one wall that you doubt were left there by the Dwarves that installed it. You take that as a good sign and move on. At the Amethyst Order you're quite surprised to be shown into the office of Elspeth von Draken, who apparently commutes from Nuln on the back of an Encarmine Dragon to maintain whatever hold she has over that city. The meeting is brief but cordial, and she informs you that the Tomb has already been of use - a promising Battle Wizard is apparently well on the road to recovery from an unfortunate incident that has lead to that entire wing of the College being closed off for the past fortnight and counting, and she credits that it wasn't a great deal worse to the Tomb absorbing and dumping most of the errant energies. The Inglenook of the Bright College is already coated in soot, the Domain of the Jades is crowded with potted plants, and the Golds have filled the Alcove with laboratory equipment to house the more dangerous pursuits of True Transmutation and other alchemical goals, and though they won't speak of the details they assure you that you've made a substantial contribution to the Empire's pursuit of the natural sciences. You continue your streak of never stepping foot inside the Light College, as apparently the Apprentices making use of the Lens are quite vulnerable to fluctuations in their environment - which you reluctantly accept, as Hysh is the most elusive of the Winds and the Light College does take in many more Apprentices than any other College, and thus end up with a lot more borderline Wizards that need careful handling. You leave the Celestials for last, both on general principle and because they've invited you to some sort of soiree for their many benefactors, because apparently using the Reikspiel word for 'party' is far too gauche. Your expectations set firmly to rock bottom, you attend at the scheduled time and find that its usual camouflage has been deactivated and the College is deigning to be visible for the evening, presumably so the guests can find it. Another notable change is the doorkeeper is standing ready outside the door instead of lurking inside and waiting until someone's right about to knock to invite them in. To make the best of it, you walk up to him and when he asks for your invitation, you glare at him until he sheepishly admits that he already knows you're invited and to go on in. The Celestial College has an enviable position amongst the Colleges in that it is seemingly perennially in fashion for noble and wealthy houses to consult a Celestial Wizard, the higher-ranked the better - and what's more, very few of them actually press too closely for details, being content with knowing in general terms whether good or ill fortune lies in store for a particular course of action instead of asking for details and being told something they'd rather not know - or rather not be known. Every influential family has its secrets, after all. So the Celestial College are the benefactors of a large number of wealthy patrons, each competing to be the most patronizing, and the Celestials don't actually have to do all that much to maintain the state of affairs. You're passed from servant to servant as you're guided deeper inside the College - which is another thing, only the Celestial College maintains anywhere near this many non-magical service staff - until you reach the central plaza, where a crowd of Altdorf notables have already gathered amongst softly-playing music coming from nowhere in particular and servants carrying plates of drinks and strange and delicate-looking morsels. The crowd is neatly sectioned off into circles in a delicate and intricate dance of status and influence, amongst which a few Celestials are caught like flotsam in a whirlpool, no circle being willing to release their grasp on such a prestigious guest. You note that your own grey robes don't invite the same reaction, and aren't entirely sure whether to feel relieved or insulted. Whatever the emotion, you snag a glass of bubble-wine from a passing tray to drown it, and start to eyeball the most recognisable foods being carried around and plan intercept courses. Then that plan came crashing down with a stage-whisper that could have drowned out a trumpet: "Oh, I quite recall her from my time with the Empress!" As almost every head in the room swivels as one, you're reminded of some of the messier times you've assassinated a Warboss. You barely have time to sigh in resignation as the unstoppable horde of determined status-seekers descends upon you. --- As the evening wears on, you find yourself having to reassess the evening. One careless debutante had asked you about the great reconquest of Karak Eight Peaks, and you'd hesitantly begin telling some of the highlights, and then perked up as some of your more weaker-stomached listeners had bowed out. By the time the Expedition had reached the Karak proper, you'd quite thoroughly winnowed your audience and it was largely split into two camps: the very young who were thrilled to hear about something actually interesting at one of these events, and those elder who had scars or bearing that suggested they'd seen something similar a time or two themselves. Even accounting for the on-the-fly adjustments you have to make to maintain the Conspiracy of Silence (and you're sure you saw a knowing nod or two from the more grizzled members of the audience when 'underground beastmen' entered the narrative) it was a great deal more fun than you expected to have at the Celestial College. By the time your own tale has concluded and the torch has been passed to others to tell their tales of derring-do, you're several glasses in and have found that despite appearances, the little orangish-pink fleshy bug-things on sticks were quite tasty. You're relaxed enough to let the mysterious tides of high society move you from group to group, and you exchange greetings and small talk with a great many people who you barely pay enough attention to to file their names, titles and faces away, just in case. Until finally you reach a name and title that demands attention: Magister Matriarch Maria Stossel, head of the Celestial College. "Such a pleasure to finally meet you, my dear," she says, her voice strangely in rhythm with the unseen music. "We've found that Hall of yours to be quite helpful. A shame that the design requires a roof, but no Celestial can guarantee the stars, so it's something they must get used to." "An honour, Magister Matriarch," you reply, trying to spool your brain back up into working order. "I do so hope you can help out those fellows of the Expedition. It could all end so very badly." "It could, the..." You pause. "Wait, is this in general or a foresight thing?" "And do take good care of that Gunnery School you've got down there. It could be very needed in the years to come." You open your mouth to ask again but she's already gone, slipping away into the currents of the crowd and taking the remains of your good mood with her. You scowl and finish your drink. Celestials. --- The EIC's headquarters is based on the most prestigious street in Wurtbad, and though that made sense at the time, the lack of space to expand has chafed, being a constantly-discussed refrain in the reports you've received. Gobbling up the two neighbouring townhouses had only sated it for a time, and buying out the whole street one house at a time would be wincingly expensive, even for the EIC, but its position between the road and Wurtbad's inner wall left no alternatives. Or so it seemed. Because under your curious gaze, in broad daylight, workmen with large hammers are breaking up the bricks of the wall directly behind the EIC headquarters. "Sally port," Wilhelmina says around a mouthful of biscuit when you ask her, her office stacked higher than usual with paperwork. "'Scuse me. We fund the construction of a new sally port on the inner wall, portcullis and all, and in exchange we can use it in times of peace. We could buy up the entire street on the other side for about what another couple of townhouses on this side would cost." "That makes sense. I thought it would be out of character for the Elector Countess to just let you knock a hole in the wall." "Let us pay handsomely for the privilege of knocking a hole in the wall," she grumbles. "Anyway, I suppose you're here about Marienburg?" "The Chamberlain of the Seal pulling me aside was something of a wake-up call." "This talk of a blockade has everyone in a tizzy. And it is a bloody blockade, even if they just say it's an embargo. It's blocking the Reik, the bloody monopolists. Glad you gave him the hardline. They'll back down, they don't have the guts to take on the Empire and Barak Varr." "I take it it's not yet war, then." "Well, they technically haven't started the embargo yet. It's all saber rattling back and forth at this point, and I won't be surprised if it never becomes more than that. The Directorate is mostly merchants, they won't take the loss from shutting off trade if they don't think it will pay off. And a miffed Dreadnought at their front door would do bad things to their bottom line, I'm sure." "They might not act so directly, though. How confident are we of heading off espionage?" "We're built on the bones of the Stirlandian League, we know to be ready for that sort of thing." She frowns, rifling papers distractedly. "But maybe not Marienburg levels. That's the big leagues. So I've taken a lesson from the Ostermark-Talabecland trouble. The Templars are sitting on massive amounts of confiscated peat, and the Dwarves want that peat - fuel for some expedition or something. So I give the Templars crossbows and mark-one Repeaters for that peat, and the Dwarves give me gold, but more important than the gold is if someone interferes with us, they've just interfered with the flow of materiel to the Templars and to Karak Kadrin. And we're already supplying the Army of Stirland and shipping niter to Zhufbar and have our partnership with Barak Varr. If we get caught in the crossfire, it guarantees that war the Marienburgers are so worried about." "I'd rather it not come to that, but if Marienburg is that willing to dig their own grave there might not be anything we can do to stop them." She nods grimly. "They've had it too easy ever since Dieter IV let them loose, if you ask me. They need to learn there's some consequences not even Ulthuan can shield them from." "Apart from that, how've you been? And how's young Eike?" "You know me, there's always something that needs doing," she says with a shrug. "As for Eike, leaps and bounds. Wonderful age she's at. Old enough to learn, young enough to be taught. Hard to believe she's my son's, but then again, hard to believe he's mine. How about that Karak of yours? Any chance it's going to start spitting out silk any time soon?" "It's in Francesco's hands and he's working on it, but we're basically starting from scratch. Neither the Cathayans nor the Elves are going to share how to spin it, even if the same techniques would apply." "He's travelled the Silk Road, so I guess he'd have to know what he's sitting on. Just wish he could get on with it. Every time I see the price of silk I mourn for the profits unmade." On that note, you bid Wilhelmina farewell, slightly reassured and slightly not that she's still as single-minded as ever. To be continued.

The Magister Patriarch of the Gold Order

Instead of charting a course around Sylvania like you normally would to reach Karak Kadrin from Altdorf, you instead detour near it. Your destination is Leicheberg, the unofficial headquarters of the Battle Wizards contributing to the fight against the remaining Vampire-ruled towns. With the armies of Stirland elsewhere, there's plenty of tents and barracks to give each Battle Wizard plenty of space and peace to keep themselves centered without unduly bothering the locals. There is a known trend for Wizards to become less and less able to connect with 'normal' people as they venture further and further into the embrace of their Wind, though the specifics vary from Wind to Wind and Wizard to Wizard. The Gold Order in particular is known for becoming more rigid and uncompromising as they advance, and less able to connect emotionally to others. This makes Magister Patriarch Feldmann an oddity, and an extremely dangerous one, as either through chance or through carefully cultivated ability he has retained the ability to interact usefully with Burghers and Nobles alike. He can claim a great deal of credit for the ever-growing wealth of the Gold Order, built atop the contracts he has bargained and the contacts he has maintained. If there is a downside to this rare power, it's that he tends to be the one sent along with the Battle Wizards to soothe ruffled feathers and calm panicked citizenry, and ever since Emperor Luitpold unleashed the Battle Wizards upon Sylvania, Feldmann has been there alongside them to coordinate, communicate, and keep everything under control. He also, it seems, has made himself quite at home in Leicheberg, having acquired a large and rather opulent manor located between the town proper and the camp occupied by the Battle Wizards. Something akin to a landing pad has been set up in lines of shimmering metal sketched into the hardpacked earth, and the pilot needs some coaxing to be convinced to land on such obvious Zhufaz. When you do finally touch down, a well-dressed majordomo has positioned himself nearby to greet you, welcome you, and show you in, ignoring with solemn dignity the dust kicked up by the gyrocopter that has turned his doublet a light brown. "Magister Weber," Feldmann says as you enter his office, and you take a moment to take the room in. The books lining the walls are clearly his own rather than having come with the manor, as Reikspiel is often crowded out by Lingua Praestantia or alchemical symbols in the titles. Being in control of the corporation that would likely have been responsible for shifting all of this, you're sure the cost of transplanting this library would have been considerable - but compared to the wealth and power of the Gold Order, it probably didn't even register. As for Feldmann himself, he is a tall man with a build that tells of a war fought between muscle and an encroaching waistline, and his eyes are as gold as his robes - truly gold, instead of the light brown sometimes described as such. He also has a neatly-trimmed beard and moustache framing his mouth, mostly black hair with flecks of grey. If he was not wearing the robes of his order, he'd not be out of place in any of the upscale portions of the Empire's cities. "Magister Patriarch Feldmann," you reply, giving a short bow which he returns with a nod of his head. He indicates the seat in front of him with an airy wave of his hand, and you sink into the overstuffed softness of it. "I've been following with interest your work in Karak Eight Peaks," he says, sliding open a drawer and rummaging through it. "It's become something of a matter of pride to my Order that we tied with the Ambers for having the right amount of foresight and ambition to get in on a good thing early. You are to be commended for your diligence, and for your ability to forge ties with the Dwarves - which I can attest is no small feat." "Thank you, Magister Patriarch," you say cautiously. With a tut, he slides the drawer closed and opens another. "You are a woman of many hats," he begins, then eyes your more literal hat and seems to lose his train of thought for a moment. "Magister, of course," he says after rallying. "Knight. Thane. Businesswoman. Loremaster. Archmage, one could argue. None could argue against the results, but if I may be frank with you, and I mean no aspersion in saying so, I have my disagreements with the timetable. Split so many ways, the results of any one facet of your efforts are delayed more than I'd like. Any year could bring war to our beloved Empire once more, and so each year is crucial." "We're talking, I take it, of our subterranean foes?" He smiles. "Your cautiousness does you credit. I do speak of them, and more specifically I speak of the many artefacts and writings you've accumulated. These were, of course, honourably acquired through conquest and I would not dream of simply asking you to hand them over. But you cannot deny that in your hands, the undoubtedly brilliant insights you would achieve would be spread out over years or decades. I would quite like to accelerate that schedule, and I've spoken on the matter to Dragomas and to Algard, who have pointed out both precedent and law give you the power to share or not as you see fit. So as per Articles 4, 11, and 12, I ask you simply to name your price." You control your reaction, and consider his words. "For everything, I take it." "Everything. We'll take responsibility for transport, and our scribes will produce copies of every book and scroll and scrap of paper for you to retain for your own library. The Gold Order can bend considerable amounts of talent and resources to the task, and, one hopes, have usable insights ready and weaponized before the next existential threat we all face. Let us not forget that our Orders were founded in the face of the Everchosen, Asavar Kul, and each year might bring his successor, or a new Waaagh, or a fourth Vampire War, or some other threat to life as we know it. And the calendar will not do us the courtesy of waiting for us to be ready." He places his hands on the desk and leans forward slightly - not enough to be an attempt at intimidation, instead apparently being an expression of sincere intensity. "I am asking you to give up a lot of opportunities, and I do not do so lightly. So in exchange for giving up so many papers and books and all the reputation and goodwill that would come with those, I say to you: name your price. The Gold Order has wealth and influence and secrets beyond measure. Tell me what we must surrender to you, so that you will release your grasp on the secrets of the Skaven." [ ] Name your price: write in. [ ] Decline Example prices: GIANT ROBOT Gold Magisters or Battle Wizards or Wizard Lord assistance for a specific project or expedition Outfitting of an entire College-scale library Complete Gold Order cooperation for the Waystone investigations Gold Order creates and supplies a 'seviroscope' - a way to provide Windsight without interacting with the brain Gold Order outfits a branch college (created through separate Great Deed expenditure) Insights on creating independent, temporary, and combat-capable constructs in the vein of Gehenna's Golden Hounds Gold Order influence, politicking, and bribery to assist with a vote to legitimize the worship of Ranald Outfit the K8P gunnery school with the best equipment, texts and tools available Buy me some spy networks A flying warship, suited for exploration, warfare, and research - There will be a three hour moratorium. Please suggest prices in that time to populate the list with some examples. - The Gold Order is, indeed, very wealthy and very powerful. There's little they couldn't make happen if they put their mind to it. - Magister Patriarch Feldmann is a Magister Patriarch. If he says he spoke to Dragomas and Algard, he's telling the truth. Lying about that sort of thing is a career-ender. - If you accept, this will clear out your remaining Skaven artefacts but will not affect your library. - If you accept, you would receive copies of any papers produced, but will not have future access to the artefacts. - The Gold Order would be extremely able to make it up to Johann and Maximilian if you agree to sell. - Approval voting is permitted. If you want to split the vote between multiple items, do so under a plan name. In the examples below, replace the * with X. - Splitting the vote will get you lesser results than focusing on one item when it comes to the big-ticket items. If you ask for a robot and a flying boat, you'll get less robot than if you'd just asked for robot, and less flying boat than if you'd just asked for flying boat. [*] Example Approval Vote 1 [*] Example Approval Vote 2 [*] Plan Split Vote -[*] Example Split Vote 1 -[*] Example Split Vote 2

Turn 29 Social - 2484 - Part 2

Spoiler: Voting results [*] Insights on creating independent, temporary, and combat-capable constructs in the vein of Gehenna's Golden Hounds You have quite a few thoughts in rapid succession, including vague offence that he thought you could be bought, and then admission that on this particular matter you probably could be when you consider the amount of as yet unpursued ideas you've got that could be made possible or much easier with the right piece of Gold Order lore or expertise. You spend some time mentally wrestling with the idea of a device for visualizing the Winds, but you're still at least reasonably confident you could be able to build one yourself, so the other possibility comes to the fore. "Gehenna," you say. "I want to know how her Golden Hounds work." Magister Patriarch Feldmann leans back in his chair, his face going blank. "I assume you mean on a deeper level than just knowing how the spell is cast. Is this a personal interest, or an institutional one?" "Personal." "You'll have to swear an oath not to pass it on." "The information itself, that would be fine. But I want to be able to pass on anything I create derived from that." "Would you be willing to claim it was entirely an independent creation?" You barely manage to keep yourself from frowning. In the Colleges, you'd normally need to get someone at gunpoint to get them to give up academic credit. But for this, the Gold College would require it? "Yes. I would." Feldmann is silent for a while, then nods. "Very well. I'll have an expert on the matter made available to you. When you're satisfied with your knowledge of the secret, they'll return with the items in question." --- Karak Kadrin, despite its reputation, is not all about mournful doomed souls. The above-ground portions of the Hold are constantly abuzz with comings and goings of hundreds, perhaps thousands of humans at any given time, and as many are speaking Kislevarin as are speaking Reikspiel. Ever since the disappearance of Karak Vlag, Karak Kadrin has been Kislev's only convenient supply of the Dwarven crafts they value so highly, from weapons and armour to the coin dies for their currency. Also for sale are metal ingots and precious stones, hewn from the endless bounty of the World's Edge Mountains. But perhaps more in demand than anything are certificates of passage, the shockingly expensive small steel plates to be affixed to a certain vessel that allows it perpetual passage through Karak Kadrin's territory - whether that be wagons through Peak Pass, or boats through the soon-to-open Stromurbaz Kadrin. A canny merchant could easily recoup the price with only a few toll-free trips through one or the other, but the overconfident merchant could end up paying more than they otherwise would if a wagon or boat is lost, as the plates are non-transferable. There's always a few that think they can get away with moving a plate from one vessel to another, or outright forging their own, and the Dwarves let them think they've gotten away with it right up until they try to pass while laden with goods and the cargo and vessel alike is confiscated. Which, in turn, draws even more traders to the Karak as they bid on confiscated goods and wagons and draft animals, and some of the major merchant houses of the eastern Empire pay the Dwarves for the privilege of having an employee permanently stationed there so they never miss a single auction. The Dwarves may not engage in trade in quite the same way as humans do, but that doesn't mean they're any less good at it. In a closely-guarded warehouse on the Karak's entrance level, a different type of endeavour is underway. In a scene more suited to Zhufbar than the Slayer Keep, a veritable hive of Engineers are at work on the steam-wagons, which are quite different than you expected. Instead of a wagon with various gyrocopter-y bits attached somewhere, they're more like a river monitor given conventional wheels instead of paddle wheels. No wonder the Expedition is so concerned about weather - any decent-sized snowfall could completely rob them of mobility and turn them into oddly-shaped fortifications. Your name got you into the warehouse and resulted in a runner being sent, but said runner still has to delve through the three complete and two half-built 'wagons' to find the leadership of this expedition, so you take your time considering the wagons. Each one must surely represent a fortune in steel and labour alone, let alone the cost of whatever engineering would allow these things to be mobile. The Dwarves are far from impoverished, but this is still a substantial outlay on what amounts to a gamble. Every steel plate could have been a suit of armour, every rivet could have been a bullet, and all the hands at work here and soon to be sent north could have been seeing to the wellbeing of the extant Karaz Ankor. But many Dwarves are unable to fully cut their losses and focus on consolidating. Every loss from the Empire of their ancestors is a constant niggling shame demanding to be addressed. So the Dwarves march off to war once more, and for all their sterling qualities in the field of warfare, they are definitely less suited to offence than they are to defence. You can only hope that this one matches the success of Karak Eight Peaks. "Zhufokrul Weber!" comes a booming voice with an accent you're unable to place. "I understand you represent King Belegar's contribution to this project. Borek Forkbeard of Clan Grimnar, at your service and your..." He hesitates for just a moment. "Your guild's." "And I at yours," you say automatically, sizing him up. Borek has muscle enough to mark him as a member of a Warrior Clan, but between the accent, his position of leadership, and above all the Runes of Grungni rather than Grimnir on his person, you peg him as nobility - almost certainly that of the lost Karag Dum. "I'll be providing what aid I can to help the Expedition get underway." "I look forward to you fulfilling your reputation, then. Allow me to introduce my two lieutenants, Gotrek Gurnisson of the Engineers Guild and Snorri Farstrider of the Rangers." A pair of introductions that speak volumes, as being spoken of by their Guilds rather than their Clans indicates that their Clans aren't recognized by the Karaz Ankor. That usually means an Imperial Dwarf, those that live amongst the men of the Empire instead of the Dwarves of the Karaz Ankor. Is nobody of repute willing to lend their name to the Expedition, or did other qualities get them the positions that would otherwise have gone to more traditional candidates? You exchange the polite greetings with the two, and reach into your robes to produce the collated information you've gathered thus far. "I've compiled information from sources the larger Karaz Ankor doesn't have access to - information extracted from prisoners taken during the Karak Eight Peaks Expedition, and some provided by a member of my Guild who has travelled the area while combating the Dawi-Zharr." You hand it over to Borek, who skims it before handing it on to Snorri, who gives it a much closer examination. "It is almost entirely concerned with the Zorn Uzkul, which I understand to be the intended route for the Expedition." "Aye, we originally intended to go through Black Blood Pass and straight on to Karag Dum, but Runelord Thorek advised otherwise while he was visiting, saying it was more important to minimize time spent in the deep Wastes than it was to go the shortest route." "Which I've said all along," Snorri says distractedly, not looking up from the report. "You're not a Runelord, Snorri," Borek says, exasperation thick in his voice. "Works out better for the wagons anyway," Gotrek says, his voice having a touch of the manic quality Gotri gets when talking about gyrocopters. "I'd give them better odds against a thousand miles of steppe than a hundred of mountain." "In any case, that's the route. We'll have gyrocopters stationed on High Pass, what manlings call Belyevobota-" "She's an Imperial, Borek," Snorri interrupts again. "They use the same names we do." "Well, that's handy. If there's a good thaw going by mid-spring next year, we go. Otherwise we keep preparing for the next year, and failing that as well, we go on the third year, come snow or shine." "Bold," you comment, your gaze meeting Snorri's who has an expression of profound tiredness. You wonder how long it took Borek to be talked into potentially putting it off for even that long. "What is the mission of the Expedition, precisely?" "We'll see," Borek says. "Evacuation," Gotrek and Snorri say at the same time. "We'll see," Borek repeats firmly. "Our Norse kinfolk lasted near four thousand years. Karag Dum will not have fallen in a mere two hundred. If we can establish a new road to them..." "Kraka Drak fell to the Great War, and by the Grudgebearer's tales, they were much better fortified and prepared for it than even Karag Dum," Gotrek says, exchanging glances with Snorri. "Karag Dum has been the front line against Chaos since time immemorial. Grimnir himself set off into the Wastes from there. There is none better able to withstand whatever evils the Wastes can provide." As the bickering continues, you make some unheard farewells and back away from the conversation. --- Emerging from the markets of Barak Varr is the second half of your dragonbone bounty, taking the form of a large and yellowed bone half as long as you are tall, allegedly coming from something called a 'Shard Dragon'. A consultation of your library revealed a great deal of debate about whether they are a 'true dragon' or not, though the exact distinction seems to be hazy and oft disagreed upon. Whatever it is, it makes a fine centrepiece for your next convention of the Duckling Club, and Johann and Max prove difficult to pry away from their inspections of it. Adela talks at length about her growing knowledge of engineering, which you smile and nod indulgently through even though you were already aware of it from Johann's reports to you. Gretel's news is her quick mastery of her new spell, which you're also already aware of, and also that Braganza's Besiegers - still on retainer in Barak Varr - have heard that they're likely to be deployed to patrol the banks of the Skull River to ward off any attacks from bandits. Those Border Princes who live in the shadow of Barak Varr would normally never dare to interfere with them, but Marienburg gold could buy a lot of bravery. Hubert has little to report, but does mention that he's thinking about seeking out a familiar, probably inspired by Wolf's sterling example. Johann's news is quite clear, and hints that Magister Patriarch Feldmann is moving quickly on handling his side of the deal: a gilded staff topped with a steel globe the size of a fist, which at a thought from him can detach itself and float around the place - or, if the wielder is so inclined, propel itself with sufficient speed to punch a hole through an Orc's torso. The staff is also apparently solid steel under the gilding, so it would come in handy for a more traditional bludgeoning as well. Max's reward is apparently more ephemeral, as he mentions he'll be travelling to Altdorf soon for his Magisterial examination. "As some of you know," you say, "we'll be wrapping up our investigations into Skaven artefacts. There's only a few of us here and we're fairly busy, and I've been convinced that the Gold College has the resources for a more thorough and rapid investigation that will hopefully provide useful results for the Empire as a whole. The library will remain intact, though individual books will be rotated out for scribing." Eyes turn to Johann's staff, and to Max's smug smile. "Convinced," Adela says dubiously. "Uh-huh. And what's your part of the payment?" "It's a secret," you say mysteriously. Panoramia smiles. "As in you can't tell because that's secret, or that your payment was being told a secret of theirs?" Perhaps not as mysterious as you thought. "That's a secret too," you say, as loftily as you can manage. --- EIC reports are quite ordinary to the untrained eye, but to someone that has been keeping an eye on their doings since they were founded, it's clear that the company is hunkering down. Manpower on the more far-flung routes has been doubled, arms and training in how to use them is being distributed to anyone who wants it, and a great deal of the recent contracts have been moving goods to or from entities with the power to make their displeasure very clear should someone engineer a disruption. Amongst this consolidation, the Hochlander has been selecting those with the discretion, loyalty, and cunning to handle a different sort of workload, many of them coming from the Internal Investigations division. Though on paper they'll retain their current title and they'll still manage enough regular work to keep up appearances, they'll also begin recruiting agents of their own to turn their attentions to unconvering information of use to the EIC - or to you. The word on the street from throughout the EIC's area of operations shows that more and more eyes are turning north as Marienburg's saber rattling draws attention. Prices on luxuries that travel through the so-called gateway to the Empire are climbing steadily as people stock up in anticipation of supply disruption, and the roads are safer than usual as bands of mercenaries travel in one of two directions: northwest to Marienburg, or south to Barak Varr. Even if it never does come to war, there's going to be quite a few mercenaries richer for the retainer they'll be able to negotiate from one side or the other. The Sylvanian campaign is going quite different to your expectations, as Roswita seems to have developed her patience enough that the Armies of Stirland didn't immediately charge on the enemy walls. Waldenhof is more picketed than besieged as the captured villages of Thyrnau and Hundham are incorporated into Stirlandian rule and being introduced to taxes paid in gold, rather than blood. Mikalsdorf is the weaker of the two remaining towns, but is going to be a nightmare to try to besiege, being bound by Hel Fenn on one side, Grim Wood on a second, and Grim Moor on a third. You're not surprised that Roswita is leaving it for last. But even if it doesn't have enemies visible from the battlements, every road leads to enemies and their allies in Talabecland have gone to the pyres, so unless they can find new allies - easier said than done after the example the Witch Hunters set - they'll be feeling the pinch more and more as the months go on. --- [ ] [TOWER] Grey Battery Seek to expand the capability of the Grey Tower to absorb and store power, whether for firing the Eye of Gazul or other purposes. 50gc. [ ] [TOWER] Far Sight Filled to the brim with refraction cantrips, this tower would allow anyone in it to see in detail any point within line of sight. 2 College Favours. [ ] [TOWER] Protection (COLOUR) Build a tower to magically reinforce or protect the others. Specify wind. 5 College favours. [ ] [TOWER] Anti-Air (COLOUR) Build a tower to magically attack any airborne enemies. Specify wind. 5 College favours. [ ] [TOWER] Smoke and Mirrors Build a tower to enable longer-range teleportation. Will require an action to set up, exact implementation will be determined by rolls and choices with that action. Library Purchases Budget: 300gc, 2 Dwarf Favour. Anything not spent will not accumulate. [ ] [LIBRARY] No purchase. [ ] [LIBRARY] Write-in. Dwarf Favour Purchases Aethyric Vitae can be spent instead of favour at an exchange rate of 3 favour per gallon; for Rune-related purchases, this will also guarantee the cooperation of Runelords who may otherwise be disinterested. To use this, simply add 'paid by Vitae' or similar to an item you are voting for. [ ] [DWARF] No purchase. [ ] [DWARF] Write-in. College Favour Purchases [ ] [COLLEGE] No purchase. [ ] [COLLEGE] Write-in. Other Purchases [ ] [PURCHASE] No purchase. [ ] [PURCHASE] Write-in. - There will be a two hour moratorium. Remember to do all your voting in the same post. - Feel free to suggest other tower purposes.